Okay, game point.
15-14. This team serves.
Let's go. Service! Come on! Come on!
Keep it up. Let's go.
Teamwork! Keep playing.
Hit it to Carrie. She'll blow it.
Don't blow it, Carrie. Hit it.
Carrie!
She blew it again.
- We almost had the game.
- Play the game.
We can't win a game
with her on the team.
Look at her! Just standing there.
You eat shit.
Ow!
- Help me! Help me!
- What are you doing?
Help me! Help!
Help me! Help me!
Have a Tampax.
- Help me!
- Here you are, Carrie.
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
Gross! Gross!
Here. Plug it up. Plug it up! Plug it up!
- Plug it up!
Plug it up! Plug it up!
What is going on here?
This isn't a pep rally.
Plug it up!
Plug it up! Plug it up! Plug it up!
Plug it up! Plug it up!
- Sue, what are you doing?
- Carrie, she's just got her period.
- Who's got her period?
- Carrie.
What are you doing?
Plug it up! Plug it up! Plug it up!
Carrie. Carrie. Come on. Carrie.
Jesus, Carrie!
Carrie, quit it. Jesus. Come on.
Stop it! Now relax. Calm down.
Listen to me.
It's okay. Just stand up and take care
of yourself. Come on. Come on.
Grow up. Stand up and take care
of yourself. Come on, do it. Do it.
- Did you see that?
- No!
Get out of here. Go on. Right now. Move!
Carrie.
Carrie, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I didn't know, okay? I'm sorry.
Baby, come on, now.
Don't you know? Listen. Listen.
I'm gonna talk to you about it. Okay.
Now just calm down. Just relax.
See? They're all gone. It's gonna be okay.
- Isn't she a bit old for her...
- Her first period.
Yes.
Morty, until a half-hour ago, I don't even
think she knew there was such a thing.
That's really hard to believe
in this day and age a girl in high school
wouldn't know something about
- facts...
- Well, she didn't.
But I don't know why
that should surprise us,
I mean, knowing that mother of hers.
Miss Collins, we can't interfere
with people's beliefs.
I know. I know.
- As for the girls...
- Carrie's always been their scapegoat.
- You'll have to do something.
- I will.
But see, the thing is, Morty,
that I knew how they felt.
See, the whole thing just made me
want to take her and shake her, too.
You know what I mean?
- It was just her period, for God's sake.
- Well, we'll send her home.
- Miss Finch, send in Cassie Wright.
- It's Carrie White.
- Come in, Cassie.
- Carrie.
Miss Finch,
would you bring in a dismissal slip?
I thought you might take
the rest of the day and
go home, take care of yourself, Cassie.
We're all very sorry about this incident.
It's Carrie.
Thank you.
Would you like to go to the infirmary?
Lie down for a while?
I think Carrie can go home.
Would you like a ride?
We could call you a cab.
I'm sure she can walk home.
And, Carrie, you're dismissed
from gym for a week.
Just take study hall instead, okay?
- We're all sorry about this incident, Cassie.
- It's Carrie!
Creepy Carrie! Creepy Carrie!
Were you in Chicago
two years ago?
Chicago?
Yes, Bill. Chicago.
Yes, I was living in Chicago.
You knew that, didn't you?
I told you that, didn't I?
No, you didn't. I found out.
You're looking at me
so strangely.
- Mrs. White.
- How have you been, Mrs. Snell?
- Fine.
- And the doctor?
Fine.
- And your daughter?
- Sue is fine.
- Won't you come in, Mrs. White?
- Oh, how kind of you.
- I think Carrie is in some of Sue's classes.
- Yes.
- Perhaps sometime she'd like to visit.
- I'm here on the Lord's work, Mrs. Snell.
Spreading the gospel of God's salvation
through Christ's blessing.
- Yes, of course.
- I have something here,
I know is gonna interest
the doctor and you.
The Teenager's Path to Salvation
through the Cross of Jesus.
I don't think Sue would be very interested.
The children are wandering through the
wilderness of sin these days, Mrs. Snell.
- My Sue is a good girl.
- These are godless times, Mrs. Snell.
I'll drink to that.
We'll all read these.
Excuse me. Please sit down, Mrs. White.
Hello?
Betty, can I call you back?
Margaret White is here.
Are you accusing me?
White.
I can't believe this.
Just let me get rid of her
and I'll call you right back.
I have something here, Mrs. Snell,
that I think you might profit from.
Mrs. White, I'd like to contribute five...
$10.
I see.
I pray you find Jesus.
Wasn't that Carrie White's mother?
Hey, I didn't hear you come in.
What'd she want?
Yes?
Yes.
Thank you.
I know you're listening.
Come on downstairs.
Mama? Who was that called?
You're a woman now.
Why didn't you tell me, Mama?
"And God made Eve from the rib ofAdam.
"And Eve was weak
and loosed the raven on the world.
"And the raven was called sin. " Say it.
- The raven was called sin.
- Why didn't you tell me, Mama?
- Say it.
- No.
- The raven was called sin.
- And the raven was called sin!
"And first sin was intercourse. "
- First sin was intercourse.
- I didn't sin, Mama.
- Say it!
- I didn't sin, Mama!
The first sin was intercourse.
First sin was intercourse.
And the first sin was intercourse.
Mama, I was so scared,
I thought I was dying.
And the girls, they all laughed at me,
and threw things at me, Mama.
- "And Eve was weak. " Say it.
- No, Mama!
- Eve was weak.
- No!
- Eve was weak. Say it, woman.
- No, Mama!
- Say it!
- Eve was weak. Eve was weak.
"And the Lord visited Eve with a curse.
And the curse was the curse of blood. "
You should have told me, Mama.
You should have told me.
Lord, help this sinning woman
see the sin of her days and ways.
Show her that if she had remained sinless
the curse of blood
would never have come on her.
She may have been tempted
by the Antichrist.
She may have committed the sin
of lustful thoughts...
- No, Mama! No!
- Don't lie, Carrietta.
Don't you know by now,
I can see inside you?
- I can see the sin as surely as God can.
- No, you don't, Mama.
- You're hurting me.
- We'll pray.
- We'll pray, woman.
- No!
No!
Pray to Jesus for our lustful, sinning souls.
"God visited Eve with a curse.
And the curse was the curse of blood.
"And he visited Eve with a second curse.
And this was the curse of childbearing.
"And Eve brought forth Cain
in sweat and blood. "
Genesis 3:16.
Mama! Let me out!
Mama, please let me out!
Mama, please! Let me out! Mama! God!
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
Thank you, Mama.
You can go to bed now.
There is power power
wonder-working power
In the blood of the Lamb
Carrie?
Carrie? Carrie?
- Open the door.
- It's open, Mama.
What was that noise?
What noise?
Go to bed.
Yes, ma'am. Saying my prayers.
"What are you
going to leave for us,
"you people in your big cars,
spewing pollution into the air?
"You people with heavy feet,
trampling down the wilderness?
"You people who peer into
the back seats of our cars,
"hours after you come out of
the back doors of your motels?
"Soon all we will have is each other.
"And that could be enough,
"if you will let us have
room enough and air enough
"and peace enough to love each other,
"as you never could. "
I really must say, I must confess,
this poem displays
the most extraordinary talent.
A talent extraordinary for you,
Tommy Ross.
You know, Tommy,
this is slightly different
from running touchdowns
and hitting home runs.
Well, class, any criticisms?
Anyone?
It's beautiful.
Carrie White! Beautiful.
Beautiful.
Beautiful!
"O beautiful for spacious skies,
For amber waves of grain. "
Is that the beautiful you mean?
Is it, Carrie?
Well, I'm afraid, Carrie,
this is hardly a criticism.
You suck.
Tommy? Did you say something, Tommy?
- Who, me?
- Yes, you.
I said "Aw, shucks. "
- Roll call. Blake.
- Present.
- Bourne.
- Here.
- Gogin.
- Present.
- Grace.
- Here.
- Hargensen.
- Litton.
- Yeah.
- McDermott.
- Present.
- O'Shea.
- Pollock.
- Here.
- Shires.
- Present.
- Snell.
- Here.
- Watson.
- Present.
And the Wilsons.
Okay, line up. Line up!
Move it!
On your feet, right now. Two lines.
Alice and Mary, eyes front.
Katie.
You too, Chris. And spit out that gum.
- Where'll I put it, Miss Collins?
- You can choke on it for all I care.
Just get it out of your mouth.
Wipe that smirk off your face, Norma.
Okay. Now, I want you all to know
that you did
a really shitty thing yesterday.
A really shitty thing.
Did any of you ever stop to think
that Carrie White has feelings?
Do any of you ever stop to think?
No, I guess you're too busy
thinking about your dates and the prom.
I guess you can take your pick, Chris.
Who's the lucky guy?
- Billy Nolan.
- Who?
- I'm sorry, could you speak up?
Billy Nolan!
Well, isn't he the lucky one.
What about you, Sue?
- Who's taking you?
- Tommy Ross.
Right.
Now, my idea
for this little trick you pulled
was three days' suspension
and refusal of your prom tickets.
What?
God.
That'd get you where you live, wouldn't it?
And you deserve it.
I don't think any of you have any idea
of just how nasty what you did really was.
But the office has decided
you're to have one week's detention.
Still, there's one little catch.
It's to be my detention.
That's 50 minutes every day,
starting today, on the athletic field.
- Get the picture?
- I'm not coming.
That's up to you, Chris.
That's up to all of you.
Punishment for skipping detention
is three days' suspension
and refusal of your prom tickets.
Any other thoughts?
Good. Now change up.
- Where are you going?
- I can't stay...
- Come on.
- Aren't you going to come?
- I'm not coming.
- You're really not gonna come?
- I'm not gonna miss the prom, Chris.
Fuck!
And, one, two, three, four.
Two, two, three, four.
Three, two, three, four.
Four, two, three, four. Five, two...
Energy, Norma! Come on. Come on.
Eight, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four.
Two, two, three, four.
Three, two, three, four.
Stretch, two, three, four.
Stretch, Norma. Stretch.
One, two, bend, up.
Bend, up, one, two, one, two.
One, two. Faster!
And, one, two, one, two, one, two, one.
And two and three and four
and five and six
and seven and eight
and nine and ten
and 11 and 12
and 13 and 14 and 15.
And, one, two, one, two, one, two,
one, two, one, two, one, two,
one, two, one, two.
Get your knees up.
One, two, one, two, one, two, one, two.
- Come on, you hotshots.
- She can't get away with this.
- I'm gonna get her.
- Let it go, Chris.
Like hell I will.
One, two, one, two, one, two.
- The period's not up, Hargensen.
- It is for me.
Keep running.
- Well, there are ten minutes left.
- Stick them up your...
You can't hit us.
You'll get canned for this, you bitch!
One more word from you
and I'm gonna knock you down.
Do you understand me?
She can't get away with this
if we all stick together. Norma?
Helen?
- Sue?
- Shut up, Chris. Just shut up.
This isn't over.
This isn't over by a long shot!
You're out of the prom, Hargensen.
Okay, the show's over.
In place, run!
One, two, one, two, one, two.
"Telekinesis.
Thought to be the ability to move
"or to cause changes
"in objects by force of the mind. "
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Coach said I'm in the nationals.
- Are you kidding? Hey, terrific.
- What's up?
- Can I talk to you?
- Right now?
- It's real important.
All right.
- Tommy, if I asked you to do something...
- Yeah?
...very special for me, would you do it?
Yeah.
I want you to take
Carrie White to the prom.
How's it looking there?
Hey, Freddy!
Want to go over to Minsky's
for some hard stuff?
No. Some other time.
- You pussy!
- Give me one of them beers.
- Suck on this.
- All right!
Hey, man!
- Oh, shit.
- Watch it, you stupid shit.
- Don't call me that.
- Well, look what you did.
Stupid shit.
- I told you not to call me that.
- Look out!
Dumb punk!
- What, are you scared?
- What, you want to get us killed?
Dumb shit.
You fuck!
Okay, I'll do it.
Don't be in such a hurry.
Come on.
"Don't be in such a hurry. "
I'm hurrying away from you,
you know that?
No, you're not.
- Pain right in the ass.
- You don't mean that.
I don't mean that.
You're crazier than a son of a bitch,
you know that?
Come here.
Oh, shit.
Jesus, what's wrong with you?
- Can't you wait a minute?
- Well, what for? We do this all the time.
You're so ignorant.
Yeah, but that's what you
like about me, right? I know that.
Bullshit.
No? No?
I know what you like about me.
This. Don't you?
No!
Dumb shit.
I thought I told you never to call me that.
You know, you are totally fucked up.
That's it.
You really are, I know that. I'm convinced.
Billy...
Come here.
Billy, come on.
Come on.
I want you to do something.
- What?
- Something important.
Billy.
Oh, Billy.
Oh, Billy. Billy. Billy.
Oh, Billy, I hate Carrie White.
Who?
Hi, Carrie.
Hi.
- How are you?
- Okay.
Good.
What are you doing?
Reading.
Yeah? What are you reading?
It's about sewing.
Sewing. That's good.
If you don't have a date for the prom next
Friday, would you like to go with me?
- What?
- To the prom.
It's next Friday.
I know this is late notice, but...
Carrie. Carrie, let...
You guys go on. Practice those drills
from yesterday. I'll be right there.
Carrie?
Carrie.
Hey, Carrie, what's the matter?
- What happened?
- Nothing.
Was it one of the girls?
- Did one of the girls do something to you?
- No.
Well, what is it, then?
You can trust me, you know that?
- Would you tell me?
- I got invited to the prom.
That's great. That's fantastic.
So what are you down here,
moping around for?
- Tommy Ross asked me.
- That's even better.
- He's really cute.
- I know who he goes around with.
They're just trying
to trick me again, I know.
Maybe not.
I mean, maybe he really meant it.
Hey, Carrie, let's think about this now.
I mean, it might be terrific.
You might have a really good time.
Carrie.
Hey, Carrie, I want to talk to you.
It's about this attitude
you have about yourself.
I mean, you're always walking around
with your hair down, all moping around.
Carrie.
Come here, you big silly.
I want you to look at yourself.
Would you look at that?
Come on.
Now, that's a pretty girl.
Look at your eyes.
Little mascara to bring it out. A little.
Your lips. Try some lipstick. You have
nice pretty lips. And your cheekbones.
Look at your hair. It's beautiful hair.
You could just put it up a little.
Maybe add a little curl.
What do you think? Yeah.
Well?
- Well, what do you want to know?
- Why Tommy asked her to the prom.
- Well?
- I asked him to.
Why?
What for?
What could you possibly
have had in mind?
I thought it would be good for Carrie
to get her to join in with a few things,
and be with people...
- Make her a part of things?
- Right.
Come on, Sue. We're not that stupid.
- Neither is Carrie.
- Maybe not. I don't know.
You mean you're not gonna go?
You're just gonna stay home
and miss your own senior prom?
Come in.
- What is it?
- Just the attendance sheets, Miss Collins.
Thank you.
You know you can't go without a date.
- Is there anything else, Norma?
- No, Miss Collins.
Thank you, Norma.
- Which brings us to you.
- Miss Collins, I have to get to practice.
Well, it's too bad, isn't it?
If you don't mind,
this is between Sue and I.
But I do mind.
Unless, of course, you'd like to continue
this little discussion
in Mr. Morton's office.
What is the big deal?
Because it is a very big deal
for Carrie White, and you know it.
- She already said no, anyway.
- With a little effort you can change that.
- Don't count your chickens.
- Just don't try.
- Fine. I won't try.
- Wait a second. It's not fine.
You can't order someone
not to take someone to the prom.
You know, I can make sure that
you don't hurt Carrie White anymore.
We're not trying to hurt her, Miss Collins.
We're trying to help her.
How?
Hey, Tommy, don't you think
you're just gonna look a little ridiculous
when you walk in with Carrie White?
We don't care how we look.
Do we?
What?
- Hi, Carrie.
- Hi.
- So this is where you live.
- What are you doing here?
You gonna ask me in?
Why not?
Mama's resting.
- What do you want?
- God, right to the point, huh?
- About the prom again.
- I already told you.
I know, but there's nothing
to say you can't change your mind.
- Girls do it all the time.
- Why are you doing this?
- 'Cause I want to.
- No, you're not.
Carrie, now come on,
I don't do anything I don't want to.
- I can't.
- Yes, you can.
Carrie?
- You better go.
- Not till you say yes.
- No. I can't.
- Yes, you can.
I said I can't.
Carrie?
Yes, you can.
- Will you please go?
- Not till you say yes.
Why is it so important to you?
I don't know.
Maybe because you liked my poem.
Carrie.
- Okay, okay, I'll go.
- Good. I'll pick you up at 8:00.
Okay.
What's the matter, Willie?
We gonna wake up the little piggies?
You know, this is a hell of a risk for a joke.
- You want out?
- No, no. It's a good joke.
- You bet it's a good joke.
- It's a good joke.
Look at this.
- What?
- All these pigs.
- What are you talking about?
- These painted pigs.
Stupid Old Man Henty's nitwit
cousin painted them all over the place.
I know, I went out with the girl
that posed for them.
She was a real pig!
Will you shut up?
- Will you let me up here, man?
I'm gonna kill that pig, right?
Piggy! Here, piggy!
I'm gonna bash your little heads in,
and you don't have to worry
about the bomb no more.
Come here, little piggies.
Come here, sucker.
Come here, you little sucker. Come here.
Here's the one, right here.
Come here.
- Will you shut up and do it already?
- We gotta give them a chance.
- Come here, you sucker. Come here.
- Oh, yeah?
You can't do it from standing out here.
Get her done, man, get her done.
- I can't. I can't. You.
- Oh, I knew it. I knew this would happen.
Hold it there, you pig. You fuck-up.
- Do it, Billy.
- You know it. You're just a fuck-up.
- And you shut up.
- Just do it!
All right, move it out, move it out!
That's it. That's it. Come on. Come on.
Move it out.
Yeah, that's my baby. Yeah. Yeah.
Do it! Do it! Do it!
Carrie, you haven't touched
your apple cake.
Gives me pimples, Mama.
Pimples are the Lord's way
of chastising you.
- Mama?
- Yeah?
Mama, please see that I've gotta start
to try and get along with people better.
What are you going on about, Carrie?
I've been invited to the prom.
Prom?
Yeah, the senior prom, you know.
Everybody's going.
It's that teacher that called, wasn't it?
Please see that I'm not like you, Mama.
I'm funny.
I mean, all the kids think I'm funny.
I don't want to be. I want to be normal.
I want to start to try
and be a whole person
before it's too late for me to...
His name is Tommy Ross
and he's a very nice boy, Mama.
- No.
- And he promised to stop in
- and meet you.
- I said no.
- Mama, I've accepted!
- No. No.
- I've accepted, Mama!
- I accepted.
- Come to your closet.
No.
- After all you've been taught.
- Everyone isn't bad, Mama.
- Everything isn't a sin.
- Come to your closet and pray.
Ask to be forgiven.
He's a nice boy, Mama. You'd like him.
You'd really like him, Mama.
Boys.
The boys. The boys. Yes, the boys.
After the blood come the boys,
like sniffing dogs,
grinning and slobbering and trying
to find out where that smell comes from.
Where the smell is. That smell.
Listen, I know where they take them
'cause I've seen it, all right.
- Well, you're not going.
- I already said I would.
Tell that boy you're not going,
or we're gonna move from here.
No.
We'll move and you'll never see
that boy again. The rain's coming in.
- Mama, please sit and talk to me.
- I'm gonna close the window.
Mama, please sit and talk to me!
I'm going, Mama.
And things are gonna change around here.
Witch. You've got Satan's power.
It's nothing to do with Satan, Mama.
It's me. Me.
If I concentrate hard enough,
I can move things.
- Satan is clever.
- No, Mama. I'm not the only one.
Other people can do it. I read about it.
You poor child. Don't you know?
He doesn't let you know
he's working through you.
Mama, I'd know.
He entered your father and carried him off.
- He ran away, Mama.
- The devil tempted him.
He ran away with a woman, Mama.
Everybody knows that.
You must renounce this power.
You must give it up.
You must never use it.
I'm going, Mama.
You can't stop me
and I don't want to talk about it anymore.
Will you keep
that damn light straight?
Hurry up.
Watch it, you stupid shit.
You're getting blood all over the place.
Who you calling a stupid shit?
I mean, you can't even keep
that fucking light straight.
Just hurry up.
Yes, ma'am. We's doing the best we can.
We really are, boss.
Hurry up. I want to go home.
Just keep your tits on
and I'll let you pull the rope
when the time comes.
- I plan to.
- I know.
Ernest. Listen, tonight's prom night
- and everything, right?
- Hi, Freddy.
I didn't know you were interested in going.
I'm not interested in going.
I'm a student here, aren't I?
- I don't know. Are you?
- Sure I am.
I got so much spirit in this school,
I want to be on the committee.
You're a little late, Freddy.
I could have used you a week ago
on the decorating committee.
No, I'm not late, Ernest.
I'm right on time, pal.
I want to collect the ballots, you know.
For the king and queen and the voting,
and, you know.
- Think we can arrange that?
- Okay. Can you be here 6:30?
No. No, I can't be here at 6:30.
I'll be here at 8:00. How's 8:00?
8:00's fine with me.
- Yeah, that'll do. Okay.
- Okay. Well, we'll see you then.
- Yeah. See you, Freddy. Take it easy.
- I'll take it any way I can get it, pal.
Hey, Helen. Helen? Helen!
- What?
- Did you hear about Tommy Ross?
- He's taking Carrie White to the prom.
- No!
- Yeah.
- He can't do that. Where's Sue?
- Yes, he can. He asked her.
- What's she gonna wear?
- Who, Carrie?
A sackcloth?
Freida, you gotta keep
those stars coming faster.
They're coming.
What's this I hear
about Tommy taking Carrie to the prom?
Whatever you heard, it's true.
Why's he doing it?
Everybody is talking about it.
I asked him to
'cause I thought I owed it to Carrie.
And where's that put everybody else?
They gotta deal with it in their own way.
- What do you mean?
- Just something.
- Well, you're not going to the prom.
- Oh, I'll be here.
- You'll be here?
- I sure will.
What do you mean?
You're going to the prom?
Shut up. I will tell you later.
You're gonna be in on it.
Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna be in on it? What?
- Come on. Tell me.
- I'll tell you later.
- I want to know now, Chris.
- Just wait.
Can't you give me a hint?
I won't tell anybody, I promise.
I won't say a word. I promise.
I'm your best friend.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Look, you gotta rent yourself
a tuxedo for the prom.
I know. I only got ten bucks, though.
Ten bucks, you can rent yourself a tuxedo.
You don't have to look great.
- Does this look nice?
- He looks beautiful.
You'll make a good impression
for once in your life.
- Would you go out with me?
- Not with ruffles.
All right, you don't have
to get ruffles for yourself.
You always gotta make a joke, right?
No, I just don't like ruffles.
You don't like...
You don't have to get ruffles!
All right, now look at me, Beak.
Don't I look sharp?
Yeah, it looks good on you,
but I don't look right in a tuxedo.
How do you know?
Have you ever put on a tuxedo?
I don't have a tuxedo body.
- I know, they have tuxedos here for you.
- I wouldn't look right.
Wait a second,
I know just the tuxedo for him.
Well, what do you think, huh?
- I like it. I think it's terrific.
- Look at that. No ruffles at all.
Red. I might've known it would be red.
It's pink, Mama.
Look what Tommy gave me, Mama.
Aren't they beautiful?
I can see your dirty pillows. Everyone will.
Breasts, Mama. They're called breasts.
And every woman has them.
Take off that dress.
- No.
- We'll burn it and pray for forgiveness.
No, Mama.
Well, he's not coming.
He is coming, Mama. Now stop it.
I'm nervous enough.
No, he's not coming.
He's not gonna come.
Go away.
Stop it, Mama.
- Stop hurting yourself, Mama.
- I'm not.
He's gonna laugh at you.
They're all gonna laugh at you.
- No, they're not gonna laugh at me.
- It's not too late.
You can stay here with me.
I don't want to stay with you, Mama.
Look, I'll answer the door
and I'll tell him you're sick.
- I'll tell him you changed your mind.
- Be quiet.
Sit down! Be quiet!
All right. Look,
- I'll tell him that you changed your mind.
- Sit down!
Just sit there, Mama,
and don't say a word until I'm gone.
I'll be home early.
I love you, Mama.
"Thou shalt not suffer a witch to live. "
Tommy, could we wait here just a minute?
Are you scared?
Maybe this was a mistake.
Oh, no. It's not gonna be that bad.
They're a good crowd. Really.
Really.
Don't be so nervous.
Besides, I'd look awfully stupid
dancing by myself, wouldn't I?
Now come on.
As I look back upon my younger days
I really was a maniac
Blowin' up a john with a cherry bomb
Gave the janitor a cardiac
Well, the teachers would say
they should lock him away
And throw away all of the keys
Please
He's outta control
The devil's got a hold of his soul
Many were the times
that my buddies and I
Choked upon a cigarette
Gettin' too drunk to talk
and we could barely walk
Swearin' for the hell of it
Then we'd hitch a ride
to see the president's daughter
Her parties were so outta sight
Right
Dancin' till dawn while her parents
were clean outta town
High school, preschool
Now twelve long years
of the education blues
Teachers, preachers
Now I don't know how
I ever made it through
Boy, you know, Ross,
if I knew you'd look this sharp,
I would have taken you
instead of whatshername.
Don't bother about them.
If they self-destruct, I'll dance with you.
Hey, where did you buy that dress?
I love it.
- I made it.
- Made it?
- The decorations, don't they look great?
- Yeah.
I'm so nervous.
It's okay. You can sit with us.
- Hey, what time is it?
- 8:00.
- Where are you going?
- Just out.
What?
- See you later.
- Sue!
Would you like to dance?
Could we just sit here for a minute?
Oh, sure. Sure, anything you want.
- Carrie.
- Hi, Miss Collins.
- You look so pretty.
- You too. You look beautiful.
Thank you. I know I don't, not really,
but thank you anyway.
- May I sit down?
- Grab a chair.
Thank you.
I'm gonna go and talk to some people.
I remember my prom.
I had a date with
the captain of the basketball team.
And he was 6'7" tall,
so I went out and bought a pair
of three-inch spike heels
so our kiss goodnight would be
less awkward.
So anyway, we went in his pick-up truck,
which, of course, broke down,
and we had to get out
and walk the last half-mile to the prom.
So, by the time I got there,
my feet were so covered with blisters
that all I could do was sit there.
I mean, I couldn't dance.
So we just sat there and just talked.
And it was magic. Is it like that for you?
It's...
- It's nice.
- Just nice?
No. It's...
It's like...
- It's like being on Mars.
- You'll never forget it.
I don't think I will.
Thank you.
Hey, what's going on here?
What are you doing with my date?
- Well, we were just talking, you know.
- Yeah?
Have a lovely time, okay?
And you too.
Bye.
Don't let me catch you
hugging any guys like that.
- I won't.
- Better not.
I won't.
Do you really have to be home so early?
Yeah, I promised.
Okay.
- Sorry.
- That's all right.
Some of the kids are going to go over
to Lewiston's after the prom.
- That's okay.
- What?
If you want to go with your friends,
I don't want to spoil anything.
Would you let me finish?
What I was gonna say
is that, if you'd like to, we could stop in
at the Beehive for a couple of minutes.
- I've never been there.
- No?
Good. Well, then, let's go.
- Okay.
- Okay? For sure.
All right.
Are you ready to dance?
Come on.
- I can't. I don't know how.
- Come on.
- I can't, Tommy. I can't.
- Come on. Sure you can.
I'm not sure
But the more that it's real
The more it's right
What a night
It's as though we've been lovers
All of our lives
There must be a God
Could it be that he's heard me at last?
Because you look at me
As though I'm beautiful
- I can't.
- Yeah, you can. Come on. Come on.
Give me your hand. Just put it right there.
- Like that?
- Yeah. Put this on my shoulder.
- That's right. Okay, just relax.
- All right?
- Okay.
Okay. Just listen to the music.
That's right.
See, you got it. That's good.
You're as good as anyone else out here.
You got it.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
- It's just...
No harm. No foul.
- I can't do anything.
- Yeah, you can.
I can't dance. I can't even... I don't know.
- Tommy?
- Yeah?
Why...
- Why what?
- Why am I here?
Because it's the prom.
Why am I here with you?
Because I asked you.
- Why'd you ask me?
- 'Cause I wanted to.
Why'd you want to?
Because you liked my poem.
Only I didn't write it. Somebody else did.
Carrie, we're here,
and we're together, and I like it.
I do, I like it.
Where there are other girls
But tonight there's only me
I never dreamed someone like you
Could love someone like me
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Hey, you two behave yourselves, okay?
We want to dance.
Just take your seats, please, and
we've gotta vote for the king and queen.
- Tommy, we're on here.
- I know.
You want to decline?
Do you?
Hell, no. If you win, all they do is put you
up there for a school song and a dance.
And then some guy takes your picture
for the yearbook,
so everyone can see
we look like a couple of idiots.
- Anyway, it's the last year. Why not?
- It was so beautiful.
Hey, you're beautiful.
Well, who should we vote for?
They're more your crowd than mine.
I don't even have a crowd.
Let's vote for ourselves.
- No.
- Why not?
Please don't vote for ourselves.
Carrie...
Come on. To the devil with false modesty.
The devil.
Billy! Shut up.
Will you close that a little bit?
Jesus, you want to get caught?
- That Carrie White, she sure is cute.
- Shut up.
Thank you very much
for your...
Thought you said they were gonna win.
They will. Won't even be close.
I called in a few favors.
Can I have your ballot, please?
- Hello.
- Hey, thanks, Bobby.
- Ballots. Can I have your ballots, please?
- Thank you.
Thanks.
Well, thank you very much, there.
- Thank you.
- Thanks there.
Thank you.
Thank you, there.
Ballots, please. Thank you.
Thank you.
Now, Freddy, hurry up, please.
Ballots. Ballots.
Good. Good. Thanks a lot there, Vic.
- Get all of them?
- Yeah.
They're right in back of you,
so start kicking.
Good luck.
More ballots? Thank you.
- I have some more ballots for you guys.
- Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I've got the winners.
All right.
I give you Tommy Ross and Carrie White!
They're all gonna laugh
at you.
They're all gonna laugh at you.
Plug it up! Plug it up! Plug it up!
- Plug it up! Plug it up!
- They're all gonna laugh at you.
We're all sorry, Cassie.
- We're all sorry, Cassie.
Trust me, Carrie. You can trust me.
- Trust me, Carrie. You can trust me.
- They're all gonna laugh at you.
Come on, let's go. Billy.
- We're all sorry, Cassie.
- Trust me, Carrie. You can trust me.
- They're all gonna laugh at you.
- We're all sorry, Cassie.
- Trust me, Carrie. You can trust me.
Trust me, Carrie.
Somebody open this door!
What is going on?
Help!
Attention, students! Calm down!
Mama?
Mama. Mama.
It was bad, Mama. They laughed at me.
Mama, hold me.
Hold me, Mama. Please, hold me!
I should have killed myself
when he put it in me.
After the first time, before we were
married, Ralph promised never again.
He promised. And I believed him.
But sin never dies.
Sin never dies.
At first it was all right. We lived sinlessly.
We slept in the same bed,
but we never did it.
And then, that night,
I saw him looking down at me that way.
We got down on our knees
to pray for strength.
I smelt the whisky on his breath.
And he took me.
He took me
with the stink of the filthy
roadhouse whisky on his breath.
And I liked it.
I liked it.
With all that dirty touching
of his hands all over me.
I should have given you to God
when you were born.
But I was weak and backsliding.
And now the devil has come home.
- We'll pray.
- Yes.
We'll pray.
For the last time, we'll pray.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come, thy will be done...
Hello?
Oh, Betty, thank God it's you.
I don't think I could've handled
one more reporter.
Yeah, well, we're all a little edgy.
She's better. Sleeping too much, I guess,
but Dr. Schneider said that's to be
expected after all she's been through.
Well, he said that she's young enough
so that she'll forget all about it in time.
No. I wouldn't let her go to the funerals.
With Tommy and all the others gone,
it's best we just go away for a while.
It's all right!
It's all right.
No, no, no!
No!
It's all right. It's all right. I'm here.
It's all right.