Check, check.
Head count. Head cou—
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Demo set.
- Let's move.
Clear.
Low Boy, Low Boy, this is Black Cat.
E.T.A. Romeo LZ, one-niner.
We are hot. Copy.
Come on. Get out there! Go, go!
Come on!
Get in.
Cover, cover. On the roof.
Go!
This is Low Boy.
Package is wrapped.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Three weeks ago...
Russian and American
special forces...
apprehended the self-proclaimed
leader of Kazakhstan...
General Ivan Radek.
The forces of Radek were directed
towards the suppression of democracy.
His nuclear arsenal could have
brought the world into a new cold war.
But thanks to the support of one
of the world's greatest leaders...
Radek is now in prison.
Today, we are honouring
this brave man.
Ladies and gentlemen, my friend...
the president
of the United States of America.
The dead remember
our indifference.
our silence.
I came here tonight
to be congratulated.
But today, when I visited
the Red Cross camps...
overwhelmed
by the flood of refugees...
fleeing from the horror
of Kazakhstan...
I realized I don't deserve
to be congratulated.
- None of us do.
- What's he doing?
- Let's speak the truth.
- That's not the speech.
The truth is,
we acted too late.
Only when our own national
security was threatened...
did we act.
Radek's regime murdered over
200,000 men, women and children...
and we watched it on TV.
We let it happen.
People were being slaughtered
for over a year...
and we issued economic sanctions and hid
behind the rhetoric of diplomacy.
How dare we?
The dead remember, real peace
is not just the absence of conflict.
It's the presence of justice.
And tonight I come to you with a pledge
to change America's policy.
Never again will I allow
our political self-interest...
to deter us from doing what
we know to be morally right.
Atrocity and terror
are not political weapons.
And to those
who would use them:
Your day is over.
We will never negotiate.
We will no longer tolerate,
and we will no longer be afraid.
It's your turn to be afraid.
Good evening. Can I get you
to open the briefcase?
- The Russian was a nice touch.
- Tell my mother. She wanted me to study French.
- You know what you committed us to, sir?
- Yeah, I know exactly what I committed us to.
Gentlemen!
Welcome to Air Force One.
Please present your equipment
for inspection.
W-We were just inspected
at the gate.
Sir, this plane carries the president
of the United States, although we—
I understand.
I'm terribly sorry.
Please place your thumb
on the ID pad.
Access cleared.
Hello there. I'm Melanie Mitchell,
deputy press secretary.
- I'll be takin' you in from here.
- Oh, Miss Mitchell.
It is so nice to finally
meet you in person.
The president and I were delighted
we could accommodate your news crew.
So, if, uh, you boys
are all clear?
Now, you know the president's
on a very tight schedule.
So, this is how it works: During
the flight, two members of your crew...
will be allowed outside
the press area for filming.
You'll get exactly ten minutes
with the president, 20 with the crew.
Listen, Gary, the president
is ready to take Congress on.
He's not gonna kiss
their ass for each vote.
Let 'em vote us down
and stand on their record.
Yeah, I'm with him now.
I'll call you from the plane.
- What do they say about the speech?
- Your speech is leading the news.
- They're already calling it the "Be Afraid" speech.
- Good.
With all due respect, sir, next time you
want to make a major policy departure...
you might want to discuss it with your
National Security Advisor first.
- We did discuss it, Jack.
- We discussed it in private, which is
where I thought it would remain.
Well, now it's public.
Now it's policy.
- Get behind it.
- The allies are gonna be very upset
they weren't consulted about this.
It might come back and bite us
in the ass in November.
It's the right thing to do,
and you know it.
There goes the neighbourhood.
If you'd like, I think
we have time for a quick tour.
- It would be delightful.
- Good.
- Andrei, Boris.
Just follow me. Ahead of this staff
cabin is Secret Service, right here.
Don't ever try to go past 'em without
an escort. You will be very sorry.
- Hello!
- Hello.
- Hi.
Thanks for the warning.
And here we have
our in-flight offices.
Mr President!
Over here!
Over here, Mr President!
A lot of the plane's features are classified,
but I can tell you that it's bullet-resistant...
and that it's even protected
against the pulse of a nuclear blast.
I'm not sure
that's very comforting.
Up those stairs is the cockpit...
along with the most advanced communications
centre on or above the face of the earth.
We could run the whole country
from here, or even a war if we had to.
Just last week, the president called
the shuttle astronauts right from up there.
- Melanie?
- Yes?
- The president's arriving.
They should all take their seats.
Right away.
I'll get out of here
and let you all get some sleep.
- Mr President, welcome aboard, sir.
- Hey, Danny. How are ya?
- Mr President.
Change in plan, Danny.
Let's go to Barbados.
- Anything you want. You're the president.
- Boy, I wish.
- Mr President.
- Mr Gibbs, where's my bunch?
The ballet ran late.
They'll be here in five minutes.
- Okay. Lewis, you tape the game?
- Oh, it was a real squeaker, sir.
Lewis, don't brief me on it.
I want to watch it, for Christ's sake.
- We'll be under way in about 30 minutes, sir.
- Okay.
- Mr President-
- Sir?
- Yeah, could you put the game on now, please?
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah, Jack.
- The Iraqis have mobilized
two armoured brigades towards—
Just got it. Gimme 15 minutes.
Get the guys together.
Repel them, repel them. Make them relinquish
the ball. Hear about Notre Dame, Jim?
- Don't, don't, don't, don't.
Don't tell me the score.
- Great game.
- Mr President.
- We need to strategize,
smooth some things out politically.
- What was that?
- Oh, it's not so important.
- It's damage control. Now, what if-
- Gimme a minute alone, will ya?
- What if a quote,
high-ranking White House official—
- Just give me a few moments alone, please.
- A quote, high-ranking White House official...
- unquote, were to qualify what
you said last night, leak it to...
- Stop.
- Drop it. Drop it. Do your self a favour.
- The Washington Post?
It's policy. Drop it, or find yourself
another ride home. Yeah?
Mr President, the Russian news crew's with us.
I told them you'd give 'em a sound bite...
- about life in the White House.
- There is no life in the White House.
- You said it. The president needs some time alone.
- Aha.
Fourteen-thirteen Michigan!
All right, Mr President.
That wasn't you napping during
the performance, was it, Tom?
No, ma'am, it was very enjoyable.
Come on, Alice. You can finish it on the plane.
Let's not keep your father waiting.
- Just try and smile, sweetheart, okay?
- Quick picture, Alice?
- Alice! Alice!
- One picture for me?
- Thank you very much, Alice.
...up over the ball.
Second and five at the Notre Dame 28.
Hudson split wide, Muhammad the l-back. Gives
to Muhammad over the right side, number 25.
He's hit hard by Ron Davis and—
Shh. Daddy's asleep.
How was the ballet?
- It was great!
- Ow!
- Oh!
- Brat. Are you trying to kill me?
- Dad-Daddy!
- Was it really good?
Did you enjoy it? Did you love it?
- It was great!
- Men in tights. Did you hear my speech?
- Yeah.
- "Yeah"?
- You're gonna get yourself re-elected.
That's what I keep tellin' them.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the aircraft commander.
- We'll be taking the runway
in just a few moments.
- So, are you guys comfortable?
- Yes, very.
- I brought you VIP press kits.
- Oh, thank you.
- You're welcome.
...he's allowed to jam that receiver-
- Pass interference.
- That's cheating!
- Only if they get caught.
- Dad.
- Way of the world, kiddo.
The ball's marked at the 37-yard line.
Let's call it third and a long three.
Why didn't you take me with you when
you went to the refugee camp today?
Well, for one thing,
it's not 100% secure.
You got your whole life to live, baby.
You don't need to see that kind of stuff.
Come on, Dad. It's not like
I don't see it on the news.
- It's different on the news.
- All I'm saying is, I'm ready.
You know, for things you
don't think I'm ready for.
- Maybe I'm not ready.
- I'm 12 years old, Dad.
In the caveman days,
I'd be having children of my own.
That's what we call progress, young lady.
You're missing the best part of the game.
God.
Well, we're so looking
forward to seeing you.
- I just can't tell you—
- She is so anxious to grow up.
- Oh, I know, she's—
Yes. The both of us.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Well, she couldn't stay
your little girl forever, Jim.
Well, I was hoping it would last
till she was 14 or 15 or 50.
They hated your speech,
didn't they?
They're afraid we won't
have the guts to back it up...
and that if we do,
it'll be political suicide.
- Remember our first campaign?
- In the House?
- Yeah.
- Downstate, driving around with, uh...
- Who's that kid, our volunteer?
- That— Remember, with the-
- Henry.
- Henry, with the convertible...
- Yeah.
- With the broken top, and the—
- Snow comin' in.
Yeah, and we were the only three people
who thought you could win that.
You didn't give a damn. You knew what
needed to be done, and you did it.
And you spoke from your heart.
And that's what I heard tonight.
Well, it felt good.
Yeah, I'll bet it did.
Sir—
Sorry to interrupt.
Everybody's assembled, sir.
United States Air Force One.
It is an honour to clear you for
immediate take-off on runway two-five.
Air Force One clear for take-off.
Thank you for your hospitality, Moscow.
In Moscow tonight,
President Marshall defended...
the joint military action
against the Radek regime...
an act the administration had been
calling a one-time intervention.
But, in a rare display of emotion,
the president alluded...
to a major change in U.S.
Foreign policy, when he stated...
that America will no longer tolerate
any terrorist government.
Meanwhile, in Kazakhstan, Radek's ouster
has stalled the neocommunist revolution.
These are two of Saddam Hussein's
Republican Guard brigades...
- that have been moved north.
- He knows we're watching.
He knows we'll retaliate.
Why the hell is he sending tanks
to the border?
Could be a response to your speech,
Mr President.
- Maybe he's got a son-in-law out there.
- Very funny.
Think there's one or two he hasn't
shot yet. What does State have to say?
The Iraqi ambassador
is claiming it's just an exercise.
Let's not waste any more time.
Send the Nimitz back in.
...we're leaving Berlin's airspace, and—
...and Roger-
- Gibbs.
- Guys.
- Sleepin' on the job?
- No, sir.
Hey, guys. These are
the advance team reports...
from the, uh,
Miami field agent.
- Take a look at 'em.
- Thank you.
Smoke. There's smoke!
Steward!
Steward, there's smoke in the cabin!
Everybody move to the back of the plane.
Now! Please!
Smoke! Smoke!
Notify the cockpit!
Come on! Come on!
Mr President, stay back.
Get down! Everybody down!
- Oh, my God!
- Code Red! We have a Code Red, Jeremy!
Shots fired on board.
Flight deck Code Red acknowledged.
Bridges, lock that door, now.
- Yes, sir.
- Flight control, this is Air Force One
declaring emergency.
- Get down! Get down!
- Cover up! Stay back!
Move up! I'll cover ya!
Go! Go, go!
- What's goin' on?
- Shots fired, sir!
- My family! What about my family?
- We're handling it, sir.
- Boy Scout's comin' out!
Cover! Cover! Give him cover!
- Daddy?
- Alice, get back!
- Daddy!
- Alice? Alice, get down!
Around here!
Take him around here! Get down!
Ramstein Tower, this is Air Force One.
We are Code Red.
Shots fired on board. Request emergency
assistance. E.T. A: 15 minutes.
Air Force One, acknowledged.
We are scrambling our fighters.
Emergency equipment
will be standing by.
- Get him to the escape pod.
- Boy Scout is headed to the vault.
- The football! The football!
- There it is.
- Get around here!
- Get him down to the pod!
- Don't move!
- Everybody, head down!
Get the president!
- Move! They're on us!
- Where's my family?
- Get in the pod, sir. Get in!
- What about my family?
Air Force One, landing runway 09.
I repeat, runway 09.
Roger. Turning to heading 185.
Descending to 5,000 feet.
Hurry, he's in the escape pod.
Ramstein. This is Air Force One.
Emergency pod has been deployed.
I repeat.
The emergency pod has been deployed.
Ramstein Tower, acknowledge.
We are picking up the homing beacon
and deploying search and rescue.
- Are the scenario options ready to look at?
- Just about, sir.
- Has General Northwood arrived?
- Yes, he has.
- Give me an update.
- Madam Vice-President, this way.
We'll avoid the press.
- Is the president secure?
- Not yet. The recovery team
will have him very soon.
Air Force One, this is Halo Flight Lead.
You are now under escort.
All airspace has been cleared.
Alert forces have been mobilized.
- Is everyone here?
- We're workin' on it.
How the hell did this happen?
How the hell did they get Air Force One?
Gentlemen. Mr Secretary.
Ramstein Tower, we are at ten miles
northwest to final, coming in red hot.
Roger, Air Force One, wind is zero-niner-zero
at one-two. You are clear to land.
They're landing.
- Hey, what are you guys-
- Get down now!
Open the door!
Open! Open the door!
No matter what happens, we land
this aircraft. Is that understood?
Come on, come on.
Flaps, 30.
If we land, we're finished.
- No!
- Get the fuck in the air!
Now! Take this plane up!
Up! Up!
- Get us back in the air now!
- Artie!
- Take it up!
- Artie—
Get this plane back in the air now,
or you die!
- Get up now!
- No!
Get him!
No! Jesus!
Come on, come on!
Come on!
Air Force One,
this is Ramstein Tower.
- Contact those F-15s.
- Sir.
I want them to keep Air Force One
in visual contact at all times.
- What are our airborne scenarios?
- There are no airborne scenarios.
Well, we'd better start generating them,
hadn't we, General? And they better be
damn good, and they better work.
How long can they stay up there
with the fuel they have?
- That's a question of air speed. Wind.
- Altitude.
We need an Air Force One pilot in here.
Any educated guesses as to where
they might be going?
- Iraq, Libya, Algeria—
- Those are guesses.
I don't know if they're educated.
So we better notify our allies. We'll need
secure airspace. Could we keep that under wraps?
- We'll do our best.
- If you could just try and relax,
Kathryn. I'm in charge here.
Well, I don't know, Walter.
It seems to me that they're in charge.
- Air Force One, this is Ramstein Tower.
Please respond.
- We're heading home.
- Air Force One, this is Ramstein Tower.
- Let's get him.
State your intention.
- Don't hurt me!
- Go.
- Yes, I will.
- Here.
- Go.
The president.
The president is no longer on board.
He made it to the pod and escaped.
Keep moving!
Moscow police found six members
of a Russian TV news crew murdered—
the same crew that was cleared
to fly on Air Force One.
- Jesus.
- Oh, please tell me it's not that easy.
No. You would have to generate fake ID,
photo, fingerprints-
- Could be with a little help from Moscow.
- How would they get the weapons
on board the plane?
There's no way to get weapons
aboard Air Force One. It's impossible.
Well, there are enough weapons
already on board to take Panama.
But who has access to them?
- You think someone on the plane helped them?
- What if somebody did,
and they're still on the plane?
Who do they trust up there?
Who do we trust?
Madam Vice-President?
Mr Secretary.
All compromised nuclear launch codes
have been cancelled. New codes are active.
Ramstein, the president's
escape pod has been located.
We're homing in at 285 degrees.
There it is.
Ramstein, we have a strong signal.
E.T. A: Two minutes.
Oh, my God!
Where is the wife and daughter?
- Just wait.
- I want to talk to him.
- Wait, wait, wait.
No, let me go.
Let me see him.
Let me—
Where is my husband?
He has fled.
The coward chose to save himself.
- Yes!
But one can always
strike a bargain.
No, you listen to me.
I don't know who you are
or what you want...
but you will never get it.
He will not negotiate.
Really?
His wife. His daughter.
A man could not live
with himself.
And it would be
such bad politics.
- I think he will negotiate.
- Oh, my God.
Escape pod is visually acquired.
Location off Ramstein
is 284 degrees...
12 miles out.
All the weapons have been collected.
Nevsky, check the plane again.
You have the first watch.
I'll check downstairs.
Ready.
It's Air Force One.
They want to talk to the vice-president.
Hello, can you hear me?
This is the vice-president of the
United States. To whom am I speaking?
This is the person
who controls Air Force One...
the world's most secure aircraft.
What is it that you want?
We'll get to that.
- I would like to speak to the First Lady.
- No.
- No. Why?
- I need to know that they're safe.
The president is safe.
But then, you must know that.
He ran from here
like a whipped dog.
I'm sure you can't wait for him
to get back to making the decisions...
so you can stop sweating
through that silk blouse of yours.
What is the condition
of the people on board?
- Some are dead.
- Jesus.
- What are your intentions?
- What arrogance...
to think you could ever understand
my intentions.
I want to understand
what it is that you want.
What do I want?
When Mother Russia becomes
one great nation again...
when the capitalists
are dragged from the Kremlin...
and shot in the street...
when our enemies
run and hide in fear...
at the mention of our name...
and America begs our forgiveness—
on that great day of deliverance...
you will know what I want.
We can give you a forum
for your grievances.
We can contact
the Russian government.
But you must understand
that it will take some time.
Oh, really? Well, when you talk to
the president, you might remind him...
that I am holding his wife,
his daughter, his Chief of Staff...
his National Security Advisor,
his classified papers...
and his baseball glove!
If he wants them back, he will prevail
upon the puppet regime in Moscow...
to release General Radek.
Fifty for one.
It's a good deal.
How's your blouse?
What assurances do I have
that you'll keep your word?
I'll wait for confirmation that
General Radek has been released.
Until then...
I will execute a hostage
every half an hour.
You have my word.
You must understand that we—
- Hello?
- They're off!
- Dave's the language expert.
- Damn it.
Nobody does this
to the United States.
The president will get back his baseball glove
and play catch with this guy's balls.
We can't do anything in half an hour.
We need more time.
He's a zealot. Tough to negotiate with.
All you can do is wear them down.
Mr Secretary!
Mr Secretary, sir.
We found the escape pod.
It's empty.
So where's the president?
I think we have
to acknowledge the possibility...
that the president...
may be dead.
Why wouldn't they tell us?
Diversion, trying to buy some time.
Could have happened at a crossfire,
and they're afraid we'll retaliate.
Damn right we'll retaliate. We'll release
General Radek into the goddam atmosphere.
It doesn't add up. That terrorist knew
that we'd recover the pod in short order.
He expected
that we'd be talking to Marshall.
Let's not bury him yet.
He could still be alive in that plane.
Let's not forget, this president
is a Medal of Honour winner.
In Vietnam, he flew more helicopter rescue
missions than any other man in my command.
- He knows how to fight.
- Then he's taking a terrible chance
with his life.
The element of surprise
is a formidable advantage in combat.
If he's up there,
he's the best chance that we have.
That pod was designed
for a reason, General.
He has no right
to take chances with his life.
Everything is all right.
What does the psych profile say?
How far do they say he'll go?
He's a Radek loyalist. That tells us
all we need to know, doesn't it?
He'll see this thing through
to the last hostage. Or his own death.
You release this bastard and all
of Central Asia will go up in flames.
- I'm well aware of that, Walter.
- Bring back the old Soviet Empire
under a flag of genocide?
Radek with a nuclear arsenal?
I hate to say this, but 50 people is a small
price to pay to stop that from happening.
- Even if one of them is the president?
- The presidency is bigger than any one man.
- Didn't they teach you that at Yale?
- Can't we release him today
and pick up the pieces tomorrow?
- We caught him before, we catch him again.
- If Petrov releases Radek,
his government will fall.
I promise you that.
Then who's gonna stand up to Radek?
You go to catch him again,
you're gonna find him in Moscow.
With all respect, Mr Secretary, we don't
need more dramatics. We need options.
- It's not an option.
- We need a decision.
- It's not her decision.
- Oh?
- This is a military situation.
I'm the Secretary of Defence.
Check your regs. In the absence
of the president, the buck stops here.
Get the Attorney General
with a copy of the Constitution.
We have— oh, my God—
19 minutes.
I'm gonna consult
with President Petrov.
...37-yard line.
Let's call it third and a long three.
It's gonna be a double tight end set.
Alexander and Brooks.
Malcolm is split wide again
right behind the tailback.
Madam Vice-President, I'm sorry.
I cannot release him.
We would train all our military might
against this one target.
I assure you, though,
he wouldn't stay at large for long.
Maybe so, but millions of lives are hanging
in the balance. I am trying to save a nation!
As am I. No nation can easily survive the loss
of nor soon replace a great leader.
Now, let us be pragmatic. 50 lives
means nothing in the grand scheme.
Well, then, let me be
equally pragmatic.
Our president took a great risk
to come to your aid...
against strong opposition
in both parties and among our allies.
It would be politically impossible
to do so again.
If it meant saving his life,
I would gladly do it.
But I would have to know for sure,
and you cannot tell me he's alive.
- Can you?
- No, Mr President, I cannot.
Then there is nothing I can do.
I am truly sorry. Goodbye.
Okay, Walter.
You and your generals get to work.
He was in Afghanistan with me
for five years.
Find out who killed him
or you lie down next to him.
Okay. They can't keep the plane
in the air indefinitely.
There are only four possible
landing sites in Kazakhstan...
that are still controlled by Radek's forces;
we have to go in and take all of them.
- Can we do it?
- I'd rather take my chances in the air.
No, I just looked at the airborne scenarios.
They're no good. Can we do this?
In the time we have? Messy.
Three more minutes
before they execute the first hostage.
- You have to buy us some more time.
- All right.
It's time.
Transfer the phone
to the conference room.
You, both. Come here.
No. No.
Now!
They will transfer the call here.
So, let's just wait.
Excuse me.
Sir, if you will permit me. I am the
National Security Advisor at the White House.
I'm the man the president
would be listening to.
I believe that you are negotiating
right now with the vice-president?
Unfortunately, in our system of government,
the vice-president is like the Queen of England.
She can't even get airline tickets
without talking to somebody like me.
Therefore, let me speak to
the White House, because I promise you...
I'm the one person who can
make this all work out.
Has he been released?
I've contacted the Russian government.
We've set things in motion...
but at this point
we have to be realistic.
It's going to take more time.
More time?
Your National Security Advisor
has just been executed.
He's a very good negotiator.
He bought you another half hour.
Mrs Marshall, Alice...
if you please, come with me.
It's the first time you ever
seen a man killed, huh?
Leave her alone.
You think I am a monster
that I would kill this man?
Somebody's son?
Somebody's father?
I am somebody's son too.
I have three small children.
Does that surprise you?
- Tell her to answer.
- You leave her alone.
Shut up!
Why did you kill him?
Because I believe.
When I shoot this man
I know in that instant...
how deep was my belief...
that I would turn my back
on God himself...
for Mother Russia.
My doubts, my fears,
my own private morality-
it dissolve in this moment...
for this love.
You know, your father
he has also killed.
- Is he a bad man?
- That's not true.
Why?
Because he does it in a tuxedo
with a telephone call and a smart bomb?
You are a monster.
And my father is a great man.
You're nothing like my father.
What's the goddam number?
- What city, please?
- Washington, D.C., please. The White House.
- Just a moment. Here's the number.
- Can you connect me to that number?
- There's a connect fee of one dollar, sir.
- Fine.
White House switchboard.
How may I direct your call?
All right, listen.
Listen carefully.
This is an emergency call from Air Force One.
This is the president.
Connect me to the vice-president,
please.
Who did you say is calling?
- This is the president.
- Yeah, right.
- And I'm the first lady.
- Don't cut me off. This is an emergency.
Sir, the president doesn't call this particular
phone number. So, whoever you are...
- Trace the call.
- Get a life.
Follow your standard
security procedure...
and trace the goddam call.
Okay, sir. You wanna make a federal case
out of this, fine by me.
- Look- Anyone there?
- Don't move!
- I traced the call, sir.
- Give me the gun.
- Are you there?
- Very slowly.
Oh, my God. I'll put you
right through, Mr President.
Good. Go.
The switchboard has a call from someone
claiming to be the president.
She traced it back
to the White House satellite account.
- The caller's gone but the line is still active.
- Put it through.
Listen to me.
You know who I am.
I'm the president of the United States.
Yes!
Don't think that means
I don't shoot you.
Put your hands
behind your head and move.
This is your lucky day. What more could my
people do? Tell the F-15s to fire at the plane?
Even if they tried, we're equipped
with tactical countermeasures.
- He's talking to us.
- What are you telling me? What do you mean?
I just want you to feel secure.
That way no one will get hurt.
The computer'll fly circles...
around any missile they fire at us,
and they'll hit just a shock wave.
- He's telling us what to do.
- Believe me...
all that'd happen is we'd get
knocked off our feet, that's all!
Shut up, goddam it!
My God. Is he saying
what I think he's saying?
- If we're going to act we have to act now.
- It's too risky.
The president is up there
with a gun to his head.
He's asking us to do that
to Air Force One?
He's not asking. Your commander in chief
has issued a direct order. Do it!
Sir, are you sure that's
what you want me to do?
You heard me, Carlton. And let's pray
it works the way it's supposed to.
Okay, boys, give me some room. I've just
been ordered to fire on Air Force One.
I'm in position.
Missiles are armed.
All right.
Target is acquired.
I have a good lock.
God, I hope this works.
Fox three!
What's going on?
The Americans fired at us.
I have no control.
The computer is flying.
- Mom!
- Are they crazy?
This is Marshall.
Anyone there?
- We're here, Mr President.
- Where's my family? Are they safe?
Well, the terrorists claim
they're holding them. We can't confirm.
Who are they?
What do they want?
They're Russian
ultranationalist radicals.
- They want General Radek released from prison.
- Radek?
- What are our tactical options?
- We're working on that, Mr President...
but the bastards
do have us in a corner.
- There is no rescue attempt?
- I ruled out a midair rescue.
- There's nothing we can do while
the plane is still in the air.
- Then we gotta get this plane on the ground.
Take me off the goddam speakerphone.
Where's Bennett?
- Mr President.
- We cannot release Radek.
They're gonna shoot a hostage
every half hour until we do.
I don't want a plane full
of dead people.
Jim, they shot Jack Doherty.
Oh, Christ.
Kathryn, we can't give in
to their demands. It won't end there.
And if you die on that plane,
does it end there?
Kathryn, we've got a job to do,
whatever the cost.
- Mr President, l—
- Kathryn...
if you give a mouse a cookie—
He's gonna want a glass of milk.
We've gotta get
this plane on the ground.
- Has Bazylev returned?
- No.
Get the plane on the ground.
This man down there evades us.
My patience is running out.
I thought I'd ask you
to come and join us.
It's starting to feel
a little empty up here.
Sit down, please.
Come.
Tell me your name again...
for the record.
Melanie.
Melanie Mitchell.
You travel often
with the president.
- Yes.
- So you, you know everyone on the plane.
Yes.
I bet they like you, huh?
You're a nice person, yes?
Okay. I guess so.
You are trembling.
Why are you afraid?
Because I don't wanna die.
I don't wanna die.
Tell me, what am I doing
at this moment?
You're pointing a gun at me.
Thank you, Melanie.
This is to the Secret Service agent
in the baggage deck.
I will count to ten.
And if you do not surrender,
this nice woman will die.
- No.
- One.
- No, please, don't.
- Two.
- Don't do this.
- No!
- Three.
- Let me talk to him.
- Four.
- I beg you, please.
- Five.
- Let me talk to the agent!
- Six.
- He might listen to me!
- Seven.
- Please, I beg you. Don't do this.
- Eight.
- Don't do this, please!
- Nine.
- No!
God.
Let's just think about that one
for a moment...
and then we'll start again.
Next time, I'll choose
someone more important.
I know what you are thinking,
First Lady.
You want me dead.
Well, it may come to that.
In a war, people die.
This isn't war.
You just murdered
an unarmed woman!
You, who murdered 100,000 Iraqis
to save a nickel on a gallon of gas...
are going to lecture me
about the rules of war?
Don't!
- Mr President. How can I help you?
- Chief, you could help me dump some fuel.
Who's down there on the baggage deck?
The Russian said it was a Secret Service agent.
Who?
- We have no idea, sir. We lost contact.
- Melanie was shot because one of
your men wouldn't show himself.
- I wanna know who the son of a bitch is.
- We'd like to know ourselves.
- Sir?
It's someone who's smart enough to know
if you're hunting with one bullet...
- you wait for a clean shot.
- What are you saying, Major?
I'm saying, sir, whoever that is
down there, he may be our only hope.
Our only hope is that Washington
complies with this bastard.
Because, any minute now,
another one of us is dead.
And you know what?
I'm afraid it might be me.
- Sir, do you see the maintenance panel?
- Yeah, I see it.
Pop it open. There should be
a red switch. Toggle it up.
Hang on.
Okay, we got some
indicator lights here.
To dump the fuel you have to close
the circuit for the pump.
There's no switch, Mr President,
so you'll have to cross the wires.
- Open the fuel control door.
- Hang on here.
There should be five of them.
- Do you see them, sir?
- Yeah, I see 'em. Yeah.
Jesus. A lot of goddam wires.
All right, is, um—
All right, we got five:
Green, yellow, red, white and blue.
- Okay, just hang on.
Let me double-check something.
- Come on, man. Oh, for Christ's sake, hurry up!
Sir, if you get the wrong wire, you'll cut
the engine feeds, and the plane will crash.
Well, then, we don't want
to get the wrong wire, do we?
- First, cut the green wire.
- Green wire. Okay. Green.
- Okay, cut.
- And then, cross that with the-
With the, with the what?
Hello? Cross it with the what?
Say again. Cross the green wire
with the, with the-
For Christ's sake.
Green, yellow,
red, white and blue.
Cross with—
Green—
I'm countin' on ya,
red, white and blue.
Sirs, it looks like
Air Force One is losing fuel.
We're losing fuel.
Somebody is pumping it out of avionics.
I'm going downstairs.
Take Sergei.
If it isn't us coming out, shoot.
A magazine, quickly.
Are you okay?
Sergei? Kolchak?
What's happening?
He's dead. Give us a hand.
Madam Vice-President, the time has come
for you to demonstrate your good faith.
I've been reading
through your press kit.
I understand Air Force One
is able to refuel in midair.
Well, we need fuel.
And we need it now.
I'm sure we can come
to some sort of arrangement.
If you land the plane,
we'll trade fuel for hostages.
This is bullshit.
It's simple physics.
Without fuel the plane crashes.
Everybody dies.
We're trying to do
everything that we can.
- Tell me what I want to hear...
- I need—
or I will execute a member
of the senior staff...
and continue killing
one hostage every minute...
until the plane crash
or refuelling plane arrive.
Well, what do you say?
- Fuel's on its way.
- Thank you.
They'll refuel us.
Ready.
Everything all right?
Yes.
Move.
- Jim. What are you doing here?
- Mr President!
- I never left.
Gibbs.
Watch the door.
Where's my family?
They took 'em to another part of
the plane. We haven't seen them since.
We've got weapons now.
We should try to retake the plane.
Not while they've got Grace and Alice.
I can't take that chance.
What about trying to disable the plane
and force them to land?
I tried to do that. I dumped some fuel.
And now they're gonna refuel us in midair.
- A refuelling tanker? Jesus.
- Sir?
- There may be a way to get
these people off the plane.
- What do you mean?
We have emergency parachutes
in the tail cone, but we're too high.
If we could somehow get a message
to the refuelling tanker...
get him to drop to 15,000 feet,
we could jump.
- They've disabled the phones.
They control the radios.
- No. M-Mr President?
- Sir? The fax machines.
- Told ya the phone lines are out.
No, voice lines and faxes are on
two different systems of encryption.
You disable one,
be very easy to overlook the other.
If this works,
you get to be Postmaster General.
- Come with me. Get these people ready to go.
- Yes, sir.
Remember: 15,000 feet and 200 knots,
otherwise it's suicide.
I don't need this.
Good luck, people.
- Give me a pen.
- Where are we sending it?
- Situation room.
It makes me so proud, Mr President,
that you stuck with us.
- Thanks.
- Whatever happens.
- Yes!
- Come on.
Madam Vice-President,
the Attorney General's here.
- Thank you for coming, Andrew.
- Hello, Kathryn. Walter.
- It's good that you're here.
I'm told that you want
my interpretation as to what...
- the Constitution says about this situation.
- Yes, yes.
Now, Andrew,
my understanding is that...
if the president is out of contact
in a military situation...
the Secretary of Defence
is in charge as second in command.
- Yes, of course.
- Good. Then that settles it.
It doesn't settle it at all.
The president is not merely out of contact,
he is also under duress:
His family is held hostage,
possibly himself a hostage.
It creates an incapacity to discharge
the office under the 25th Amendment...
uh, surely just as if
he'd had, uh, a stroke.
I think the president would dispute
that any incapacity exists.
It exists if a majority of the cabinet,
including yourself, says it exists.
The president may be alive,
but he may not be the president.
- Madam Vice-President,
I think you need to see this.
...CNN breaking news.
We interrupt programming to bring you
this breaking news bulletin.
CNN has received unconfirmed reports
that Air Force One has crashed.
- Oh, my God.
- The presidential aircraft...
- How'd they get that?
- I don't know.
- Was en route from Moscow
when it began its Mayday hail.
- I repeat, we have unconfirmed reports...
- Call the pressroom. We have to issue a statement.
- That the president's plane
has crashed in Eastern Europe.
- Walter. General.
This follows an earlier unconfirmed report
of an aborted landing at a U.S. Air base-
These guys have—
- Take this.
- Got it.
- Bruce, has Air Force One crashed?
- Look, as far as I know that is a rumour.
- Where'd the story come from?
- I don't know where that story came from.
- Listen, listen!
I cannot confirm anything at this point.
- Anything you can tell us? Anything at all?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have a statement.
The president's plane,
Air Force One, has been hijacked.
- Who are the hijackers?
- Please—
Ladies and gentlemen,
please let me finish.
For security reasons I cannot divulge
the identity of the hijackers...
or who was on board the plane.
But I am here to assure
the American people...
that we are doing everything
we can to resolve the situation.
For the safety of all
the people on the plane...
I cannot tell you any more
than I already have.
- I'm sure you understand that.
- Is James Marshall still the president?
I am coordinating with
the National Security Council...
at the White House pending
the president's return...
and, yes, James Marshall
is still the president.
At this time—
At this time I would like
to ask all Americans...
to pray for the safety of everyone
on board Air Force One.
Thank you.
Where is the president?
Everything all right down there?
Yes.
Folks, listen up.
Listen up.
This is your main rip cord. As soon as
you clear the plane, give it a yank.
If your chute doesn't open, this is the lollipop,
your reserve chute. Pull it down. Clear?
Air Force One.
Air Force One, do you read?
Yes, we read.
Go ahead.
Air Force One,
this is Extender 1-0.
- We have been instructed to refuel you.
- Go ahead.
Drop to 15,000 feet
and slow to 200 knots.
Acknowledged.
Two hundred.
- They got the fax.
- Fax.
- Sir, your chute.
- No, no.
- Oh, please, sir.
- I'm not leaving without my family.
Okay, Air Force One, you need to open
your receptacle door.
Pull the yellow lever
on the upper control panel.
- Done.
- Go ahead and close distance, nice and easy.
Almost there.
- Where are your chutes, guys?
- We stay with the president, sir.
Thank you.
All right. That's close enough.
Here we go!
- Go, go!
- Go!
- Go! Come on! Come on!
Go check. Do it!
- Go! You, come on!
- Come on, come on!
The hostages are gone!
We've got—
Okay, so far 25 chutes.
- I can't hold her. I can't hold her!
- What are you doing, Air Force One?
Break away! Break away!
Sir! Can you reach my hand?
Everybody break!
Now, now, now!
- Don't move!
- Let me save him!
He's the president,
for God's sake!
Go get him!
Grab my hand!
Major!
I got ya.
We have the president.
We've lost the tanker?
What else?
- They're counting 32 survivors.
- That means they still have hostages.
- What about the first family?
- No word yet.
Losing hostages will make
the terrorists even more desperate.
Madam Vice-President,
we got Air Force One on the line.
This is Vice-President Bennett.
We're listening.
I now hold hostage...
the president of
the United States of America.
Soon we shall enter
the sovereign airspace of Kazakhstan.
You will cease your military escort
at the border.
If you violate our airspace...
I will execute a member
of the first family.
- Tell our fighters to back off.
- Right. Let's get NATO on
the line and make sure they—
- I want that B brief-
- Get me Ops.
You said a presidential incapacity could be
declared by the majority of the cabinet.
- Would you sign it?
- Under the circumstances.
See who else would.
Move! Come on. Move!
Move!
Dad!
Oh, Jim! Jim!
- It'll be all right. It'll be all right.
- I know. If you go, we go.
You've been very busy downstairs...
haven't you?
Killing my men.
- No!
- You don't wanna do this.
I'm what you came for.
Don't forget that.
Then I kill them.
Just one. You pick.
That's what you do in the White House.
You play God.
Go ahead.
Which one lives?
- I love you.
- Go ahead.
You're not here for this.
You want something.
- What is it?
- Radek.
- How can I do that? I can't do that.
- Well, then you die, the three of you.
I'll do anything to save my family.
Don't ask me for something I can't give!
The most powerful man on the earth and now,
suddenly, there are things you cannot do?
This is very curious.
Stop with your fuckin' lies!
No!
Petrov will never give up Radek.
Petrov is a dog.
He does what you tell him.
Tell him to do this.
Petrov used me.
I just wanted to stop the bloodshed.
He wanted a personal victory.
Petrov hates Radek.
Of course he hates Radek.
Radek is everything he is not:
A great man, a strong man.
Are you saying
he would refuse you?
You'd be playing right into his hands.
Are you an idiot?
You'd make him into a hero:
The man who stopped
the terrorists.
Or better yet,
the man who stopped me.
You talk as if you have
nothing to do with this.
This is all your doing.
This infection you call freedom—
without meaning,
without purpose.
You have given my country
to gangsters and prostitutes.
You have taken
everything from us.
There is nothing left.
Call him.
No. No.
- No.
- No!
- No! Leave her!
- Leave her!
- No.
- I have no choice.
- You have the choice.
- Leave her alone. This is between you and me.
You lose a child,
it hollows you out.
We're soldiers.
You take my life.
Have you no honour?
- I'll count to five.
- No.
- It's gonna be all right, honey.
- One.
- It's gonna be all right.
- Two.
I'll do it.
- Yes.
- I'll do it.
You just leave my family alone.
Leave 'em alone.
Sir, the president of the United States.
Mr President.
We just got an intercept. The president
called Petrov and asked him to release Radek.
- He can't do that.
- He must have no choice.
We have a choice.
I have the signatures
of the majority of the cabinet...
attesting to the president's incapacity.
- Sign it and you can overrule him.
- No, l-I won't do that.
The United States does not
negotiate with terrorists.
It's been our bedrock principle
for 25 years.
You can't give in to them now. It'll be
open season on the United States.
Many more will die.
Jim isn't making this decision as a president,
he's making it as a husband and a father.
History will judge you
by what you do right now, Kathryn.
For God's sake, sign it.
No.
You are released.
I can now confirm that General Radek
is in the process of being released.
I repeat: General Radek
is now being released.
Yes. Yes. General Radek
has been released.
It is confirmed.
They are releasing
the general.
- Now what?
- Now we return to our homeland...
where Radek will decide
how best to use you...
now that we know you are
willing to negotiate.
Our nation needs so many things.
- You said you were gonna release us.
- Forgive me. I lied.
Listen.
Honey, stay down. Jim!
Dad!
- Sir, are you hit?
- Stay with the major, honey.
- Alice, get in the cockpit.
- Don't worry. Come on. Lie down.
Grace?
Grace!
Jim! Jim!
- Let her go!
- Not until Radek is safely away.
Jim! Call it off!
Don't give up Radek!
If anything happens to the general,
your wife will die!
Don't! Jim!
Comrades.
Our forces have arrived
for the general.
They'll pick him up any minute.
You hear that?
It's almost over, Mr President.
Drop the gun!
You make one mistake when you killed
my pilot, Mr President.
No one left
to fly the plane.
And no parachute.
Whatever happens...
you lose and I win.
Get off my plane.
- You all right?
- They're leading the general to the courtyard.
Go. Go! Call Petrov!
Stop! Don't move.
They killed him.
They killed Radek!
Radek is dead.
He almost got away.
Did you hear me, sir? Radek is dead.
Yes! It's the president.
We have retaken the plane!
- How's he doin'?
- Not good, sir.
- I don't suppose you know how to fly.
- No, sir.
- Come along, Major. I'll need a co-pilot.
- Yes, sir.
- How long since you've flown, sir?
- Twenty-five years.
Little planes. Never jets.
- Nothin' like this. Anybody there?
- Yes, we're here, sir.
All right. You got somebody
that can help me fly this thing?
- Sir, this is Colonel Jackson.
- Bob.
- We need to get you out of hostile territory.
- Good idea, Bob.
I need for you to look above
the central video screen.
There's a series of L.E.D. Numbers.
Now, one of them should read 110.
- Got it.
- That's your course heading.
Now, just below there's a knob
surrounded by hash marks.
I want you to turn that knob
counterclockwise to two-niner-zero.
Two-niner-zero.
- We're turnin', Bob.
- Good.
- This course'll take you out of Kazakhstan.
- You're okay, baby.
Now, sir, we can't land
this plane on autopilot...
so we're gonna need
to go over a few things.
- First, let's plan—
- Where's the nearest safe landing site?
Incirlik, Turkey.
- General Northwood.
- Madam?
- What's that?
- Madam Vice-President,
that red dot represents MiGs.
- On a course to intercept Air Force One.
Christ, they took off
from Aktyubinsk.
The base commander there
is loyal to Radek.
General, send our fighters
into Kazakhstan.
Order them to use any and all means
to protect the president.
When you're on final approach, I want
you to keep the throttles mid-range.
- Right.
- Mr President, can you hear me?
- Yes, Kathryn.
- We're tracking six MiGs
closing on your position.
I'm sending in our F-15s
to protect you.
- Shit.
- She say MiGs?
Yeah, she said MiGs. Honey, get in
that seat and put a seat belt on.
We're havin' a little trouble here.
Guys, these MiGs get closer,
I'm gonna have to manoeuver this thing.
- How do I get it off autopilot?
- Push the button on the yoke by your left thumb.
I'll try a little, uh, right turn.
Just keep your moves smooth and steady.
It's all flying, sir.
Just step on the ball, huh?
That's right.
Just like riding a bike.
Halo Flight, we are cleared to commit,
bearing 090.
Jettison tanks and push it up.
These MiGs,
how far away are they?
Never mind.
We've got one comin' at us.
Countermeasures are activated.
Left turn.
- Jesus Christ!
- We need some help here.
U.S. Fighters, this is Air Force One.
We are under attack. Where the hell are you?
Air Force One, this is Halo Flight
closing on your position.
- E.T. A: Two minutes.
- We may not be here in two minutes.
We're hit!
Christ! Um, we're on fire.
We got an engine on fire.
- Number four engine is on fire.
- Pull the fire handle overhead.
Okay, I got it. I got it.
- Christ, we're rolling right.
- Left rudder. You have to compensate.
- Should I pull back on number one engine?
- Negative. You'll slow down.
- You have to trim it out.
- How do I do that?
- Knob. Aft pedestal.
- Jesus Christ!
We got a red light here. Oh, Christ.
Looks like we're losing fuel.
Halo Flight,
everybody lock a bandit.
Stand by for max range,
and Fox three!
Kill one! Kill one!
Kill two! Four more bandits
bearing 090. Halo Flight engage.
Good guys are here.
- Air Force One, bug out west. We'll cover you.
- You got it!
- Sir, pull up! You got one on your tail!
- Get him off my tail!
Missile away.
Air Force One, break left and climb!
Shit!
Sir, we've lost countermeasures.
This is Halo Two. They've lost
countermeasures. I'm goin' in.
Two's down! Halo Two is down!
Air Force One, are you still with us?
Yes, we're still here.
- Bandit's above us. Bandit's above us!
- Not so fast, you son of a bitch!
The last three MiGs
are bugging out, sir. We're clear!
Yes!
- Bob, are you still there?
- Yes, sir.
- We've a little problem here.
- My rudder is sluggish.
- Let me take a look, sir.
Oh, man. Sir, you're torn up
pretty bad out here.
Do you have
any elevator control?
Sluggish too.
And we're still losing fuel.
Okay.
We got a problem up here.
Sirs, Air Force One is badly hit.
With the damage,
there's no way they can land.
I'm sorry, sir.
- Thanks for your help.
- I'll stay on your wing, sir.
Take it straight and steady
until we figure out what to do.
Sir...
you did great.
They can't control the plane. The engines
are failing, and they're losing fuel.
There must be something
we can do to help them.
- General, is that our airstrip strike team?
- Yeah. Why?
I just had a wild idea.
Time is critical.
Start turning north.
- You'll get more details en route.
- Yes, sir.
Change of orders acknowledged.
Try to hold your heading, sir.
They'll be rejoining from the south
in about 25 minutes.
- All right.
- We know it's risky.
- Understood.
But we are all out of options.
- Dad?
- Yeah, baby?
It'll be okay.
Everything's gonna work.
Concerned Americans have gathered here
at the White House...
to await word on the president and his family,
but CNN has learned that Air Force One...
is severely crippled
and virtually unlandable.
Sources report that the first family
is still trapped on board...
and a daring midair rescue operation
is said to be under way.
Air Force One, this is Liberty 2-4,
approaching on your left side.
- Do you read?
- Air Force One, loud and clear.
Gibbs, they're here.
Get the door.
- Yes, sir.
- We'll need 10,000 feet, 200 knots.
We gotta get her
slowed down now.
Air Force One and Liberty 2-4,
this is AWACS Blue Star.
We have you on radar contact.
Liberty 2-4,
they're almost out of fuel.
Roger, Blue Star. Air Force One,
you've got to keep the wings level.
If the engines fail,
sacrifice altitude to maintain airspeed.
- Ready!
- Liberty 2-4, ramp leader.
First man is on his way.
Back up. Easy.
Air Force One, come left six.
- How's my speed?
- It's good. Everything's good.
See if you can hold it.
A little more left, sir.
Three, two, stop.
Take my arm!
Pull me in!
Come on! Come on!
- Unhook me!
- I got it! I got it!
Good!
Liberty locked in.
Where's the president?
Up in the cockpit.
- Just lost another engine.
- Liberty, we just lost another engine.
- Liberty 2-4, acknowledged.
- Sir, time to go.
- Who's gonna fly the plane?
- I'll take care of that, sir.
- Got it.
- Go!
Ramp to pilot.
Second P.J.'s on the way.
- Mr President, this way.
- My family first.
- Sir, I have orders
to take you off this aircraft.
- Them first.
Blue Star, the third parajumper
is boarding Air Force One.
- Standing by for recovery.
- Roger. Moving into the receiver position.
- Dad?
- You'll be all right, honey.
- Promise?
- Promise. Close your eyes.
You can do it.
Just hold on tight.
It's okay. Don't worry.
- She's okay.
- Ah, Dad!
- Hang on! Hang on!
- Ramp to pilot. We got her. We got her.
Got her? Here you go.
Yeah. I got you.
I'm right behind you.
- That's it. Come on.
- There, get your hand!
Just hang on! Hang on!
- You're next, sir.
- Him next. He's wounded.
- Yes, sir.
- No, you go.
- Come on, Shep. Come on, pal.
We've lost another engine.
Air Force One, you're sinking too fast.
We only have time for one more retrieval.
We're passing 3,000 feet.
Impact in less than two minutes.
Get the president out of there!
Right here! Right here!
Easy there. Hurry up!
- He's on.
- Sir, get your harness ready!
It's time to go!
- What about the other team?
- There's no time for the other team.
- I can only take one more.
- No! We're all going!
- That's impossible, sir. I have to take you.
- Mr President...
it's time to get you
off this plane.
Go, sir. Go!
Please, go.
It was you?
- Give me the strap.
- I trusted you with my life.
So will the next president.
Now, give it to me!
You have to release the cable.
We're descending through 1,200 feet.
I'm getting off this plane!
Seven hundred.
Five hundred.
We have to pull up.
Blue Star,
Air Force One is down.
I repeat,
Liberty 2-4,
do you have the president?
Shift your weight around!
You can do it!
- Liberty, do you have the president?
- Stand by.
Wind him in! Wind him in!
- That's it!
- Hang on, sir! Hang on!
We got him!
Liberty 2-4 is changing call signs.
Liberty 2-4 is now
Air Force One.
Mr President,
welcome aboard, sir.