Captain, I'd like to request that
it be me who's the attorney...
That it be myself who's assigned...
No, that it be I who am assigned...
That it be I who am assigned?
That's confidence inspiring!
Good grammar, there!
- Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
- Captain West is expecting you.
Jo, come on in.
Lt. Commander Galloway.
You know Commander Lawrence?
- I appreciate you seeing me.
- Will you sit down?
- I'm fine, sir.
- Have a seat!
- We've had some trouble in Cuba?
- Yes, sir. Last Friday.
Two Marines, a Corporal Dawson
and a Private Downey...
...entered the barracks room of
a Private Santiago and assaulted him.
Santiago died in hospital
an hour later.
Naval Intelligence Service says
the two men...
...wanted to stop Santiago naming
Dawson in a fenceline shooting.
- The hearing's at 1600 hours.
- What's the problem?
They're both model Marines.
Santiago was a screwup.
- It sounds like a Code Red.
- Christ!
I'd like to have them
assigned counsel.
Someone who has both
the legal skill...
...and a familiarity
with the military.
I'd like to suggest that
I be the one who that...
...that it be me who is assigned
to represent them, myself.
- Why don't you get a cup of coffee?
- I'm fine, sir.
Leave the room, so we can
talk about you behind your back.
I thought Code Reds weren't
going on anymore.
Who knows what goes on at Guantanamo
with the Marines?
We'd better find out before
the rest of the world does.
What about this Commander Galloway?
She's been working a desk at Internal
Affairs for a little over a year.
She disposed of three cases
in two years.
Who's she handling? Rosenberg's?
- She's not a litigator.
- But a hell of an investigator...
In Internal Affairs, sure. She can
crawl up a lawyer's ass with the best.
I know, I know, all passion,
no street smarts. Bring her back in.
Jo.
- We'll have the defendants moved here.
- Thank you, sir.
And I'll have Division
assign them counsel.
But, not me?
You're too valuable to waste...
...on a five-minute plea bargain
and a week's paperwork.
- There might be more involved.
- Don't worry about it.
Division will assign the right man
for the job.
Let's go, let's get two!
Sorry.
Nothing to be sorry about.
Look the ball into your glove.
Keep your eyes open!
Then you'll have a better chance.
- Kaffee!
- You seem distraught.
You're stalling
on the McDermott case.
We do it now,
or I'll hang him from a yardarm!
- Do we hang people from yardarms?
- I don't think so.
Sherby doesn't think
we do that anymore.
I'll charge him with being under
the influence on duty.
You plead guilty, I'll recommend
30 days in the brig.
- It was oregano!
- He thought it was marijuana.
He's a moron. That's not illegal.
I got people to answer to.
I'm gonna charge him!
With possession of a condiment?
If you ask for jail time,
I'll file a motion to dismiss.
You won't get it!
I'll file a motion seeking to obtain
an evidentiary ruling in advance...
...then I'll file against
pre-trial confinement.
You'll get three months' paperwork...
...because he smoked
a dime bag of oregano.
Let's go! Let's get two!
- 20 days in the brig!
- 15 days' restricted duty.
- Why am I agreeing?
- You have wisdom beyond your years.
Good morning...
How's the baby, Sam?
- She'll say her first word soon.
- How can you tell?
She just looks like
she has something to say.
Excuse me, sorry I'm late.
You don't have a good excuse so
I won't force you to tell a bad one.
- Thank you, sir.
- This first one's for you.
You're moving up in the world.
Division wants you.
- To do what?
- Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
A Marine Corporal named Dawson
fires a round...
...from his weapon, over the fenceline
and into Cuba.
What's a fenceline?
- Wall between good guys and bad guys.
- Teacher's pet.
Santiago threatens to rat on Dawson
to Naval Investigators.
Dawson and another member of
his squad, Private Louden Downey...
...go into Santiago's room,
tie him up...
...stuff a rag down his throat...
...an hour later, he's dead.
Attending physician says the rag
was treated with a toxin.
- They poisoned him?
- Not according to them.
- What do they say?
- Not much.
They're being flown up tomorrow.
On Wednesday...
...you'll catch a transport down
to Cuba to find out what you can.
In the meantime, go and see
Lt. Commander JoAnne Galloway.
- Any questions?
- I fly at 0600? In the morning?
We'll go by the book,
so I'm assigning co-counsel.
- Any volunteers?
- No. I've a stack of papers to do.
- Work with Kaffee.
- For just four days?
Doing various administrative...
things.
In other words, no responsibilities?
My kind of case!
Right, but I need that report
by Wednesday.
- Hi!
- Hold on... Hi!
Daniel Kaffee.
I was told to meet...
...Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
- About a briefing.
- I'll call you back.
- You're the attorney?
- Yes, and this is Sam Weinberg.
- I have no responsibilities.
- Have a seat.
- Have you been in the Navy long?
- Nine months now.
- And when did you graduate?
- A year ago.
- I see.
- Have I done something wrong?
When I asked for counsel,
I hoped to be taken seriously.
No offence taken.
He's our best litigator. He obtained
44 plea bargains in nine months.
- Almost got my steak knives.
- Have you ever been in court?
I had my licence suspended...
They need a priest, not a lawyer.
No, they'll need a lawyer.
Dawson's family has been contacted.
Downey just has his aunt.
- Shall I contact her?
- Sure, if you feel like it.
You'll be seeing Colonel Jessep.
You've heard of him?
Who hasn't?
The papers say he's tipped for
the National Security Council.
- Santiago sent these from GITMO.
- That's Guantanamo Bay.
He wrote to all the senior officers,
even his senator.
He wanted a transfer.
No one listened. Are you with me?
Then he offered to trade information
about the shooting for a transfer.
Right. Is that all?
It seems your client had
a motive to kill Santiago.
- Got you! And Santiago is... who?
- The victim.
These letters are not flattering
about Marine Corps life?
And an investigation might
embarrass the Security Council guy?
- Colonel Jessep...
- 12 years.
If they drop "conspiracy" and
"conduct unbecoming".
- You haven't done anything yet!
- Impressive, huh?
- You'll have to go deeper.
- Do you have jurisdiction here?
My job is to make sure
you do your job.
So my jurisdiction's in your face.
Read the letters.
Report when you return from Cuba.
- Dismissed!
- I always forget that part.
He's preoccupied.
He has a baseball game next week.
Tell him not to get cute.
Guantanamo Marines are fanatical.
- About what?
- About being Marines.
"My name is PFC William Santiago -
- of Rifle Security Company
Windward, 2nd Platoon Bravo.
I am writing to inform you of my
problems here in Cuba.
L've fallen out of runs before,
because of dizziness or nausea.
On May 18th, I'd fallen back about
20 yards going down a rocky hill.
My sergeant pushed me down the hill,
then I saw all black and fell down.
The hospital said
it was heat exhaustion.
I ask your help.
I need a transfer out of RS C.
Sincerely, PFC William T. Santiago,
US Marines. "
"PS: In ex change for my transfer, -
- I have information about
the shooting on August 2nd. "
Who the fuck is
PFC William T. Santiago?
He's in 2nd Platoon Bravo, sir.
Apparently he's not happy here
at Shangri-la.
He's asked everyone but
Santa Claus for a transfer.
Now he's telling tales about a
fenceline shooting. Matthew?
- I'm appalled, sir.
- You're appalled.
This kid ratted on a member of his
unit, to say nothing of the fact -
- that he's a US Marine
who can't run without collapsing.
- What is going on in Bravo company?
- Can we discuss it in private?
I can handle this situation, sir.
Like you handled Curtis Bell?
Don't interrupt, I'm your superior!
And I'm yours, Matthew.
What are we going to do about this?
- He should be transferred at once.
- He's that bad?
If word of this letter gets out,
he'll get his ass whipped.
Transfer Santiago? You're right.
Yes, that's the thing to do.
Wait! I've got a better idea.
Let's transfer the whole squad.
No, let's transfer
the whole division off the base.
Jon, go and tell the boys
to pack their bags.
Tom!
Get me the President. We're
surrendering our position in Cuba.
Wait a minute, Tom. Maybe we
should consider this for a second.
Dismissed, Tom.
I'm just spit-balling here, -
- but maybe it's our responsibility
to train Santiago?
Maybe we have a responsibility
to this country to see -
- that those protecting it
are trained professionals.
I think I read that somewhere once.
And I'm thinking, Colonel, that your
idea of transferring Santiago, -
- while expeditious and painless, -
- might not be quite
the American way?
Santiago stays where he is.
We're going to train the lad.
Jon, you're in charge.
If Santiago doesn't get 4.6, 4.6
in his next proficiency report, -
- I'm going to blame you.
And then I'll kill you.
I think that's a mistake, Colonel.
Matthew, I think
I'll have that word in private now.
That's all. Meet me at the "O" Club.
We'll talk about William's training.
- I'll welcome your suggestions.
- Dismissed.
Matthew, sit down. Please.
- What do you think of Kendrick?
- I don't think my opinion...
I think he's a bit of a weasel.
But he's a very good officer, and
we agree on how to do our job.
Our business is saving lives.
We have to take that seriously.
I believe that if we transfer a
Marine who is not up to the job, -
- we put lives in danger.
Sit down, Matthew.
We went to the Academy together,
served in Vietnam together.
But I've been promoted with
more speed and success than you.
If that causes you tension or
embarrassment, I don't give a shit.
Our business is saving lives,
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson.
Don't ever question my orders
in front of another officer.
All the paperwork's in order.
Step over there.
- Hal, is this Washington D.C.?
- All right, let's move.
I wanted to talk to you
about Dawson and Downey.
- Say again?
- Dawson and Downey.
- The names seem familiar, but...
- Your clients?
The Cuba thing! Oh yeah, right.
I've done something wrong again.
Why are they sitting in jail
while you're hitting a ball?
- We need to practice.
- That wasn't funny.
Would you be insulted
if I recommended another counsel?
- Why?
- I don't think you're up to it.
You don't even know me! It usually
takes people hours to find that out.
That was funny!
You're wrong. I do know you.
Daniel Alistair Kaffee,
born June 8th, 1964, in Boston.
Son of Lionel Kaffee, former
Attorney-General, died 1985.
You went to Harvard, then joined the
Navy, because your father wanted it.
You're just treading water here
until you get a real job.
But that's fine, I won't tell.
But if you handle this case in your
usual slick manner, -
- then something's gonna get missed.
I can't let Dawson and Downey
sit in jail -
- because you chose
the path of least resistance.
Wow!
I'm sexually aroused, Commander!
I don't think it was murder.
There was no intent.
Santiago asphyxiated
from acute lactic acidosis.
It was suggestive of poison.
Whatever that means, it sounds bad.
When he died, the doctor
didn't know the reason.
- Two hours later, he said poison.
- Was it Prof. Plumb in the library?
I'll see your supervisor.
He's in the big white house
with the pillars.
I don't think you'll have much luck.
Division must think I'm good.
I appreciate your interest and
enthusiasm, but I can handle things.
Do you know what a Code Red is?
What a pity.
Officer on deck, ten-hut!
Corporal Dawson, sir!
RS C Company Windward!
You haven't been "working
well with others", Harold!
PFC Louden Downey, sir!
I'm Daniel Kaffee,
this is Sam Weinberg. Sit down.
This your signature? Don't say "sir".
Is this yours?
- Sir, yes, sir!
- At least don't say it twice.
- What's a Code Red?
- It's a disciplinary action.
If a Marine falls out of line,
the others get him on track.
- What's the garden variety?
- Sir?
You say "sir" and I look for
my father. Danny, Daniel Kaffee.
What's a typical Code Red?
If a Marine won't bathe,
the men give him a GI shower.
- And what's that?
- Scrub brushes, steel wool.
Was the attack on Santiago
a Code Red?
Does he ever talk?
He will answer any direct question.
- Was there poison on the rag?
- No, sir.
- Turpentine, antifreeze?
- We were going to shave his head.
- When suddenly...
- Blood was dripping down his mouth.
There was blood all over his face,
so Dawson called the ambulance.
- Did anyone see you call it?
- No, sir.
- Were you there when it arrived?
- Yes, and we were arrested.
Did you on Aug. 2nd fire a shot
across the fenceline into Cuba?
Yes, sir. My mirror engaged, sir.
Every American sentry has
a Cuban counterpart. His "mirror".
Santiago's letter says
you fired illegally.
He says the "mirror"
never made a move.
Harold...?
You see what I'm getting at?
Why else would you
give him a Code Red?
He broke the chain of command.
He went outside his unit.
He should have spoken to me first,
then his sergeant...
All right.
Did you intend to kill Santiago?
- No, sir, to train him!
- Train him to do what?
To think of his unit before himself.
To respect the code.
- What's the code?
- Unit, Corps, God, Country!
- Pardon?
- Unit, Corps, God, Country... sir.
The government
wants to charge you with murder.
You want me to tell the prosecutor
'Unit, Corps, God, Country'?
That's our code, sir.
That's your code.
We'll be back.
- You need anything? Books, papers?
- No, thank you, sir!
There's a concept
you'd better get used to.
- Sir?
- I'm the only friend you've got.
- Welcome to the big time!
- You think so?
I hope you're better at law
than at softball.
Unfortunately I play softball best.
I'm off to Cuba, Janelle!
Say hi to Castro for me.
If they plead guilty
they get 20 years and serve half.
- 12. They called the ambulance.
- They killed a Marine.
The lab says maybe
the rag was poisoned.
The Chief of Internal Medicine
says he's sure.
- What do you know about Code Reds?
- Oh, man...
Are we off the record?
You'll get the 12 years.
But you should know -
- Lieutenant Kendrick specifically
told the men not to touch Santiago.
- We playing hoops tomorrow?
- Do we have a deal?
I'll talk to you when I get back.
- Any luck getting me replaced?
- Everyone's your friend.
Listen, I came to make peace.
What do you say, friends?
I took Downey
the comic books he wanted.
He hardly knows
why he's been arrested.
- Look, Commander...
- Call me JoAnne. Or Jo.
You contact them again,
I'll have you disbarred. Friends?
I had authorization
from Ginny Miller, his aunt.
- Aunt Ginny authorized you?
- I called her.
- We spoke for an hour.
- You were authorized by Aunt Ginny.
- It's within my province.
- We can hold the trial in her barn.
I'll sew the costumes,
Uncle Goober can be judge.
I'm going to Cuba with you tomorrow.
"And the hits just keep on coming".
- How's it going, Luther?
- Another day, another dollar.
- Play as they lay.
- What goes around comes around.
- I got my health.
- You got everything. See you!
Not if I see you first.
You're my witness: The baby spoke.
She said a word.
- She made a sound.
- Come on! It was definitely a word.
You heard her.
She pointed and said "Pa".
- She was pointing at a mailbox.
- Yes. "Pa! Look, a mailbox".
- Jack Ross offered me the 12 years.
- That's what you wanted, right?
- I mean... I guess I'll take it.
- So...?
- It took about 45 seconds.
- Take the 12 years, it's a gift.
You don't believe them.
You think they should get life.
I believe every word of their story,
and I think they should get life.
See you tomorrow.
- Don't forget to wear the whites!
- I don't like them.
We're going to Cuba.
You got Dramamine?
- That keeps you cool?
- No, but you get airsick.
It's because I'm afraid of crashing.
Dramamine won't help.
I got some oregano,
I hear that works.
Ross said a strange thing,
just before I left.
He said Lt. Kendrick had told
the men not to touch Santiago.
- So?
- I don't even know who Kendrick is.
What the hell. See you tomorrow.
I'm Corporal Barnes, I'll escort you
to the Windward side of the base.
I have camouflage jackets,
I suggest you wear them.
We're going close to the fenceline.
If the Cubans see an officer in
white they might take a shot.
Good call, Sam.
We'll just take the ferry.
- We're taking a boat?
- Across the bay.
No one mentioned a boat.
I'm just not crazy about them.
- Jesus Christ, you're in the Navy!
- Nobody likes her very much.
Nathan Jessep. Come on in.
Daniel Kaffee, attorney.
Lt. Commander
JoAnne Galloway.
Observing and evaluating.
Lt. Weinberg, my assistant.
This is Colonel Markinson,
and Platoon Leader Lt. Kendrick.
Lieutenant Kaffee.
I met your father once.
He spoke at my high school.
- Lionel Kaffee?
- Yes, sir.
Jon, this man's dad
once made a lot of enemies.
Jefferson versus
Madison County School District.
They didn't want a black girl
in a white school.
Lionel Kaffee said,
"We'll see about that".
- How the hell is your dad, Danny?
- He passed away seven years ago.
- Don't I feel like an asshole!
- Not at all, sir.
- What can we do for you, Danny?
- Not much, sir.
This is really just a formality.
- They insist we interview everyone.
- JAG Corps can be demanding.
Jon'll show you what you want to
see, then we can meet for lunch.
You met with the men that afternoon.
What did you say?
I told them we had an informer, -
- but that Private Santiago
was not to be harmed.
- What time was that?
- 1600.
That's four o'clock.
We should make sure somebody
gets this to his parents.
- Lt. Kendrick, may I call you Jon?
- No.
- Have I offended you?
- No, I like all you Navy boys.
When we have to fight,
you fellas always give us a ride.
Do you think he was murdered?
I believe in God and Jesus Christ,
so I'll say this:
Santiago's death is a tragedy.
But he died because he had no code,
and no honour. And God was watching.
- How do you feel about that theory?
- Sounds good.
Are you going to investigate,
or just take the guided tour?
I'm pacing myself.
They ran around
looking for something white to wave.
Some of them surrendered
to a crew from CNN.
Walk softly and carry an armoured
tank division, I always say.
That was delicious.
- I do have to ask some questions.
- Shoot!
An NIS agent told you that Santiago
knew about a fenceline shooting.
Santiago was going to say who did it
in exchange for a transfer.
If you feel there are any details
I'm missing, tell me.
Thank you.
You called Colonel Markinson and
Lt. Kendrick into your office. And?
We agreed that for his own safety
he should be transferred.
Santiago was set to be transferred?
On the first flight to the States.
0600 next morning.
Five hours too late, it turned out.
All right, that's all.
Thanks very much for your time.
The corporal will drive you back.
- Wait, I've got some questions.
- No, you don't. No!
On the morning of the death,
did you meet Dr. Stone?
- Of course. One of my men was dead.
- You see? He was dead. Let's go.
- Have you ever heard of Code Red?
- I've heard the term, yes.
In February, you received a memo
from the Fleet Commander -
- warning against enlisted men
disciplining their own?
Whoever wrote that memo has never
looked down a Cuban AK-47 rifle.
However, I gave it due attention.
What is your point, Jo?
She has no point,
it's part of her charm. Goodbye!
My point is that I think
Code Reds still go on. Do they?
- He doesn't need to answer that.
- Yes, he does.
- No, he really doesn't.
- Yeah, he really does.
Colonel?
You know, it just hit me.
She outranks you, Danny!
I want to tell you something.
Listen well.
You're a very lucky man.
There is nothing sexier then a woman
you have to salute in the morning.
Promote 'em all, I say!
If you've never had a blowjob
from a superior officer, -
- you've missed the best in life.
- Code Reds are still condoned here?
But I'll just take cold showers
till they elect some gal president.
- I need an answer to my question.
- Watch your tone, Commander.
I'm a fair guy, but this
fucking heat makes me crazy.
You asked me about Code Reds.
On the record, I discourage it.
Off the record,
it's an invaluable part of training.
If it goes on without my knowledge,
so be it. That's how I run my unit.
If you want to investigate me,
take your chances.
I eat breakfast 300 yards from
4,000 Cubans trained to kill me.
So don't think you can come
down here and make me nervous.
Let's go.
Colonel, I just need a copy
of the transfer order.
Santiago's transfer order.
For the file.
- For the file?
- Yeah.
Of course you can have a copy.
I'm here to help any way I can.
You believe that, don't you, Danny?
That I'll help any way I can?
The corporal will take you by
Personnel and get it for you.
But you have to ask me nicely.
- I beg your pardon?
- You have to ask me nicely.
I can take bullets, bombs and blood.
I don't want money or medals.
What I do want is for you, with your
faggoty uniform and Harvard mouth, -
- to extend me
some fucking courtesy.
You got to ask me nicely.
Colonel Jessep, I'd like
a copy of the transfer order. Sir.
No problem.
- Who is it?
- It's me.
I've really missed you.
It's been three hours...
Markinson's disappeared.
He's gone U.A. Unauthorized Absence.
- When?
- This afternoon, after we left.
- I'll find him in the morning.
- I've already tried.
You're close to "interfering
with a government investigation".
I'm Louden Downey's attorney now.
Aunt Ginny feels like she knows me.
So I suggested that I get more
directly involved with the case.
She had Louden sign the papers
an hour ago.
You're not making this up
just to bother me?
- You're still lead counsel.
- Splendid.
I think Kendrick ordered the
Code Red, and so do you.
Ten-hut!
Did Kendrick order the Code Red?
Not: "Did you clean the latrine?"
Did Lt. Kendrick order you
to give Santiago a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
- Did he?
- Yes, sir.
- Why didn't you say so before?
- You didn't ask us, sir.
I get paid, no matter how long
you spend in jail.
- I know you do, sir.
- Fuck you, Harold!
At ease. Let's sort this thing out.
There was a platoon meeting
on September 6th.
Lt. Kendrick says he told you
nothing was to happen to Santiago.
Is this true?
I want you to speak freely.
That's correct.
But then he dismissed the platoon.
- What happened then?
- Lt. Kendrick came to our room.
About five minutes after the
meeting broke. About 16.20.
And then?
Lt. Kendrick ordered us
to give Santiago a Code Red.
Jack!
They were given an order.
- Jack...
- I'll be right back.
- Did you know about the order?
- Jo Galloway: Downey's lawyer.
- What are you accusing me of?
- Did you?
He didn't know,
or he would have had to tell us.
Now our clients might plead not
guilty and say they were ordered.
Kendrick told them
not to touch Santiago.
And then he told Dawson and Downey
to give him a Code Red.
- Kendrick's lying.
- You have proof?
23 Marines and a highly decorated
lieutenant disagree.
- Why did Markinson go U. A?
- You'll never know.
- I can't subpoena Markinson?
- You won't find him.
You know what Markinson did
for 17 years? Counterintelligence.
Markinson's gone.
There is no Markinson.
Look, Danny,
Jessep's star is on the rise.
Division wants to spare him
and the Corps any embarrassment.
I'll knock it down to involuntary
manslaughter. Two years.
No, we're going to court.
- No, you're not.
- Why not?
You'll lose. And if we go to court,
I'll have to go all the way:
Murder, conspiracy,
conduct unbecoming.
Danny's got me by the balls here,
but not in the courtroom.
He doesn't want to see them get life
if they could be home in six months.
That's the end of this negotiation.
See you at the arraignment.
Here's the story: They're offering
involuntary manslaughter. Two years.
You'll be home in six months.
Wow! You're the greatest lawyer in
the world! How can we thank you?
Did you hear what I just said?
You'll be home in six months.
I'm afraid we can't do that, sir.
Do what?
- We can't make a deal.
- What are you talking about?
We did nothing but our job.
I'll accept the consequences.
But I won't say I'm guilty, sir.
- Did she put you up to this?
- We have a code, sir.
You and your code plead not guilty.
You'll be in jail for life.
Do what I say,
and you'll be home in six months.
Do it, Harold.
Six months, it's nothing!
- Permission to...
- Speak! Jesus!
What do we do then? After six months
we'll be dishonourably discharged.
- Probably.
- What do we do then, sir?
We joined the Marines because
we wanted to live by a certain code.
You're asking us to say we have no
honour, that we're not Marines!
If what we did was wrong,
I'll accept my punishment.
But I believe I did my job. I will
not dishonour myself, my unit -
- or the Corps,
so that I can go home in six months.
Sir!
I'd like to talk to Corporal Dawson
alone for a minute.
Sergeant!
- We'd like to go to another room.
- Sit down.
You don't like me very much,
do you?
Forget it, it doesn't matter.
You know...
Downey worships you.
He'll do whatever you do.
Are you going to let this
happen to him because of a code?
Do you think we were right?
Do you?
I think you'd lose.
You're such a coward.
I can't believe you're in uniform.
I won't be responsible for this.
If you go to Leavenworth for life,
I don't give a shit!
What about saluting
an officer when he leaves the room?
I don't believe it!
He's going to jail to spite me!
If he wants to jump off a cliff,
that's his business.
- How do I get him a new lawyer?
- At the arraignment.
Just tell the judge
you want new counsel assigned.
That's that.
One thing, though.
Be sure and ask nicely.
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to make an argument.
That didn't help Calley at My Lai,
or the Nazis at Nuremburg.
Do you think that's the same -
- as two teenagers executing an
order they didn't think would harm?
Don't look now,
but you're making an argument.
I'll get them a new attorney.
What are you afraid of?
You father's expectations?
Spare me the psychobabble!
They'll just have another lawyer.
They need you.
You know how to win.
If you walk away from this now,
you've sealed their fate.
Their fate was sealed
when Santiago died.
- Do they have a case?
- You and Dawson are dreamers.
It's not what I believe,
but what I can prove.
So, don't tell me what I know
or don't know. I know the law!
You're just a used-car salesman.
An ambulance-chaser with a rank.
You're nothing. Live with that.
So I told Duncan, " If you want me
to take this to court, -
- you'll get a year's paperwork -
- because a 90-year-old
misread the Insurance Code."
Fifteen minutes later,
he makes a deal.
All rise.
- Where are we?
- Docket nr. 411275 VRl5.
The United States versus Corporal
Dawson and Private Downey.
The accused are charged with murder,
conspiracy and conduct unbecoming.
Does the defence
wish to enter a plea?
- They're not guilty.
- Enter a plea of "not guilty".
Adjourned until 10.00, three weeks
from today, when we will reconvene.
Why would a lieutenant with so
little experience get a murder case?
Would it be, so that it never sees
the inside of a courtroom?
We'll work at my apartment.
Jo, bring legal pads and pens.
Sam, start a medical profile.
Jo, get Dawson's, Downey's
and Santiago's conduct reports.
I've only got Yoo-hoo and Cocoa
Puffs, so bring your own food.
So this is
what a courtroom looks like!
Did you speak
to your friend at the NIS?
She said, if Markinson doesn't
want to be found, he won't be.
I could be Markinson,
and you wouldn't know.
- Are you Markinson?
- No.
I'm not Markinson.
That's two down.
What?
Now that JoAnne's on this...
Do you still need me?
- They were ordered, Sam.
- An illegal order.
You think Dawson and Downey
knew it was illegal?
- Any decent person would have...
- They can't question orders.
What's the secret?
I give orders nobody obeys!
We have softball and marching bands.
They risk getting shot at.
I need you.
You're better at research than I am.
And you know
how to prepare a witness.
I've got medical reports
and Chinese food. Let's eat first.
What?
Got any kung pao chicken?
They can't prove there was poison.
Code Reds are normal at Guantanamo.
And there was an order. Kendrick
gave it, they had no choice.
- What about their motive?
- That doesn't make them guilty.
We'll deal with that later.
We must show that Santiago could
have died from something else.
Jo, find out all about
lactic acidosis.
This is Lt. Galloway, I'm trying
to find a Lt. Col Markinson...
Doctor, was there any sign
of injury? Scrapes? Cuts?
Bruises? Broken bones?
Any sign of violence?
- Other than the dead body?
- I always walk into that.
He ordered me and Dawson
to give Willy a Code Red.
The answers must come faster.
It's like he's searching for it.
And call him Private Santiago.
Willy is someone with a mother.
The jury has seven men and two
women. All experienced officers.
The women have no children.
Too bad.
A jury trial
is about assigning blame.
Santiago's dead. They want to know
who's to blame. We say, Kendrick.
This won't be won by the law,
but by the lawyers. So, poker faces.
If something goes wrong,
don't hang your head or scribble.
Look like you expected it.
- Pass me documents...
- "Swiftly, and don't look anxious".
That perfume
wrecks my concentration.
I was talking to Sam.
- What time is it?
- Time to go home and sleep.
- Give me a ride?
- Sure.
- You're a good man, Charlie Brown.
- See you in court, counsellor.
I know. We've had our differences.
We both said things we didn't mean.
If you've gained some respect
for me, I'm happy about that.
But it's no big deal.
You needn't say you like me.
I was just going to tell you
to wear matching socks.
Okay. Good tip.
- We're ready.
- You'd better believe it.
We're gonna get creamed.
- You are gonna save our son?
- I'll do my best.
Danny,
meet Ginny Miller, Louden's aunt.
You're Aunt Ginny?
- I was expecting someone older.
- So was I.
- Last chance. I'll flip you for it.
- All rise.
Too late.
All having business with this
court martial, stand forward.
Colonel Julius Randolph presiding.
Is the government prepared
to make an opening statement?
On September 6th, the accused
entered P.F.C. Santiago's room.
They woke him, tied him,
and forced a rag into his throat.
A reaction called lactic acidosis
caused his lungs to bleed.
He drowned in his own blood,
and was dead at 00.37 a.m.
These are
the undisputed facts of the case.
What I've just told you
is exactly what you will hear -
- from Corporal Dawson
and Private Downey.
We will also show that
they soaked the rag in poison, -
- and entered Santiago's room
with motive and intent to kill.
Lt. Kaffee is going to try
and work a little magic here.
He'll try a little misdirection.
Astonishing stories of rituals.
Dazzle you with official-sounding
terms like "Code Red".
He may even try to cut
into a few officers.
He has no evidence,
but it'll be entertaining.
But in the end, all this magic
will not obscure the fact -
- that Willy Santiago is dead,
and Dawson and Downey killed him.
- These are the undisputed facts.
- Lt. Kaffee.
It is futile to try and prove that
there was poison or intent to kill.
Dawson and Downey didn't go to
Santiago seeking vengeance.
And they weren't looking for kicks.
They were ordered to do it.
I'll say that again:
In the real world, or here in
Washington, that doesn't mean much.
But if you're a Marine
in Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, -
- you follow orders,
or you pack your bags.
Dawson and Downey are sitting here
because they did their job.
- Call the first witness.
- We call Mr. R.C. McGuire.
Raise your right hand, please.
Will you tell the truth, the whole
truth, and nothing but the truth?
I do.
State your name and occupation.
Robert C. McGuire,
Special Agent, NIS.
Did you receive a letter from PFC
Santiago on the 3rd of September?
- We did.
- What did it say?
That a member of the unit had shot
across the fenceline.
Was he named?
No. I told Colonel Jessep that I
would be coming down to investigate.
And what did you find?
Only one sentry
had a bullet missing.
- Who was that?
- Corporal Harold Dawson.
- What did Dawson say about this?
- That he was engaged by the enemy.
- But you don't believe him?
- It's not...
Why was Dawson never charged?
- There wasn't enough evidence.
- Thank you.
Why was there not enough evidence?
You had the letter.
Santiago was the only eyewitness.
I had no chance to interview him.
- And now we'll never know, right?
- No.
- No more questions.
- The witness is excused.
Corporal Carl Hammaker,
RS C Windward, 2nd Platoon Bravo.
Were you present at a meeting held
by Lt. Kendrick on September 6th?
- Yes, sir.
- What was said there?
Lt. Kendrick told us
we had an informer.
That Santiago had reported to the
NIS on a member of our platoon.
- Did that make you mad? Truthfully?
- Yes, sir.
- How mad?
- Santiago betrayed our code.
- Were other men also angry?
- Objection. Speculation.
Were Dawson and Downey?
Objection! The witness is asked
how my clients felt on Sept. 6th.
Sustained.
Did Lieutenant Kendrick give you
a standing order at that meeting?
- Yes, sir.
- What was it?
He said, not to take
matters into our own hands.
- What was the order?
- Santiago wasn't to be touched.
Your witness.
Were you in Dawson and Downey's
room five minutes later?
No, sir.
- Thanks. No more questions.
- The witness is excused.
Corporal Raymond Thomas.
Captain Ross is planning to call
the entire platoon.
The platoon leader's instructions
are relevant testimony.
The defence concedes that all 22
will confirm Hammaker's account.
But none of them were in
Dawson and Downey's room at 16.20.
- Captain?
- The government will concede that.
Then we will adjourn. You can
call your next witness tomorrow.
All rise.
- Let's go over the doctor again.
- It's the right approach.
We've been over this already.
At 3.00 a.m., he didn't know
what killed Santiago.
But after he met Jessep, he said
it was poison. He's lying.
Great! We can say,
"Liar, liar, pants on fire".
We can't prove coercion.
Let's go over what we have.
Private Santiago was hospitalized
at 00.12, -
- and was pronounced dead at 00.37.
Doctor, what is lactic acidosis?
It arises if the muscles and cells
burn sugar instead of oxygen.
It caused Santiago's lungs to bleed.
How long does it take, before
the muscles start burning sugar?
- 20 to 30 minutes.
- What made it faster with Santiago?
- Some kind of poison.
- The witness is speculating!
He is an expert medical witness.
It is not speculation.
He is not a criminologist.
The medical facts are inconclusive.
But I'm sure you don't mind
if we admit his opinion now.
Not at all, sir.
- Was Willy Santiago poisoned?
- Absolutely.
But you know that the coroner's
report shows no trace of poison?
- Yes, I am.
- How do you justify...
There are dozens of toxins
which are virtually undetectable.
The nature of the acidosis
is the compelling factor here.
Could a person have a condition
that could speed up acidosis?
- Is it possible?
- It's possible.
What might
some of those conditions be?
A coronary disorder
would make it more rapid.
If I had a coronary condition and
someone stuffed a rag in my mouth, -
- would I still burn sugar
after the rag was taken out?
If it was very serious.
Could such a condition have
such mild initial symptoms, -
- that a routine examination
might not reveal them?
- There would still be symptoms.
- What kind?
Chest pains?
Shortness of breath? Fatigue?
Of course.
- Is this your signature?
- Yes, it is.
This is an order for Santiago
to be put on restricted duty.
Would you read your remarks?
"Patient complains of chest pains,
shortness of breath, and fatigue".
"Restricted from running distances
over five miles".
Couldn't it have been a
heart condition, not a poison, -
- that caused the
rapid chemical reaction?
- No.
- It's not possible?
No. I examined Santiago thoroughly
and gave him a clean bill of health.
So it had to be poison. If you
give a man a clean bill of health, -
- and he later dies,
you'd be in trouble, right?
- Object! Move to strike!
- Sustained.
I've no more questions, your honour.
You've been a doctor for 17 years.
You are Chief of Internal Medicine -
- at a hospital
which has served 5,426 people.
In your professional opinion,
was Santiago poisoned?
We ask that the doctor's testimony
be stricken from the record.
- The court should disregard it.
- The objection's overruled.
We strenuously object,
and ask to confer with you -
- before you rule on this objection.
- The objection has been overruled.
- Move to reconsider.
The witness is an expert,
and the court will hear his opinion!
In your expert professional opinion,
was Willy Santiago poisoned?
- Yes.
- Thank you, sir. No more questions.
You may step down.
While we reserve the right to call
further witnesses, government rests.
We'll recess until Monday, when the
defence will call its first witness.
"I strenuously object".
Is that how it works?
"Overruled!"
"No, I strenuously object!"
- Oh, then I'll reconsider!
- I got it on the record.
You object once, so we can say
he's not a criminologist.
If you keep after it, it looks like
a bunch of fancy lawyer tricks.
It's the difference between
paper law and trial law!
- The judge called him an expert!
- Sam, she made a mistake.
I'll go call my wife.
I'll see you tonight.
- Why do you hate them?
- They beat up a weakling.
The rest is just coffeehouse crap.
They tortured a weaker kid!
They killed him,
because he couldn't run very fast!
- Everybody take the night off.
- I'm sorry...
We've been working 20 hours a day.
Go see your wife and daughter.
Jo, go and do... whatever you do
when you're not here.
It's Saturday tomorrow?
We start at ten.
Why do you like them so much?
'Cause they stand on a wall and say:
"Nothing's gonna hurt you tonight".
Don't worry about the doctor.
This trial starts Monday.
Sorry to bother you.
I should have called first.
No, I'm just watching the ball game.
Come on in.
How would you feel
if I took you to dinner tonight?
Is this a date?
It sounded like you were
asking me out on a date.
- I wasn't.
- That's what it sounded like.
Do you like seafood?
I know a good seafood place.
My third case was a "drunk
and disorderly". It took nine weeks.
- Nine weeks? And the plea bargain?
- 15 days.
- You sure hustled them.
- I got shifted to Internal Affairs.
But I have two medals
and two letters of commendation.
Why are you always
giving me your rsum?
- I want you to think I'm good.
- I do.
No, you don't.
You're an exceptional lawyer.
The court members respond to you.
You'll convince them. Dawson and
Downey will owe you their lives.
Jo...
You've got to prepare for losing.
Ross's statement was all true.
Even if it mattered to the court,
I can't prove they were ordered.
All we have is the testimony of
two people accused of murder.
- We'll find Markinson.
- We're gonna lose, huge.
Corporal Barnes, Windward Barracks,
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
For what reasons might a Marine
receive a Code Red?
Being late, being disorderly,
falling back on a run...
- Have you ever received a Code Red?
- Yes. I dropped my weapon.
It was over 100 degrees. My palms
were sweaty and I hadn't used resin.
- What happened?
- They threw a blanket over me.
They punched me on the arms
and poured glue on my hands.
And it worked.
I've never dropped my weapon since.
- Was Private Santiago ever late?
- Yes, sir.
- Was his barracks ever disorderly?
- Did he fall back on runs?
- All the time.
Did he ever receive a Code Red
before September 6th?
No, sir.
- Never?
- No, sir.
You got a Code Red just for
sweating. Why not Santiago?
- Dawson wouldn't allow it, sir.
- Dawson wouldn't allow it.
The guys talked tough,
but they were too afraid of Dawson.
- Objection. Speculation.
- Did you want to punish Santiago?
- Why didn't you?
- Dawson would have kicked my butt.
Captain Ross will ask you
some questions.
Corporal Barnes, this is the Marine
Recruit Outline. Do you know it?
Have you read it? Good.
Look up "Code Reds", please.
- Sir?
- Just find the page with Code Reds.
"Code Red" is just a term we use
down at GITMO. I don't know...
Oh. We're in luck, then!
"Standard Operating Procedure.
RSC, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba".
- Can we find "Code Red" in there?
- No, sir.
I'm a Marine. Is there no book,
no set of orders or regulations -
- telling me that one of my
duties is to perform Code Reds?
No book, sir.
No further questions.
Would you find the page that says
where the mess hall is?
That's not in the book, sir.
- You mean you've never had a meal?
- Three square meals a day, sir.
How did you find the mess hall,
if it's not in this book?
- I guess I just followed the crowd.
- No more questions.
Corporal Barnes, you may step down.
We do our final Kendrick review
tonight. I want to slam-dunk him.
- Hey, Luther.
- Admiral! How's the big case?
- Nose to the grindstone.
- No flies on you.
Rolling stone gathers no moss.
Well, it ain't over
'till the fat lady sings.
- You can say that again.
- Not 'till the fat lady sings.
I walked into that one.
- Jesus Christ!
- You left the door unlocked.
- You scared the shit out of me.
- Just keep driving.
Are you aware you're under subpoena?
And the lives of two Marines are in
your hands. I have to help you.
- What do you know?
- I know everything.
- Was it a Code Red?
- Yes.
Did Kendrick give the order?
Did you witness it? Did you?
- No.
- Then you don't know shit.
He was never gonna be transferred.
- Jessep wanted him "trained".
- But you signed the transfer order.
I signed them when you got to Cuba,
five days after Santiago's death.
I'll get you immunity. In four days
you can tell this to the court.
I'll check you into a motel.
We'll start from the beginning.
I don't want a deal, or immunity.
I'm not proud of what I have done,
nor of what I am doing.
- Where is he?
- The Downtown Lodge.
- I want him guarded.
- That's a good idea.
- My clearance code is 4115273.
- I don't have a clearance code.
He also says Jessep's lying about
the first flight being at 6.00 a.m.
Markinson says there was one seven
hours earlier. Did you hear that?
- Isn't there a record of flights?
- You need the Tower Chief's log.
- We're gonna win.
- Jo, we don't know anything yet.
You take care of Downey,
I'll talk to Ross.
Hi, Danny. Nice work today.
The redirect on Barnes!
- I have Markinson.
- Where is he?
In a motel room in Northeast,
under guard.
The transfer order is phoney. And
Jessep lied about the first flight.
I'm gonna put Kendrick
on the stand and have some fun.
If you accuse Kendrick or Jessep
without evidence, -
- you'll be court-martialled,
and that will go on your record.
Markinson won't hold up, he's crazy.
I'm just telling you to help you.
And I think you're all insane,
and your code of honour is shit!
Don't lump me in
with Kendrick and Jessep.
Your clients don't belong in jail,
but it's not my decision.
I represent the government without
prejudice, and my client has a case.
Please acknowledge that
I've informed you -
- of the consequences of accusing
an officer without evidence.
I've been so advised.
You got bullied into that courtroom.
By everyone. By Dawson. By Galloway.
Shit, I practically dared you.
And you were bullied
by the memory of a dead lawyer.
You're a lousy fucking
softball player, Jack!
Your boys are going down, Danny.
I can't stop it anymore.
- Was Santiago a good Marine?
- I'd say he was average.
Your proficiency and conduct reports
all indicate he was below average.
He was below average, but I don't
want to trample on his grave.
- I know, but you're under oath.
- I'm aware of my oath.
Here are your last three
reports for Corporal Dawson.
He rated exceptional twice,
but on June 9th he's below average.
- I'd like to discuss that.
- Fine.
Dawson scored perfect at
Infantry School.
But unlike most of his class,
he hasn't been promoted.
- Was this report the reason?
- I'm sure it was.
- Do you know why he got this grade?
- No.
I have many men.
I write many reports.
Do you recall
an incident with PFC Curtis Bell?
- He stole from the Officers' Club.
- Yes.
Did you report him
to the proper authorities?
I have two books by my bed:
The Marine Code and the Bible.
The only proper authorities I know
are Col. Jessep and God.
Then you don't recognise this court
as a proper authority?
- Objection. Argumentative.
- Sustained. Watch yourself!
- Did you report Bell?
- I thought very highly of him.
- I didn't want to charge him.
- You wanted it handled in the unit?
- Yes, I most certainly did.
- Do you know what a Code Red is?
- Have you ever ordered one?
- No.
Did you order that Private Bell
get nothing but water for a week?
You're distorting the truth.
He was on barracks restriction.
He had water and vitamins.
His health was never in danger.
I'm sure it was lovely for him.
But it was on your orders.
- You denied him food?
- Yes, I did.
- Would this be called a Code Red?
- No.
Would the other 478 Marines
consider it a Code Red?
The witness can't know what
478 other men would say.
These questions are argumentative,
and irrelevant badgering.
Sustained. I would remind you -
- that the witness has
an impeccable service record.
Was Dawson rated below average
for sneaking food to Private Bell?
- Object!
- Not so fast. Lieutenant?
Dawson was given a below average
rating for committing a crime.
What crime did he commit?
Lt. Kendrick, Dawson brought
a hungry guy some food.
- What crime did he commit?
- Disobeying an order.
So, because he made a decision about
the welfare of a Marine -
- that conflicted with your order,
he was punished.
Dawson disobeyed an order!
It wasn't a real order, was it?
It's peacetime!
He wasn't asked
to advance on a beachhead.
Surely a Marine of his intelligence
could distinguish important orders -
- from those that might be
morally questionable?
Can Dawson determine on his own,
which orders to follow?
- No, he cannot.
- He learned that?
- I would think so.
- You know so, don't you?
- Object!
- Sustained.
Finally: If you had ordered Dawson
to give Santiago a Code Red...
- I told them not to touch him!
- Would he dare disobey?
- Don't answer that!
- I'm through.
Did you order Dawson and Downey
to give Willy Santiago a Code Red?
- Lieutenant Kendrick...
- No, I did not.
What's the word?
I have the Tower Chief's log.
Jessep's telling the truth.
- Working late tonight, Lieutenant?
- Oh, yeah...
There was no flight at 11 o'clock!
The first flight left at 23.00, and
arrived at Andrews at 2.00 a.m.
Then why isn't it in the log?
- Jessep.
- He fixed the logbook?
I can prove that a plane landed.
I'll get the log from Andrews.
- You won't find anything.
- He can make a flight disappear?
Jessep is about to join the NSC.
He knows how to sidestep landmines.
- He can't sidestep you.
- You still want me to witness?
Thursday morning. Ten o'clock.
Someone must know about the flight.
Do you know how many planes
take off and land every day?
- No one will remember it.
- Well, how do you know...
Forget the flight. Forget the flight.
Markinson will testify that
the transfer was forged.
That and Downey's testimony
will be enough.
Why did you go
into Santiago's room that night?
- To give him a Code Red.
- Why did you do that?
I was ordered to by
Lieutenant Jonathan James Kendrick.
You're gonna do fine.
- Can we rejoin the platoon soon?
- Absolutely.
Remember the order of the
questions. And use small words.
- Just go slow.
- I'm gonna go slow.
Okay. And get him off
as fast as you can.
What? It's gonna be fine.
Dear Mr. And Mrs. Santiago,
I was William's executive officer.
I knew your son only by name.
Soon, the trial of the two men
who killed him will be over, -
- and the jury will try to offer you
an explanation for his death.
I've done what I can
to bring the truth to light.
But your son is dead because
I wasn't strong enough to stop it.
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson,
United States Marine Corps.
Please tell us one last time:
Why did you go to Santiago's room
on the night of September 6th?
A Code Red was ordered
by Platoon Commander Kendrick.
Thank you. Your witness.
According to the log,
you were at post 39 until 16.00.
- They keep that log pretty good.
- How far is post 39 from barracks?
- It's a ways, sir. It's a hike.
- About how far by jeep?
About 10-15 minutes, sir.
- Ever had to walk it?
- Yes, sir, that day.
The pick-up private...
we call him that...
...also 'cause he can get the girls.
He got a flat tyre at post 39, so
we had to jog back to barracks.
If it's 10-15 minutes by jeep,
it must be an hour on foot, right?
- We did it in 45 minutes, sir.
- Not bad.
You've said your assault on Santiago
was ordered by Lt. Kendrick -
- in your room at 16.20, right?
- Yes, sir.
- But you weren't back before 16.45.
So how could you be
in your room at 16.20?
Well, sir, there was a blowout...
Did you actually hear
Lt. Kendrick order a Code Red?
- Hal said...
- Did you actually hear the order?
- No, sir.
- I'd like to request a recess.
- The witness has rights!
- He has been read his rights.
The question will be repeated.
Why did you go to Santiago's room?
Did Dawson tell you to?
- Don't look at him!
- Answer the captain's question.
Yes. I was given an order by
Corporal Dawson, and I followed it.
Where do you think he is?
As far as Downey was concerned,
it was an order from Kendrick.
- Danny, I'm sorry...
- Don't worry about it.
All we need to do is call someone
to talk about implied orders, -
- or call Downey back first.
Or how about getting Dawson charged
with the Kennedy assassination?
- Are you drunk?
- Pretty much. Yeah.
I'll put on a pot of coffee.
She's gonna make coffee?
That's nice.
Downey wasn't in his room.
He wasn't even there.
That was important information,
don't you think?
Danny, it was a setback.
And I'm sorry.
We fix it, and move on to Markinson.
Markinson's dead.
You really got to hand it
to those marshals.
He didn't hang himself by his laces,
or slash himself with a butterknife.
He got into full dress uniform,
drew a nickel-plated pistol, -
- and fired a bullet into his mouth.
Since we're out of witnesses,
I thought I'd drink a little.
- I still think we can win.
- Maybe you should drink a little.
In the morning,
we'll ask for 24 hours delay.
- Why?
- To subpoena Colonel Jessep.
What?
No, Jo! Your passion is compelling,
but useless.
Louden Downey
needed a trial lawyer today.
You chicken shit!
You just want an excuse to give up.
It's over!
Why did you ask Jessep
for the transfer order?
- I wanted it!
- You could have got it anywhere.
You just wanted
to see Jessep's reaction.
Your instinct was right.
Now let's call Jessep, and end this.
- What possible good would that do?
- He ordered the Code Red.
He did? That's great!
And of course, you have proof?
- You missed that day at Law School?
- Get it from him.
We get it from him!
Yes, no problem.
Colonel, didn't you
order a Code Red on Santiago?
Sorry, time's up!
What do the losers get?
For the defendants,
life at Fort Leavenworth!
And for defence counsel Kaffee:
That's right! A court martial!
After accusing a decorated officer
of conspiracy and perjury, -
- Kaffee can expect a career -
- teaching typewriter
maintenance at a women's school!
Thank you for playing "Follow the
Advice of the Galactically Stupid".
I'm sorry I lost you
your steak knives.
Stop cleaning up.
Sam, stop cleaning up.
- You want a drink?
- Yeah.
- Is your father proud of you?
- Don't do this to yourself.
I'll bet he is.
I'll bet he bores the shit out of
neighbours and relatives:
"Sam's got a big case.
He's making an argument".
My father would have enjoyed
seeing me graduate from Law School.
He would have liked that a lot.
I wrote a paper about your father
in college.
- One of the best trial lawyers.
- Yes, he was.
But if I were Dawson and Downey,
and had to choose you or him, -
- I'd choose you any day.
You should have seen yourself
thunder away at Kendrick.
- Would you put Jessep on the stand?
- No.
- Do you think my father would?
- With the evidence we have? Never.
But we can't get around this:
Neither Lionel Kaffee nor
Sam Weinberg are lead counsel here.
So there's really only one question:
What would you do?
Jo, get in the car.
JoAnne, please get in the car!
JoAnne! I apologise. I was angry.
I'm sorry about what I said.
I'm going to put Jessep
on the stand!
- What do you suggest?
- Use the phoney transfer order.
- Our witness to that is dead.
- A problem, to a lesser attorney!
Last night he was swimming in
Jack Daniels, today he's Superman!
I'm getting my second wind.
Sit down, both of you.
Jessep told Kendrick
to order a Code Red.
For us to win,
Jessep has to say he gave the order.
- And you can get him to say that?
- I think he wants to say it!
He made a decision, and that's it!
He eats breakfast 300 yards from
4,000 Cubans trained to kill him.
No one tells him how to
run his unit. Least of all me.
I'll lead him
right where he's dying to go.
That's the plan?
How are you going to do it?
I've no idea. Where's my bat?
I think better with it.
- I put it in the closet.
- You put it in the closet?
I was tripping on it.
Never put that bat in the closet!
- I'm going to the office.
- He does think better with the bat!
- Hello?
- Sam, I need you to do something.
- What's going on?
- I'm going out to Andrews.
- Did Sam get the guys?
- Yes.
Can I talk to you for a second?
How are you feeling?
I think Jessep
will have his hands full.
Listen, Danny,
when you're out there today, -
- if you feel like
he's not going to say it, -
- don't go for it.
You could get into trouble.
I'm with Internal Affairs. I know.
You're not suggesting that I
back off a material witness?
If you can't get him... yeah.
All rise!
- Where's Sam?
- On his way.
- Where is he?
- Don't worry.
Lieutenant! Call your witness.
Defence calls Colonel Nathan Jessep.
Raise your right hand, please.
Will you tell the truth, the whole
truth, and nothing but the truth?
- Yes.
- Have a seat please, sir.
State your name,
rank and current billet.
Colonel Jessep, Commanding Officer,
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
He's not here.
When you learned
of Santiago's letter, -
- you had a meeting
with your senior officers, correct?
Platoon Commander Kendrick,
and Lt. Colonel Markinson.
And Markinson is now dead,
is that right?
- What is the counsellor implying?
- Just that Markinson is not alive.
The colonel
doesn't need to confirm that.
He may not be aware that Markinson
took his own life two days ago.
The witness, the court
and now the jury are aware.
We thank you.
Move on, Lieutenant.
You gave Kendrick an order, right?
I told him to tell his men
not to touch Santiago.
Did you give Markinson an order?
I ordered him to have Santiago
transferred immediately.
- Why?
- His life might be in danger.
- Grave danger?
- Is there another kind?
This is the order
that you and Markinson signed -
- for Santiago to fly out
at six the next morning.
- Was that the first flight?
- Yes, it was.
You flew here today, didn't you?
- You're wearing your dress uniform.
- As are you.
- Did you wear it on the plane?
- Is this relevant?
I'm asking the court
for a little latitude.
A very little latitude.
- I wore utilities on the plane.
- You brought the uniform?
Toothbrush, shaving kit, underwear?
Is his underwear a state secret?
You'd better get somewhere fast
with this, Lieutenant!
I brought a change of clothes
and some personal items.
After Dawson and Downey's arrest,
Santiago's room was inventoried.
Four pairs of camouflage pants,
three khaki shirts, boots.
- Four pairs of socks...
- Is there any question coming?
- Lieutenant, state your question.
- Why hadn't Santiago packed?
We'll get back to that. This is a
record of phone calls from the base.
You've recently made three calls.
Do you recognise the numbers?
I called Colonel Fitzhughes
to tell him I'd be in town.
The second was to arrange a
meeting with Congressman Richman.
- And the third was to my sister.
- Why did you call her?
- I invited her to dinner tonight.
- Your honour.
I'll put a stop to this.
These are the records
for September 6th.
And these are the 14 letters
Santiago wrote in nine months, -
- begging for a transfer.
But when he finally got it, -
- how many people did he call?
Zero! Nobody.
Not one call to his parents or
a friend, saying he was coming.
He was asleep at midnight, and you
say he had a flight in six hours.
Yet everything he owned was
in his closet or his footlocker.
For one day, you packed
and made three calls.
Santiago was leaving
for the rest of his life.
And he hadn't called a soul,
or packed a thing.
Can you explain that?
There was no transfer order,
was there?
Objection! Lt. Kaffee is trying to
smear a high-ranking officer -
- hoping to suggest impropriety
and win points.
I recommend that he be reprimanded,
and the witness be excused.
- Overruled. The objection is noted.
- Colonel?
- Is this funny, sir?
- No, it's tragic.
- Do you have an answer?
- Absolutely. I don't have a clue.
Maybe he was an early riser.
Maybe he didn't have any friends.
I'm an educated man, but I don't
know the travel habits of Santiago.
What I do know is that he was
set to leave at 0600.
Are these really the questions
I was called here to answer?
I hope you have something more.
These two Marines
are on trial for their lives.
Please tell me their lawyer hasn't
pinned their hopes to a phone bill.
Do you have any other
questions for me, counsellor?
Lieutenant Kaffee?
Lieutenant, do you have anything
further for this witness?
- Thanks, Danny. I love Washington.
- I didn't dismiss you.
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm not through. Sit down.
"Colonel".
He should address me as
"Colonel" or "sir".
- Call him "Colonel" or "sir".
- What kind of unit is this?
And the witness will address me
as "judge" or "Your Honour".
Take your seat... Colonel.
What shall we discuss?
My favourite colour?
Colonel, the 6.00 a.m. Flight
was the first one?
There wasn't one seven hours earlier
to Andrews?
Haven't we covered this?
These are the flight logs for
Guantanamo Bay and Andrews.
There's no flight at 11.00 p.m.,
and no arrival at 2.00 a.m.
I'd like to admit them as evidence.
- But the flight never existed!
- We believe it did, sir.
We call Airmen O'Malley and
Rodriguez of Andrews Air Base.
- They're not on the list.
- They are rebuttal witnesses.
- I'll allow the witnesses.
- This is ridiculous!
Colonel, a moment ago...
- Check the logs, for Christ's sake!
- We'll get to that in a minute.
You said, you told Kendrick to say
that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
- He was clear on what you wanted?
- Crystal.
- Can he have ignored the order?
- Ignored the order?
- Or forgot it?
- No.
Could he have thought,
"The old man is wrong"?
When Lt. Kendrick talked to the men,
any chance they ignored him?
Ever been in the infantry, son?
Ever served in a forward area?
Ever put your life in another
man's hands, and his in yours?
We follow orders, son.
Otherwise people die.
It's that simple. Are we clear?
- Are we clear?
- Crystal.
One last question, before I call
Airmen O'Malley and Rodriguez.
If you ordered that Santiago wasn't
to be touched, -
- and your orders
are always followed, -
- then why was Santiago in danger?
Why would it be necessary
to transfer him off the base?
He was a substandard Marine.
He was being transferred...
You said he was transferred
because he was in danger.
I said, "grave danger?" and you
said... we can read it...
- I know what I said!
- Then why the two orders?
- Men can do things on their own.
- But your men never did.
Your men obey orders.
So Santiago wasn't in danger, right?
You snotty little bastard.
- I request a recess.
- We'll wait for an answer.
The court will wait for an answer.
If Lt. Kendrick gave an order that
Santiago wasn't to be touched, -
- why did he have to be transferred?
Kendrick ordered a Code Red,
because you told him to!
And when it went bad, you signed a
phoney transfer and fixed the logs!
You coerced the doctor! Colonel
Jessep, did you order the Code Red?
- You don't have to answer that.
- You want answers?
I want the truth!
You can't handle the truth!
Son, we live in a world with
walls that must be guarded.
Who's gonna do it? You?
You, Lt. Weinberg?
I have more responsibility
than you can fathom.
You weep for Santiago
and curse the Marines.
You don't know what I know.
Santiago's tragic death saved lives.
And my existence,
while grotesque to you, saves lives!
But deep down, in places
you don't talk about at parties, -
- you need me on that wall.
We use words like
honour, code, loyalty.
They're the backbone of our lives.
You use them as a punchline!
I haven't the time or inclination
to explain myself -
- to a man who needs my protection -
- but questions the way I do it.
Better just to thank me.
Or pick up a gun and stand a post.
But I don't give a damn
what you think you are entitled to!
- Did you order the Code Red?
- You're goddamn right I did!
I suggest the jury be dismissed, and
we move to an article 39a session.
- The witness has rights.
- Captain Ross?
Jack?
The members of the court
will retire.
What the hell is this?
I did my job, I'd do it again.
- I'm going back to my base.
- You're not going anywhere.
MP's, guard the colonel!
- Captain Ross.
- What the hell is this?
You've the right to remain silent.
I'm being charged with a crime?
This is funny, that's what this is!
I'm gonna rip the eyes out of your
head and piss in your skull!
Colonel Jessep,
do you understand your rights?
You fucking people have no
idea how to defend a nation.
All you did was weaken a country,
Kaffee!
You put peoples' lives in danger.
Sweet dreams, son.
Don't call me son.
I'm a lawyer, and a naval officer.
And you're under arrest,
you son of a bitch!
The witness is excused.
All rise!
- Have you reached a verdict?
- We have, sir.
Corporal Dawson
and Private Downey.
Of the charge of murder,
the members find the accused -
- not guilty.
On the charge of
conspiracy to commit murder, -
- the members
find the accused not guilty.
On the charge of
conduct unbecoming a US Marine, -
- the members
find the accused guilty as charged.
You are sentenced to
time already served, -
- and to be dishonourably
discharged from the Marines.
This court-martial is adjourned.
What did that mean?
Hal?
Colonel Jessep said
he ordered the Code Red.
- What did we do wrong?
- It's not that simple.
- We did nothing wrong!
- Yeah, we did.
We're supposed to fight for people
who can't fight for themselves.
We were supposed to fight for Willy.
Lt. Kaffee, I have to
take these men for some paperwork.
Harold?
Sir?
You don't need a patch on your arm
to have honour.
Ten-hut! There's an officer on deck.
O'Malley and Rodriguez,
what exactly could they testify to?
Probably that they had absolutely
no recollection of anything.
- Strong witnesses.
- And handsome too.
- I've got to go arrest Kendrick.
- Tell him I said "Hi".
Will do.