Don't worry, it's a pack of wolves.
Come on, we're almost rid of it.
- Caleb, it's after me!
- Grab on!
Run! Run!
No, Benjamin, we have to finish this.
Come on, help me bury it.
What if someone digs it up?
May God have mercy on his soul.
- Hi, Alan.
- Hi, Miss Magruder.
- Afternoon, Alan.
- Hey, Frank.
- All yours, Alan.
- Thanks, Bill.
Get him!
Prepare to die, Parrish!
Parrish, what's the rush?
He's going to the factory!
He's going to daddy now.
Go on, Parrish! Run to Daddy.
We'll be waiting.
Hi, Carl.
Hey, Alan, my man. I gotta
show you something. Come here.
I've been working on
this for almost a year.
I got an appointment with your father...
...to show him this. Go ahead, take it.
What do you think? Think he'll like it?
What is it?
What is it? This is the future. If
Wilt Chamberlain will wear them...
...there'll be a pair of those
in every closet in America.
That will be the height of fashion.
What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Alan!
Thanks, Bob.
What are you doing? This factory
isn't a playground. It's dangerous.
Dad, can I have a ride home?
Oh, Alan.
Is Billy Jessup picking on you again?
Son, you're gonna have to
face him sooner or later.
If you're afraid of something,
you've got to stand and face it.
Now, run on, son.
You know better than to
let the boy play here.
Sorry, sir.
- What was it you wanted to show me?
- Just a minute, sir.
What the devil...?
Who did this?
Well?
I did, sir.
Being a Parrish doesn't mean you
can hang around with my girlfriend.
We're just friends.
Not anymore.
Get him!
I’ve got his bike!
Jerks!
Neat.
Alan?
Are you home?
Alan, not again. Come on.
Hard work, determination,
cheerful outlook...
...attributes that have
exemplified the Brantford spirit...
...since our forefathers
first settled this town.
Despite the harshness of our native
clime and the granite of our soil...
...we have...
- Prospered.
- I knew it all this morning.
You'll know it all tonight.
- Right. Let's go.
- Sam, we have to talk to Alan.
Well, we're on our way.
Okay.
I told your father what you told
me, that it wasn't just Billy Jessup.
- If I'd known that, I wouldn't have...
- It's okay, Dad.
But I'm proud of you. You faced them,
even though you were outnumbered.
Since you took it like a man,
your mother and I have decided...
...that you're ready to go to
The Cliffside School for Boys.
Congratulations, sweetheart.
You don't want me living here anymore?
Alan.
It's always been the plan
that you go to Cliffside.
I mean, Parrishes have been going
to Cliffside ever since the 1700s.
Even your Uncle Skylar went there.
Look at this. Parrish Hall?
It's the main dormitory.
This is great. Kids are on my
case here because I'm a Parrish.
Just wait till I'm living
in a building named after me.
It was named after my father.
Good. Why don't you live in it?
I did. I wouldn't be who I am
if it weren't for my years there.
Maybe I don't want to be who you are.
Maybe I don't even want to be a Parrish.
You won't be. Not till
you start acting like one.
- Sam...
- Get your coat.
I guess I'm not ready
for Cliffside, then.
We're taking you there next Sunday.
I don't want to hear another word!
You won't! I'm never
talking to you again!
- Sam...
- Don't.
- Sam.
- What?
Nothing.
What are you doing here?
I brought your bike.
You didn't have to. I was going
to Billy's to get it myself.
I told Billy to stop picking on you.
You wasted your breath. We'll
talk about it some other time.
What was that?
- You heard it too?
- Of course I heard it.
Come on, I found this really
weird game in the factory.
A game?
"Jumanji.
A game for those who seek to find
a way to leave their world behind.
You roll the dice to move your
token. Doubles gets another turn.
The first to reach the end
wins." You want to play?
I quit playing board
games five years ago.
Sarah!
It's gotta be magnetized or something.
Alan, look.
"At night they fly, you better run.
These winged things are not much fun."
What was that?
I don't know.
- Put it away, Alan.
- Okay.
Oh, no.
The game thinks I rolled.
What do you mean, "the game thinks"?
"In the jungle you must wait...
...until the dice read five or eight."
In the jungle you must
wait? What does that mean?
Sarah!
Roll the dice!
A bed-and-breakfast is
just what this town needs.
It was pretty hard to pass up.
Especially full of furniture.
Oh, boy.
I keep forgetting how big this place is.
Judy, Peter, come look at this.
I'm gonna put a reception
area right over here.
And a bar over here in the parlor.
That sounds lovely.
I'm sure you and your kids
will be very happy here.
Well...
Actually, they're my late brother's.
He and his wife passed
away just last winter.
Is this something, or what?
It sure is.
What do you think? Is
it big enough for you?
Peter hasn't spoken a
word since it happened.
Oh, my. I'm so sorry.
How terribly awful.
It's okay.
We barely even knew our
parents. They were always away.
Skiing in St. Moritz,
gambling in Monte Carlo...
...safariing in darkest Africa.
We didn't even know if they loved us.
But when the sheik's yacht went down...
...they managed to write
a beautiful goodbye note...
...that was found floating in a
champagne bottle amongst the debris.
Excuse me.
They were very devoted parents.
It was a car crash in Canada.
- You'll send me the escrow papers?
- First thing tomorrow.
I'll have to get a
locksmith for this one.
Peter, pick up your toys, please.
Peter, take this
suitcase up to the attic.
Then we can all have
ice cream. And bourbon.
What? What is it?
I'm going to Motel 6.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
I don't see any guano.
He said it looked like that.
That's an African bat. Some kid
said she saw some back in the '60s...
...but we don't get bats
like that in New England.
That's what he saw.
Well, whatever it was, it's gone now.
Bats aren't what I'd worry
about in this house, anyways.
What would you worry about?
Well, personally...
...I wouldn't want to live
where someone was murdered.
- Murdered?
- Yep.
Little Alan Parrish. I
say his father did it.
There's 1001 places he could've
hid the body in this house.
Especially if he chopped it up first.
Hey up there!
You don't want to be late
for your first day of school.
- Not a bat in sight, ma'am.
- Hear that?
There's nothing to be
afraid of in this house.
I can't believe I have to see your
principal after your first day.
What am I gonna do?
Let's try to relax and finish
dinner. Talk about something else.
We know why you got the house cheap.
Twenty-six years ago, a kid
named Alan Parrish lived here.
One day he just disappeared.
His parents chopped him up
and hid him in the walls.
That's it. I'm sick and tired
of your lies. You're grounded.
Fine, there's nowhere to go
in this stupid town anyway.
Just for your information,
that wasn't a lie.
Did you hear anything?
Do you miss Mom and Dad?
No.
Liar.
Cut that out, or they'll
send you to a shrink.
Where are they gonna send you
if you don't start talking?
If I get held up at the
permit office, I'll call.
The school bus will be here any minute.
You guys still have your keys?
You guys listening to me?
Hello?
What?
Maybe I should wait till the bus comes.
Did your parents used
to put you on the bus?
No.
Are you sure?
I could drop you off.
No, don't worry about us. The
bus will be here any minute.
Okay. Please be good today.
You do hear it.
Hear what?
Where's it coming from?
Let's bring it over here.
Weird. They're stuck.
"Jumanji, a game for
those who seek to find...
...a way to leave their worlds behind.
Roll the dice to move your
token. Doubles get another turn.
The first player to reach the end wins."
It's gotta be microchips or something.
You go first.
Okay.
Six.
"A tiny bite can make you itch,
make you sneeze, make you twitch."
Don't!
"This will not be an easy mission.
Monkeys slow the expedition."
What is that?
I bet those monkeys came from the game.
The mosquitoes too.
I didn't see this part.
"Adventurers, beware."
"Adventurers, beware. Do not
begin unless you intend to finish.
The consequences of the game vanish
when a player has reached Jumanji...
...and called out its name."
- The monkeys are gone.
- Good.
- Put it away.
- Wait!
If we finish the game,
it'll all go away.
Let's do it, or Aunt
Nora'll pitch a fit.
We should get through it quickly.
I mean, there's no skill involved.
No, you rolled doubles.
You get another turn. Roll.
Five.
"His fangs are sharp.
He likes your taste.
Your party better move posthaste."
I don't like the sound of that.
Someone's in here.
It's not real, Peter.
It's a hallucination.
Run, Peter!
I'm back.
My bike.
Somebody roll a five or an eight?
He did.
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you.
Sorry if I scared you.
I'm back!
Mom! Dad!
I'm home!
I'm back!
It's me! It's me, Alan, Mom and Dad!
I'm home! I'm back!
Are you my little sister?
No, I'm Judy and he's Peter.
Where's Mom? Is Dad at the factory?
Are you...
...Alan Parrish?
Yeah. Who are you?
We live here now.
Where's my mom and dad?
We don't know.
This house has been empty for years.
Everyone thought you were dead.
Sorry.
- Give me that description again.
- Red fur and tail.
Get down off of my car, please,
and get up on the sidewalk.
- What year is it?
- It was brand-new.
- No. What year is it?
- 1995, remember?
Ninety-five...
You got some ID? Let me guess,
it's in your other Tarzan outfit.
- Twenty-six years. -
Are you from around here?
I was. But I’ve been in Jumanji.
Indonesia. He was in the Peace Corps.
- Carl Bentley, the sole man.
- Is this man related to you?
- Yes, he's our uncle.
- Does he always dress like that?
Yeah, he's a vegetarian.
Get out of there!
Monkeys. Monkeys.
Is he all right upstairs?
He suffered a head
injury a few months ago.
Don't you move!
- Stop!
- Don't move, don't move.
Wait! Where are you going?
To find my parents!
Come on.
Wait!
My dad used to make shoes here.
They were the best shoes in New England.
Hey!
Sorry.
Easy, girl.
Do you know what happened
to the shoe factory?
Yeah, it folded up. Like
everything else in this town.
It's pretty cold out there.
How about some coffee?
Why would they close Parrish Shoes?
When his kid ran away, Sam put
everything he had into finding him.
His time, his money...
Everything.
After a while, he
stopped coming to work.
He just quit caring.
I don't think anybody loved
his boy more than Sam did.
Here.
You're gonna freeze out there.
Thank you. Are the
Parrishes still around?
- I see them now and then.
- Yeah?
They're over on Adams Street.
Our parents are dead too.
They were in the Middle East
negotiating peace when...
Our dad was in advertising.
I bet you miss him, huh?
Me too.
There he goes again.
I know you're upset, but
we should finish the game.
We? Why do you need me?
Just in case any other
scary stuff comes out.
Plus there's a lion in my aunt's room.
Do I look like a Ringling Brother?
She'll be home soon.
Won't she be surprised? I hope
she's not allergic to cats.
Larry, we need the
wheels. Give me a hand.
- Did we hit her hard?
- No, it looks like another weird bite.
- Yeah, it's another one.
- Jesus, over 50. What's going on?
Easy now, easy.
- Isn't that Mrs. Thomas?
- Who's that?
- The realtor.
- Quiet.
Listen.
You hear that?
Hear what?
Get in the car.
Okay, think. What came
out of the game before me?
There was a lion, a
bunch of monkeys and...
That!
It's okay, it's okay. It's
just a bug. We're safe in here.
We're fine.
If we stay low, he can't
get through there too far.
Don't you worry. We're fine.
He can't get through the glass.
We're safe.
Do you know how to drive?
No? That's no problem.
My dad used to let me back
the car down the driveway.
Once.
So, what's the big deal?
- Buckle up.
- Here we go!
Wait a minute. What? Wait.
Alan, the top!
Piece of cake.
Yeah.
Alan.
Keep that thing away from me!
When are you gonna help us
play? Our aunt will be home soon.
Good. You can inform her that
she's the ex-owner of this house.
I hope you realize with my parents
gone, this home belongs to me.
Oh, thank you.
No more banana leaves.
Yes.
What do you think those monkeys
will do to the ecosystem?
Hello?
What happened to you? Did you
shave with a piece of glass?
What happened to you? Did the
Clampetts have a yard sale?
I’ve never shaved before.
Where are you going?
How about Peter and I play,
and you just sort of watch?
Thanks, I’ve seen it.
If you won't help us,
what are you gonna do?
I don't know. Pretty much
take up where I left off.
I wonder if Mrs. Niedermeyer's
still teaching sixth grade.
Come on, he's not gonna
help us. He's afraid.
What did you say?
You're afraid. It's okay to be afraid.
Let's set it up in the living room.
You have no idea what
you're getting yourself into.
Whatever it is, we can handle
it. We don't need your help.
I don't think so.
You think monkeys,
mosquitoes and lions are bad?
That's just the beginning.
I’ve seen things you've
only seen in your nightmares.
Things you can't even imagine.
Things you can't even see.
There are things that
hunt you in the night.
Then something screams.
Then you hear them eating.
And you hope to God
that you're not dessert.
Afraid?
You don't even know what afraid is.
You will not last five
minutes without me.
So you're gonna help us?
I'll watch...
...but I'm not afraid.
Peter, that was very cool.
It's reverse psychology. Dad used
to pull it on me all the time.
Ready?
Yeah.
Alan, ready?
There is no "ready."
I'll try it again.
Alan, it's not working.
Oh, no.
It's not your turn.
I rolled first. Then Peter
twice because he got doubles.
Now it's my turn.
No, look. Two of the
pieces are yours, right?
Who's the other pieces?
The elephant was mine.
You're playing the
game I started in 1969.
I'm gonna have to play.
It's not my turn.
Whose turn is it?
Sarah Whittle.
This is where she used to live.
This place gives me the creeps.
We used to play on this porch.
I knew she still wouldn't live
here. Probably married Billy Jessup.
- Come on.
- Let's at least ask.
- Maybe she'll know where Sarah went.
- She'll know. She's a psychic.
Good point.
I remember the porch being a lot bigger.
Hello?
- Can you help us?
- Do you have an appointment?
- No, we're trying to find someone.
- Madam Serena can't see anyone now.
Maybe you can help us.
What is it?
We're looking for someone
who used to live here.
No, I’ve lived here my whole life.
Then you must know Sarah Whittle.
What do you want with Sarah Whittle?
Sarah?
I don't go by that name anymore.
Sarah Whittle?
What do you want?
Twenty-six years ago, you played a
game with a little boy down the street.
A game with drums.
How do you know that?
I was that little boy, Sarah.
Alan?
You killed her.
Leave a message and the
doctor will call you back...
...at his earliest convenience.
Dr. Boorstein, it's Sarah Whittle.
Please call me as soon as you can.
I think I need to
have my dosage checked.
That event we've been discussing,
the one that didn't really happen?
I'm having an episode here with
the boy who didn't really disappear.
I'm sitting in his living
room, drinking lemonade.
If you could call me, I'd really be
interested in your interpretation.
- He'll call me back.
- While we're waiting...
- God! No, no, no!
- Sarah.
- Oh, no, no, no.
- It's okay. Sarah.
I’ve spent 2000 hours in therapy
convincing myself that doesn't exist.
What happened to you was so
awful, I made up this thing...
It was awful. It was awful.
It really was.
But it was real. Real.
No, it wasn't real. Your father
murdered you and chopped you up.
Sarah, come on.
My dad did that?
My father could barely hug me...
...let alone cut me into little pieces.
Twenty-six years ago, we
started playing a little game.
And now...
...we're all gonna sit down
and we're gonna finish it.
And guess what?
It's your turn.
No.
Here.
Play the game.
- Oh, no, no.
- Fine.
Just give me the dice and you can
go home. You don't have to play.
Thank you, Alan.
Oh, my God! How could you do that?
It's the law of the jungle.
You'll get used to it.
When I think of the energy I spent
visualizing you as a radiant spirit...
Go on, read it.
"They grow much faster than bamboo.
Take care or they'll come after you."
Oh, great.
Oh, God. Tell me this isn't happening.
It is. Stay away from the
walls. Don't touch anything.
No quick movements.
- They're beautiful.
- Yeah, they're beautiful.
Don't touch the purple ones.
They shoot poisonous barbs.
And definitely stay away from
the pods. The big yellow ones.
What big yellow ones?
Peter!
I got you! Get his arms!
Get it off me! Get it off me!
Oh, my God!
Hang on.
Got him? I'll be right back.
Oh, my God.
Sorry, Angus.
Harvest time!
Are you okay?
Peter.
Oh, my God!
My car. Oh, my car.
Carl, come in, please.
Come in please, Carl.
Has anybody seen...?
I can't believe this.
Start, start, please. Yes.
- Carl? Come in, Carl.
- Carl here.
Where have you been? We've got
an animal-control situation.
Get Stan and Willy on it.
I’ve gotta check out a suspicious
character at the Parrish place.
I should've been a fireman.
Yeah.
Sarah!
Get your hands off me!
- The game is not over yet.
- It is for me.
You are not in the jungle anymore.
Stop this! You don't
treat people like this.
Okay.
Anybody up for iced tea?
I'm gonna make some tea.
Please, last time I played
this game it ruined my life.
- It ruined your life?
- Yes.
"In the jungle you must wait
till the dice read five or eight."
I was a little girl, Alan.
You disappeared.
And a bunch of bats surrounded
me and chased me down the street.
I was afraid.
I'm sorry, Alan.
No one believed me. I was alone.
So was l, for 26 years, Sarah.
Me too.
It's okay, Sarah. We're scared too.
But if we finish the
game, it'll all go away.
What if I get stuck in the game?
You won't.
Because I won't stop playing.
And neither will I.
I won't either.
Come on, Sarah.
Please?
I knew this was gonna be a bad day.
Come on, we'll be fine.
We just have to keep our heads.
And roll with the punches.
"A hunter from the darkest wild...
...makes you feel just like a child."
What is it?
Van Pelt.
You miserable coward! Come
back and face me like a man.
Not good enough, Sonny Jim.
Coming, ready or not.
Hey, you!
Drop your gun and get
your hands in the air!
Man, I don't believe this.
Even if Alan gets out
of this situation...
...it'll happen over and over again.
When you carry repressed anger, it
attracts a lot of negative energy.
Things happen, like ending up in
the jungle. That was no accident.
There are no accidents.
Whose turn is it?
- It's my turn.
- Really? Great.
You might've told us there
was a man who hunts people.
I didn't know. It's just
the roll of the dice.
Is he the reason you
didn't want to play?
You didn't want to play, either?
Mr. We-Started-26-Years-Ago-
and-Now-We-Gotta-Finish-It?
What's with this guy?
He's a hunter. He kills things.
Right now, he wants to kill me.
- Why you?
- Why me?
I don't know. You'd think
it'd be a waste of his time.
Maybe he needs something for his wall.
It's your turn.
Have you ever talked with
him about your differences?
- Are you crazy? The man has a gun...
- Don't ever call me crazy. Ever.
Everyone's called me crazy ever since
I said you were sucked into a game.
- Maybe I should roll.
- Yeah.
I was the girl who saw you murdered.
Did anyone come to my birthday party?
- Hello, I'm rolling now.
- Billy who?
Are you an owl? Come on, Madam
Serena, dig into your consciousness.
- Here, just roll.
- Find the memory...
...of your old boyfriend.
- The kid who'd steal your bicycle?
- The kid who took you to the movies.
"Don't be fooled, it isn't thunder.
Staying put would be a blunder."
- You're immature.
- You are.
- I know you are, but what am l?
Do you feel that?
Run!
It's a stampede!
Come on.
The game!
Don't look back!
Not the game!
Why didn't you grab the game, Peter?
Ignore him. He's a Libra.
- Where are you going?
- He'll head for water!
Here we go. Come on.
- Hello?
- It's Aunt Nora.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry, dear. You
have the wrong number.
Wait for me!
- What can I do for you?
- I'll have a gross of these.
They stopped making these in 1903.
Damn. Then I shall need
a replacement weapon.
There's a waiting period.
And you'll have to fill out these.
Or I could fill these out.
Louise.
Now, anyone asks, you
didn't get this here.
You're not a postal worker, are you?
Alan!
Quiet.
Here.
No!
- Peter!
- Peter, are you okay?
- That was great.
I can't believe you did
that. That was so cool.
- You gave me chills.
- It was great.
Alan.
Nice work. Come on, give
me the game. Let's go.
Oh, no.
Act natural.
Hey!
Hide the game.
Every time there's
trouble, I run into you.
I don't know what you're talking about.
- I'm taking you in.
- I'm not going anywhere.
All right.
Just a second. You
can't take him, he's...
- Her fianc?
- You said he's your uncle.
It's all right. I'll be back soon.
Blast.
You said you'd never
abandon your friends.
- We'll finish the game later.
- Later?
Van Pelt. Van Pelt.
I suggest you all go home now.
Okay.
Now how are we supposed
to finish the game?
We can't. We can't
finish it without him.
Judy.
What?
What happened?
I thought I could end the
game. I was only 10 spaces away.
"A law of Jumanji, having been broken...
...you will slip back
even more than your token."
You tried to cheat?
No, I tried to drop the
dice so they landed on 12.
Okay, honey. Well,
that would be cheating.
Peter, your hands! Look at your hands!
Come in, this is Willy. They
cleaned out Larry's Hardware.
I can't stop them. Get the
National Guard down here.
What is this about? I know you know.
Yes, I do. But you wouldn't
believe me even if I told you, Carl.
Wait a minute. How do
you know my name is Carl?
I know a lot more than that.
You used to work at Parrish Shoes.
They used to call you "Sole Man."
Sole Man, that's right.
I was in there too...
...till old man Parrish fired me.
- He fired you?
- Yeah, man.
And I had something that could've
turned this whole town around.
- Your shoes.
- Right.
Listen, Carl?
I know it doesn't mean
much after 26 years...
...but I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for what?
It's me. Alan.
Thank you.
What's going on?
Well, apparently there's a sale, honey.
You saw three monkeys on
a motorcycle, didn't you?
- Yes.
- Good girl.
Maybe we can bail him out with a check.
Thank you.
Tell that sniveling
coward if he wants...
Boy!
Get out of my way!
- Give me that, boy!
- No!
Hey!
- Peter!
- Help me!
Get me out of here!
- It's all right.
- Oh, my God, Peter.
All right.
There it is.
Wait here.
Gotcha, girlie.
No.
When Alan hears of your
predicament, he'll come.
He doesn't know I'm here. It
won't work. Your plan's ruined.
- Move and I'll blow your brains out!
- Okay.
Call the cops!
- That should do the trick.
- Oh, yeah.
Price check!
If you let me go, I can stop all this.
It's like The Twilight
Zone, but it's true.
Please, you gotta help me on this.
I know I'm gonna regret this.
Just hold still.
- Okay.
- There, I let you go.
Now what are we gonna do?
- You're staying here.
- My keys!
It's for your own good.
- My handcuff keys!
- I have to do this!
- Alan!
- You'll thank me someday.
Carl, code red.
Hostage situation at Sir
Sav-a-lot. A woman and two children.
It sounds like the armed
perpetrator in the pith helmet.
Carl? Come in, Carl.
- Lorraine? -
What's Sir Sav-a-lot?
- It's a discount store.
- Move over.
- Wait. Gently, gently.
- All right, all right.
Don't worry, I’ve done this before.
Once.
Where's Sir
Sav-a-lot?
- Monroe and Elm.
- The Episcopal church.
Not anymore. Now it's a Speedy Burger.
At least it was. I don't know
what's left. People are going loopy.
Judy!
We got company.
It's all right. He'll back us up.
- Here's the game.
- Get out of here.
Rats.
- Turn the siren off. Right there!
- Okay, I got it.
Stop cringing, I could
have shot you at any moment.
Why didn't you?
You didn't roll the dice, Alan did.
There it is, there
it is. Hit the brakes!
- Hit the brakes!
- I'm hitting it. I'm hitting the brakes!
- I'm hitting the brakes!
He'll be here.
Sarah!
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- Where's Peter?
- I'm here.
Oh, great.
So remember, circumstances are
never, ever out of your control.
End of tape three.
Update on the extraordinary
events in Brantford, New Hampshire.
Ninety-eight people have been
hospitalized with symptoms...
...ranging from inexplicable
fevers and rashes to seizures.
Local resources are strained
to the breaking point.
And state officials are now asking
those with such symptoms to dial 911.
I got it.
Alan, talk to him, please?
What? We don't have time for this, okay?
I know, but he's a kid
and he was trying to help.
- All right, come on.
- Thank you.
Judy, come on.
I warned you about this, Peter.
No, you wanted to play the game.
What, are you crying? You don't
cry, you keep your chin up.
Come on, keep your chin up.
Crying never helped anybody do anything.
If you have a problem,
you face it like a man.
Hey. Hey.
I'm sorry. Twenty-six years
buried in the deepest jungle...
...and I still became my father.
It's okay. Come here, I'm
sorry. Hey, it's all right.
It's all right to be afraid.
It's not that.
What is it?
Okay.
Ready?
Don't worry, we'll have you back
to your old self in no time flat.
Because we'll go in here together,
sit down and finish that game.
No matter...
...what.
Suddenly, I feel right at home.
Lorraine, this is Carl.
I'm heading over to the Parrish
place. Give me some backup.
Lorraine?
Wait! Wait!
Now what?
Stop!
Wait! Stop!
Is there a problem?
- Can I have a ride home?
- Where do you live?
Jefferson Street. The old Parrish place.
Do you have children? A boy and a girl?
- What happened?
- Get in.
I'll explain it all on the way.
Fine! Take it!
We gotta get to that house.
- Shouldn't we play someplace else?
- No.
I grew up in this. It's
out there that scares me.
- Okay, it's my turn.
- Sarah, if you roll a 12, you win.
Okay, ready? Here I go.
It's okay.
"Every month at the quarter
moon, there'll be a monsoon...
...in your lagoon." Monsoon.
At least we're inside.
Yeah, right.
Well, a little rain never hurt anybody.
But a lot can kill you.
Come on!
This way!
- What do we do now?
- We get to higher ground.
- Okay.
- Come on! Stay together!
You okay?
- Judy!
- Alan?
- What?
- What is that?
Swim! Look out! Look out!
- Alan!
- Swim! Go! Move!
Keep going!
Stay on the table!
Feet out of the water!
On the chandelier!
Come on, Sarah.
Peter!
Hang on, Sarah!
Are you okay?
Where...?
- Alan!
Judy? Peter!
Step back and let me
handle this, please.
It's nothing. They probably
left the TV on too loud.
Peter? Judy?
I always wanted to do this.
Could you step back, please?
- Alan, give me your hand!
- Alan!
- Grab my hand!
- I got it.
Alan!
Take the game.
Here you go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Alan, you wrestled an alligator for me.
It was a crocodile.
Alligators don't have that
fringe on their hind leg.
Come on.
My mistake.
It's okay.
Come on.
Okay, it's my turn.
I've got it.
Colonel Mustard in the
library with the wrench.
Clue.
Okay.
"Beware the ground on which you stand.
The floor is quicker than the sand."
Alan!
- Okay.
- Sarah.
- Help me.
- Okay. Stay calm.
Don't struggle. Stay calm.
- I'm calm.
- Alan!
- Grab on!
- Pull!
Okay. I got it. Pull!
Stay calm!
Come on!
Oh, good!
I got you...
Stop giving me things that come apart!
"There is a lesson..."
All right.
"There is lesson you will learn."
I got you.
"Sometimes you must go back a turn."
- Did I hurt you?
- Oh, no.
Oh, dear.
Thank you, Judy. Thank you.
That was very quick thinking.
Sarah and I would like
to get out of the floor.
It's your turn, Peter.
Okay.
I thought I'd lost you again.
Thanks for sticking around this time.
"Need a hand? Why, you just wait.
We'll help you out. We each have eight."
What's that? What is it?
- Nothing.
- You don't go... for nothing.
Peter, my dad kept an ax
in the woodshed. Go get it!
- Okay.
- Hurry! Go, go, go!
Sarah!
Judy?
Peter?
Aunt Nora, it's me. Peter.
Sorry. I can't talk right
now. I'll explain later.
- Sarah.
- What?
It's your turn. You can
finish if you roll seven.
- I can't roll.
- Put the dice in your mouth.
Bring the game. Hurry!
Judy!
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Help them.
Come on, Judy.
- Judy!
- Judy.
Give me the dice.
"You're almost there with much at stake.
But now the ground begins to quake."
Judy!
- Oh, my God!
- What? What?
I wish Mom and Dad were here.
So do l.
Her only chance is
if we finish the game!
It's your turn!
Oh, my God!
Get the game!
I won't let you go!
Alan!
Don't move.
Stand up.
What's in your hand?
Drop it.
End of the line, Sonny Jim.
Game's up. Start running.
No.
Aren't you afraid?
I'm terrified.
But my father told me...
...you should always face
what you're afraid of.
Good lad. You're finally
acting like a man.
Any last words?
Jumanji.
It's Jumanji.
No, Alan, no!
What...?
I forgot my speech notes.
Dad, I'm so glad you're back.
I've only been gone five minutes.
It seems like a lot longer to me.
I thought you were never
going to talk to me again.
Whatever I said, Dad, I'm sorry.
Look, Alan, I was angry.
I'm sorry too, son.
Look, you don't have to go to
Cliffside if you don't want to.
Let's talk it over
tomorrow. Man-to-man.
How about father to son?
Great.
I've gotta get going.
I'm the guest of honor.
Dad?
Back in 196... I mean,
today in the factory...
...it wasn't Carl Bentley's fault.
I put the shoe on the conveyer belt.
I'm glad you told me, son.
Thanks.
Bye, Dad.
Goodbye.
- Holy smokes! Judy and Peter!
- Alan.
They're not there.
It's 1969.
They don't even exist yet.
I'm forgetting what it's
like to be a grownup.
That's okay, as long as
we don't forget each other.
Or Judy and Peter.
There's something I've
been wanting to do.
I better do it before I
feel too much like a kid.
They probably don't teach driver
training in the sixth grade, huh?
Merry Christmas.
Do you want these?
Dad, the new cross-trainer's
doing fabulous.
No, it's not a bra, it's a shoe.
Honey, they're here.
Dad, I gotta run. We'll
pick you up tomorrow, okay?
You'll be the best Christmas
gift of all. Bye-bye!
- They're here? Come on, let's go.
- Yeah. Okay.
Lisa, hi.
Pardon me.
Jim! Glad you could make it.
- Thanks. This is my wife, Martha.
- Hi. This is Sarah.
- Hi, Sarah.
- Where are the kids?
Oh, my God, there they are.
How'd you know?
A guess, of course. They're your kids.
Right, these are our children.
Judy and Peter. Say hi
to Mr. And Mrs. Parrish.
Nice to meet you.
You're just like we remembered you.
I feel like we know so much about them.
Because, you know...
- You've told Alan about them.
- And I told her.
- I'll get the presents.
- Sure, honey.
Well, we love children.
- Merry Christmas.
- Cool.
When can you start?
We were going to take a skiing
holiday up in the Canadian Rockies.
No!
Sorry.
We just...
Need you to get that marketing
done on the new line, pronto.
No problem. I could start next week.
Great. Let me introduce you to
the folks you'll be working with.
Come on in. Our house was your
house. Is. Anytime you'd like.
What's that noise?