Good morning. Oh.
- Thank you.
- No. Thank you.
Hello. Hi.
I'm across the street.
Who? No. No, no. There's nothing
wrong with the ad layouts.
I checked them myself.
No, no. Marjorie just must've
gotten the months wrong again.
Yeah. Well, have you
talked to Laslo yet?
I don't care if he's upset.
Call Peter back and tell him
the layout has got to be four pages.
Not seven, not six, not five. Four.
- After...
- Hey, Robin.
Well, that's because
we changed photographers.
You must be kidding.
I... I double-checked everything.
- What's wrong with the ad layouts?
- What's wrong with the ad layouts, Leo?
I'll tell you what's wrong.
Practically everything.
- Because they're the wrong ad layouts.
- Marjorie, I... I have no idea...
Now, why am I standing here looking
at 30 pages of wrong layouts, Leo?
I'll tell you why.
Because someone...
Leo... didn't do their job!
Okay, the copy on the cover reads:
"Office Love Affairs...
How To Get Him And Your Raise."
- Good.
- Yeah?
Okay, look at me.
Come in a little closer.
Okay, right here. Great.
Good, I think we got it.
Carry on. Papaya diet?
Big problem. They're talking
about changing the fruit.
- What kind of fruit
are we talking about?
- I don't know.
- They said kiwi or something.
- I don't like kiwi.
These came for you.
They're from Frank.
My goodness. He is so sweet.
He was in London.
- Very exotic and expensive.
- Ohh.
"Can't wait to see you.
It's felt like an eternity."
- How long has he been gone?
- Two days.
- Two days?
- Yes.
"Meet me here at 7:30."
Ooh, good choice.
"Bring doll."
Doll. He does this kind
of thing all the time.
Hula dolls.
Polynesian restaurant.
Now just what are you up to?
- It's all part of the surprise.
- Thank you.
- Thanks. Uh-huh.
- Surprise?
Surp... You're not breaking up
with me, are you?
- No.
- Okay. You sure?
Because 69% of all relationships
break up in restaurants.
- We're not breaking up.
- Okay.
In fact, I want to increase
the romance in our lives.
- Oh, you do?
- Uh-huh. First, close your eyes.
- Now?
- Close 'em.
- Okay.
- All right.
Now, remember all the times
that you said we never go anywhere...
- And we're always working...
- Uh-huh. Right.
- And we never have any fun?
- Well, yeah.
Well, open your eyes
and look where I'm taking you.
- Oh.
- Come on.
- Oh, you're kidding!
- You and me in two weeks.
- In two weeks? I can't.
- Oh, oh, you can.
- I can?
- Uh-huh. I cleared it with Marjorie.
You did? Oh, you're a sneak.
Yeah. Six days and seven nights
on the secluded...
tropical island paradise
of Makatea.
Yeah. Yeah.
We arrived 15 minutes late.
- Oh, is that a problem?
- No, no. That's fine.
Uh, I'll tell you what.
Why don't I go find the bags...
and you... you get to go find
the charter, okay?
- I do? All right. Okay.
- Yeah. I'll see you in a few minutes.
- Sweetie?
- Huh?
- Love you.
- Uh, excuse me.
- Aah! Son of a bitch!
Miserable piece of rat shit.
Could you help me?
I'm looking for Tropical Charters.
- You goin' to Makatea?
- Yes.
Well, we'll be ready
in ten... twenty minutes.
But this...
this isn't the plane.
- What?
- The plane.
Where... Where's its mommy?
Oh. Tropical's plane
is laid up in Fiji.
We're filling in.
You're in luck. I'm your pilot.
Oh.
No. I ca... Uh, no. I, um...
I can't go in this.
It's, uh... It's broken.
No, it's not broken.
It's being maintained.
- This is my plane.
- Uh-huh.
This is a De Haviland Beaver.
This is one of the safest,
most reliable planes ever built.
Sweetie, is there a problem?
Uh, yes. He, um... He seems to think
we're gonna go in this old thing.
- What?
- Uh, I-I think... I think
we could find another charter.
- Don't you?
- Won't find one.
There's a boat leaves from the port.
Takes three days.
- Honey. Frank, honey, honey.
- All right. All right.
Uh, sweetie, I'm sure
the plane is perfectly safe...
and I'm sure the pilot
is a trained professional.
- He is the pilot.
- He...
Well, if you're going,
it'll be 20, 30 minutes.
I gotta get some oil.
- Oil? He's gonna get some oil now.
- You're gonna need help
with this luggage.
- No, thanks.
- No, we're good.
All right.
Everybody tied down?
Listen.
Are these really necessary?
Only if we crash.
- Hi.
- Everybody, this is Angelica,
our flight service director.
Hello.
Thank you. Hi.
- Sorry. Excuse me. Oh!
- Ohh.
Oh, I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- Oh!
- Hi, baby.
Mmm, hello.
Are you guys going to Makatea?
- We hope.
- Oh, you'll love it.
Are you from the States?
- Yes.
- I lived there for a while too.
It's very fun.
Hey, Quinn, look.
Look what I got. Check it out.
- What's that, baby?
- It's a bathing suit, silly.
I thought it was an eye patch.
Welcome to Makatea.
Here we are.
Thanks for flying Harris Freight...
where frequent flyers earn bonus points
good for valuable merchandise.
Hey, you're not trying
to steal my vest, are you?
- Mr Martin, Miss Monroe?
- Yes.
- Welcome to Hanaiti.
- Thank you.
- I'm Phillippe St. Clair,
the general manager.
- Hi.
Uh, can we have the reservation
for Mr Martin?
Oh! Oh, this is beautiful.
Wow.
Okay. All right,
we're never leaving.
Yes.
I want this to be the most
unforgettable vacation of our lives.
- Having a good time?
- Oh, honey, I'm having a great time.
- Hey, you know what today is?
- What?
- It's our anniversary.
- We have an anniversary?
Yeah, unofficially.
- Oh.
- Three years ago today, we first met.
- Today? Today?
- Today. You don't remember?
We fought over a cab.
- Oh, I called you a jerk. Yes. Yes.
- Yeah. Oh, great. That you remember.
- Sorry.
- Yeah. See? But that's okay.
It was all part of love's odyssey.
- Odyssey?
- Mm-hmm.
If I asked, would you wear
something special for me tonight?
- What did you have in mind?
- This.
Will you marry me?
The Calypsonians
were all gathered together
Singing such a mournful tune
I don't know
if it was in the summertime
It could be the month of May or June
- Believe me, baby, I know the best
- I'll be back in a sec, okay?
- All right.
- When I find myself
I poke out my chest, oh
Over loving
Over, over, over
Over loving you
I always thought
this was a beautiful island...
but with you here,
it is even more beautiful.
- Oh!
- How long have you been on Makatea?
- Oh, you're kidding, right?
- No.
Well, you brought me here.
Today? Five hours ago?
Oh, I'm so...
So much has happened since...
Oh! Oops. Oopsy.
Wow. Here you go. What's...
- I slipped.
- Yeah.
So, where's your, uh, copilot?
Oh, she's busy with the tourists.
Well, that sounds like
you don't like us.
Oh, no. Never bite the hand
that-that feeds...
uh, your mouth, whatever.
Besides, you know, they're...
they're good for a laugh.
- You're a big laugher, are you?
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh.
- Mm-hmm.
They come here
looking for the magic...
expecting to find romance...
when they can't find it
any other place.
Maybe they will.
It's an island, babe.
If you don't bring it here,
you won't find it here.
Oh, heavy. Pilot and philosopher.
- Let me buy you a drink.
- Hey, I'm here with somebody.
You remember him?
He came in with me.
- I meant both of you.
- No, you didn't.
You're from New York, aren't you?
Hey, is everything okay?
- Oh, hi. Nice to see you again.
- Yeah, you too.
- Let me buy you a drink.
- Oh, that's very, uh...
- Let's go.
- Oh, but we're leaving, and so...
Well, maybe some other time...
- Ta-ta.
- I'll buy you a drink.
- Okay, bye.
- Was he bothering you?
- Oh, no. He was just a little...
- Was he hitting on you?
From over there,
it looked like he was hitting on you.
- Maybe a little.
- He was?
- Do you want me to do
something about it?
- Like what?
Hey, I don't go to the gym every day
just to watch old guys shower.
- You know, I will...
- Really?
- Yeah.
Well done, ocean.
Well done, sky.
Well done, maitais.
- Well done, silicone. Oh, my.
- Hey!
Hey, I'm, I'm getting
a little toasty here.
You want me to put
some cream on you, honey?
You'd do that for me?
You... You'd cream me up?
Only for you. Where is it?
Excuse me. Miss Monroe?
You have a phone call.
- I do?
- You could take it at the bar.
What... Who would be
calling you here?
I have no idea.
I'll be right back.
- Can I get two maitais, please?
- Yes, ma'am.
Thank you. Hello?
Look, I know you're on vacation...
but this is a dire emergency.
- Oh, no.
- The photo shoot's on...
but it's an availability nightmare.
Vendela and Evander Holyfield
only have a mutual 17-hour window.
If we don't get them now,
nobody's available...
for four months and
we lose them for the May cover.
Well, there's gotta be somebody closer
whose life you can screw up.
That's the ironic thing, dear.
There's not.
Vendela's in Sydney.
Evander's in Osaka.
I threw Taylor on a plane
this morning to Papeete.
- Tahiti?
- Yes. They're all coming to you.
All you have to do
is fly back to Tahiti...
baby-sit the shoot,
fly back out.
- Fifteen hours at the most.
- Look, this is complicated.
Uh, Frank proposed
to me last night.
Oh, my God!
This is so exciting.
Sweetie, I'm so happy for you.
Well, I'm glad, but...
The point is, what kind of message
am I sending to Frank...
if the day after our betrothal, I'm
leaving him to go on some photo shoot?
An excellent message.
This is the perfect opportunity
to establish parameters.
- Oh, God.
- I read somewhere...
that 38.6% of all women...
are pressured into quitting their jobs
in the first year of marriage.
Marjorie, you read that
in our magazine, and we made it up.
Oh, Please, Robin, please.
Please, please, Robin, please?
- Deal.
- Oh, good!
- Do you have a way back to Tahiti?
- Oh, yeah, I can...
- That's good? Yeah?
- Mmm. Mm-hmm.
Thanks.
Don't move a muscle.
Lay down. Stay. Yeah.
- Hi.
- Hello. Hi.
- Uh, I'm looking for...
- Quinny, it's for you.
Okay. Hi there.
- Ohh.
- Hi. I'm really sorry to interrupt you.
I-I sort of have an emergency.
Emergency? What's going on?
Well, my boss called me, and she
wants me to go to Tahiti tonight.
Oh, well, I'm sort of
on my layover here.
Right. Uh, would $500
cut your layover short?
Um, baby, want to go to Papeete?
I can't. I have a show tonight.
Tuesday is tamure night.
- Uh, it's tamure night.
- Oh.
My hands are tied.
That's for later.
You know, I'm stuck.
I-I-I really...
This is really important.
You'd be doing me a tremendous favour.
- How would 700 be?
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Great.
- I'll meet you at the plane in...
- Give me an hour.
- Great. Thank you.
Honey, it's a known fact
that 38.6% of all women...
are pressured into quitting their jobs
the first year of marriage.
That was in your magazine.
You probably made it up.
If you had to work,
I would understand.
That's because you're not
as romantic as I am.
Ohh. So, come with me.
- No.
- How come?
Because if I go with you,
I'll resent the fact that I'm there.
If I stay here, I'll miss you, but
you'll feel guilty. I like that better.
Come on.
It's only for one night, hubby.
- Say that again.
- What, hubby?
- I like that. Say it.
- Hubby.
- Ready to go.
- Is it safe to fly?
- It is with me.
- Oh, you're that good, huh?
I'm the best you've ever been with.
I'm not sure
I trust your equipment.
We may be old, but we're sturdy.
Mm-hmm. What's all this?
Hotel overstocks, local trinkets.
I was gonna fly 'em to Tahiti tomorrow.
But with your job,
I got a twofer.
Oh, how handy for you.
Excuse me. I just want to keep this
from flying at you.
There we go.
Do you have my, uh, money?
Oh. Yes.
- Thank you.
- It's all there.
I trust you.
So what kind of work do you do,
uh, back there in New York?
I'm an assistant editor
for a magazine called Dazzle.
- Dazzle?
- Yeah.
Never heard of that one.
Well, you're not exactly
the demographic we shoot for.
Uh, this is it.
"Dazzle."
"Your Derriere: Five Exercises
to Tame the Beast."
"Ten Ways to Light His Fire."
For Pete's sake.
You know how a woman
gets a man excited?
- How?
- She shows up.
That's it. We're guys.
We're easy.
Of course, for that you can't charge
six bucks an issue, can you?
Now, does that advice
come with the $700...
or do I need to pay extra for that?
- It's on the house.
- Thanks.
Um, island flight watch,
Beaver 0318.
We are at 3,500
on a heading of, uh, 1-1-0.
I'm looking for a weather update,
please, uh, along our route of flight.
Thirty-six Victor, be advised...
...southwestern...
- Say again.
I'm sorry. This weather came up
quicker than anybody anticipated.
We're gonna have to turn back
to Makatea.
- It's just not worth the risk.
- Uh, all right.
A line of squalls
has got us boxed in.
Tighten up your seat belt.
It's gonna get bumpy.
Wha... Uh.
Y-You don't-don't mind
if I just come sit up here with you?
Get your seat belt on.
- What are those?
- Uh, Xanax.
My doctor prescribed them
for situations of tension.
- I think this qualifies.
- Give me a couple.
You just drive.
- What are you taking now?
- Xanax.
My doctor prescribed them
for situations of "sension."
Give me those.
Whoo! Hey,
that was close, huh? Whoo!
That was more than close.
That hit us.
- Oh, no.
- Shit. It fried the radios.
Oh, no. That's bad, huh?
Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
Beaver 0318.
Unable to maintain altitude.
Can anybody hear this?
- Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
- Attention, KMart shoppers!
Snow shovels are on sale for $12.99.
Put that down.
I'm unable to maintain altitude.
Forty miles south-southeast of Makatea.
Mayday, mayday, mayday
How many of those things
did you take?
Um, you know, I just don't know.
- Look.
- What?
We're in trouble here.
I want you to sit back...
be quiet, keep your seat belt tight
and let me fly this thing.
Yes, sir.
There's an island down there.
I can see a beach.
- I'm gonna set us down.
- Okeydokey.
- Rock on the beach!
There's a rock on the beach!
- Son of a bitch!
Good morning.
Could you get me a cup of coffee?
Sure, I'll get right on it, ma'am.
Oh, God, whe...
- Where are we?
- Here.
Where? Where?
Somewhere between Makatea and Tahiti.
That's... That's the best
I can do for you.
Whoa! What happened?
It crumpled the landing gear
when we hit.
Well, aren't you gonna fix it?
I mean, can't we...
can't we reattach it somehow?
Oh, sure. We'll, like,
glue it back on.
- How's that?
- Aren't you one of those guys?
What guys?
Those guy guys.
You know, those guys with skills.
- Skills?
- Yeah.
You send them out into the wilderness
with a pocketknife and a Q-tip...
and they build you
a shopping mall.
- You can't do that?
- No. No, I can't do that.
But I can do this.
Does that help?
I can get us out of here.
- Oh, good.
- Yeah.
Hey. Right? Huh?
Phone, huh?
I'm gonna get us out of here.
Pronto.
Right. Come on, phone.
So, what are we,
like, shipwrecked?
- How do you want it?
- Excuse me?
Do you want it sugar-coated
or right between the eyes?
You pick.
We've only got one wheel,
so we can't take off.
Lightning fried the radio
and the emergency location transmitter.
Air-Sea will probably try a rescue,
but without a beacon to hone in...
it's like trying to find a flea
on an elephant's ass.
The only thing we've got is...
this flare gun and a single flare.
Is it too late
to get it sugar-coated?
That was sugar-coated.
Well, then, what's the bad news?
The bad news is
we may be here for a long time.
You and me.
For a long, long...
long, long, long, long time.
Well, I want my $700 back.
- What?
- You heard me. My $700. I want it back.
You said you were gonna take me
to Tahiti. You didn't.
Give it back. Come on.
One, two, three...
- Wha...
- I figure I got you halfway.
Halfway? Halfway?
- Halfway.
- Halfway? Whoo!
Halfway? Oh, boy, you're good!
Whoo! You got me halfway!
That's fantastic!
Wha... What are you doing?
Hey! Hey! Get away from my plane!
- Oh, you be quiet.
- Goddam it! Get outta there!
- I'm gonna do something!
- Hey! Leave that stuff alone!
- You shut up!
- Come on out! Get outta there!
What do you think you're doing?
Leave my stuff a... Hey, hey, come on!
What's this?
It's a boat.
- It's a life raft.
- We can use that to get off the island.
Where are you gonna go?
You don't even know where you are.
Last thing you wanna do
is go bouncing around the ocean...
in an eight-foot blowup boat.
- Don't tell me what I want!
- Give that... Give it!
Hey, don't pull on that!
Leave it alone! Hey, hey!
Oh! Oh! Get... Wait! Wait!
Get me out! No! Oh!
Quinn!
Get me out of here!
Get me... Get me out of here!
Are you gonna stop acting
like a lunatic?
- Fuck you!
- Pardon me? What'd you say?
- That's what I thought you said.
- Quinn.
Yeah.
Mr Martin? There's
a telephone call for Miss Monroe.
Oh. I'll take it.
Hello? Hello?
We... This is Frank Martin.
Who is...
Oh, hi, Marjorie.
It's Frank.
No, she... she left yesterday.
What?
Mary, it's Phillippe
at Makatea.
Uh, Quinn flew a lady
back to you last night.
Can you look if the De Haviland
is at the gate? No, I'll wait.
I ran into Tony. He said
that Quinny didn't make Tahiti.
Hold on, Angelica.
We don't know anything yet.
Yes, Mary, right here.
Get Air-Sea Rescue, Mary.
Call me back.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, no.
Come on. You wanna drink water,
you gotta haul water. Let's go.
- What are you lookin' at?
- Nothing.
- Something.
Oh, don't give me that.
You were ogling.
- Ogling?
- Yeah.
- Ogling? Let me ask you something.
- What?
When you go into the store
to buy something like that,
what do you say to the clerk?
"Give me that outfit
so nobody'll look at me"?
No, I like people looking.
Just not you.
If it makes you feel any better,
you're not my type.
- Oh, good. Why?
- Why?
Yeah. You know,
I'm making conversation. Why?
You talk too much.
You're opinionated.
You're stubborn,
sarcastic and stuck-up.
Your ass is too narrow,
and your tits are too small.
Hey, you wanna know why
you're not my type?
Nope.
- I'm American.
- Oh, thank God.
- Tom Morrow. I'll take you up.
- Frank. Listen, so how do we find them?
Well, we're gonna fly over the water
and look out the window.
Wh... Whoa-Whoa-Whoa-Whoa.
That's it?
What about the, uh,
the modern technology?
Don't you have, like,
satellites, lasers...
- Mr Martin, take a seat.
- Heat-seeking kind of...
- Hey, I'm Ricky.
- Good. Great. I'm Frank.
- Listen, money is no object, all right?
- Yeah. Just get in.
Try breathing very deeply.
I find that helpful.
If they went into the water,
it's only been 12 hours.
- There's a good chance we'll find them.
- Okay.
Hey, Bwana, why don't you
let me lead for a while?
Okay. This'll be interesting.
Now there. You see?
I found it.
Come on, Quinny.
Oh, my God.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Quinn, this is...
Whoa! Whoa!
Wha... Who... Wait! Oh, God!
- Hey! Hey-Hey-Hey-Hey, hold on!
- Whoa!
- What are you doin'?
- What the hell's that?
It's a pig.
What are you worried about?
He's more afraid of us than we...
Watch! Watch!
Hah! Go on! Go on!
- Go on! Get outta here! Go on!
- Hyah! Hyah!
- Ohh!
- Bye-bye! Come on!
- Come on!
- Hey, Quinn?
Huh? What?
What?
I'm sorry to interrupt you, but, uh,
I'm having a bit of a problem.
What's the problem?
Some sort of creature
has just swum up my pants.
I'm guessing... I'm guessing a snake.
Oh. That's bad.
So, uh, what do I do?
I mean, I could reach down
and, and grab it.
No, that... that could be risky.
It might be poisonous.
Well, right. But on the other hand,
if it's poisonous and will bite me...
do I want to allow it to continue
to swim around in my shorts?
- All good questions.
- Would you just give me some advice?
All right? Just advice, input, anything.
Just give it to me.
I'm very open at this particular
juncture, all right?
- Just stand still.
- Still.
- Stand still.
- Right. Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- Relax.
All right.
Oh, God.
- No.
- What?
- Not good.
- What? Wha...
Shhh. I'm trying to concentrate here.
Okay. Okay.
All right, let's see.
Better not catch you smiling.
Oh, God. Oh, God!
- Thanks.
- Well, I'm not without skills.
Oh. You're going on a date?
- Do you like it?
- Why the fashion statement?
- Goin' hunting.
- Oh. For what?
No! You wouldn't!
They are magnificent creatures!
And I hear they taste
just like chicken.
Chicken.
Maybe I should have a taste.
You know, just in case somebody asks me
someday, "Have you ever had peacock"...
I can say, "Yes, I have."
You won't regret it.
Okay. Perfect.
Whoa! Ah.
Oh. Oh, my God!
Mmm. Mmm. Wow.
Chicken. Okay, chicken.
- Have you always been a pilot?
- All my grown-up life.
- Like doing what?
- All kinds of flying.
- Mm-hmm.
- I had my own very successful business.
What happened?
I found a better way of life,
that's all.
- Like what?
- Came out here...
got a nice little house
on a beautiful beach.
- Mm-hmm.
- Got my plane.
Uh-oh. Hmm.
I'm doing what I wanna do.
Got peace and quiet.
Living the life
every man dreams of.
Well, yeah, until they're 12.
I'm sorry.
That was out of line.
- No.
- I'm just...
I'm just cranky, you know,
from being shipwrecked.
Look at that sky. You don't see
a sky like that in New York City.
No, that's a good sky.
- Whoa.
- All right. Sorry. I'm...
I'm just a little tipsy.
That's...
Good night.
Suave.
Really suave.
Oh.
Oh, my God. It's a plane. Oh!
Oh, it's a plane. What do we, uh...
Flare! We need the flare!
Uh, Quinn?
Quinn, uh, get up!
There's a plane! We need...
Oh, God! Quinn, we need...
Okay. Oh. Oh!
Careful.
Flare! Jesus!
- Hey, baby.
- Oh, no.
Uh-oh. Oh, boy.
Oh! Oh, no.
Oh, uh-oh. Oh, no.
- Wha...
- Oh, nuts.
What... Oh!
What the hell did you do?
What the... You...
You wasted our only goddam flare
to shoot a goddam palm tree?
I wouldn't have shot the goddam tree
if you hadn't rolled into me.
I was trying to signal
the goddam plane!
Wha... What goddam plane?
That goddam plane.
- That goddam plane?
- Yeah.
That's a commercial airliner.
It's five miles high,
going 600 miles an hour!
They wouldn't see a nuclear explosion
if they were looking for it
much less a flare!
How the hell was I
supposed to know that?
If you hadn't drunken yourself into
a coma, maybe you could've told me that!
- Do you know what you've done?
- What?
You've taken our one good chance
of being found and pissed it away!
Don't you dare blame this on me!
If you were half a pilot...
we wouldn't be on this island!
I am the best goddam pilot
you're ever gonna meet!
Huh! I've flown with you twice.
You've crashed half the time!
And there is nothing
wrong with my tits!
- There's so much water.
- Don't worry.
Wherever they are, Quinny is going
to take good care of your girlfriend.
What do you mean by that?
Come on, let's pick up
the pace a little.
I want to get to the top
before dark.
Goddam.
I've had just about as much
vacation as I can stand.
Whoo! Whoo! God!
- Stop. Stop. Stop.
- What stop? What? Stop.
- Stop!
- What?
- Stop.
What?
We better find the beacon.
This way.
That beacon better be up there.
Look, the storm blew us
southwest 40 minutes.
Good chance this is Tamitange.
Ah, Tamitange. Well,
that explains everything.
There's a radio navigation beacon
on the top of Tamitange.
We find it. We shut it down.
They come out and fix it. We're rescued.
It took 'em two years to fix
the streetlight outside my apartment.
Wow.
Oh, wow.
Wow, this is beautiful. Well?
So, where's the beacon?
Huh?
- Well...
- Oh, let me see.
Well, it's this one, right?
Tamitange, the one with the funny-shaped
peninsula to the north, right?
- Yeah.
- Well, tha... that's north, right?
- Right? Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
There's no peninsula.
Who stole the peninsula?
- No.
- This isn't Tamitange?
So there is no beacon
that we're gonna turn off...
and they're gonna come fix it
and find us?
Well, well, we could be, um...
We could be further to the south.
This could be Mata Nui.
And what's on Mata Nui?
Us.
What? What do I want...
What are you doing?
Son of a bitch! Goddam it!
Uh, please don't do that again.
I just want one goddam thing
to go right.
Oh, God. I know. Come on.
Ever since we've been here,
you've been so confident.
- You have all the answers.
- Well, I'm the captain.
That's my job. It's no good for me
to go waving my arms in the air...
and screaming,
"Oh, shit, we're gonna die."
That doesn't evoke
much confidence, does it?
No, no, that does not.
I need you to be
my confident captain.
I can't tell you how difficult
this is gonna be for me if you lose it.
Okay.
- I'm all right now.
- Oh, good. Good.
Wait. Quinn.
What? What?
What do you need?
Hey. Come on. Get out of there.
- What do you want?
- Look, look, look, look.
Oh, yes.
It's a boat.
Looks like they're puttin' in
to that cove.
Yeah, well, how do we signal 'em?
- A flare would be nice.
- Don't start. Come on.
What do we do?
How do we get down there?
Well, we go...
- Down the mountain, up the mountain,
down the mountain.
- Yeah.
- We get to our life raft...
- Uh-huh.
and hope they'll still be
there in the morning. Come on.
Oh, God.
- Come on. I'll take over.
- Oh, God. Thanks.
So what's the deal
with you and, um...
- Angelica.
- Yeah.
No deal. We're friends.
She works at the hotel
a couple months a year.
We have some laughs.
Keep it simple.
Has it always been simple...
or has there ever been
anyone complicated?
That's a yes. Yes?
How complicated?
Scale from one to ten?
- Twelve.
- Twelve?
God. What happened?
Well, tragically,
she, uh, she...
Died? Oh, my God.
I'm so, I'm so...
- No, she didn't die!
- Oh. Oh.
- You gonna let me tell the story,
or what?
- I'm sorry!
Sure. Tell it.
She, uh, fell in love
with somebody else.
Not just somebody else.
My best friend. My partner.
The guy I was in business with.
God. What did you do?
Well, I, uh, bowed out.
I gave 'em my blessing.
Are they still together?
No. They broke up.
- Not before I sold 'em
my half of the business.
- Uh-huh.
Came out here. Got my plane.
Never looked back.
Best thing that ever happened to me.
- There are two boats.
- What? Two boats?
Two boats!
Look.
God, this is great, huh?
Hello!
- Sit down! We gotta get out of here!
- Why? Why?
- We gotta get out of here!
- What? Get out of here?
- Shit! Shit, shit, shit.
- What are you talking about?
Oh, my God!
- Who... Who are they?
- Pirates!
Pi... Pirates? As in, "argh"?
Smugglers. Thieves.
They rob boats!
- Rob boats? They just killed a guy!
- They'll kill us too.
- Just for bein' here!
Just for seein' 'em!
- Wha...
- Shit, he just saw me.
- We got company.
Ohh. Oh, no.
They just lowered a boat!
- What kind of a boat?
- A motorboat!
Shit! Shit!
Shit!
Oh, God! Row faster!
Go! Go, go.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
How'd he get over there?
- Go.
- Where? What?
Don't!
Let's not make this difficult.
That was a very stupid thing to do.
Now I'm gonna have to kill you.
- Say goodbye.
- We've got gold.
Up.
Gold?
- Gold.
- Yeah, we've got gold.
I'm a jewellry designer.
I design jewellry with gold.
And precious stones.
- Precious stones, like, uh...
- I have sold to all the finest stores.
And, um, we've got display cases
on the... on the boat.
Because, uh, we're expanding
the business in the Far East.
But that's my husband's end
of the business.
- 'Cause I'm-I'm in marketing.
- Wiz! You're a wiz!
Take us to the boat.
Hey!
Oh, my God! Now what?
We go on three.
One, two...
I can't!
You go. Save yourself.
- I'm sorry.
- For kissing me?
No. For this.
Damn!
You know how some people say...
"You don't know what you had
until you lose it"?
It's a load of crap.
I knew what I had.
God, I loved her.
Love her. Love her.
Not to insult you, but...
I don't think men know
what love is.
- I mean...
- I do.
- Yeah?
- I do!
Well, guys, they tell me
they love me all the time.
Well, I'm sure at least
some of them mean it.
No, they don't.
Do you think they gave up?
I don't know.
We shouldn't go back to the camp.
The plane's too easy to spot.
I am so scared.
If it makes you feel any better,
I'm a little scared myself.
No. No, that does not
make me feel better.
- I thought that's what women wanted.
- What?
Men who weren't afraid to cry...
who are in touch
with their feminine side.
No, not when they're being chased by
pirates. They like 'em mean and armed.
Whoa.
This is not a good island
for aeroplanes.
It's a Japanese World War II
float plane.
It's been up there
for 50 years.
Jesus.
You don't think there's
any way that you could...
Nah.
This looks like a safe place
to spend the night.
I'm gonna see if there's
anything I can use up there.
- Hi.
- Hey.
This is me here.
We gotta meet them
at 6:00 a.m.
They're gonna widen the search.
I may be too drunk
to wake up at 6:00 a.m.
I know how... how...
Are you sure you're okay?
You're-You're fine?
Yeah, I'm...
I'm just going
to take a shower...
and get into bed.
- Are you okay?
- I'm good. Yeah.
I mean, do you want
to stay here tonight?
- Stay?
- Yeah, with me.
I mean, you probably think
I'm being slutty or something, but...
I'm feeling bad,
and you're feeling bad.
And I'd really like
for you to stay.
I-I just don't th...
Yeah. Sure, why not?
- Yeah?
- No, no, I can't.
I mean, I'm, I'm still clinging
to-to hope.
And if-if I...
I mean, if-if we, you know...
Holy...
- No!
- No?
N-No, I...
Are you sure?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, no, I seem
to be leaving the room.
Breadfruit.
- It's not bread.
- It's not fruit.
I want to kiss you.
I really liked kissing you.
I liked kissing you.
But?
But if I start,
I'm not gonna be able to stop.
- Sounds good.
- Doesn't it?
I-I... Oh.
I can't.
We should get some sleep.
Come here.
This feels good.
And safe.
Feels good and safe.
Good morning.
Wh... What-What are you doin'?
- I got a plan.
- Good.
Anything I can do to help?
Yeah.
Yeah, just a second.
What is it?
What's wrong?
Angelica, the helicopter's
going up in 20 minutes.
If you're going, vite, huh?
Oh, Geez, I didn't realize
it was...
Okay. Thank you, Phillippe.
Tell them I am on my way, okay?
The helicopter's going up
in 20 minutes.
Oh, God. What did...
What did I do?
And how many times
did I do it?
- Are you okay?
- Huh? No, no. This was wrong.
This was all wrong.
Excuse me?
How could you say that?
No, I mean, everything you did
was very right.
But what I did was wrong!
This was wrong!
No, no. It's just we are
going through a terrible ordeal.
It's like when after a funeral...
- Yeah?
- Everybody has sex.
Not everybody.
- No?
- No!
Oh.
What?
Nothin'.
You know that woman
I was tellin' you about?
- The heartbreaker?
- She was my wife.
- Oh.
- Twelve years.
You have any kids?
No, we didn't have
any kids, thank God.
But I always wanted kids.
- A bunch of them.
- Really?
There's still time.
What? Come on.
How old are you?
Well, what do...
How old do you think I am?
- Hmm. Let me think.
- Guess.
Forty-five.
Forty-eight?
Fifty. You fifty?
You still look good.
I still am good.
Let's get these apart.
We gotta take 'em down one by one.
You first.
Careful!
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Okay, your turn.
How can I eat?
I'm scum! I'm garbage!
This experience has tested me and has
revealed no character whatsoever.
Stop beating yourself up.
You're a guy. You can't help it.
Mr Martin, forgive me.
I just heard they decided
to call off the search.
I'm sorry.
That's it?
Okay!
It's working!
Keep comin'!
Push!
- Ready?
- All right!
Put her down!
Oh, shit. Look!
Get out of here!
Too far back to the right.
Oh, God. Are you okay?
Oh, you're hit!
It's not bad.
Come on, come on!
I'm in! I'm in!
Get in the plane! Hurry!
Hurry!
All right! Hurry up!
Take off!
Come on!
Fire!
Damn! Get out of the way!
Reload! Quickly!
Take off! Take off!
We're gonna hit 'em!
Gimme a hand! Pull!
- Pull!
- Pull.
- Look out!
- Abandon ship!
Come on. Come on.
Stay with me here.
Stay with me.
You're doin' great.
- Come on.
- Look.
I should tell you
a few things about aeroplanes.
Why is that?
'Cause I may not be conscious
when it comes time to land this thing.
Oh, shit.
Take the controls. I want you
to get a feel for the yoke.
You're serious, aren't you?
I got it.
- Okay.
- Okay. Sm... Hey! Hey!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Small corrections.
- Sorry.
Small corrections.
Just look at the horizon.
When we get there...
you're gonna line up about
a hundred feet out from the beach.
Hundred feet out from the beach.
We are here today...
to honour two fine people:
Miss Robin Monroe...
and an old friend, Mr...
Father, please forgive me, for I have
sinned. I've been bad. Very bad.
Oh, God.
Quinn?
Quinn, don't make me do this alone.
Please, Quinn, don't make me
do this alone.
Shit.
I would say a few words
about our friend.
Quinn Norris was the kind of man...
It's Quinny! It's Quinny!
Look!
All right.
I'm lined up with the beach.
Throttle to 65 knots.
What the hell's a knot?
It's Quinny! Look!
Thank... Thank you, God!
Uh, flaps. Flaps, flaps.
All right.
Nose slightly elevated for landing.
Here we go.
And... Help me, God!
I'm coming, Sweetie!
Quinn? Quinn? Quinn!
We did it.
I'm coming! Robin!
Sweetie, hold...
Robin! Oh, my God, you're alive!
- You're hurt! You're hurt!
- No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
- He needs a doctor.
Get him... Get him a doctor.
- A doctor! We need a doctor!
- Come on, sweetie.
- Quinny? Are you okay, baby?
- Can you move your leg?
- Be careful!
- Watch out.
- Are you okay, baby?
I'm okay.
- Slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly.
- Be careful.
- They brought the tea!
- Oh, great.
You want some honey, sweetie?
Sure.
The guy said
the hotel's offered us...
a month's free stay
anytime we want.
They're probably afraid
I'm gonna sue them.
- How are you feeling? Are you all right?
- Oh, yeah. I'm just, you know, tired.
Here we go.
Whoops. Sorry.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I didn't get much sleep.
Frank, Come here. Come here.
Sit down.
It was terrible.
I mean...
I think deep down, I, uh,
I never expected to see you again.
You know, I was...
I was lost. I was...
We're just people, you know.
You know?
Robin, we're not perfect. I mean,
under... under that kind of pressure...
I mean, people do things.
You don't know... right, wrong...
You're cra... You're nuts.
You know, you...
Hi.
Keepin' busy?
Yeah.
How are you?
Good. Good, thanks.
This is not so bad.
- How 'bout you, your...
- It's fine.
Good.
What's the deal here?
- Deal?
- With us.
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
Was what happened
on that island anything?
Or was it just something
that happens to two people...
when they're alone
on an island together?
It was something.
Something?
Yeah.
So...
now what?
Look, I'm... I'm pretty set
in my ways, and...
you got all kinds
of possibilities.
You deserve someone...
fresher.
Don't you think
that's up to me to decide?
Let's be smart about this.
You're not gonna move out here
and become my copilot.
And I'm not gonna go to New York
and be your receptionist, so...
Where does that leave us?
I don't know.
I guess it leaves us nowhere.
So let's not complicate things.
Oh, I forgot
you like things simple.
Right.
All right.
Well, good luck.
Good luck to you too.
I hope everything works out...
for you.
So, how's that shoulder today?
Need something for the pain?
Yeah.
Well, 14 more hours,
then back to reality.
- Frank?
- Hmm?
I don't think
we should get married.
What?
How come?
Because I think it's wrong
for two people...
to get married when something is
hanging over their heads.
Oh, my God, I'm sorry!
Robin, I'm sorry!
I was... I was...
I was distraught.
And then she-she took off her blouse,
and it was like, "Oh, my God."
But I...
I walked away. I did.
I went back to our room. I tried
to go to sleep, but I thought of you.
I thought, oh... I didn't know
if you were dead or what.
So I went back to her bungalow,
you know, just... just to...
And she...
Robin, she answered the door with...
On.
- Who?
- Angelica.
- You slept with Angelica?
- Who slept? Are you ki...
- Didn't you know?
- How would I know?
Wait a minute. You just said
there was something hanging over our...
What did...
Wh-What do you mean?
Quinn and me.
- Aha!
- Oh, Frank...
something happened.
Something happened that shouldn't have
happened if you and I were really...
In love.
Boarding flight number 58
to Honolulu.
All ticketed passengers
should board immediately.
- Hey!
- Sorry.
Hey!
Hey, hey.
- Where's the plane... plane to New York?
- Right there.
I-I'm sorry.
I just had to get off the plane.
Well, I'm sorry
I delayed the flight. I just...
Where are my bags?
You don't speak any English?
What's in my bags is illegal?
Wait a minute.
Oh, please don't search my bags.
It's just important
that I stay.
You're here!
Why... Why did you
get off the plane?
Wh-Why didn't you...
Why did you come here?
I've decided
my life is too simple.
It is?
Yeah. I w... I want to
c-complicate the hell out of it.
So, uh, where are we goin'?
Um, your place is
in New York, right?
Uh-huh.
I don't think I can wait that long.
How 'bout my place?
Oh, yeah. Your little house
on the beach.
More like a shack, actually.
- A shack.
- It's, uh... It's not much.
Uh-huh. You do have a bed,
don't you?
Are you gonna be this fussy
about everything?
I wanna love ya
And treat you right
Every day and every night
We'll be together
With a roof right over our head
We'll share the shelter
Of my single bed
We'll share the same room, yeah
But Jah provide the bread
Is this love, is this love
is this love
Is this love that I'm feelin'
Is this love, is this love
is this love
Is this love that I'm feelin'