You lose.
Again.
Change your flight sequence.
That's enough.
Stop. Pay attention.
Pericles, stop.
I mean it or no treat.
How well do I know you?
Lieutenant Beaudry,
please report to Engineering.
Lieutenant Beaudry to Engineering.
- "F" to "E" Good.
- Easy now. Slow down.
- Yes.
- That's it.
We did it yesterday.
Hey, there you are.
What? Was the Homo sapien
mean to you again?
We all know it's just
rocket envy, don't we?
Ever consider an actual boyfriend?
You mean do I enjoy being miserable?
No, thanks. I'll
stick with my chimps.
Hey.
- I'm teaching him.
- No, you're teasing him.
Well, he's gene-spliced,
chromosome-enhanced.
He's a state-of-the-art monkey.
He can handle it.
When you frustrate them, they lose
focus. They get confused, even violent.
Hey, congratulations, Pericles.
You're gonna be a daddy.
Thought I saw a smirk on his face.
Actually, the female
was the aggressive one.
Hey, Leo.
You got a postcard.
Leo! Leo!
Leo, it's been two years. When are you
gonna come home? We miss you!
Don't come home too quick.
I'm really enjoying that apartment.
- No! We miss you!
- Are they letting you fly yet?
- No.
- Are the chimps doing all the work?
We got something
to tell you. Uh...
Hey, Leo, when you gonna make
that kind of commitment? You...
Captain
Davidson, report to the bridge.
- We found it.
- It's moving like a storm.
That's what it is.
It's an electromagnetic storm.
- All the digital clocks are stopped.
- It's beautiful.
Yeah, so is the sun
until you get too close to it.
This is weird.
I'm picking up frequency patterns.
Tune 'em in.
I'm getting every electronic
communication from Earth from all time.
The storm must be
bouncing it back to us.
Okay, let's get to work. We'll start
with a pass through the central core.
Take initial radiation, gamma-ray
readings. You get your monkey ready.
Excuse me, sir, I hope you don't mind
my saying, but this is a waste of time.
We have standard
operating procedures...
I'm well aware of the procedures, but if we
go through all of them, it could be gone...
No manned flights.
We start sending out an ape.
If it's safe, we talk
about a pilot. In that order.
You need somebody there who can think.
Why don't you allow me to do my job?
He's the canary.
That's the coal mine.
Your monkey launches at 1600.
All right, you just follow
your sequence and come home.
Understand? Home.
- Stand by.
- Alpha pod launch in 30 seconds.
Chart his course
to the eye of the storm.
Okay, Pericles, start sequence one.
Activate reading systems.
Ignition.
Have him
start taking perimeter readings.
What's wrong?
- He's off course.
- Lock on him.
He cannot respond.
There's a surge in
the heart rate. He's scared.
Light him up again.
Can't.
He's gone.
He's trained to come
back to the Oberon.
You think he's still alive?
- Sir-
- For now we just sit tight and wait.
I'm gonna run some
sequences in Delta pod...
see if I can figure out
what he did wrong.
The signal is breaking up.
Stay on him. He must be panicking.
No, he'll do what he's
trained to do, return to the Oberon.
- He's off vector. I can't hold him.
- Okay, that's it. We lost him.
- Want to send up another chimp?
- No, it's too dangerous.
I'm not wasting another pod.
Shut down launch operations.
Sir? Delta pod has launched.
Delta pod!
Your flight is not authorized.
- Goin' to get my chimp.
- You bring that thing back now.
Return to base!
Never send a monkey to do a man's job.
Oberon, I got a visual
on Alpha pod. Over.
Oberon, come back!
Oberon, come in!
I'm getting a Mayday.
Alpha pod?
- I don't know. It's coming in strong.
- Put it up.
Mayday!
Mayday! Come in, guidance!
Request instructions!
We're goin' down!
Come in! Mayday!
Delta pod, abort.
No! N-N-No!
This one looked at me.
Take your stinkin' hands
off me, you damn dirty human!
Hyah! Hyah!
- Hyah!
- Stinkin' humans!
You guys smell!
Hyah!
Knives sharpened!
Swords and knives sharpened here.
Hey, where am I?
What is this place?
Fresh fruit! Fresh fruit!
Pineapples, bananas, plantains!
Fresh fruit!
Here, I'm open.
Come on. Here!
You got it! Dribble it down!
Open shot! Take it!
Make way! Clear the path.
Get the humans!
Get outta here!
You guys smell!
- Get the humans!
- Take this!
Oh, that was a good one!
Yeah! Get outta here!
Stupid humans!
Stop it!
Who told you, you could
throw stones at humans?
- My father.
- Did he?
He's wrong, very wrong.
You can tell him for me I said so.
Human lover.
Let's go!
Hyah!
Whoa! Open it up!
What? Are you trying
to put me out of business?
Oh, these are the skankiest...
scabbiest, scuzziest humans
I've ever seen.
- You don't want them?
- I'll take the whole lot.
I must be out of my mind-
out of my mind.
I'll have to make it up on volume.
All right! Get 'em out!
And get 'em clean! Chop, chop!
Let's go.
Keep it moving. Move along.
Come on! Hurry up.
Get out of there.
Hurry up! Let's go.
Gentlemen on the left.
Ladies to the right, please. That way.
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
Very touching really.
I can't see for the tears in my eyes.
Come on. That one's got-
Crawling with lice.
- Hurry.
- Yeah, oh, oh.
Check the teeth on that little
one right there. Yeah. Nice.
Get in there!
Stay back. Back!
Move! You too!
How many times do I have to tell you?
Wear gloves when you handle humans.
You're getting soft, Limbo.
You normally hack off a limb.
Uh, yes, General.
That's true.
But, unfortunately,
they're worth more intact.
Keep your eye on this one.
He's feisty.
Are these the ones that have been
raiding the orchards, sir?
I know an old country
remedy that never fails.
First, you simply gut one human,
and you string the carcass up.
The human rights faction
are nipping at my heels already.
Do-gooders. Who needs 'em?
I mean, I'm all for free speech,
as long as they keep their mouths shut.
I promised my niece
a pet for her birthday.
Excellent. Oh, the little ones
make wonderful pets.
Oh, but be sure
you get rid of it by puberty.
One thing you don't want
in your house, it's a human teenager.
Oh, yes.
Any one you'd like, sweetheart.
That one.
Oh, isn't she pretty...
I-I'll get that for you, sir.
And I have a pretty new collar...
just for you.
Compliments of the house.
You stink of humans.
It's disgusting
the way they treat humans.
Demeans us as much as them.
Ari, let's go.
Let's get 'em marked!
I got orders to fill!
- No!
- Quiet!
Next!
Oh, no, not you again.
You know me. Just can't
stand by while human beings...
are being mistreated,
tortured, mutilated.
The only reason I put up with your
nonsense is because of your father!
Hey, if you want me to stop,
give up your filthy business.
Hey, I do the job
that nobody else wants.
Besides, I don't see
any of you bleeding hearts...
spending all day with these
dangerous, dirty, dumb beasts.
They're not dumb.
They can be taught to live with us
as equals, and I'm gonna prove it.
Don't do that.
Don't do...
Stay back.
Well, now, there's your proof.
Now I'm gonna have to put him down.
Help me. Please.
Please help me.
You are giving me such a headache.
I don't need this aggravation!
Sell him to me.
Are you crazy?
He's wild. They're both wild.
- Then I'll buy them both.
- Oh, now, that would be expensive.
That would be very, very expensive.
I'm sure we can, you know,
come to a deal.
No?
Deliver them to my house.
Semos, help me.
Rise when your master enters.
Wild humans in my house?
Yes, but this one seems different.
Different? How could he be different?
You can't tell one from the other.
My guests are here.
Keep the savage ones out of sight.
And especially from General Thade!
And you better be nice to him!
And wash your hands before dinner.
Senator Nado, good evening.
My dear, you look lovely.
Thank you,
but I'm having a bad hair day.
Yet she spends
a fortune grooming herself.
- And I'm worth every penny.
- Ha, ha.
Would you like to freshen up?
We're fine.
How the hell did these
monkeys get like this?
- What other way would they be?
- They'd be begging me for a treat now.
What tribe are you from?
U.S. Air Force.
I'm going back to it.
Finish your work.
Please, everyone sit.
We just returned from our
country house in the rain forest.
How was it?
- Boring.
- I find it relaxing...
being away from
the frantic pace of the city.
I wanted to go out,
but there was no place to go.
Nothing but trees and rocks.
- All you did was nap.
- Exactly.
A bit of time away from politics is
what is needed for a weary soul like me.
Ah, we used to lose ourselves...
for days in the rain forest
when we were young.
Now I can barely climb a tree.
Trite but true,
youth is wasted on the young.
Oh, how did I get so old so fast?
Living with your daughter, Senator,
would age any ape quickly.
You've long been
a stranger in our house.
I apologize for my lateness, Senator.
I stopped to see my father.
- How is my old friend doing?
- Slipping, I'm afraid.
I'd like to spend more time
with him, but these are troubled days.
The humans infest the provinces.
Yes, because our cities
encroach upon their habitat.
They breed too quickly while
we grow soft in our affluence.
Even now they outnumber us
four to one.
Why can't the government
simply sterilize them all?
The cost would be prohibitive.
Although, our scientists do tell me...
these humans carry terrible diseases.
How would we know that?
The army burns the bodies
before they're examined.
Father?
Mm-hmm.
Uh, at times perhaps...
the Senate feels that the army
has been a tad extreme.
Extremism in defense of apes
is no vice, Senator.
Your ideas threaten our prosperity.
The human problem cannot be
solved by simply throwing money at it.
The government tried that once.
All we got for it was a welfare state
that nearly bankrupted us.
I think the city has about
as much diversity as I can handle.
Look. Look at this garment.
This was made by one of my humans.
Can you deny the skill?
Isn't it obvious that they
are capable of a real culture?
Everything in the human culture
takes place below the waist.
Bow your heads!
We give thanks to you, Semos,
for the fruit of the land.
Bless us, holy Father,
who created all apes in his image.
Hasten the day when you will return
and bring peace to your children.
- Amen.
Next you'll be telling us
these beasts have a soul.
Of course they do.
The senator's daughter
flirts with blasphemy.
Is there a soul in there?
Do you have a towel?
I've lost my appetite.
Hmm. Hmm.
Hmm.
I have no patience for these
society dinners. I came to see you.
Oh, how sweet.
You've wasted your time.
My feelings haven't changed.
I still care about you.
You only care about my father's
influence... and your own ambition.
I know about the trouble you caused
today. I could have you arrested.
I'd do it again.
You feel so much for these humans...
yet you feel nothing for me.
A moment, sir.
What is it?
- We found something.
- What?
We think you should see it.
There's a curfew for humans.
If they see you on the street
at night, they kill you on sight.
You stay here, you're already dead.
Can you lead me back
to the place where they caught us?
Not without my family.
Here. This is
where I saw it.
Go on.
Something fell from the sky
with wings of fire.
There was a thunderous sound,
and the ground itself shook.
Sure you weren't dreaming this?
It was no dream,
sir. Look.
- You told no one about this?
- No, sir.
We knew we had to come right to you.
You did exactly the right thing.
Do you smell that?
Don't start now.
We're off duty.
And I'm starving.
You're hurt.
How did you get away?
- Who are you?
- Somebody trying to get out of here.
She promised to show me the way
back to where they caught us.
This is one of their house humans.
- Shh. He thinks he's better than us.
- He thinks he's part ape.
Hey!
We'll go together.
Oooh.
Good night, little girl.
You go this way. You go that way.
The rest of you, come with me!
Send a squad to
the north gate. Hurry!
Wait. Someone's comin'.
You're lucky I found you
before they did. You're surrounded.
Come. Back to the house.
I can reason with them.
- We know how apes reason.
- Is there another way out of the city?
Do not get involved with these humans.
Why did you help me?
Huh? Why would you
take that chance?
I- 'Cause...
you're... not usual.
Show me a way out, I promise you
I'll show you something...
that will change your world forever.
Trust me.
When I was little, I- I used to
sneak outside the city walls...
where... no one
could find me.
I- I can show you the way.
If we are caught, then not even
your father can protect us.
Trust me.
What about her?
A human child cannot
survive the journey.
Bon can take her.
Take her and hide her at home.
Check every house.
- Have you seen any humans?
- No, I haven't.
Hurry.
- Father-
- Don't worry. I'll be right beside you.
Come on.
No!
Stop!
Where are the other humans?
Through the tunnels.
They can't have gone far.
When you find them, kill them all.
Except for the troublemaker.
I wanna talk to him before he dies.
Sir, the senator's daughter
is with them.
- They took her?
- She's helping them.
I saw her myself.
She had no choice.
They threatened her life.
I'll report the message
to the senate myself.
They'll beat their chests
and ask for my help.
They are weak without you, sir.
- Your father was a brave man.
- What do you know about my father?
Let me go.
Thade will be here soon.
There's still time to go back.
I can't now.
That's where I flew in.
- You did that?
- No, my retro-burners.
Sure he'll explain everything.
There's no way to explain
what can't exist.
Talking monkeys can't exist.
Apes.
Monkeys are further down
the evolutionary ladder...
just above humans.
Calm down, will you?
What's wrong?
Apes are afraid of the water.
They can't swim.
- We drown.
- That's why every day we pray for rain.
How long can a human
hold his breath under water?
I thought you guys
were afraid of water.
Two dead monkey...
apes- apes down
at the bottom.
Someone else knows you're here.
- What is that?
- It's a messenger.
Keeps an open frequency
with my ship so I can talk to them.
What, it talks?
- With radio waves.
- Sorcery.
It's not sorcery.
It's science.
I have contact.
Jesus, they're already here.
They must be waiting for me.
The messenger has a homing beacon
that will lead us to them.
We're in control now.
We're the 800-pound gorilla.
Who are you?
Captain Leo Davidson,
a pilot in the U.S. Air Force.
- I come from a planet called Earth.
- Your apes permit you to fly?
Our apes live in zoos.
They do what we tell them.
I think it's fair
to call this hostile territory.
We got exactly 36 hours to rendezvous with
my friends, and I'm out of this nightmare.
What happens to us?
Where do we go?
You're going nowhere.
This one still belongs to me.
- Stop!
- You I've had enough of!
Take it easy, little fella.
I'm not gonna hurt ya.
I wouldn't hurt my own property.
But for you, I'll make an exception.
Hey, no harm done.
Come here, kid.
Come here.
You're not hurt, right?
You're young.
Hoo-hoo-hoo.
Oh, these kids,
they bounce right back.
Play dead.
- Kill him.
- Slave trader.
Shh. Shh.
You kill him, and you'll only
lower yourself to his level.
Exactly.
Oh, she is extremely smart.
You know, I've heard her
talking about apes and humans...
uh, uh, separate but equal,
to each his own.
Or something like that, right?
Look, whatever it is,
I-I agree with it completely.
Can't we all just get along?
I'm probably just
in the way right now.
So why don't I just get going, hmm?
- He'll lead them to us.
- Then we'll make him our guest.
Cuff him.
Uh...
Ow!
Aah! These things hurt.
- What the hell are you doin'?
- You could use that against us.
- I can't allow that.
- Who would invent such a horrible thing?
- That thing was gonna keep us alive.
- We're better off without it.
- What do you mean, "we"?
- Must you be so difficult?
Why don't I act more like a slave?
- That's not what I meant.
- Shut up!
That goes for all species.
If ever I thought that those humans
were capable of kidnapping my daughter...
Don't blame yourself, Senator.
Your family, above all, have been
compassionate with the humans.
- Look how they've repaid you.
- Can you find her?
If you untie my hands.
What do you want?
Declare martial law.
Give me absolute power...
to rid this planet
of the humans once and for all.
Now is not the time
to be timid or indecisive.
I am the only one who can bring
your daughter back to you alive.
He's not in the city.
We underestimate this human.
I will hunt him down myself.
Your father sent me to find you.
You must come quickly.
Alert the outposts.
Don't let the humans pass.
I understand, sir.
Apart from my father,
I rely on you the most.
We are not just soldiers.
We are friends.
I am depending on you.
Yes, sir.
- So many questions I want to ask.
- Me too.
These zoos you speak of, what
are they? This word is not familiar.
- Zoos are where you find our last few apes.
- What happened to them?
Gone. After we
cut down their forests...
the ones who survived...
were locked up in cages
for amusement...
or used for scientific experiments.
- That's horrible.
- We do worse to our own kind.
I don't understand. You seem
to possess such intelligence.
Yeah, we're pretty smart.
The smarter we get, the more
dangerous our world becomes.
Hmm. I knew it.
You're sensitive.
It's an uncommon quality in a male.
Why don't your apes object
to the way you treat them?
Our apes can't talk.
Maybe they choose not to
given the way you treat them.
Apes in cages.
Right.
Father.
I don't have much time.
Tell me...
about this human...
who troubles you.
I will capture him
with little trouble.
No. You're not
telling me everything.
You believe he is not born
of this world.
Has he come alone?
Yes.
More will come looking for him.
How can you possibly know?
I... have something
to tell you...
something my father told me...
and his father told him...
back along our bloodlines to Semos.
In the time before time...
we were the slaves...
and the humans...
were the masters.
Impossible.
Break it.
What you hold in your hand
is the proof of their power...
their power of invention,
their power of technology.
Against this,
our strength means nothing.
This has the power
of a thousand spears.
I warn you...
their ingenuity goes
hand in hand with their cruelty.
No creature...
is as devious, as violent.
You must find this human quickly.
Do not let him get to Calima.
The forbidden area?
Calima holds the secret
to our true beginnings.
Damn them.
I will stop him, Father.
Damn them all to hell!
What is it?
The apes put them
where they don't want us to go.
Why? What's so important
on the other side of that hill?
It leads all the way
to the sacred ruins at Calima.
- What is that?
- Calima?
That's where- Well,
according to our holy writings...
that is where creation began.
Where the Almighty
breathed life into Semos...
the first ape...
in the time before time.
It is where Semos will return.
Of course, most educated apes consider
such religious notions as fairy tales...
metaphors we use to
explain our origins.
I doubt if there ever
really was a Semos.
Well, that's where my crew is,
so that's where we're going.
Doesn't he ever stop?
- Are you sure the apes are scared of water?
- Yes.
We should cross the river
another way- over the mountains.
There's no time. It's dark.
We're going right through.
Semos smiles on me.
I win again.
You win too often. What have you
hidden up your sleeve?
All of them!
Cheater!
Who's in charge here?
I am, sir. They did not tell me
you were coming.
This camp is a disgrace!
Some humans have escaped.
If they come this way,
we will crush them.
These humans are different.
They travel with apes.
- You find this amusing?
- No, sir.
I'm assuming command. I'll personally
make sure this camp is prepared.
All right. Just grab
the reins with one hand.
Hold onto this as tight as you can with
the other. We're gonna cross the river.
Hey, horses are great swimmers.
They'll carry you across, okay? Okay.
Yeah, well, good luck,
everybody. Have a nice ride.
- Just leave me. I'll slow you down.
- You're letting him go?
- Bless you.
- No. He'll ride with us.
No, wait, wait, wait.
This is suicide.
Ride through an army encampment.
Only a human would think that this could work.
Hear my prayers, Semos,
father of all apes.
No, no!
I'm on your side!
Come on!
Come on. We have to swim.
Hey! I won't
let go of you.
Come on.
- No, no. Wait. There's no need now.
- Says who?
Says them.
They tried to kill me...
like I was nothing
but a- a-a miserable...
Human?
- Ow!
- You're hurt.
She was holding on pretty tight.
Soldiers will head downstream
until they find a crossing.
We should move quickly.
- Where is he?
- They crossed the river.
And you didn't stop them?
They were carried by horses.
Horses?
Our horses, sir.
Forgive me, my friend.
I'm not angry with you.
My father was taken from me.
He was a great leader.
Your family are direct
descendants of Semos.
And now it is time for you to lead.
- Form the divisions.
- Form divisions!
Full battle ready!
Sound the call to march!
Tomorrow we reach Calima.
He'll stay like that all night.
He's a soldier, isn't he?
A general. Well, he was
till he opposed Thade.
And then when Thade ruined
his career, my father took him in.
He was a great soldier.
Attar was his best pupil,
and now they're enemies.
I'd like to see your world.
I don't know.
They'd probably prod you and
poke you and throw you in a cage too.
You'd protect me.
They think you're going to save them.
Tomorrow after you meet your friends,
we'll never see you again.
That's what I've been trying to tell
them. I didn't promise them anything.
No.
You just dropped in from the stars.
They're not here.
Hello?
They were never here.
You said they'd come for us.
Oh, no.
It's impossible.
What is it?
It's my ship.
But these ruins are
thousands of years old.
I was just here a few days ago.
This is what the messenger
was picking up- the Oberon.
What are you doing?
The ship has a nuclear power source
that's supposed to last forever.
Hmph!
If I can access the database,
the ship keeps a visual log.
It's a way for them to tell their own story.
Maybe I can figure out what happened.
Mayday! Mayday! Come in, guidance!
Request instructions.
We're going down!
We were searching for a pilot lost
in an electromagnetic storm.
They couldn't find me because
I got pushed forward through time.
We haven't had any communications
since we crash-landed.
This planet is uncharted
and uninhabited.
The apes we brought along
have been very helpful.
They were a lot stronger
and a lot smarter...
than we ever imagined.
The apes are out of control.
One male named Semos...
who I raised myself
has taken over the group.
We have weapons, but I don't know
how much longer we'll last.
Maybe I saw the truth when they
were young and I wouldn't admit it.
They were good students and...
They're all dead 'cause
they were out looking for me.
We're alive because of you.
Who the hell are they?
Your story is spreading
through the villages.
They all want to see this
human who defies the apes.
- Hell, send them all back.
- Back where?
They left their homes to be with you.
I saw them.
- How many?
- As far as I could see.
Thade has brought all his legions,
which means the senate has capitulated.
He answers to no one now.
Get your people out of here.
Tell them to go to the mountains
and hide while there's a chance.
They won't listen to me.
This is a fight we can't win.
I want you all to break up
and scatter.
I'll draw them off.
I'm the one they want.
All right? Come on!
Let's go.
Let's go!
Come on!
Whoa. Hyah!
You gotta make your people understand.
It's over.
There's no help coming.
You came.
Stop! Come closer
and identify yourself.
How dare you show your face here.
It was not my decision.
I wish to speak to Thade.
Why have you come here?
To be with you.
A trade, is that
what you're proposing?
Yourself for the humans?
Even when you were a child
you took in stray humans.
Your family indulged your every whim.
Now look what you've become.
I've been... mistaken.
Forgive me.
So you want to be human?
Then wear their mark.
Let her return.
She can die with her friends tomorrow.
We were searching for a pilot
lost in an electromagnetic storm.
We haven't had any communication
since we crash-landed.
I'm so sorry.
This planet is uncharted
and uninhabited.
I'm responsible for all of this.
I'm never going home...
just like them.
The apes are out of control.
One male named Semos...
who I raised myself
has taken over the group.
We have weapons, but I don't know
how much longer we'll last.
I can't go home either.
Maybe we're not so different.
No.
We're very different.
You care about everybody but yourself.
It doesn't matter...
apes, humans, my planet, your planet.
The universe seems only
to reward cruelty with power.
No. Not always.
Not if we fight back.
I'm just not sure how.
You better take care of that.
I respect your courage.
But my advice to you
is to put that away...
and head for the mountains.
All right. There's one
possibility, but that's it.
We've gotta draw them in close.
I want those people behind the ship, but
don't hide them. They need to be seen.
What about us?
You're gonna be on horseback in front of the ship.
You're gonna be the bait.
- I won't move till you say so.
- You won't even be out there.
- I can do this as well as anyone else.
- I know you can.
I need you back there with them, okay?
All right.
We've got one shot. Let's go.
Listen up, everyone.
I've got an idea.
It may give us a chance.
I need everybody to get
back behind the ship.
Hey, we can win this.
It's been done before on my planet.
Look, our history is filled with men
who have done amazing things.
That history belongs to you now.
Listen. Sometimes even a few
can make a difference, okay?
Now, come on.
This is the day you've waited for.
This is the day you get to
stand up to the apes. Let's go!
Leo.
You know you can't
defeat Thade's army.
We might be able
to surprise and confuse them.
Maybe it'll give us a chance.
You don't understand Thade.
He'll keep coming for you
no matter what.
That's kind of what I'm counting on.
Everybody behind the ship.
Get those children behind the ship.
Come on, go.
We gotta go now.
- Let me go with them.
- No.
- Let me prove I can help.
- No, I need you here with me.
Help clear them back.
- What are you doing?
- I'm part of this.
- Get back.
- No! I'm staying.
Send in the first wave.
Here they come.
Now!
Oh, God.
Go on!
Jesus!
Come on.
Come on!
Wait.
Now! Now!
With that weapon,
we cannot defeat them.
I'm tired of this human.
No. Wait!
My fight is with Thade, not you.
Then your fight is with me.
- Semos.
Pericles, that was
a better landing than me.
Sir, the prophesy is true.
Semos has returned to us.
Come on.
Okay. Let's go explain
evolution to the monkeys.
Hey.
He'll turn us all
into slaves. Kill him!
Listen, this is where you're from.
We brought you here.
It's the truth.
We lived in peace together.
It was Semos. He's the one
who killed everybody.
He's lying.
Help me, my friend.
Kill him!
Everything I have believed is a lie.
You and your family have betrayed us.
I won't help you any more.
Ari.
You okay?
You came home.
It's safe.
You can come out now.
What, it's over?
I-I was just getting ready
to make my move.
We will leave the graves unmarked.
No one who comes here will
be able to tell apes from humans.
They will be mourned together...
as it should be from now on.
- Take good care of him, okay?
- Yeah.
Well, I can promise you
I won't put him in a cage.
It's found the coordinates
of the storm that brought me here.
You know, it would mean
a great deal to everyone...
if you would stay.
It would mean a great deal to me.
I have to leave now.
I have to take a chance
it'll get me back.
You know, one day
they'll tell a story...
about a human who
came from the stars...
and changed our world.
Some will say
it was just a fairy tale...
that... he was never real.
But I'll know.
- Oh.
- Keep it.
You know, I'd like to thank you...
for opening my eyes
to a brave new world of trade...
with the humans.
Yeah, no problem.
Farewell, spaceman.
All right, kids.
Who wants to buy some aspirin?
Maybe you'll come back.
Z.D.C. air-traffic
control to unidentified aircraft.
Switch your radio
to 121 .5 megahertz.
Z.D.C. to unidentified aircraft.
Do you copy? Over.
Copy that.
Unidentified aircraft, you are
entering restricted airspace.
- Request permission to land.
- You're way off target- way off target. Abort.
I can't!
Let's go. Let's go. Move.
Keep your hands up.