This is Richard Valeriani
reporting live for CNN
from the French aircraft carrier Foch
somewhere in the Mediterranean.
Six days ago, as the rebellion in Chechnya
spread to the neighboring
Caucus republics,
the Russian president ordered
bombing strikes against rebel positions
around Rutul and Belokani.
Appalled at the loss of human life,
the president of the United States,
the French president
and the British prime minister,
suspended all foreign aid to Russia.
Ultranationalist leader Vladimir
Radchenko denounced the US pressure
as an act of war against the Russian
Republic and Russian sovereignty.
Denouncing his own president
as a US puppet,
he called on the Russian people
to join him in revolt.
He said, "This brutish and hypocritical
American intervention
will not go unanswered."
On Tuesday at ten o'clock in the morning,
Moscow time,
the Russian parliament was suspended
and martial law was declared.
With a government in crisis,
the Russian Republic was entering
into what can only be described
as a state of civil war.
Then yesterday at dawn,
Radchenko and rebel forces
seized the region around Vladivostok.
including a naval base and a nuclear
missile base housing Russian ICBMs.
As regular Russian military forces
move in to encircle Radchenko,
Allied military forces are
in a state of high alert.
These French planes taking off behind me
have been deployed near the Caucasus
since the beginning of the crisis.
And a crisis which started in the Caucasus
has now spread to the Far East
and appears to be turning into the worst
standoff since the Cuban missile crisis.
This is Richard Valeriani
reporting live for CNN
from the French aircraft carrier Foch
somewhere in the Mediterranean.
Abracadabra!
I can't hear you.
It was worth the 50 bucks, right there.
Huh. Where have you been?
This guy's costing me $125.
- Get out.
- Before the tip.
...a volunteer from the audience.
- Me!
Me, me, me!
A brave volunteer.
Me! Me! Me!
Preferably... Preferably somebody
who was born on October 18th,
nineteen hundred and ninety.
- That's Robin!
- That's you, honey. That's you.
Over here? Over here? Ah!
You must be the birthday girl.
- What's your name?
- Robin.
Russian ultranationalist
leader, backed by his rebel army,
threatened nuclear attack
on the United States and Japan.
The threats are a response
to US involvement in Chechnya
and are not considered idle.
Now sit on the board. And tell me, Robin,
do you believe in magic?
- Good. Because if...
- Where'd he go?
I'll get him. I'll get him.
Be right back.
... a flying carpet.
... emergency session...
- You'll miss your daughter's levitation.
- ... with his joint chiefs of staff.
That footage was taken yesterday,
but half an hour ago,
surrounded by hostile forces,
rebel leader Vladimir Radchenko...
Maybe it's not as bad as it looks.
... the Russian army, move in on him.
... cannot be viewed as an idle threat.
Sander Vanocur standing by.
It is.
Commander Hunter.
Annapolis.
Five patrols on fast attacks.
Two on boomers. One as XO.
Hm.
A year at...
Excuse me. Harvard?
I talked to your former CO.
He tells me he tried to adopt you.
As you no doubt heard,
my XO has appendicitis.
He's the best I ever had.
I need a good man to fill his spot.
Your name was at the top of the list.
Well, that's good to know, sir.
It was a short list.
Your interests, Mr. Hunter.
What do you like to do? Do you, uh...
Do you paint, play ball, play
an instrument, ride motorcycles? What?
- I ride horses.
- Horses.
- What's the best horse you ever rode?
- Arabian, sir.
An Arabian?
That's a powerful animal.
Yes.
- You ever ridden one?
- Me? Are you kidding?
Nah, I couldn't handle an Arabian.
Nah, just give me an old paint.
Yeah, horses are fascinating animals.
Dumb as fence posts, but very intuitive.
They're not too different
from high school girls.
They might not have a brain in their head,
but they know the boys want to fuck 'em.
You don't have to be able to read Ulysses
to understand them.
No, sir.
He approves of you.
Jack Russells. Smartest dogs alive.
Name's Bear.
Goes everyplace with me.
Well, welcome aboard the Alabama, son.
Do me proud.
I will, sir.
- Congratulations, Mr. Hunter.
- Thank you.
If one Russian citizen is killed...
and I am president,
then I will kill 900.000
of the people who are responsible.
You would kill 900.000 people?
Are you aware of the effect...
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Play that back.
Are you aware of the effect of this talk...
She's got some huge tits under that shirt.
Attention!
At ease. Be seated.
My dear young lady,
I do not engage in "talk."
These are serious threats, which I hope
to be in the position to carry out.
I take it you've seen enough?
Gentlemen, after a nice little vacation,
looks like we're back at it again.
I hope you enjoyed the peace, because
as of now, we're back in business.
In the good old days of Cold War,
the Russians could be depended on
doing whatever is in
their own best interests.
But this Radchenko's playing a whole new
ball game with a whole new set of rules.
Now I've heard people talk,
but I don't think he is talking
to get his picture in the paper.
He seems to have a serious weed
up his ass and a legitimate gripe.
Always a dangerous combination.
And I think he's capable of doing every
damn thing he says he's going to do.
That's why we have to go out there
and give the man a moment of pause.
So ends theory.
Thus, let us begin the facts.
The NSA informs us that an entire rebel
corps of the Russian army is involved.
That's four armored divisions,
numbering 60,000 men.
There seems to be massive defections.
Vladimir seems to be winning the hearts
and minds of the Russian soldiers.
- Admiral.
- Thank you, sir.
They've seized the region by
the Chinese and North Korean borders.
That includes a submarine base
from which they've surged
four Akula class attack subs.
They have acquired
a nuclear base at Artem,
that houses 25 hardened silos
for Russian ICBMs,
armed with up to ten warheads apiece.
The Russian government
assured us talks are underway.
They claim that Radchenko forces
do not possess the launch codes.
But if Radchenko were to crack them,
they could launch against
our west coast direct,
or come in over the pole,
take out Washington and New York.
The commander in chief has directed US
military forces to set DEFCON four.
We've been ordered
to get underway at 0600 hours
to assume alert coverage, mid-Pacific,
the Far Eastern TVD target package.
Keep your men informed.
Lieutenant Commander Hunter
is our new XO.
Please bring him up to speed on
ship's personnel and supplies.
Any questions?
- Admiral?
- No, that's it.
On your feet.
- Here we go again, Commander.
- Thank you.
Hey, Bobby. This is Bobby Dougherty.
He's Supplies.
- Mr. Dougherty.
- Billy Linkletter, TSO.
- Mr. Linkletter.
- Commander.
- And you know Darik.
- Yes. Westergaurd. Long time no see.
- How's Julia?
- She's excellent.
- And Roy Zimmer, Communications.
- Welcome aboard.
- Thank you.
- We served together on the Baton Rouge.
- Twice.
- That's right.
And, uh... we're lucky to have him.
I think his dog gave me
the final seal of approval.
He's crazy about that dog. Navy looks
the other way 'cause he's Ramsey.
Navy looks the other way 'cause
he's a skipper who's actually seen combat.
- He took SEALs into Panama in '89.
- Tomahawks in the Gulf in '91.
- Took out eight or nine XOs in '94.
- Ouch.
- Last one caught... What? Appendicitis?
- Yeah, right.
Take care of Mom.
And you, sailor.
- You listen to Granny, OK?
- Yeah.
- Can I have a salute?
- Bye, Dad.
- The Enemy Below.
- Robert Mitchum.
- And?
- And what?
- Robert Mitchum.
- Incomplete answer.
- The German guy with the white hair?
- What's his name?
- Who was it?
- Curt Jürgens.
- Keep my side of the bed warm, babydoll.
- I will.
Hurry home.
Don't worry.
- Bye.
- I love you. OK, bye.
You listen to Mom.
Be good.
Bye, baby.
- Hardy Krüger.
- No way.
Robert Shaw in his Nazi period.
- Question was invalid.
- We're even.
- How you doin'?
- I'm fine. Thanks.
Good. Address me as "sir"
when you speak to me!
Stand at attention, sailor!
Is he gonna fit in the sub?
Doubtful.
Who was the German sub commander
in The Enemy Below?
- Was it Curt Jürgens or Hardy Krüger?
- Sir, I...
Wrong answer! Drop down
and give me 20! Now! Move! Move!
One. Two.
- Run Silent, Run Deep.
- Three.
The guy with the ears
and a little moustache.
Cary Grant.
I'm worried about T.
- Why?
- She doesn't know what's goin' on.
I think she thinks I'm goin' away forever.
I'll take care of her.
- You will?
- Yeah.
- You promise?
- I promise.
- I love you, Dad.
- I love you too, son.
OK.
- You know I don't know what to say.
- Just say goodbye.
See you in my dreams.
Give me a kiss.
- Davis.
- How you doin', sir?
Crew present and accounted for, sir.
Little ducks,
there's trouble in Russia.
So they called us.
And we're going over there
and bringing the most lethal
killing machine ever devised.
We're capable of launching
more firepower
than has ever been released
in the history of war.
For one purpose alone -
to keep our country safe.
We constitute the front line
and the last line of defense.
I expect and demand
your very best.
Anything less,
you should have joined the Air Force.
This might be our
commander in chief's navy,
but this is my boat.
And all I ask is that you keep up with me.
And if you can't,
that strange sensation you'll be
feeling in the seat of your pants
will be my boot in your ass.
- Mr. Cob?
- Yes, sir.
You're aware of
the name of this ship, Mr. Cob?
Very aware, sir.
It bears a proud name, doesn't it, Mr. Cob?
Very proud, sir.
- It represents fine people.
- Very fine people, sir.
- Who live in a fine, outstanding state.
- Outstanding, sir.
- In the greatest country in the entire world.
- In the entire world, sir.
- And what is that name, Mr. Cob?
- Alabama, sir.
- And what do we say?
- Go, 'Bama!
Roll tide!
Chief of the Boat, dismiss the crew.
Dismiss the crew.
Aye, aye, sir.
Crew, department heads,
attend to your departments.
Fall out!
Here.
Part of your qualification for command.
The last breath of polluted air
for the next 65 days.
Gonna miss it.
I don't trust air I can't see.
This is my favorite part.
Right here, right now.
Bravo, Hunter.
Sir?
You knew to shut up and enjoy the view.
Most eggheads want to talk it away.
Your stock just went up
a couple of points.
Thank you, sir.
Allow me to give you a tiny bit of advice.
If you want your own boat someday,
the very worst thing you can do is worry
about yourself or try to impress me.
I can't stand save-asses
and I won't abide kiss-asses.
You keep your priorities straight -
your mission and your men.
How you like that cigar?
- It's good, sir.
- It's your first.
Yeah.
Don't like it too much.
They're more expensive than drugs.
- XO, take her down.
- Take her down. Aye, sir.
Control, Bridge. Sounding.
Bridge. Control.
Sounding 1-2-0 fathoms.
- Lookouts, clear the bridge.
- Clear the bridge. Aye, sir.
Officer of the Deck, prepare to dive.
- Captain down.
- Captain is down.
- XO down.
- XO is down.
Submerge the ship.
Diving Officer, submerge the ship.
Depth 1-5-0 feet.
Make my depth 1-5-0 feet. Aye, sir.
Chief of the Watch, on the One MC,
dive, dive!
Make your depth 1-5-0 feet.
Five degree down bubble.
- Uh, I don't understand.
- What?
Radchenko is a fanatic. He's a potential
Hitler. Somebody should just shoot him.
- I have no problem with that.
- Good.
It's fanatics who make history. Colonel
Patton was a fanatic. That made him great.
You think this guy is Patton?
He's a dangerous lunatic
and he's threatening nuclear war.
What's that make us, being the only
nation to drop a nuclear bomb?
It makes us a prime target.
Some Third World countries with
atom bombs would love to drop one on us.
So we should drop one on them.
Are you a communist? You have a problem
with dropping nuclear bombs on Japan?
Shut up, Dougherty.
- You think it was a mistake, Mr. Hunter?
- Sir?
Using the bomb on Hiroshima
and Nagasaki.
If I thought that, sir, I wouldn't be here.
- Interesting way you put that.
- How'd I put it, sir?
Very carefully.
You do qualify your remarks.
If somebody asked me if we should've
bombed Japan, a simple, "Yes.
"By all means, sir.
Drop that fucker. Twice."
I don't mean to suggest
that you're indecisive, Mr. Hunter.
Not at all.
Just, uh...
complicated.
Of course, that's the way
the navy wants you.
Me, they wanted simple.
You certainly fooled them, sir.
Be careful there, Mr. Hunter.
It's all I got to rely on,
being a simpleminded son of a bitch.
Rickhover gave me my command,
a checklist, a target and a button to push.
All I had to know is how to push it.
They'd tell me when.
They seem to want you to know why.
I would hope they'd want
us all to know why, sir.
At the Naval War College,
it was metallurgy and nuclear reactors,
not 19th-century philosophy.
"War is a continuation
of politics by other means."
von Clausewitz.
I think that what he was actually
trying to say was a little more...
Complicated?
Yes, the purpose of war is
to serve a political end,
but the true nature of war
is to serve itself.
Ha! I'm very impressed.
In other words, the sailor most likely
to win the war is the one most willing
to part with the politicians and ignore
all except the destruction of the enemy.
You'd agree with that.
I'd agree that, uh...
that's what Clausewitz was trying to say.
- But you wouldn't agree with it?
- No, sir, I do not.
No, I just think that in the nuclear world...
the true enemy can't be destroyed.
Attention on deck.
von Clausewitz will now tell us
exactly who the real enemy is.
von?
In my humble opinion, in the nuclear world
the true enemy is war itself.
So the captain's walking on the bridge,
and he and the dog come across
two sailors fucking each other in the ass.
How can they fuck each other in the ass?
- One's fucking the other in the ass, stupid.
- Shut up, Hunsicker.
So these two are fucking each other
in the ass, the captain says:
"What the fuck is going on here?"
The sailor said, "Hunsicker fell
overboard, I'm saving his life."
- Fuck you.
- Captain says:
"Give him mouth-to-mouth resuscitation."
Sailor says, "How do you think
this got started in the first place, sir?"
Move!
Fire in the galley! Chief of the Watch,
sound the general alarm!
Damage control,
bring fire extinguishers...
- Fire's out of control.
- You hit the kill switch?
Couldn't get to it. Too hot.
Attention, all hands.
Fire has been contained.
Damage control party,
assess damage and report to Control.
- Initiate weapons system readiness test.
- Aye, sir.
Station a reflash watch.
This thing could flare back up again.
Conn, Radio. We are receiving flash traffic.
Emergency action message.
Recommend alert one.
Alert one. Man battle stations missile
for weapons systems readiness test.
- Spin up all missiles.
- Why is he runnin' a missile drill now?
- You're in charge.
- Aye, sir.
Man battle stations missile
for weapons system readiness test.
Spin up all missiles.
This is an exercise.
Captain's in Control.
I agree. Message is properly formatted.
Sir, we have a properly formatted
emergency action message
for weapons system readiness test.
- I concur, sir.
- Where's the XO?
Sir.
Good of you to make it, Mr. Hunter.
Get the authenticator.
Let's go.
- Sir, request permission to authenticate.
- Permission granted. Authenticate.
"Alpha, Alpha, Bravo,
Echo, Charlie, Zulu, Tango."
"Alpha, Alpha, Bravo, Echo,
Charlie, Zulu, Tango."
- Captain, message is authentic.
- I concur.
- I agree.
- Message is authentic.
Sir, your captain's missile key.
Set condition One SQ for WSRT.
This is the captain. This is an exercise.
This is the XO. This is an exercise.
- That fire could still flare...
- Now is not the time.
Make your depth 1-5-0 feet. All stop.
Make my depth 1-5-0 feet.
All stop. Aye, sir.
Weapons, Conn.
Simulate pressurizing, all tubes.
Conn, Weapons. Simulate pressurizing,
all missiles. Aye, aye, sir.
- Simulate pressurizing, all missiles.
- Simulate pressurizing, all missiles. Aye.
All stations, proceed to One SQ.
Ready all missiles for launch.
Let's go!
Weapons, Captain.
Report approximate time for One SQ.
Captain, Weapons. Approximate time
to weapons system One SQ -
14 minutes, sir.
Ship is at launch depth.
Ready to hover, sir.
- Commence hovering.
- Commence hovering. Aye, sir.
Control, Sick Bay. Chief Petty Officer
Marichek is undergoing cardiac arrest.
- We're beginning CPR.
- Chief of the Watch, on the One MC.
Gentlemen, may I have your attention?
We've received word that a shipmate
has a medical problem.
We're terminating the drill. Mr. Mahoney,
take the conn. I'm going below.
- XO.
- Aye, sir. I have the conn.
Clear.
It's OK, Chief.
Thank you, sir. Sorry, sir.
Hiya, boy.
Hiya, hiya, hiya.
How ya doin'? Oh, boy. Yeah.
So, Mr. Hunter, do you think
I was wrong to run that drill?
Not necessarily, sir.
- Do you think I got that man killed?
- No, sir.
One thing had nothing to do
with the other. It was an accident.
- Would you have run the drill?
- No, sir, I would not.
Why not?
The fire could have flared back up.
I would have seen to it first.
I'm sure you would have.
Me, on the other hand, I tend to think
that's the best time to run a drill.
Confusion on the ship is nothing to fear.
It should be taken advantage of.
Lest you forget, Mr. Hunter, we are
a ship of war, designed for battle.
You don't just fight battles
when everything is hunky-dory.
Do you think I'm some crazy old coot
endangering everyone as I yell "yee-haw"?
That was not my first thought, sir.
But there's no excuse.
At the time I was fighting the fire in the
galley, I did not agree with your call, sir.
Take a seat.
Just so we understand each other.
I don't have any problems
with questions or doubts.
As I said to you before, I'm not
seeking the company of kiss-asses.
When you got somethin' to say to me,
you say it in private.
And if privacy doesn't permit itself,
then you bite your fucking tongue.
- Are we clear about that, Commander?
- As a bell, sir.
Those sailors out there are just boys,
boys who are training to do a terrible thing,
and if that ever occurs,
the only reassurance they'll have
that they're doing the proper thing
will derive from their unqualified belief
in the chain of command.
That means we don't question each
other's motives in front of the crew.
It means we don't undermine each other.
It means in a missile drill they hear your
voice right after mine, without hesitation.
- Do you agree with that policy, sailor?
- Absolutely, sir.
We're here to preserve democracy,
not to practice it.
There'll be a memorial service in
the enlisted men's mess at 1100 hours.
- Go see to it.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Oh, Hunter. I'd like you to speak to Cob
about his weight.
I find it difficult,
I've known him so long.
Yes, sir.
Short of the outbreak of World War III,
the ship sinking
or being attacked by a giant octopus,
I'd like to be undisturbed for 30 minutes.
I'll see to it, sir.
By the way, it was Marichek's
300 pounds that killed him.
Not the fire.
Dismissed.
One, two, three, four.
Back. Back.
One, two. One, two.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Does it make sense to you to start
a drill in the middle of a fire?
- Fire was out, wasn't it?
- Yeah, and a man died too.
- Not 'cause of what the captain did.
- What?
- Weps.
A fire is a serious threat to the ship.
Where was he? Why not check it out first?
That's his style. He's a hard-ass.
- So what?
- So you wanna fight him, go ahead.
You wanna get along,
understand him a little bit.
Two schools of thought here.
To him, you're Annapolis, Harvard,
expert on theory,
- well-versed in world affairs.
- Ha!
He's had his head up his ass
drivin' ships for the 25 last years.
He's probably a little paranoid about that.
I mean, navy's all he's got.
Navy and that little rat dog of his.
That's why his wife left him.
So what are you saying?
I'm just sayin' watch out.
Give him a little room.
Let him get to know you.
You do pants too?
Conn, Radio. Receiving emergency action
message. Recommend alert one.
Alert one. Alert one.
Incoming emergency
action message.
Alert one. Alert one.
Incoming EAM.
Captain.
Captain has asked me to brief you on the
emergency action message we received.
As you know, before we got underway,
the Russian army was in position
encircling the rebel camps,
and Radchenko started making threats
should anyone move in on him,
that he would launch his land-based
nuclear weapons at the US and at Japan.
The safeguard was that the Russian
government controlled the launch codes.
Intel now indicates that those
launch codes have been compromised,
and US military forces have been
directed to set DEFCON three.
The last time we hit this state of emergency
was 32½ years ago,
during the Cuban missile crisis.
So this is what it's all about, gentlemen.
It's what we train for.
It's why this ship was built.
And it's what our nuclear weapons
will be used for if necessary.
Captain.
The NCA has determined that
should our satellites detect
rebel missiles being fueled -
which means they could be
launched in just over one hour -
we'll be compelled to act.
Now, given our patrol sector
here in the Emperor Sea Mounts,
it seems clear that our friends
in the Pentagon
are setting us up for
a potential preemptive strike.
It's important to remain focused.
Keep your men informed.
Any questions?
Dismissed.
We lost that frying unit and then...
I'm gonna fuck you up!
Get out! Get...
Get out of here, man! Get him out!
Motherfucker!
Fuckin' Guinea piece of shit.
- Rivetti, what's up?
- I'm sorry, sir. Just a difference of opinion.
- What about?
- It's too silly, sir. I'd rather just forget...
I don't give a damn about what you'd rather
forget about. Why were you two fighting?
I said the Kirby Silver Surfer
was the only real Silver Surfer,
and that the Moebius Silver Surfer was
shit. Bennefield's a big Moebius fan, and...
Things got out of hand. I pushed him, he
pushed me. I lost my head, sir. I'm sorry.
Rivetti, you're a supervisor.
You can get a commission like that.
I know it, sir. You're 100% right.
- It'll never happen again.
- It better not.
I see this kind of nonsense,
I'll write you up. Understand?
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
You set an example
even in the face of stupidity.
Every comic book reader
knows that Kirby Silver Surfer
is the only true Silver Surfer.
Now, am I right or wrong?
- You're right, sir.
- All right. Get out of here.
Captain.
- How can I help you?
- Test results from the missile drill.
This the best they can do?
- No, sir, but that's what they did.
- I want this down to five minutes.
- Train on it.
- Yes, sir.
Tell your buddy Weps
we're gonna do it again.
We're gonna keep on doin' it
until he gets it right.
Damn.
Feels like the whole crew
needs a kick in the ass.
Or a pat on the back, sir.
I just witnessed a fight down in
crew's mess. No big deal, but...
I think the men are... a little on edge
with all we're going through.
Morale seems to be a bit low.
Well, you seem to have
the pulse of the men.
Thank you, sir.
Attention, please.
Mr. Hunter has brought it
to my attention
that morale may be a bit low.
That you may be a bit...
On edge, sir.
...on edge.
So I suggest this,
any crew member who feels
he can't handle the situation
can leave the ship right now.
Gentlemen, we're at DEFCON three.
War is imminent.
This is the captain.
That is all.
Very inspiring, sir.
Come on, Bear.
Come on. Come on.
Come in.
Sir.
Cob, this is a difficult subject
to talk about. Uh...
- I gather from...
- Maybe I can help, sir.
I know I'm overweight,
but this is my last tour.
I retire after this.
I just... can't seem to stop eating.
- Have a seat, Cob.
- Yes, sir.
What did you think of
the captain's speech?
Well, the captain seems to know
what his men seem to need.
A pat on the back or a kick in the ass?
His speech made sense to me.
So why don't you say
what's really on your mind?
With all due respect, this thing between
you and the captain is no good.
Somebody's gotta bend, sir,
and he is the skipper.
I'm aware of that, Cob.
Yes, sir.
Sir, what I think we have here is
a difference in management styles.
But as unpredictable as he is,
there is a logic to it.
He navigates by his own star,
not many men can do that.
Cob's rules of navy leadership.
One, look like you know what you're doing.
Two, the men must believe you
know what you're doing.
And three, and most important,
everybody's got an opinion
but the captain's gotta make a choice.
You live and die with that, and that's where
the skipper's earned his stripes, sir.
I've seen it time and time again.
So when you're right, you're right.
That's what my daddy said.
Right's right, and wrong's for nobody.
You hungry?
Always.
Let's get something to eat.
Yes, sir.
Sup? Come here.
You hear that?
I've got a broadband contact bearing 0-4-7.
Assigning tracker Sierra in ATF.
Conn, Sonar. We have a possible
submerged submarine bearing 0-4-7.
Designate contact Master 2-8.
Sonar, Conn, aye. Man battle stations
torpedo. Rig for ultraquiet.
- Make tubes one and four fully ready.
- Tubes one and four fully ready. Aye.
Man battle stations torpedo.
What do you got?
Sir, a possible submerged submarine,
bearing 0-4-9, designate Master 2-8.
Best depth for evasion, sir,
is 8-3-1 feet to avoid that sub.
Mahoney, this is the captain.
Increase your speed to standard.
Come left to course 2-7-0.
Make your depth 8-3-1 feet, smartly.
- You find out who that is.
- Aye, sir.
Who are you, sweetheart?
Helm, all ahead standard.
Dive, make your depth 8-3-1 feet, smartly.
Aye, sir.
Conn, Radio. Receiving emergency
action message. Recommend alert one.
Recommend alert one.
Alert one. Alert one.
Incoming emergency action message.
Captain, we have a properly formatted
emergency action message
from National Command Authority
for strategic missile launch.
- I concur, sir.
- Get the authenticator.
Chief of the Watch,
secure for battle stations torpedo.
Man battle stations missile
for strategic launch.
Secure for battle stations torpedo.
- Man battle stations missile...
- Permission to authenticate.
Permission granted. Authenticate.
"Bravo, Echo, Echo,
Charlie, Alpha, Tango, Alpha."
"Bravo, Echo, Echo, Charlie,
Alpha, Tango, Alpha."
- Message is authentic, sir.
- I concur, sir.
I concur, sir.
- Message is authentic.
- Sir, your captain's missile key.
This is the captain. Set condition One SQ
for strategic missile launch.
Spin up missiles one through five
and 20 through 24.
The release of nuclear weapons
has been authorized.
This is not a drill.
XO, take the conn. I'm going
to my stateroom for the launch keys.
XO has the conn.
Set condition One SQ
for strategic missile launch.
Spin up missiles one through five,
20 through 24.
The release of nuclear weapons
has been authorized. This is the XO.
Conn, Weapons. Estimated time to One
SQ for strategic launch is 14 minutes, sir.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
Go, sailor, go.
Set condition One SQ
for strategic missile launch.
- Comin' through!
- Spin up missiles one through five
and 20 through 24.
- I have the conn.
- The captain has the conn.
Passing 5-5-0 feet.
Conn, Radio. Sir, we're out of VLF radio
range. Full message capacity is cut off.
Radio, Conn.
Extend extremely low frequency antenna.
Passing 600 feet.
Coming to 8-3-1 feet, sir.
Jesus. Oh, God. Uh...
Conn, Sonar.
Uh, sir, we have his classification.
Mark that tape.
Get the classification on your monitor.
What the hell is going on?
Sir, the Master 2-8 is classified as
a Russian Akula class hunter-killer.
Bearing 1-9-6, sir. He's close,
but I don't think he's spotted us.
- Stay on him!
- Aye, sir.
- Captain has the conn.
- Passing 800 feet, sir.
Continue to dive.
Give me five degree down bubble.
- Continue rigging for ultraquiet.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Five degree down bubble.
Rigging for ultraquiet, sir.
Gentlemen, this is the captain.
We have an Akula class submarine
out there.
We know Radchenko controls at least
four submarines. This could be one.
Russian rebels have threatened
to launch against our country,
and are fueling right now.
They will have launch capability
in 60 minutes.
We have orders to launch our missiles,
which is exactly what we're going to do.
We are rigging for ultraquiet.
All hands, be ready.
This is as real as it gets.
We'll presume nothing,
defend ourselves at all cost.
If that sub so much as comes around
or opens up a tube door, we'll take her out.
Passing 900 feet.
He's gone.
Like hell he is.
He's up there.
9-5-0.
Conn, Weapons. Missile systems
ready to launch in 11 minutes.
Conn, Radio. Receiving transmission
on extremely low frequency receiver, sir.
Very well.
Mr. Hunter, go to Radio, please.
- OK, pull up the code.
- What do you got?
XO, incoming EAM, but we're too deep
to receive any radio communication, sir.
- Captain.
- XO.
We got a limited radio transmission
indicating an incoming EAM.
We need to go shallow
to reestablish communications.
With that sub still up there?
Mr. Hunter, it's my inten...
- Come up to Conn, Mr. Hunter.
- Yes, sir.
- Zero bubble.
- Zero bubble. Aye, sir.
1275 feet, sir.
Conn. Weapons. Missile systems
ready to launch in ten minutes.
- Sir.
- Attention, all hands.
- Ship has been rigged for ultraquiet.
- Captain?
When our missile system is ready,
Mr. Hunter,
it is my intention
to rise to launch depth,
launch our birds and then get
the hell out of there. Not until then.
I can't jeopardize
the safety of this ship.
Yes, sir.
May I suggest that we float the buoy, sir?
We have enough cable.
That should give us enough reach
to receive the EAM transmission. Sir.
Very well, float the buoy.
- Chief of the Watch, float the buoy.
- Float the radio buoy. Aye, sir.
Radio buoy
deploying, sir. Tension, 2,000 pounds.
Very well.
Conn, Weapons. Estimated time
to One SQ, eight minutes, 30 seconds, sir.
The winch!
Conn, Sonar. We have a sound short
from the buoy winch!
Stop the goddamn winch!
Winch is stopped, sir.
Goddamn it.
- TSO, is that sound still out there?
- Sonar, TSO. Is that sound still out there?
Sound's gone, sir.
I'm getting something.
- Sup, he's comin' around.
- Conn, Sonar. Akula is turning toward!
- They're range gating, sir.
- What's range gating?
They've got the torpedoes locked on us.
Conn, Sonar.
Torpedo in the water. Bearing 2-4-1.
Conn, Sonar. Second torpedo
in the water. Bearing 2-4-2.
All ahead flank.
Right full rudder.
Conn, Sonar.
3,000 yards and closing, sir.
Maneuvering, Conn. Cavitate.
- Sound the collision alarm.
- Aye, sir.
- 2500 yards.
- Rig ship for impact.
Hang on to your ass, gentlemen!
2.000 yards.
1500 yards.
Bearing 0-7-0-0-7-1.
1,200 yards.
1,000 yards and closing fast.
Conn, Radio. Receiving emergency
action message. Recommend alert one.
950 yards.
Launch a five-inch evasion device.
Launch countermeasures.
- Countermeasures away, sir.
- Shift your rudder to left full.
500 yards and closing fast.
300 yards and closing, sir.
Sir, the first torpedo's
going after the countermeasures.
They missed! They missed!
Sonar, Conn. Second torpedo incoming.
It's gonna be close.
Conn. Sonar.
The Akula's disappeared in the thermal.
All ahead standard.
Rudder amid ships.
- All ahead standard. Rudder amid ships.
- All stations.
All stations, report damage.
Report damage.
Engine room reports
number one ASW-pump failed.
Torpedo room. Water in the bilge.
Request a team with a submersible pump.
Engine room. Request all E-division
personnel to assist in ground isolation.
Sonar, Conn.
Report hostile contact.
- Conn. Sonar. We lost him, sir.
- Keep looking. He's looking for us.
Aye, sir.
Weapons, Conn.
Estimated time to One SQ.
Conn, Weapons. Missile systems
ready to launch in six minutes.
Very well.
Main seawater pump
is out of commission.
Mr. Zimmer, where's that EAM?
- You all right, son?
- Yes, sir.
- That's it?
- Uh-huh. It's incomplete, sir.
We lost it when
the radio buoy cable got severed.
All right.
All right, gentlemen, let's get on with it.
All ahead one-third.
Steady as you go.
Steady. Aye, sir.
Make your depth 1-5-0 feet.
Zero bubble.
Up slow and silent to launch depth.
Aye, aye, Captain.
Captain?
Got the EAM.
- What do you think?
- I think there's nothing on this.
Yes, sir.
It got cut off during the attack.
Then it's meaningless.
Sir, this is an EAM pertaining to nuclear...
No, Mr. Hunter,
that's a message fragment.
Because it got cut off during the attack, sir.
It could be a message to abort...
- It could be a fake Russian transmission.
- Which is why we need to confirm.
I'm asking for time to get back online.
- Calm down, Mr. Hunter.
- I am calm.
You don't appear to be.
Conn. Weapons. Missile systems
ready to launch in four minutes.
- Step aside, seaman.
- Yes, sir.
We have orders in hand and those
orders are to make a preemptive launch.
Every second we lose increases
the chances that when our missiles arrive,
their silos could be empty
'cause they've struck us first.
- Yes.
- You know as well as I do
that any launch order received
without authentication is no order.
That's our number one rule.
That rule is the basis for the scenario
we've trained on time after time.
It's a rule we follow without exception.
Captain, National Military Command
Center knows what sector we're in.
They have satellites
to see if our birds are aloft,
and if they're not,
they give our orders to somebody else.
That's why we maintain
more than one sub - redundancy.
- I know about redundancy, Mr. Hunter.
- All I'm saying...
All I'm saying, Captain,
is that we have backup.
Now, it's our duty not to launch
until we can confirm.
You're presuming that we have
other submarines ready to launch.
As captain, I must assume our submarines
could've been taken out by other Akulas.
We can play these games, but I don't have
the luxury of your presumptions.
- Sir...
- Mr. Hunter.
We have rules that are not open
to interpretation, personal intuition,
gut feelings, hairs on your neck,
little devils or angels on your shoulders.
- Captain...
- We're all very well aware of our orders.
They come from our commander in chief.
They contain no ambiguity.
- Captain...
- Mr. Hunter. I've made the decision.
I'm captain of this boat.
Now shut the fuck up!
Damn.
Weapons, Conn.
Shift targeting to target package
SLBM 647412/2.
This is the captain.
- I cannot concur.
- Repeat my command.
We don't know what this means.
Our target could have changed.
You repeat this order
or I'll find somebody who will!
- You won't.
- You're relieved of your position.
Cob, remove Mr. Hunter from the control
room. Get Lieutenant Zimmer in here!
I do not concur.
I do not recognize your authority
to relieve me under navy regulations.
Cob, arrest this man
and get him out of here!
Operating procedures governing
release of nuclear weapons
we cannot launch our missiles
unless both you and I agree.
Cob, what are you waiting for?
This is why your command must be
repeated. It requires my assent.
I do not give it.
You continue to insist upon this launch
without confirming this message first,
I will be backed by
the rules of precedence...
As commanding officer
of the USS Alabama.
I order you to place the XO under arrest
on the charge of mutiny!
I say again, I order you to place the XO
under arrest on the charge of mutiny!
Cob!
Captain, please, the XO is right.
We can't launch unless he concurs.
"To the USS Alabama.
Rebel-controlled missiles being fueled.
"Launch codes compromised. Dissidents
threaten launch at continental US.
Set DEFCON two. Immediately launch
ten Trident missile sorties."
They're fueling their missiles!
We don't have time to fuck around!
- I think you need time to think this over.
- I don't have to think this over!
Captain, I relieve you of your command.
Cob, escort the captain to his stateroom.
- I'm assuming command.
- You're not.
Chief of the Boat, Captain Ramsey's
under arrest. Lock him in his stateroom.
- Captain, please...
- Now, Cob!
Aye, sir.
Mitchell, Walker.
Take the captain below.
You're way out of your league, Hunter.
You're not ready to make
tough decisions yet.
What the hell we waitin' for?
Anybody here disagrees
with what I've done...
then you feel free
to relieve yourself of duty now.
Anybody?
All right.
- All stations.
- Aye, sir.
This is the executive officer.
I have assumed command of this ship
under authority granted me
by navy regulations.
I have relieved Captain Ramsey
of his duties for acting in contravention
of the rules and regulations
regarding nuclear weapons release.
It is my intention
to delay the missile launch
maintaining our current state of readiness
pending confirmation of an emergency
action message cut off during the attack.
Remain at battle stations missile.
Carry on.
- What the hell are we doin', Fred?
- I'm pissin' my pants.
Come on, boy.
Conn, Weapons. Russians will have
missile launch capability in 39 minutes.
Chief of the Boat.
Sir?
Thank you, Cob.
"Thank you"?
Fuck you.
Get it straight, Mr. Hunter.
I'm not on your side.
You could be wrong. But wrong or right,
the captain can't just replace you at will.
That was completely improper,
and that's why I did what I did, by the book.
I thank you anyway.
Radio, Conn. Mr. Zimmer, get those
communications back online now.
We're working on it, sir.
Aye, aye, Captain.
- Are you ready?
- Uh... ready.
Go.
Jesus. Fuckin' thing.
This whole system is crashed. Radio buoy
is severed. What does he want us to do?
- Shit electrons?
- Hey, Vossler, we need communications.
Aye, sir.
- All stop, ten degrees up.
- Ten up. Aye, sir.
All stop. Aye, sir. All stop.
Conn, Sonar. Holy shit, sir!
He's on top of us! He's turning toward.
- Range?
- 600 yards.
Conn, Sonar. Torpedoes in the water.
Bearing 0-4-8-0-5-0.
- Left full rudder.
- Aye, sir.
All ahead full. Zero bubble.
- Torpedoes are ready.
- No. Our weapons won't have time to arm.
All ahead flank. Chief of the Watch
to Maneuvering. Max speed.
Maximum speed.
Sonar, Conn. Let me know when our range
to that Akula has opened to 1,000 yards.
Aye, sir.
Let's shoot the fucker!
What's 1,000 yards for?
It takes 1,000 yards for the torpedoes to
arm. Who'd you fuck to get on this ship?
Conn, Sonar. Torpedoes,
150 yards and closing fast, sir.
Bearing 0-7-0-0-7-4.
Launch port countermeasures.
- Countermeasures away, sir.
- Rig ship for impact.
Aye, sir.
They missed! They passed astern.
They were too close to arm, sir.
Conn, Sonar. Range to the Akula
950 yards and opening fast.
Go to arming mechanisms,
tubes two and four.
- Snapshot, two and four.
- Tubes fired electrically, sir.
Give me exact ranging
and speed on our weapons.
Range 300 yards and 50 knots, sir.
200 yards, 50 knots.
100 yards, 55 knots.
75 yards.
Weapons ready for arming, sir.
- Steady course 2-3-1.
- Aye, sir. 2-3-1.
Arm torpedoes two and four...
- Now.
- Torpedoes armed.
We're locked on the Akula!
You got him, sir! You got him!
Conn, Sonar. Incoming torpedo. They
must have got one off before they got hit.
Right full rudder.
Launch starboard countermeasures.
- Countermeasures away.
- Dive, depth 1200 feet.
Down now. Take her deep, take her deep.
Full dive on those planes. Let's go!
Hang on, everybody!
- Is everybody OK?
- Yeah!
Open the aft main drain suction!
Start the drain pump!
Go, go, go!
All stations,
make damage report to Control.
Control, this is Bilge Bay.
We've got out-of-control flooding.
Request damage control.
- Get a damage control party down there.
- Aye, sir.
Get Lieutenant Hellerman. Flooding
in the bilge bay. Get him down there now!
Conn, Maneuvering.
We've lost propulsion, sir.
- Chief of the Boat, how we doin'?
- We are going down. I need propulsion.
Forward ballast tanks are damaged, sir.
Forward air pressure, zero.
Maneuvering, Conn.
Restore propulsion as soon as possible.
Restoring propulsion
as soon as possible. Aye, sir.
Control, Bilge Bay. Flooding is slowed.
I think we got it under control, sir.
Passing 1500 feet.
At 1850, it's all over.
Passing 1600 feet.
Barnes, get over here.
Help me with this loose valve!
Passing 1650 feet.
- What the fuck is going on?
- Take it easy.
Conn, Bilge Bay. Flooding has
recommenced. Three men are trapped.
Bilge Bay, Conn. Try and get those men
out of there and seal that bay.
Sir, if we don't seal the bilge bay now,
we'll lose the ship.
Bilge Bay, Conn.
Can you get the men out?
There's no way.
If I go down there, I'll never get out.
Barnes, come on!
You've got to come! Move, move!
You can do it! Move it!
Bilge Bay, Conn.
Seal that bay.
Barnes, let's go! Come on!
I've got to close the hatch!
What the fuck are we doing here?
Bilge Bay, Conn.
I say again, seal that bay.
Sir, there are men down there.
They're gonna drown.
Lieutenant Hellerman,
you have your orders.
Now seal the goddamn bay
before we all go down!
Barnes!
Please, get the fuck out!
Come on!
Barnes!
Conn, Bilge Bay.
Seawater hatch is sealed, sir.
Very well.
Passing 1800 feet.
Approaching hull crush depth, sir.
1-8-2-5.
Conn, Maneuvering.
Turbine power restored.
Main seawater cross valve repaired.
And rising.
Propulsion limit. Ahead full, sir.
- Take us up to periscope depth.
- Aye, aye, sir.
All right, we're livin'.
We're livin', gentlemen.
- Step aside.
- I'm sorry. The XO ordered...
Fuck the XO!
The ship has been hit
and I'm going in to see my captain.
Now stand aside.
Stand aside!
Captain?
Sir.
- How bad is it, Mr. Dougherty?
- It's bad, sir.
I've just been looking at Hunter's file.
The closest to combat he's been
is a policy seminar.
Give me an order, sir.
As quietly as you can, you get
to Mr. Zimmer and Mr. Westergaurd.
How about Linkletter?
Nah, you won't be able to talk
to the TSO. He's at the conn.
But you can get to Weps.
We got to have Weps. He's the key.
You get me those men, a small security
force, then come back and get me.
- Aye, sir.
- Don't try to recruit the whole ship.
- We'll lead from the top down.
- Aye, sir. Right away.
The radio's 50%.
Can I talk to you in the passageway?
Right now, Pete.
Come on.
What's goin' on?
Sir.
We're not gonna let this go down
with the XO at the helm.
- We're not?
- No, we're not.
I've been with the captain for years and I'm
meant to follow Hunter 'cause he says so?
You've been ordered to.
That's what this is about - proper orders.
He has proper orders.
He won't act on them.
He's in command now!
If they order him to launch, we'll launch
and we'll blow 'em all to hell.
I'd rather go down myself
than get this one wrong.
Look, our procedures are clear.
In the absence of a contravening order,
in a situation like this,
we follow the orders in hand.
Exactly. Know how many checks we do
to make sure a launch order is authentic?
The XO agreed with those orders. Now
he throws them away? They don't count?
- He's lost his nerve.
- Bullshit! I know this guy, Bobby!
We've been ordered to launch.
Why would we do that
if they weren't prepared to launch at us?
We don't know that. That's the point. That's
why he wants time to confirm the message.
That's the whole fucking point
is we don't have time!
Radchenko is fueling his birds.
Why do you think he's doing that? Why?
You don't put on a condom
unless you gonna fuck.
Go back to your station.
Go back to your station and stay there.
Come on, man.
Peter, think about your family, man.
I am. I am!
What do you plan to do?
Nothing without you.
You're a senior officer, a department head.
- TSO's with Hunter.
- You have keys to the small arms locker.
Now, we want to recruit a few more men
and then we're gonna open that arsenal.
I just talked to the captain in his room.
He specifically asked for you.
He says we cannot go without you.
I don't believe this.
This is a mutiny, Peter.
There's only two sides to a mutiny.
Now, your captain is asking for your help.
What are you gonna do?
All right.
Conn, Weapons. Russian missiles
will have launch capability in 24 minutes.
You're doing the right thing.
Electrical power has been
restored. Prepare to reinitiate the system.
Radio, Conn. Mr. Zimmer,
what's the status on that radio repair?
All systems are still down, sir.
Lieutenant Zimmer isn't here.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
Very well.
- Mr. Mahoney has the conn.
- Aye, sir. I have the conn.
- Cob.
- Sir?
- Send a man and find Zimmer.
- Aye, sir.
- Get a side arm.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Chief Young.
- Aye, Chief.
Turn around.
At ease, sailor.
- Sir.
- Thank you, Mr. Ince.
- Mr. Westergaurd.
- Sir.
- Mr. Zimmer.
- Ready, sir.
Let's get on with it.
Stand guard.
All you people,
return to your stations.
- Mr. Rivetti.
- Sir?
- Follow me, please.
- Yes, sir.
Is there a problem, sir?
These are the keys
to the entire submarine.
Conn, Weapons. Russian missiles
will have launch capability in 21 minutes.
Who's in charge here?
Shit!
Me, sir. Oh, fuck!
- How long is it gonna take?
- I don't know, sir.
- Do you know what's going on?
- Yes.
No, I don't think you do.
Let me explain it to you.
If we launch and we're wrong,
what's left of Russia is gonna launch at us.
There will be a nuclear holocaust beyond
imagination. It's about knowing, Mr...
Vossler. We have to know whether our
order to launch has been recalled or not.
The only way we're gonna know is
if you fix that radio. You understand?
Yes, sir.
- You ever watch Star Trek?
- Yeah...
Star Trek. You know, Star Trek,
the USS Enterprise. All right.
Remember when the Klingons were gonna
blow up the Enterprise? Kirk says:
- "Scotty, I gotta have more power."
- He needs more warp speed. Yeah.
Well, I'm Captain Kirk.
You're Scotty. I need more power.
If you don't get this radio up,
a billion people will die. It's up to you.
I know that's a shitty deal, but you got it.
Can you handle it?
Scotty?
Aye, Captain.
- You got anything?
- No, Vossler.
Then get on it.
- I have the conn.
- XO has the conn.
Chief of the Boat, make your depth
7-5 feet. Continue up to periscope depth.
Delay that order!
Any of you officers or chiefs feel you've
been unjustly caught up in this thing,
you stand with me now.
Sir, propulsion has been restored.
All flooding has been contained.
All communications are still down.
Take him away.
Lock him up in the officers' mess.
Of all the people.
Weps, return to Missile Control.
- Mr. Zimmer, stay with me.
- Aye, sir.
Return to your stations. Inform your men
directly that the captain is in command.
- I have the conn.
- Captain has the conn.
- Diving officer, make the depth 1-5-0 feet.
- 1-5-0 feet. Aye, sir.
- One MC.
- Aye, sir.
May I have your attention, please.
Crew of the USS Alabama.
Attempted mutiny has been put down.
We'll maintain security alert. Authorized
movement only in two-man teams.
In the absence of
further radio communication,
on orders from
the National Command Center,
we'll achieve launch depth as quickly
as we can for strategic missile launch.
We all know what this means.
It's not something one would wish for,
but we have the obligation under
orders issued by our commander in chief
to prevent the attack on our country.
Russian missiles will have
launch capability in 15 minutes.
Set condition One SQ.
Spin up missiles one through five and
20 through 24 for strategic missile launch.
The use of nuclear weapons
has been authorized.
This is the captain.
Mr. Zimmer is the new XO.
Set condition One SQ.
Spin up missiles one through five
and 20 through 24 for strategic launch.
The use of nuclear weapons
has been authorized.
This is the XO.
Weapons, Conn.
Confirm target package SLBM 64741/2
for missiles one through five
and 20 through 24.
- Target package confirmation, sir.
- This is the captain.
Conn, Weapons.
Confirm target package SLBM 64741/2
for missiles one through five
and 20 through 24. Aye, sir.
Look, It's not a mutiny.
I did everything by the book.
It's not about the book.
If the Russians are gonna launch
and we sit here and do nothing,
who's gonna stop 'em?
Half of me is glad the captain came back.
He could be right, you know.
No orders are valid, Cob,
if they're wrong.
- We don't know if they're wrong.
- That's true. We don't know.
That's why we have to find out first.
What if Radchenko surrendered
and it's over? Hm?
We launch. They see us.
They launch.
Our birds pass each other
in the air. Boom!
- What do you got?
- Nuclear war.
Nuclear holocaust.
I gotta take a wiz.
OK.
Sir?
- What are you doing here?
- Just going to the bath...
Nobody moves alone.
You know the drill.
Come on, I need an escort to take a shit?
Shut up.
- I'm gonna call Control. You stay there.
- Fuck that.
I mean it, man.
OK, Moebius, open the door.
- You broke my nose, man.
- Shut up, fat boy.
- Mr. Rivetti, I'm impressed.
- I never liked him.
Go to Laundry.
Get four sets of coveralls, and four caps.
Aye, sir.
Just relax.
Davis. Can I talk to you a second?
Come on.
- Everybody ready?
- Let's do it.
- We're with you, sir.
- Let's go.
- Approaching launch depth.
- Very well.
Make your depth 1-5-0 feet.
- Zero bubble. Commence hovering.
- Aye, sir.
Conn, Weapons. Estimated time
to weapons system One SQ,
three minutes, 30 seconds, sir.
Conn, Weapons. Russian missiles
will have launch capability in 12 minutes.
Opening missile hatches.
- Weps.
- This is Hunter. Listen to me.
- Where are you?
Don't worry about that. You can't proceed.
We got other ships that can handle this.
You can't be influenced by the captain or
anybody else. Make up your own mind.
Conn, Weapons. Estimated time to
missile launch three minutes and counting.
Weps, Weps, listen.
Don't do this.
Once you launch, they cannot come back,
and you know the repercussions
if we're wrong, Weps.
If we fire now, we'll be firing while we're
blind and crippled. You understand me?
- Where the fuck are you?
- Do not remove that firing trigger.
Do not open the safe.
It's up to you.
You're the only one that knows
the combination. It's up to you, Weps.
It's up to you.
Mind your fuckin' panel!
- You guys ready?
- Just about, sir.
Radio, XO. Vossler?
XO, Radio. Sir...
I don't know, sir.
Vossler, calm down.
Take a deep breath. Are you calm?
Yeah, sort of.
Get the radio fixed, Vossler.
How long is it gonna take you?
I don't know.
Well, how much time do you need?
Shit!
- Let's go.
- OK.
Missile tubes one through five
and 20 through 24 at One SQ, sir.
Ship is hovering on automatic.
Dive is at One SQ, Captain.
Missiles at One SQ.
Ready to launch, sir.
Sir, weapons system is at One SQ.
Missiles are ready for launch, sir.
Very well.
- Weapons.
- Aye, sir.
Weapons, Conn.
Remove the tactical firing trigger.
- One MC.
- Aye, sir.
Weapons, this is the captain.
Unlock the tactical firing trigger.
Weps?
Missiles are ready to launch, man.
Sir.
Shit.
Mr. Zimmer.
No one is to touch this key.
I'm gonna launch from Missile Control.
Aye, aye, sir.
Westergaurd. Dougherty.
Come with me.
- Mr. Mahoney, take the conn.
- Aye, sir. I have the conn.
What are you doing, man?
We're at One SQ. We're ready.
- Mr. Dougherty.
- Aye.
- Station your guards fore and aft.
- Last two, forward hatch.
First two, aft hatch.
They're gonna fire from Missile Control.
We gotta get back to the conn,
disarm the system.
We'll travel in the crawl spaces.
Mr. Ince!
Mr. Ince, remove the tactical firing key.
Sir, it is my duty to...
Son, don't talk to me about duty.
Open the fucking safe!
I can't do that, sir.
I'm gonna count to three and then
I'm gonna blow your fucking head off. One.
Two.
Shit!
It does me no good to kill you. You're
the only one that knows the combination.
However...
Petty Officer Hilaire
doesn't know the combination.
Millions of lives at stake here, Peter.
Don't make a dumb decision.
One!
Two!
Sir!
- Cob.
- Yo.
You and Hunsicker
enter the conn from the bow.
We will come in through the aft.
Rivetti, you jump on Zimmer, OK?
Come on, come on!
- Fire Control ready?
- Aye.
- Launcher ready?
- Aye, sir.
Initiate fire.
- Freeze!
- Drop the weapon now!
Move forward! Move, move, move,
move, move! Get his pistol.
Fire one!
Number one did not fire, sir.
Sir, the captain's key has been removed.
Hunter.
- Come on.
- You're a piece of shit.
You and you, man the forward hatches.
You, you, man the aft hatches.
We're going up to periscope depth,
we're gonna reestablish communications
and get that message.
Now, anybody got a problem with that?
- Chief of the Boat, depth 7-8 feet.
- Aye, aye, sir. Five degree up bubble.
- Mr. Linkletter, man that periscope.
- Raising number two scope.
Radio, Conn. Mr. Vossler.
This is Captain Kirk.
I need warp speed on that radio.
Yes, sir.
Conn, Weapons. Russian missiles will
have launch capability in nine minutes.
Oh, shit!
- What happened?
- Reattach that lead.
78 feet.
At periscope depth, sir.
- Mr. Linkletter.
- No close contact, sir.
Very well. Chief of the Watch,
raise the VLF radio antenna.
Raise the VLF antenna.
Aye, sir.
VLF antenna coming up.
Conn, Radio. Sir, I think she's breathing.
We're getting close.
- Halt, sir!
- Shoot me.
Shit. Shit.
I got him.
I have the conn.
Give me my missile key.
Give me the missile key, Mr. Hunter.
I'm the commander of this fucking ship!
Give me that goddamn key!
Conn. Weapons. Russian missiles will
have launch capability in seven minutes.
Conn. Radio. Sir.
Radio, Conn.
Captain, Radio. Vossler, sir. She's
breathing again. We are really close.
You got three minutes, Vossler.
Three minutes and counting.
Yes, sir.
You got three minutes.
Come on.
Come on, Vossler. Come on.
Keep it going, keep it going.
Speaking of horses...
did you ever see
those Lippizaner stallions?
What?
From Portugal.
The Lippizaner stallions.
The most highly trained horses
in the world. They're all white.
Yes, sir.
"Yes, sir," you're aware they're all white,
or "Yes, sir," you've seen them?
Yes, sir, I've seen them.
Yes, sir, I'm aware that they're all white.
They're not from Portugal.
They're from Spain.
And at birth, they're not white.
They're black.
Sir.
I didn't know that.
But they are from Portugal.
- Come on, Vossler, come on.
- Yes. Yes.
Come on. Come on. You got it.
Some of the things they do,
uh, defy belief.
Their training program is simplicity itself.
You just stick a cattle prod up their ass
and you can get a horse to deal cards.
Simple matter of voltage.
You're gonna get it. Come on.
I almost had it. You saw it.
Conn, Weapons. Russian missiles will
have launch capability in four minutes.
- There you go! There you go!
- Ah, shit!
- Go, go, go.
- Look at it, Vossler.
There we go, there we go!
Yes!
Conn, Radio. Flash traffic.
Emergency action message.
Recommend alert one.
Fuck, yeah!
Alert one. Alert one.
Dougherty, Westergaurd, Zimmer.
- Get that EAM.
- Aye, aye, sir.
God help you if you're wrong.
If I'm wrong, then we're at war.
God help us all.
Sir, we have a properly formatted
emergency action message
from the National Command Authority.
Permission to authenticate.
Permission granted.
Authenticate.
"Delta, Delta, Sierra,
Bravo, Zulu, Delta, Tango."
- Message is authentic, Captain.
- I concur, sir.
I concur, sir.
Message is authentic.
One MC.
Crew of the Alabama.
this is the captain.
Set condition Two SQ.
Terminate launch, all missiles.
Mr. Hunter has the conn.
In the early hours, Russian army forces
moved in and met little resistance.
There were some sporadic battles, but
the specter of fighting their countrymen
proved too much for these rebel troops
and they surrendered quickly.
So a crisis that seemed to be escalating
beyond the point of no return
was ultimately resolved with fewer
than a hundred soldiers dead,
and the nuclear base captured by
Radchenko is back in government hands.
Reporting live from the French aircraft
carrier Foch in the Mediterranean Sea,
this is Richard Valeriani for CNN.
Chief of the Boat.
Captain Ramsey.
Lieutenant Commander Hunter.
Stand there Lieutenant Commander
Hunter. This won't take long.
This panel has convened
in order to investigate the events
subsequent to the setting of condition
One SQ for strategic missile launch
on-board the USS Alabama
on 1 November.
Now, based on the testimony
from personnel on-board the Alabama
and in no small measure to that
of the senior officer, Captain Ramsey,
I am prepared to make
my recommendations to SUBPAC.
Without my testimony, sir?
- You have a problem with that?
- I might, sir.
Are you concerned that
your recollection of the events
- differs from that of your captain's?
- Well...
I have known Captain Ramsey
for almost 30 years.
We served together
on more than a few occasions.
If he is lying, this will be
the first I've heard of it.
Yes, sir.
My primary concern here
is the breakdown in the system.
In this instance, the system failed
because the two senior officers
did not work to resolve their differences
while preserving the chain of command.
Now, you may have been
proven right, Mr. Hunter,
but insofar as the letter of the law
is concerned, you were both right.
And you were also both wrong.
This is the dilemma that will
occupy this panel, this navy,
and this country's armed forces as a whole
long after you leave this room.
Off the record, you've both
created one hell of a mess -
a mutiny aboard
a United States nuclear submarine.
Violation of nuclear launch protocol.
For the record,
it is the conclusion of this panel
that your actions
aboard the Alabama were consistent
with the best traditions of the navy
and in the interests of the United States.
As such, the recommendations
of this panel will be to accept
in a manner reflective of his long
and dedicated service to his country
Captain Ramsey's request
for early retirement from active duty.
And based in no small part
on Captain Ramsey's recommendation,
that Lieutenant Commander Hunter
be given his next command
at the earliest possible convenience.
Unless, of course, you wish
to challenge these recommendations.
No, sir.
- Captain Ramsey?
- No, sir.
Dismissed.
Captain?
Just wanted to say thank you.
You were right and I was wrong.
About the horses, the Lippizaners.
They are from Spain, not Portugal.
Yes, sir.