[ Crickets Chirping ]
[ Man's Voice ]
Yes.
[ Grunting ]
[ Man ]
Please. Please.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
It's utter chaos
around here.
And I'm terrified
that we're running
out of time.
Am I trying to be
too perfect ?
Oh, but I want it to be
so exquisite.
So do we.
But we're trying to be
too exquisite.
Why not aim for the stars ?
Good morning.
We do need some answers
on the flowers.
Ah, yes, freesia, freesia.
Everywhere freesia.
Daddy loves freesia.
Good morning. Good morning.
Oh. Hello. Hi.
Lights ?
''Lights.''
Not too bright
and not too dark.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm looking for
a saffron glow,
sort of tea-dance '20s.
If food is the prose
of a party,
then lights
are its poetry.
It works.
If food is the prose of
a party, lights are its poetry.
I like that. If music were
the food of love, play on.
I'm going out of my mind.
Good morning,
Mr. Parrish.
What do you think
of all this, Helen ?
It's gonna be beautiful.
And Allison says
the president may come.
The president's got better
things to do than come to my
birthday party.
Like what ?
Daddy ?
Do you have a minute ?
Good morning, Allison.
Not much more.
Big day in the big city.
What's on your mind ?
Fireworks.
Update:
We are constructing
the number 65 on the barge.
Mm-hmm.
Archers from the State College
of New Paltz will shoot
flaming arrows at it.
When it catches fire,
it will give us the effect
of a Viking funeral,
but with none
of the morbidity.
The Hudson River Authority
says that for you, they'll make
a special dispensation.
But, of course,
there will be
an overtime bill...
for the Poughkeepsie
Fire Department.
So, what
do you think ?
Good ?
No good ?
[ Chuckles ]
Allison, I trust you.
This is your thing.
But it's your birthday.
I hate arrows.
They make me nervous.
Good morning, Dad.
Good morning, honey.
Morning.
Morning. You're ''Honey.''
I'm ''Allison.''
[ Chuckling ]
Oh.
Oh, Dad, Drew called from
the helicopter, and they're
still two minutes away.
Drew's aboard ?
Mm-hmm.
He wanted to ride
back down with you.
So why don't you sit down,
relax, and get some food
in that flat tummy of yours.
Are you coming ?
No.
You've got patients
to attend to. I've got
three hysterical chefs,
one of whom loves truffles,
the other one hates truffles,
and the third one
doesn't even know
what truffles are.
I hate parties.
But, Daddy,
calm down.
You're gonna love it.
I swear.
Isn't it enough to be on
the Earth for 65 years without
having to be reminded of it ?
- No.
- [ Chuckling ]
Will you relax ?
I know it's a big deal day.
How'd you know that ?
Drew told me.
Does he tell you
everything ?
I hope so.
You like him,
don't you ?
Yep,
I guess so.
I don't want
to interfere, but, uh--
Then don't.
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
Well, here comes
our boy now.
Shall we ?
- Okay.
- Hello, beautiful.
Hi.
Good morning, Drew.
Thanks for coming up.
Well, big day.
Wanted to line up
a few ducks before kickoff.
Any thoughts,
last minute refinements,
variations, anything ?
Thoughts, no.
I did hear a voice
last night.
A voice ?
In my sleep.
What'd it say ?
''Yes.''
[ Chuckles ]
Yes to the deal ?
Maybe. Who knows ?
You know how voices are.
Hmm ?
I thank you, Delia.
Okay, let's go.
Delia, your pen.
Hi, Bill.
How you doin' ?
Morning, Quince.
I'm doin' great,
and you ?
Oh, I'm great.
This is it, ''B-day.''
Huh ?
Sorry.
Bontecou day.
We're gonna close...
with Big John.
Look at you, Bill.
You're all cool as a cat.
Over at Bontecou's,
I'll bet he's just
shittin' in his pants.
Remember, everybody,
big meeting tonight
at Daddy's.
Dinner.
You, too, Drew.
We have lots of loose ends.
Not my birthday again ?
You're only 65 once,
Dad.
Thank God.
Now let's get
the day started.
[ Allison ]
Remember, dinner in the city
at Daddy's!
Mm-hmm.
It's so ridiculous.
Do you love Drew ?
[ Drew On Telephone,
Indistinct ]
[ Drew ]
No, don't do anything.
Just stay exactly where--
Do you love Drew ?
He's not gonna get
a better offer than that.
[ Sighs ]
You mean, like you loved Mom ?
Forget about me and Mom.
- Are you gonna marry him ?
- [ Drew ]
Oh, come on.
I'm probably.
Listen, I'm crazy about
the guy. He's smart.
He's aggressive.
He could carry Parrish
Communications into the 2 1 st
century and me along with it.
Mm-hmm.
So, what's wrong with that ?
That's for me.
I'm talking about you.
It's not what you say about
Drew. It's what you don't say.
Maybe you're not listening.
Oh, yes, I am.
[ Drew ]
Give him whatever he wants.
There's not an ounce
of excitement, not a...
whisper of a thrill.
And this relationship
has all the passion
of a pair of titmice.
I want you to get
swept away out there.
I want you to levitate.
I want you to...
sing with rapture
and dance like a dervish.
- Oh, that's all.
- Yeah. Be deliriously happy,
or at least
leave yourself open to be.
Okay.
[ Sighs ]
''Be deliriously happy.''
I shall, uh--
I shall do my utmost.
[ Chuckling ]
I know it's
a cornball thing.
But love is passion,
obsession,
someone
you can't live without.
I say,
fall head over heels.
Find someone you can love
like crazy and who will
love you the same way back.
How do you find him ?
Well, you forget your head,
and you listen to your heart.
And I'm not hearing
any heart.
'Cause the truth is, honey,
there's no sense living
your life without this.
To make the journey
and not fall deeply in love,
well, you haven't lived
a life at all.
But you have to try,
'cause if you haven't tried,
you haven't lived.
Bravo !
Oh, you're tough.
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Give it to me again,
but the short version
this time.
Okay.
Stay open.
Who knows ?
Lightning could strike.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Yeah ?
Yeah.
What do you think ?
Is it just the executive
committee,
or are you guys
gonna use me ?
Quince, man, thanks for
the offer, but it's all set
for just me and Bill.
More people might--
I know. I know,
gum up the works.
[ Bill's Voice ]
''I want you
to get swept away.''
Huh ?
I was just sayin' to Quince
that we won't need him until--
Did you hear something ?
Yeah, but I was
just sayin' to Quince--
No, no, no.
Not you.
What's the matter, Daddy ?
Nothing. I'm sorry.
[ Bill's Voice ]
''I want you to levitate.
I want you to sing with rapture
and dance like a dervish.''
''Dance like a dervish'' ?
Daddy, what is it ?
Nothing, I'm just
talking to myself.
You know me.
No, I've never known you
to talk to yourself.
Oh, well,
can I give you a lift ?
No, I'm gonna catch a cab.
Listen, are you okay ?
Yeah.
Got my garters on,
my ears pricked--
ready for action.
Okay. Well--
Go get 'em, Pops.
You're damn right.
Okay.
[ Car Door Closes ]
[ Man ]
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
[ Chattering ]
Oh, haven't heard
that one before.
I'm sorry.
I had to say it.
Honey ? Honey ?
Hi, George.
[ Chuckling ]
Honey, you have to go on.
Okay ?
There's a time to sow
and a time to reap.
You have to sow.
[ Clattering ]
Sorry.
Excuse me.
No, I liked him.
I don't like him anymore.
'Cause you're my honey.
Someone messes with you,
they mess with me.
That's it. I'm on a plane
in a heartbeat.
You let me know.
Yep, when I get my phone in,
you're my first call.
I promise.
Hit the books, get the degree.
One day we'll be hanging out
a shingle together.
How's that ?
Mmm ? Okay.
You all right ?
[ Laughing ]
Yes.
You bet.
Be strong.
I love you.
Bye-bye.
Morning.
Good morning.
[ Sighs ]
I was talkin'
kind of loud there.
I'm sorry.
Oh, not at all.
It was fascinating.
Yeah, what was fascinating
about it ?
Um--
You and, uh, ''honey'' ?
It's my kid sister.
Oh.
And she just broke up
with her boyfriend
and was thinking...
about dropping out
of law school.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, nothing to be
sorry about.
That's the way it is with
men and women, isn't it ?
What's the way ?
Nothing lasts.
Oh. Yeah, I agree.
Really ? Why ?
No, I'm interested.
I was just trying
to be agreeable.
- [ Laughing ]
- Okay. All right.
I was sharpshooting.
Oh.
No, just that
''nothing lasts''stuff.
That was the problem with
Honey's guy. He didn't
know what he wanted.
So, he's fooling around,
and she catches him at it.
You know,
like one girlfriend
isn't enough for him.
- So, you're a one-girl guy.
- Yes, I am.
That's right.
Right.
Looking for her
right now, actually.
Mmm. Who knows ?
You might be her.
No, don't laugh.
I just got into town.
I got the new job.
I'm trying to get
into this apartment.
Anyway,
so you're a doctor.
Mmm.
How'd you know ?
'Cause everyone's
a doctor around here.
This apartment building--
Everyone's in green slippers,
the green pajamas.
The guy I'm waiting for
to vacate--
doctor.
He's a doctor.
[ Chuckling ]
What kind of doctor ?
I'm a resident--
internal medicine.
So, if I needed a doctor,
you could be it.
I could be her.
Yeah.
You could be...
her.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, I could.
I'm-I'm working
at the hospital, so--
I see.
This is my lucky day.
I just get in
the big, bad city,
not only do I find a doctor,
but a beautiful woman, as well.
Do you mind me saying that ?
Oh-- No, of course.
No, it's fine.
It's fine.
It's just--
[ Chuckling ]
Listen, could I
buy you a cup of coffee ?
I have some patients coming in,
so I should probably...
Yeah, yeah.
get goin'.
I gotta get to the apartment
and get off to work.
Yeah.
But I'd still like to have
another cup of coffee.
- Um--
- Would you let me do that ?
- Well, yeah, okay.
- Deal.
Mmm.
Good morning,
Mr. Parrish.
Morning,Jennifer.
So, board convenes tomorrow.
You'll recommend we close,
and it's a deal, right ?
As close as a deal
could be.
Olympic.
[ Sighs ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Bill's Voice ]
Yes.
[ Panting ]
[ Groaning ]
Yes.
[ Panting ]
''Yes'' what ?
Yes is the answer
to your question.
Ah.
I didn't ask any question.
I believe you did.
[ Wheezing ]
Who are you ?
Goddamn it.
What's going on here ?
I think you know.
I don't.
Try.
'''Cause if you haven't tried,
you haven't lived.''
What are you talking about ?
What you were talking about.
Who is this guy ?
Tell me who you are.
Are you giving me orders ?
- No. I'm sorry, I--
- No, you're not.
You're trying
to handle the situation.
But this is the one situation
you knew you never could handle.
[ Groaning ]
It's enough...
now.
[ Panting ]
Huh ?
Talk to me, please.
There's gonna be
plenty of time for that.
What do you mean ?
I think you know, Bill.
It's kind of
a pro bono job.
''Pro bono'' ?
Yeah.
[ Chuckling ]
Meaning, doing good ?
That's me.
Gonna be doing good
all your life ?
I know what you're saying.
It doesn't pay so well,
but, I like it.
Mm-hmm.
Eventually it'll depend
on the woman I marry, I think.
Maybe she'll want lots of kids,
a bigger house, better car, uh--
College doesn't come cheap.
You know ? I don't know.
Wow.
Give up what you want
for the woman you marry.
Hmm.
Yeah, you know what ?
I would.
Yeah ?
Gladly.
'Cause you make your choices,
you know ?
Say, you and I,
if we were married, I would--
No, for an example, okay ?
If you and I were married,
I would want to give you
what you need.
That's all.
I'm talking about taking care
of each other the best you can.
What's wrong with
taking care of a woman ?
She takes care of you.
You'll have a hard time
finding a woman like that
these days.
- Shoot, you think so ?
- Mm-hmm.
I don't know.
Lightning could strike.
I've gotta go.
Yeah. Listen, did I say
something wrong ?
No ?
No.
No. No.
It was--
Sure ?
It was so right,
it scares me.
That's all.
Just--
You know, I was thinking,
I don't want you
to be my doctor.
I don't want you to...
examine me and--
Why ?
Because I like you
so much.
[ Chuckles ]
And I-- I don't want
to examine you.
You don't ?
Why not ?
Because I like you
so much.
[ Both Laughing ]
Oh, boy.
Okay.
Now I gotta go, so--
Yep, understood.
All right. All right.
Fair enough.
See ya.
Bye. Bye.
Bye-bye.
[ Car Horn Blaring ]
[ Brakes Screeching ]
[ Allison ]
Music.
I know how you love music,
Daddy. And I want to have
music that pleases you,
but doesn't put a thousand
other people to sleep.
I've agonized over it
and finally settled
on Sidney Brown.
Good.
Twenty-four men--
very eclectic.
Mm-hmm.
Plus, I'm feathering in
a Latin sextet on their breaks.
You haven't heard
a word I've said, have you ?
What, honey ? Sorry.
Daddy.
[ Bill's Voice ]
Yes.
[ Allison ]
Daddy ?
[ Sighs ]
[ Woman ]
Mr. Parrish ?
- Yes ?
- Dinner's served.
Yeah.
Never mind.
Leave it to me.
[ Bill's Voice ]
Did you miss me, Bill ?
Chow time, you guys.
What are you looking
so provoked about ?
Did you miss me ?
It's a normal question.
I missed you.
But what do I get back ?
''Not an ounce of excitement.
''Not a whisper of a thrill.
This relationship
has all the passion
of a pair of titmice.''
I'm waiting outside
the front door.
[ Allison ]
Did you speak
to the governor?
He's coming.
And his wife ?
Yeah, unfortunately.
I sat between them
at the Bronx Zoo benefit.
It was better than Seconal.
[ Bill's Voice ]
I'm waiting outside
the front door, Bill.
Won't someone let me in ?
Lillian ?
Is there somebody
at the front door ?
I didn't hear a ring, sir.
Have a look,
would you, please ?
[ Allison ]
What about the mayor?
[ Quince ] He said he's going
to be there with bells on.
[ Drew ] Good.
-Maybe they'll drown him out.
-Please don't be negative, Drew.
[ Drew ] I'm sorry.
We have an acceptance list that
would do the White House proud:
the chairman of the F.C.C.,
the Secretary General
of the U.N.,
[ Quince ] Wow.
[ Allison ]
nine senators,
I don't know how many
congressmen and at least
1 2 of the Fortune 500.
Any jocks ?
Hmm ?
No.
No 20-game-winner,
Masters champion,
someone I can talk to ?
You were right, Mr. Parrish.
There was a gentleman
at the door.
He's waiting for you
in the foyer.
Show him into the library.
Tell him I'll be right there.
[ Lillian ] Yes, sir.
[ Allison ]
I've arranged favors, silver
charm bracelets for the women,
[ Drew ] Mmm.
and platinum key chains
for the men,
all engraved ''W.P.''
But now I'm thinking
of scrubbing them.
They seem so ordinary.
Are they ordinary ?
Do they seem that way
to you, Daddy ?
I don't know.
I, uh--
Let me see.
I don't think
they're ordinary.
I think they're great.
I love key chains.
Hello ?
Anyone here ?
I said, is anyone here ?
[ Bill's Voice ]
Quiet down.
Where are you ?
I'm here.
What is this,
a joke, right ?
Some kind of elaborate
practical joke ?
[ Chuckles ]
At my 40th reunion,
we delivered a casket...
to the class president's
hotel room and, uh--
Quiet.
Where are you going,
Bill ?
I, uh--
The great Bill Parrish
at a loss for words ?
The man from whose lips fall
''rapture'' and ''passion''
and ''obsession'' ?
All those admonitions about
being ''deliriously happy,
that there is no sense
living your life without.''
All the sparks and energy
you give off,
the rosy advice you dispense
in round, pear-shaped tones.
What the hell is this ?
[ Creaking ]
Who are you ?
Just think of millenniums
multiplied by eons...
compounded by time without end.
I've been around that long.
But it's only recently
that your affairs here
have piqued my interest.
Call it boredom.
The natural curiosity of me,
the most lasting...
and significant
element in existence,
has come to see you.
About what ?
I want to have a look around
before I take you.
Take me where ?
It requires competence,
wisdom and experience.
All those things they say
about you in testimonials.
And you're the one.
The one to do what ?
Show me around,
be my guide.
And in return, you get--
I get what ?
Time:
minutes, days, weeks.
Let's not get encumbered
by detail.
What matters is
that I stay interested.
Yes.
''Yes'' what ?
Yes is the answer
to your question.
What question ?
Oh, Bill.
Come on.
The question.
The question you've been
asking yourself with
increased regularity,
at odd moments, panting through
the extra game of handball,
when you ran for the plane
in Delhi,
when you sat up in bed
last night and hit the floor
in the office this morning.
The question that is in
the back of your throat,
choking the blood
to your brain,
ringing in your ears
over and over as you
put it to yourself.
''The question.''
Yes, Bill.
The question.
Am I going to die ?
[ Regular Voice ]
Yes.
Am I dreaming this ?
Are you a dream ?
I'm not a dream.
You're coming to take me ?
What is that ?
And who the hell are you ?
You are--
Yes ?
Who am I ?
Death.
You're Death ?
Yes.
Death.
That's me.
You're not Death.
You're just a kid
in a suit.
The suit came with
the body I took.
Let me ask your opinion.
Do I blend in ?
You want me
to be your guide ?
You fill the bill,
Bill.
I do ?
Mmm.
Will you
be staying long ?
We should hope
quite a while.
And then ?
It's over.
Mr. Parrish ?
Will the gentleman be staying
for dinner, sir ?
Yes.
Thank you.
This is crazy.
You're not gonna
eat dinner with us.
No, I am eating dinner
with you...
and your family.
And that is what
we're doing.
It's not open
for discussion,
nothing is.
Don't you understand ?
Yeah.
Good.
Now lead the way.
Bill,
lead the way.
Excuse me,
may I say something ?
Yes, of course.
Well, it just occurred
to me, if, uh--
Speak up, please.
When I introduce you,
if I say who you are,
I don't think anyone
will stay for dinner.
Then don't.
Here's another possibility.
It's a little last minute,
but tell me what you think.
Kaleidoscopes.
Little gold kaleidoscopes.
Some German company
went kerplunk, and Tiffany's
picked all these things up,
and they're perfect
party favors.
Okay, they're not
personalized or anything.
They're just winter scenes--
dachshunds, snowflakes.
Hi there.
Hello.
Sorry to have...
stepped away for so long.
This is a friend of mine
I asked to drop by.
We got to talking
and stuff, and, uh--
He's gonna join us
for dinner.
Great.
How nice to meet you.
And wouldn't it be nicer
if my father would
introduce you ?
How nice to meet you.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
This is my daughter, Allison,
and her husband, Quince,
and Drew, my number one,
works with me.
Daddy, does your friend
have a name ?
- A name ?
- Something he goes by ?
Oh, yeah, excuse me.
This is, uh--
This is, um--
Daddy, come on. A name.
Bill, the suspense
is killing me.
I'm sorry. It's, uh--
It's gone right out
of my head. Um--
I'm sorry.
This is...Joe.
- [ Allison ]
Joe. I love that name.
-Just plain Joe.
Me too.
Hey, buddy.
- Is there any more to it ?
- What do you mean ?
Like ''Smith''
or ''Jones'' or--
Black.
[ Allison ]
Oh, at last.
Nice to meet you,
Mr. Black.
Hey, hey,Joe Black.
Won 1 5, lost 2
for the Brooklyn Dodgers, 1 952.
I'm king of
my rotisserie league.
Are you ?
Yeah, he is.
Shall we sit down ?
Right there.
[ Sniffing ]
Have we met ?
- He's from out of town.
- How long you here for,Joe ?
As long as it takes.
You and Bill,
you old friends ?
[ Bill ] No.
No, thank you.
I have one, thank you.
- I get the feeling you've done
some business before.
- I got it.
Have you done
some business before ?
We have an arrangement now.
What side of the industry
did you say you were on ?
I didn't say.
Joe sounds like
a ringer, Bill.
I have a feeling you guys got
the broad strokes already.
You need any help
with the details ?
I'm sorry,
business at dinner.
Forgive me
for being so rude.
Certainly.
Hi, everybody.
I'm sorry I'm late.
- I had to have dinner
with my department chief.
- You ate ?
I'm here, aren't I ?
I wouldn't miss
a loose ends meeting.
What's on the table
for discussion ?
Party favors, flowers--
Hi, Dad.
Hi.
Hello.
Hi, Drew.
What are you doing here ?
You know each other ?
We've met.
[ Chuckles ]
This morning,
the Corinth Coffee Shop.
He was, uh--
He was looking for a doctor.
Well, I guess
he's found one.
[ Susan Chuckling ]
Joe,
you do get around.
That's your name ?
[ Allison ]
And isn't it a lovely one ?
So sturdy, so straight.
Stop it.
[ Laughing ]
Incidentally, Joe,
where are you staying ?
- Here.
- You're staying here ?
- In this house ?
- Yes, in this house.
[ Quince ]
Great. Great.
Great.
Will that hold you,Joe ?
Incidentally,Joe what ?
Black.
This is fun.
Yes.
Yes, Quince, it is.
[ Chuckling ]
So, what are you doing
here,Joe ?
Cat got your tongue ?
[ Chuckling ]
You weren't so silent
this morning.
This morning, yes.
I wasn't quite myself.
Well, it's a shame
whoever you were
couldn't be here tonight.
Cut it out, Susan.
We've gotta talk.
Busy day tomorrow,
everybody.
Joe, let's go.
Yes.
That stuff between
you and Susan threw me.
Threw you ?
Where ?
Shook me up.
I mean, how is it
that you happened
to meet my daughter ?
I didn't meet her.
The young man I took
met her.
That is, the fellow
she encountered in
the coffee shop this morning.
What happened to him ?
I needed a body, Bill.
So,
come in.
Uh, bathroom,
tub, towels, sauna,
chairs, lamps, bed.
Well, if there
is anything else,
don't hesitate.
I won't.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Water Running ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Dishes Clattering ]
I can try.
Will she be available
next week ?
I don't know.
Yes, sir ?
Hello.
I'm Joe Black.
It's nice meeting you.
Yes, of course,
Mr. Black, sir.
A pleasure.
Eh--
What is that ?
You mean this, sir ?
Yes.
It's, uh, Laura Scudder's
peanut butter, sir.
You like it ?
Well, I would say,
in my opinion,
it's right up there
with Jif and Skippy.
Could I offer you
a taste, sir ?
Yes.
All right.
[ Sniffing ]
[ Coughs ]
Do you fancy it, sir ?
[ Chuckles ]
More ?
Right.
Mmm.
[ Chuckling ]
You're a peanut butter man
now, eh, sir ?
Yes,
I believe I am.
I thoroughly enjoy
this peanut butter.
And I thoroughly enjoyed
meeting you all.
I'll be moseying on.
Right, sir.
[ Water Splashing ]
What are you doing here ?
I'm lost.
I can't seem
to escape you today.
I'm sorry.
[ Susan ]
Yeah.
Would you hand me
one of those ?
You must have something
very... big going on
with my father.
Big ?
Yeah.
You appear at his side
out of the blue,
stay at his house,
have dinner with his family.
That's, uh,
practically a first.
You're in the red-hot center
of big business,
and I thought you were
just a regular Joe.
I am Joe.
[ Chuckles ]
Not the one that I met
this morning.
Hitting on me in as nice
a way as I've been hit on
in a long time.
The second that you found out
I was my father's daughter,
you, uh--
[ Sniffing ]
Well, you acted
like a stranger.
That is not my intention.
What are your intentions ?
Huh ?
I mean, just to, uh,
make little dramas
in coffee shops,
turn a woman's head ?
I don't mind admitting
that my-my head was turned.
I-I liked it.
But, well, ten hours later,
I feel like a fool.
I just don't get it.
I don't.
You, my father,
here in this house.
It's, uh--
It's upsetting me,
and I--
What happened
to that sweet guy
from the coffee shop ?
Who are you, anyway ?
And...
what are you eating ?
Peanut butter.
Hmm.
But it's gone now.
Wh-- No. Please.
You act like you've never had
peanut butter before.
I haven't.
What kind of childhood
did you have ?
Do you love Drew ?
Excuse me ?
When you put your mouth
to his, it seemed
a frequent thing.
Drew is
none of your business,
and neither is where
I put my mouth.
I'm sorry.
Do you live here ?
No,Joe, I'm swimming here
and now I'm going home.
Yes, I think what
I'm trying to say is,
I would like it
if we were friends.
I've got
plenty of friends.
I don't have any.
Well, I can see why.
I didn't mean
to offend you at dinner.
I'm sometimes...
not quite at home
around people.
I get busy doing, uh,
what it is I do.
And I don't seem
to have developed--
Yes ?
I have a certain function
to perform, and it seems
to take up most of my time.
But sometimes I...
speculate...
that I haven't
left room for...
anything else.
Hmm.
I'm sorry to say
I know what you mean.
Well, um--
Good night,Joe.
Yes.
Good night to you,
Susan.
Morning, Madeline.
Oh, good morning,
Mr. Parrish.
Everything okay ?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Morning.
Good morning, Bill.
What's on the docket
for today ?
Docket ?
Hmm, yes.
What shall we do ?
Well, I have to
go to work, and--
Splendid. I'll join you.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Would you like
to ride or walk ?
Walk. I wish
to see the world.
This is crazy.
This is the left field
thing of all time.
I, uh--
I don't know if
I can get through this.
- What do I do ?
What do I tell my family ?
- You'll get through this, Bill.
As far as
your family's concerned, uh,
I wouldn't say anything.
You'll ruin the great start
we had last night.
Hmm. It felt as if
I was being treated
like a person.
Yes,Joe this,Joe that.
A nice smile.
Quince passed me the rolls.
No passion or rapture
or any of these mighty things
you're so intent on imparting.
But I am certain,
should you say who I am,
our adventure would
end abruptly.
Mm-hmm.
And I did so enjoy
your family.
What about my family ?
This adventure involves
only me, right ?
What do you mean ?
I'll tell you what.
You promise this undertaking
of yours...
involves only me
and, uh--
And what ?
I won't tell anyone
who you are.
Sounds fair enough.
Good.
Is it a deal ?
A deal ?
Yeah.
You give your word;
I give mine that we'll
do what we say.
Mm-hmm.
It is a truth exchanged
between two people.
Bill ?
What ?
You have a deal.
Ow !
That's great.
Great.
You know,
I got to thinking.
With you here
and seemingly occupied,
how's your work going,
I mean, elsewhere ?
While you were shaving
this morning, you weren't
just shaving.
What do you mean ?
You were hatching ideas,
making plans,
arriving at decisions,
right ?
Yeah, I guess so.
So you understand the concept.
While part of you is busy
doing one thing,
another part of you is doing
another, perhaps even attending
to the problems of your work.
Correct ?
Of course.
So you understand the idea.
Congratulations, Bill.
Now multiply that
by infinity, take that
to the depths of forever,
and you still will barely
have a glimpse of what
I'm talking about.
[ Horn Honking ]
Joe ?
Yes, Bill ?
How about giving
a guy a break ?
Make an exception ?
Well, there's one
to every rule.
Not this.
And call my family.
I'd like them to have
dinner with me tonight.
Didn't the family
get together last night ?
Jennifer.
Of course, Mr. Parrish,
right away.
Uh, perhaps you'd like
to wait in my office.
No.
What I'm trying to say
is this is a board meeting
and you're not a member.
I'm sure you'll find a way
to make it all right.
[ Sighs ]
Nice to meet you.
Morning.
[ All ]
Good morning.
Thank you.
Eddie.
Uh, this is Joe Black.
He's a personal associate
of mine, and, uh--
Hello, Quince.
Hey.
[ Bill ] He'll be
joining us this morning.
I know this is unusual,
and my apologies, and, uh--
Drew, carry on.
[ Drew ]
It's nice to see you.
Didn't expect you,
but, uh--
certainly you can't get
enough of a good thing.
Thank you.
Joe, would you like
to sit there ?
[ Chewing ]
Okay.
Uh, the Board
of Parrish Communications
is hereby called to order.
Our sole order of--
Our s--
Our sole order
of business today is a, uh--
is an acceptance of
John Bontecou's generous offer.
And I think Bill--
Do you have any more
of these delicious cookies ?
Thejelly ones ?
Mmm, and a cup of tea.
With milk, I think.
I'd like to try it
English style. Yes.
[Joe ]
A cup of tea
with milk, please.
Is there anything else,
Mr. Black ?
- How about some water ?
- Why, yes, thank you.
Hot or cold?
Cold.
- And a glass ?
- Mmm.
Uh, to review.
We're really crossing the T's
and dotting the I's here.
Uh, Bill had a great
and conclusive meeting
yesterday with John Bontecou,
and all that remains for us
is to put it to a vote.
Um, thank you.
Drew, um--
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah.
I did enjoy, or rather
I was interested...
in meeting
John Bontecou yesterday,
and, um--
Impressive, I suppose.
But, uh--
But--
It did get me to thinking.
See, I started
in this business because
this is what I wanted to do.
I knew I wasn't gonna write
the great American novel.
But I also knew there was
more to life than buying
something for a dollar...
and selling it for two.
I'd hoped
to create something,
something which could be...
held to
the highest standards.
And what I realized
was I--
I wanted to give
the news to the world.
And I wanted
to give it unvarnished.
Uh, the more we all know
about each other, the greater
the chance we will survive.
Sure, I want to make a profit.
You can't exist without one,
but, uh--
[ Chuckles ]
John Bontecou is all profit.
If we give him
license to absorb
Parrish Communications--
and he has his eye
on a few others after us--
in order to reach the world,
you will have to go
through John Bontecou.
And not only will you
have to pay him
to do this,
far more important,
you'll have to
agree with him.
Reporting the news
is a privilege
and a responsibility.
And it is not exploitable.
Parrish Communications
has earned this privilege.
John Bontecou
wants to buy it.
As your chairman,
I urge you to agree.
This company
is not for sale.
It sounds like
you're not leaving
much room for discussion.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I know. I'm sorry, I--
Looks like I'm
reversing my field.
That's your privilege, Bill.
But given our needs,
given the absolute necessity
for growth, given the future,
the truth is, joining
John Bontecou is every bit
as certain as death and taxes.
Death and taxes ?
Yes.
- Death and taxes ?
- Yes.
What an odd pairing.
It's just a saying,
Mr. Black.
Mmm. By whom ?
Doesn't matter.
- Then why'd
you bring it up ?
- [ Sighs ]
You're not familiar
with the phrase,
''In this world,
nothing is certain
but death and taxes ?''
Well, I am now.
Glad I could be
of some help.
I keep regular office hours
if there's any further
information you might need...
on sayings, common phrases,
manners of speaking.
My door's wide open.
The tea I can provide,
perhaps even the milk.
Low fat.
Yeah, okay, well, uh--
I think we've accomplished
everything we're going to this
morning. Shall we adjourn ?
- But the matter is still
on the table, Bill.
-Joe ?
Yes.
Thank you for
the delicious cookies.
[ Chewing ]
Mmm.
Who is that guy ?
So...
what's the deal here ?
You gonna be
breathing down my neck
right till the very end ?
I don't understand.
I'd like to be alone
for a while.
Are you sad, Bill ?
Yes, I am.
Why don't you take
a walk or something,
get some air ?
I know
I'll be seeing you.
[ Chewing ]
Of course.
Good. Now I'd like
to be alone.
This will hold you
for a while.
You know about money,
don't you ?
It can't buy happiness ?
Yeah.
Uh,Jennifer ?
Give Mr. Black a map
of the city, would you ?
It's okay, Bill.
I can manage.
Hi.
I need a medical
record number for labs.
Uh-huh.
And, uh, will you try
calling her husband ?
The number's on top.
Also, can you page me
when C.T.'s ready ?
Oh, sure.
Thanks, sweetie.
How nice you look.
Is that your uniform ?
What are you doing here ?
Are you ill ?
Oh, goodness, no.
Then why
are you here,Joe ?
I'm here to see you.
Joe, I don't--
I don't have time
to see you right now.
I'm, um, about to start
making rounds,
and I'm examining
back-to-back patients
until dinner, and, uh--
Very well. I'll watch.
Watch me do what ?
Make rounds and examine
back-to-back patients.
[ Chuckles ]
Joe, that's impossible.
I'm a doctor.
And I'll be
a visitor.
Patients have visitors,
not doctors.
I don't mind.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Woman ]
Miss ? Miss ?
Doctor.
Oh, um, just one second.
I'll be right there.
Please.
My mama is sicker
than him.
Okay.
- [ Jamaican Accent ]
Obeah.
- No, Mama.
Obeah, man.
- I goin' die.
- Mama, stop it.
It's just a man.
[ Susan ] What's Obeah ?
[ Daughter ] Bad spirit.
Shejust all fever.
She don't mean nothing.
Please help us.
Of course.
[Joe With Jamaican Accent ]
No Obeah, sister.
Everything gonna be
all right.
Have you registered ?
No.
Okay.
You gonna be all right ?
Go with the doctor lady.
Mama gonna be fine now.
Don't leave.
Don't leave me.
She'll be
right back, okay ?
Mama.
[ Inhales, Groans ]
- Obeah.
- Rahtid.
Obeah evil.
I not evil, woman.
And what you is then ?
I from that next place.
You waitin' here
to take us ?
Like you is
the bus driver to there ?
No, man,
I on 'oliday.
Some spot you pick.
Oh. Mmm.
The pain.
Pain is bad, bad.
I don't have nothin'
to do with these things,
you know.
Make it go away.
Doctor lady
make it all right.
Uh-uh.
Not this pain.
This pain go
through and through me.
Make it go away.
I can't, sister.
You can, mister.
Take me to
that next place.
It's not your time now.
Make it time.
You can't fool with
the way things
got to be.
[ Whimpering ]
Please ?
[ Quietly ]
Where she was born.
Close your eyes.
Go on, sister.
Soon.
You-- You can go with her.
I'll be right there.
Come now, Mama.
She's in a great deal
of pain.
Yes.
Have you spent much time
in the islands ?
Some.
I realize now
my being here,
uh, is not
quite appropriate.
Oh, no, please--
Please don't apologize.
Yes ?
Yeah.
I'm glad that you came.
Thank you, Susan.
I'm very happy
to be here.
Joe, I'm with Drew.
Not now.
[ Chuckles ]
I have to go.
I'm sorry to say.
Be sorry for nothing.
[ Chuckles ]
Right.
Thanks,Joe.
Good-bye, Susan.
- Good ?
- Mmm.
- Yes, what is it ?
- Cold lamb sandwich
with cilantro.
A little Coleman's mustard.
It's, uh, splendid.
Glad you like it.
My wife turned me on
to cold lamb sandwiches.
-Joan... was my wife.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Cold lamb sandwiches.
Not as chewy as roast beef,
not as boring as chicken.
She knew stuff like that.
Everything reminds me
of her.
There isn't a day goes by
that I don't think about her.
One day she didn't feel well.
The next day she was gone.
So what
are you gonna do ?
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah.
I guess you've heard all this
a trillion times before, huh ?
- More.
- Why didn't you stop me ?
I don't know.
What was it like
when you first met ?
I thought you'd heard it
a trillion times before.
This part
I'm interested in.
Well, she had on
this little blue suit...
[ Breathes Heavily ]
with a little white collar
that had a little...
red piping on it.
[ Knocking ]
Yeah ?
Hi.
- Am I interrupting ?
- Yes.
- No.
-Just kidding ?
[ Bill ]
Sit down, Drew.
Uh, before I do,
I was hoping we might
be alone, Bill.
Well,Joe and I have
no secrets from each other.
[ Drew ]
How nice for you both.
Pardon my candor, but I was
confounded by your decision
this morning.
Why ?
I was hired.
You told me to help bring
Parrish Communications
into the 2 1 st century.
This merger is the vehicle.
In my estimation--
Perhaps a merger is a way...
to bring Bill's company
into the 2 1 st century,
and perhaps it isn't.
And perhaps cheating
on your French philosophers
exam at the Groton School...
was an expedient way
to get your diploma,
and perhaps it wasn't.
Be that as it may, Drew,
a question can often
be argued both ways.
Joe, cut it out.
You too, Drew.
- I thought this was
practically a done deal.
- Well, now it's undone, okay ?
Forget Bontecou.
Scrub him.
I'm tired of his fancy name
and his fancy offer.
I'm not going for it.
Okay.
Bill,
why at this juncture...
are you letting yourself
be so concerned
by business matters ?
'Cause I don't want anybody
buying up my life's work !
Turning it into something
it wasn't meant to be.
A man wants to leave
something behind. He wants it
left behind the way he made it.
He wants it to be run
the way he ran it,
with a sense of honor,
of dedication, of truth.
Easy, Bill.
You'll give yourself
a heart attack...
and ruin my vacation.
Now listen.
I read you all the way
on the Bontecou thing,
and I know where
you're coming from,
and I am with you 1 01 percent.
Well, thank you,
Quince.
But I just gotta
tell you,
if mergers are
in the wind,
I've developed
some great prospects.
And I want to come
and talk to you about--
about 'em next week.
Next week ?
Yeah.
Or the week after.
No good ?
No. Why,
anything's possible.
It's up to Joe.
[ Exhales ]
Joe.
You just don't know
how glad I am
you're aboard,
because anybody who can
take some of the weight
off the old man,
I am--
I'm in his corner.
That's very gracious
of you, Quince.
Ah, it's no problem.
Well, I'll leave
you two alone,
because I can, uh--
I can tell, you know--
you got something
in the fire.
Now, look,
I know you're down.
But you know,
when you're down,
there's no place to go but up.
Up.
Thanks, Quince.
Forget about Bontecou.
I got a couple other
merger possibilities
up my sleeve,
and I'm pitching 'em
to the old man.
Were you ?
Yeah.
Hey, listen.
Mm-hmm.
We're gonna
go in together.
I'll clue you in.
[ Stammering ]
The timing has gotta
be right,
because the old man
says it's up to Joe.
He said
it's up to Joe ?
Mm-hmm.
Those were his words ?
Yeah.
It's up to Joe, huh ?
That's what he said ?
That's what he--
That's what he said.
That's very interesting.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I thought so too.
[ Glass Ringing ]
[ Chuckles ]
I want to thank you all
for coming.
Uh, my family, um,
Allison and Quince,
Susan and
the other members.
And, uh--
So glad when we
can get together.
I mean, I know
you all have busy lives.
- Look who's talking.
- Yeah. Speak for yourself.
Yeah.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
I remember when
you were little girls,
and, uh--
I love little girls.
And uh, now you're
all grown up,
and I, um--
I had some words prepared,
but, uh,
I've forgotten them.
Um--
Wait a minute, uh--
There's so much
I wanted to say, uh--
[ Allison ] Daddy ?
- You could sit down
if you want to.
- Yeah.
So many words I wanted to--
So much I wanted to say,
but, uh--
I can't, and so, uh--
Yeah, I better sit down.
Carry on, everybody, please.
Oh, one other thing.
Um, why don't we all...
have dinner again
tomorrow night, okay ?
Dinner again ?
Yeah.
You haven't had
enough of us yet, Dad ?
Mmm--
mmm--
no.
Come here.
- We'll be here.
- You bet we'll be here.
Bright-eyed
and bushy-tailed.
Joe.
Oh, no.
I would prefer
some peanut butter.
How would you like that,
sir ? On some kind
of toast ?
Toast.
No, just the butter.
Right away, sir.
Why do you like
peanut butter so much ?
I don't know.
Hmm. I adore
things like that.
Food I can't do without.
Don't you ?
Yes.
It comforts you,
doesn't it ?
Yes, I find
that it does.
Mind if I throw up ?
[ Bill ]
Drew.
Please.
[ Sighs ]
I'm very concerned
about the woman
you attended to today.
- I am too.
- Has her pain abated?
We're doing what we can
for her, but, uh,
it's not looking very good.
I'm sorry to hear that.
[ Whispers ]
Yeah.
Who are we talking about ?
But I know she's grateful
for the care you're giving her.
Is this a state secret ?
No, we're talking about
a patient of mine, 'cause...
[ Drew ] Uh-huh.
Joe stopped by
the hospital today.
He did?
That's more than
we get to do.
Maybe next time you go
to the hospital, you'll
take us along with you.
- Perhaps you could remind me.
- Well, I'll make a note of it.
- Anything else
I can do for you ?
- I wanna come along too.
See Susie strut her stuff.
You're on, Quincie.
Destination, hospital.
Joe, you can be
the tour guide, okay ?
Susan's a wonderful doctor.
I'm sure she is.
Bill ?
Yeah ?
I have to go.
It's been a hell
of a day.
I need a few minutes
to sort everything out.
See you tomorrow.
Joe ?
Yes, Bill ?
Um--
::music:: [ Piano Note ]
Why'd you go
to the hospital ?
I don't know.
You just curious ?
::music:: [ Piano Note ]
I guess.
About Susan ?
::music:: [ Piano Note ]
I wouldn't put it
that way.
How would you put it ?
You tell me, Bill.
No, how about
you telling me ?
I ask a simple question;
I expect a straight answer.
That's what I'm used to.
Anybody who doesn't
give it to me, I fire.
Are you going
to fire me, Bill ?
Drew ?
So, uh, I'll see you
tomorrow night ?
You include me out.
I've had enough
of the convocations.
You don't mean that.
You don't want
to disappoint Dad.
Daddy will do fine.
Besides, he's got Joe.
And it seems you do too.
You're out of line.
Well, that may be, but I don't
like the ubiquitous creep.
I don't like the way
he looks at you. I don't like
the way he talks to you.
And vice versa.
I'm sorry.
'Cause I like the way
he looks and talks to me.
And vice versa.
Okay ?
Not okay.
Thought we had
a good thing going here.
I thought
it was a good thing.
Well, that just goes to show
you never know.
Night.
[ Whispering ]
Good night.
[ Door Closing ]
How long have you
been standing there ?
I don't like the way
he spoke to you.
But I feel better now
because of the way
you spoke back.
Tell me
about yourself,Joe.
I mean, who are you ?
What are you doing here
with my father ?
You're not
going to tell me ?
You're married,
aren't you ?
Why ?
Because men
who never say anything
about themselves, they're--
they're always married.
So you're married ?
No, I'm not.
But you--
you have a girlfriend.
No.
[ Chuckles ]
Gay ?
No.
So, tell me,Joe--
How come a man
as attractive,
intelligent,
well-spoken...
diffident in the most
seductive way, and yet...
powerful...
is all alone
in this world ?
I'm sorry.
I'm s--
I didn't...
mean to pry, and, uh,
you obviously don't
want to tell me,
so we'll just--
We'll just
leave it a mystery.
That is the way you want it,
isn't it ?
Yes, thank you.
Where are you going ?
To bed.
- To bed ?
- Yes.
I'm tired.
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night.
Sleep well.
Okay.
See you tomorrow.
Good night. See you.
Good night, Susie.
Get some sleep.
Good night.
Yeah.
See you tomorrow.
Good night.
That was wonderful.
Mmm.
It's good
to get together.
Mm-hmm.
Do you mind if I raise
a little caution flag ?
Raise away.
What is the nature
of your interest in Joe ?
Well--
Remember how you told me
about lightning striking ?
Mm-hmm.
[ Chuckles ]
The nature of it's
in there somewhere.
Yeah.
Well, I won't say you're
on the wrong track, but, uh--
Then what
will you say ?
I don't think
this is the lightning
you're looking for.
I mean, Drew is a good man.
I know I didn't seem to be
completely in his corner before,
but, uh, I've come
to appreciate that, um--
Now we love Drew ?
And Joe doesn't measure up ?
What's going on ?
Nothing.
When you say
''nothing'' that way,
it is not nothing.
Then what is it ?
It's something.
[ Breathes Deeply,
Chuckles ]
Okay.
Good night.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Good night.
[ Sighs ]
I know you're all
as uncomfortable as I am
to be meeting like this.
But I got a call last night
from John Bontecou.
Not only is he still interested,
he's sweetening his offer.
Although it pains me
to say it, in my opinion,
Bill Parrish dealt with us
preemptively...
in dismissing any deal
with Bontecou.
Therefore, I'm sorry to say
that if we're to examine
this new offer responsibly,
as the Board of Directors
of Parrish Communications,
we must do so
without its chairman.
There's one
additional element.
Bontecou is so anxious
to get us,
he said he'd take
Parrish Communications
with Bill Parrish or without.
[ Board Member Coughs ]
In this crisis,
and be assured...
this is a crisis,
it's not pleasant
to say the following.
But I would be remiss
if I did not.
When we present Bill
with the improved
Bontecou offer,
and if he still refuses
to let us consider it,
once more makes an adamant
or emotional rejection,
we will have no choice but to--
You're taking this
too far, Drew.
Am I not obligated to ?
[ Whispering ]
See if Quince is here.
[ Sighs ]
How did all this
come about ?
Crisis, Bill Parrish.
Crisis, his company.
Crisis for us.
It came about
with the arrival on the scene
of Mr.Joe Black.
Mr.Joe who ?
Joe Black.
He attends
our board meetings.
He sleeps at Bill's house.
He resides in his office.
He never leaves his side,
and, in my opinion,
is always in his ear,
telling Bill what to do.
And Bill is listening.
Who is Joe Black ?
What-- What is
his relationship
to Bill Parrish,
and most important,
what is behind his influence
on our chairman ?
He's had advisors before.
Nobody tells Bill
what to do.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
Thanks for coming,
Quince.
Sure. Hi, Ed.
Hi, folks.
I didn't know everybody
was going to be here.
Nice surprise.
What's with
the new digs ?
Drew's idea of cloak and dagger.
This is a secret meeting,
Quince.
I hope you'll
respect its nature.
Have a seat, Quince.
[ Chuckles ]
Now, what we're trying
to do here is to, uh--
to gather our thoughts
in light of Bill's rejection
of Bontecou's offer...
and to make an appropriate
presentation to him...
as to how we think
the company might proceed.
Won't you share with our board
the information you gave me
last night ?
Well, uh, I'm hap--
I'm happy to tell you
I got good news.
As I was, uh,
as I was telling Drew,
uh, I've been
making a little hay while
the Bontecou sun was shining.
Two, possibly three,
new and boiling hot prospects
for merger.
Mm-hmm. And how did
Bill react to the leads
you've developed ?
He was interested.
Yeah, but he was concerned
about the timing ?
Timing ?
Yeah, he was concerned
about the timing ?
Yes.
He says it's up to Joe.
It's up to Joe.
::music:: Dum-da-dum ::music::
What's this ?
- Um, Annie made them.
- Who's Annie ?
Thank you, Lillian.
From La Rosette ?
She's only the most famous
pastry chef in America.
Um, this is orange,
made with real Seville oranges.
Oh.
And, uh, that's lemon
on a mille-feuille crust.
I don't like cake.
It's for the party, Dad.
Ah.
The goddamn party.
Mm-hmm.
[ Allison ]
Did you hear that ?
I'm sorry.
The goddamn party.
Oh.
[ Bill ]
Come on, l--
Here, let's try this one...
right over here.
Mmm.
[ Whimpers ]
This, this is terrific.
It has, um,
has vodka in it, Bill.
A little vodka, right ?
[ Crying, Gasping ]
Has, um, that fruity vodka,
that flavored stuff, right ?
Bill, put
your lips around this.
It's just out of this world.
I'm sorry, honey.
You know, I'm no good
at this.
Why don't you choose
whichever cake you'd like ?
Hmm ?
I knew you were
gonna say that.
What ?
I mean
you just don't care.
Oh, why am I doing this ?
I should have my head
examined again.
Oh, my God.
I am trying to throw
the party of the century...
[ Sobs ]
for my father in two days.
And you just don't
give a shit.
He gives a shit.
He doesn't
give a shit!
He does.
[ Bill ] Allison.
He does give a shit.
Don't you, Bill ?
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Smile.
I'm sorry.
But what should we
tell Annie ?
::music:: Bum-bum-bum ::music::
[ Chuckles ]
This one.
Mmm.
- He gives a shit !
- [ All Laughing ]
Fantastic.
Thank you.
[ Allison ]
Um, Mr. Black, would you
care for a piece ?
Yes, I'd love one.
Have you had a chance
to, uh,
look at my father's
rare books ?
He has Jefferson's
parliamentary manual,
and, uh,
this first edition
of Bleak House.
I love your smell.
Well, I like
the way you smell too.
My mom always used to say
that you could set your heart
by that clock.
Could you ?
I never tried.
Till now.
Joe ?
Hmm ?
May I kiss you ?
Why, yes, you can.
Mmm.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Joe ?
Mmm.
I don't know
who you are.
I'm Joe.
Mm-hmm.
And, uh,
you're Susan.
Mmm.
And...
I have this...
weak feeling
in my knees.
And is your heart
beating strangely ?
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Faster.
The taste of your lips
and the touch
of your tongue--
that was wonderful.
Mmm.
I should, um...
I should go home.
Mmm.
Shouldn't I ?
Yeah.
Good night, Dad.
Good night.
Hello, Bill.
Hello.
Would you like to join me
and Allison and Quince
for a nightcap ?
No. Not right now.
Okay.
Then I'll say
good night.
Good night, Bill.
[ Footsteps Departing ]
Morning, Quince.
Top of the morning, B.P.
Hello, Quince.
Hey !
Hello,Jennifer.
Good morning,
Mr. Parrish.
The board
is waiting.
What ?
The board ?
Didn't you call
a board meeting ?
No.
- Good morning.
- Morning, Bill.
Did you want to have
a cup of coffee
or something, Bill ?
I don't think so.
Do you ?
To get to the point,
we've received new information
from John Bontecou...
concerning his desires
for this company
to merge with his.
And we wanted
to set the details
before you.
Is that it ?
Bontecou wants
a quick response, and--
The answer is no.
Quick enough
for you ?
- Don't you want to hear
the details ?
- I'm not interested.
I'm not interested in
the big picture either.
What I am interested in...
is how my board got convened
behind my back...
and is entertaining a further
proposal from a man with whom
it offends me to do business.
I made a decision.
Case closed.
So am I to understand
from your response...
that you do not want to
hear the details
of Bontecou's offer ?
Yes, you are
to understand that.
And now, may I ask
you a question ?
- Certainly, Bill.
- Are you running this board,
or am I ?
That's it ?
We've got a busy day ahead.
This meeting's already
set me behind.
Shall we adjourn ?
Uh, before we do, Bill,
while we're here--
There's a second question
the board would like
a response to.
Far simpler one.
Who is the man
standing to your left ?
I've already introduced
Mr. Black to you all.
But who is he ?
What are his credentials ?
What is his relationship
to you ?
The board
is deeply concerned.
We have reason to believe
Mr. Black is not only
influencing your decisions...
in regard to this company,
but that you are relying
on him to make them for you.
The lack of response, Bill,
is not appropriate.
We are your board.
We have a right
to know how you are managing
the operations of this company.
And, most importantly,
that you have not delegated
someone to do it for you.
Okay ?
One more time.
Who is Joe Black ?
A motion has been brought
before the board...
to invoke Article 1 9
of the corporate charter.
In English, please.
[ Sighs ]
Mandatory retirement
on our chairman's 65th birthday,
at which time the chairman
will be named emeritus.
You're welcome to attend
all meetings...
and will serve as
international spokesman
for the corporation.
Plus, of course,
a settlement,
a golden parachute
of such magnitude that his feet
will never touch the ground.
Please indicate your vote
by a yes or no.
- Yes.
[ Several Members At Once ]
Yes.
[ Affirmations Continue ]
- No.
Motion's passed.
We will, of course, delay
the announcement out of respect
for our former chairman...
until after the celebration
of his birthday this weekend.
Well, thanks for allowing me
to save face, Drew.
The other motion before us
is the acceptance
ofJohn Bontecou's offer...
to merge this corporation
with Bontecou International.
Okay.
Joe ?
Who I am...
and what my relationship is
to William Parrish...
will be divulged
in our own good time.
Okay.
Thank you, Mr. Black.
It's not over
till it's over.
Please, Eddie,
no ''fat lady sings'' stuff.
I still sense some doubt
in this group.
We could turn it around.
You'll be up
in the country ?
Yeah.
The big celebration
of my mandatory
retirement birthday.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
You're an honored guest,
Eddie.
I'm gonna
stick it out here.
We still have a shot.
Get John's office on the phone.
Tell them I'll be there
in 20 minutes.
What did you do ?
You've gotten
the old man fired.
That we did.
Thanks to you.
He was wobbling, mind you,
but you supplied
the coup de grace.
I'm gonna put
a stop to this.
Quince,
you can't unscramble
scrambled eggs.
I-I didn't mean
to do this.
Train's left the station, pal,
and you're aboard.
Now, would you like to hear
the silver lining ?
Check that. Gold.
Once John Bontecou acquires
Parrish Communications,
he's gonna break it apart,
peddle it piece by piece
to the highest bidder.
That was the game plan
right from the start.
I set it up for him,
and he smacks it
out of the park.
Ramifications
for you ?
You'll be farting
through silk.
You'll sell your stock.
You'll be positively,
truly rich.
You can stop
kissing ass.
What'll it feel like
to be a man ?
I'm going
to expose you.
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
Go right ahead.
You tell William Parrish
how you betrayed him
in a secret board meeting.
Tell Allison how you helped
her father lose his company.
It's just life,
Quincie.
Wake up
and smell the thorns.
[ Water Splashing ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
You're here.
I am.
I, uh--
just dropped by.
I thought
I'd scrounge some lunch.
I was in the neighborhood.
I'm so glad.
When I called,
they said that you and Dad
had already left the office.
Mm-hmm.
He's taking a nap.
Oh. Yeah.
Well, uh,
he must be tired.
You know,
this whole Bontecou thing--
It, um, seems--
Yes, he's tired.
I believe so.
Yeah.
You must
be hungry then.
[ Sighs ]
No.
Not anymore.
Are you ?
[ Inaudible ]
[ Chuckles ]
[ Susan ]
I loved making love
to you.
It was like
making love with someone--
making love
for the first time.
Thank you.
Do you like
making love with me ?
Yes.
More than
you love peanut butter ?
Yes.
Much more.
[ Sighs ]
Where are you going ?
Nowhere. I'm here.
For how long ?
I hope
a long, long time.
Me too.
What do
we do now ?
Um...
it'll come to us.
Hello, Bill.
Did you have a nice nap ?
- I couldn't sleep.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
I'll come down.
What's going on ?
Hmm ?
I saw you kiss Susan.
Yes, I saw you see me.
You're at the wrong place
at the wrong time
with the wrong woman.
I'll be the judge
of that.
I'm her father.
With all due respect,
Bill, I'm not asking
your permission.
You goddamn well should !
You walk into my life.
You give me the worst news
a guy can get.
You have me dancing
on heads of pins with
my business, my family.
Now you're spooning
with my daughter ?
''Spooning'' ?
Yes! And stop repeating
everything I say
and turning it into a question.
Spooning, fooling around
and God knows what.
Oh, you arrive
on the scene--
Why you picked me
I still don't understand.
I chose you for your verve,
your excellence...
and your ability to...
instruct.
You've lived a first-rate life,
and I find it eminently usable.
What do you want ?
Huh ?
Everybody wants
something,Joe.
You've been taking me
from pillar to post here.
And, uh,
I thought I knew
who you were, and it
wasn't a lot of fun.
But it was
almost bearable.
But now I'm getting
something else from you,
something very--
very strange.
What is it
that you want ?
I'm only living
the Parrish bywords--
looking for that
''ounce of excitement,''
that ''whisper of a thrill
there is no sense
living your life without.''
You know
what I mean, Bill ?
[ Chuckles ]
You're violating
the laws of the universe.
- This universe ?
- Any universe that exists
or ever existed.
You may be the pro,Joe,
but I know who you are,
and you're
all fucked up.
I don't like your tone,
and I don't like
your references.
And I don't give a shit.
Perhaps it's time to remind you
this is not simply a dispute
with a putative suitor.
This is me.
So be careful, Bill.
Cut all that
''Bill'' crap out,
you son of a bitch.
I'll say it again.
Be careful, Bill.
Can I help you ?
Excuse me,
can I help you ?
[ Clears Throat ]
Yes. Dr. Parrish,
please.
She comes on at 6.:00.
Oh.
Hi.
Where's Joe ?
Joe ?
Joe's not around.
Do you know
where he is ?
I don't know.
Oh.
Why are you
looking for Joe ?
Love. Passion.
Obsession.
All those things
you told me to wait for.
They've arrived.
This is crazy.
Why ?
A man shows up,
almost never leaves
your side.
Well, you clearly trust him,
depend on him.
So why aren't those things
good enough for me ?
You don't know anything
about Joe.
What are you afraid of?
That I'll fall
head over heels for Joe ?
Well, I have.
Just like you did
with Mom.
Isn't that
what you've always wanted
for me ?
Susan...
I don't think Joe is
gonna be with us long.
Where is he going ?
I don't know.
I can't say.
Oh, come on.
The guy's working with you.
You know chapter and verse
about everyone working with you.
In this case I can't. I--
I only will tell you
that with Joe, you're on...
very, very dangerous ground.
I love him.
I don't care
if you love him !
I'm telling you !
Joe's no good for you.
Of course not, Daddy.
I'm sorry.
I love you too.
[ Jamaican Accent ]
Mr. Bad News.
'Bout time you show up.
[ Jamaican Accent ]
Don't be feisty, sister.
I'm not feisty,
mister.
You come for me ?
That's good news.
No, I come
to see the doctor.
Doctor ?
Mm-hmm.
What could be wrong
with you ?
Nothin'.
Ohh. You come
to see doctor lady ?
Yeah, man.
My doctor lady ?
Mine too, you know.
[ Chuckles ]
You're in love ?
You're loved back ?
She know your real self?
- She know how she feel.
- Backside !
What the hell kind
of business this is.
Don't need you okayin'.
Schoolboy things
in your head.
Badness for you.
Badness for her.
Badness for me,
lyin' here,
tumor big as a breadfruit,
poisonin' me inside,
and waitin'.
Bring you flowers,
and all I's gettin'
is aggravation.
The only flowers
I want to see...
is the ones
over my peaceful self
resting in the dirt.
Can't do no right by people.
Come to take you,
you want to stay.
Leave you stay,
you want to go.
Rahtid.
You're not in
your right place, mister.
Me neither.
No more.
Take me, and you come
with me now.
But I not lonely here.
Somebody want me here.
[ Chuckling ]
Hmm.
It nice
it happen to you.
Like you come to the island
and had a holiday.
Sun didn't burn you red-red,
just brown.
You sleep,
and no mosquito eat you.
But the truth is,
it bound to happen...
if you stay long enough.
So take that nice picture
you got in your head
home with you,
but don't be fooled.
We lonely here mostly too.
If we lucky, maybe...
we got some nice pictures
to take with us.
You got
enough nice pictures ?
Yes.
[ Sighs ]
Good-bye, sister.
Yes ?
I have the feeling,
all in all,
what I made this voyage for
has served its purpose.
What are you saying ?
It's time to go ?
I'm ready.
You are ?
Yeah.
Good. Tomorrow.
After the party.
Yes, Helen ?
Telephone call, sir.
Mr. Sloane
from New York.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Hey !
Hey.
Red or white ?
No. No, thank you.
Have a drink.
You look like
you need one as bad as me.
I do ?
Quince ?
Mm-hmm.
I find myself
a little confused.
Confused, huh ?
Yes.
About what ?
Love.
Oh, man.
I got problems of my own.
You love Allison,
don't you ?
Yes, I do.
How did you meet ?
Well, um,
I was this world-class loser,
and she was this
happy little rich girl,
and for some reason
she took me in.
But Allison loves you.
[ Stifled Sob ]
How do you know ?
[ Panting ]
Because she knows
the worst thing about me,
and it's okay.
What is it ?
No, it's not one thing.
It's just an idea,Joe.
It's just, um, um--
It's like you know
each other's secrets,
your deepest,
darkest secrets.
Deepest, darkest secrets ?
Yeah, and then you--
you're free.
Free ?
You're free !
You're free to l--
love each other
completely, totally.
Just no fear.
So there's nothing
you don't know about each other,
and it's okay.
Hmm.
Do you like me,Joe ?
Oh, yes, Quince.
You're one of my favorites.
What would you say
if you knew it was me who
brought down Bill Parrish ?
Oh, I told Drew and the board
that Bill depended on you.
Drew and Bontecou
are gonna chop up the company,
sell it off for parts.
Bontecou was outside.
Drew was Mr. Inside.
And I was the fool
who made it all happen.
Ohh...
God.
[ Chuckling ]
What do I do ?
Go to Bill Parrish
and tell him the truth.
He'll forgive you.
You think so ?
Yes.
You think I should wait
till after the party ?
No.
Four down here
and a sturgeon up there.
This one is perfect.
Absolutely.
Okay, I think
I want four here
like that--
Hi, Daddy.
Hi.
What do you think ?
[ Chuckles ]
Well, it's, uh--
it's starting to grow on me.
Oh, I've got a baritone
with a balalaika...
coming from
the Russian Tea Room.
I've dressed him in
a Cossack shirt, and he'll
be singing Nelson Eddy songs.
Wow.
You really are amazing.
But why, oh, why, Allison,
are you doing all this ?
I do it
because I love you.
Everybody loves you:
Mommy, wherever she is,
Susan, Quince...
all the people you work with,
anyone who's ever met you.
Ohh, Daddy.
After all, you've been
a wonderful father.
Yeah, well,
I haven't been the father
to you that, uh--
That you've been
to Susan ?
I wasn't going to say that.
But that's what
you were thinking.
And that's okay.
Because I know
that you love me.
I mean, it's not
like it is with her.
Whenever she walks
into the room,
your eyes light up.
She always gets a smile
from you, as opposed to me.
When I walk in,
this look comes over
your face, like,
''What does she want now ?''
But you've never let
either of us want
for anything.
Oh, God.
More than that, Daddy,
more than that.
I've felt loved,
and that's all that matters.
So, never mind favorites.
You're allowed to have one.
The point is,
you've been mine.
Oh, Allison.
Oh.
I really feel...
I've everything
I could've ever wanted
for my birthday.
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, wait a minute !
There's more to come.
Lots of excess,
like you love.
You know,
this is gonna be
a wonderful party.
Yes, it is.
Thank you.
Happy birthday !
Thanks.
[ Chuckles ]
::music:: [ Big Band ]
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Good evening.
Thank you.
Hello.
Welcome.
Hi, Susan.
Hi, Simone.
How are you ?
Hi, darling.
Oh, hi, Gene. Hi.
::music:: [ Continues ]
My father told me
you might be leaving.
Your father and I--
Our time together
has come to an end.
I'm in love...
with a man,
but I don't know
who he is,
where he's going
or when.
I can tell you
the when part.
Tonight.
So it does get worse.
No worse
than it gets for me.
I'm in love
with a woman who...
I don't wanna leave.
Ohh.
Then don't.
There's so little
we know about each other.
There's so much
I should tell you.
That'll come.
Will it ?
Mm-hmm.
I wanna be
with you,Joe.
I opened my big mouth
one too many times.
Everything just got
all, uh, twisted.
It's okay, Quince.
I understand.
You've always meant well,
and I appreciate that.
Sometimes things
just turn out wrong.
[ Knocking ]
Yeah ?
[ Door Opens ]
Excuse me.
No, no--
Uh,Joe, come in.
Um, I wanna thank you.
Is it okay, Bill ?
- Sure.
-Joe knows the whole story.
I told him.
And it was his idea
that I come clean.
I mean--
I wanted to come clean,
but, uh,
he gave me a pair
of balls, you know
what I mean ?
Yeah,
I believe I do.
Anyway, uh,
I can see you guys
got business.
No. However, I do have
some unfinished business
with Drew.
Get him on the helicopter.
Get him out here tonight.
I wanna tell this guy
how I feel about him
face-to-face.
That could be a tall order, B.P.
I doubt if Drew is anxious
to see you face-to-face.
- I'll deliver the package.
- Okay.
- How are you doing ?
- What the hell do you care ?
Just asking, Bill.
You wanna know ?
I'll tell you.
You're looking at a man who is
not walking through the valley
of the shadow of death.
He's galloping into it.
At the same time,
the business he built...
with his own hands and head
has been commandeered by
a couple of cheap pirates.
Oh, yes ! I almost forgot.
My daughter's fallen in love
with Death.
And I'm in love
with your daughter.
Say again ?
I'm in love with your daughter,
and I'm taking her
with me tonight.
- You what ?
- I think you heard me, Bill.
You're not taking Susan
anywhere. What does that mean,
anyway ? We had a deal.
And I'm sorry.
Susan's my daughter.
She has a wonderful life
ahead of her.
You're gonna deprive her
of it, and you're telling me
you're sorry ?
I'm sorry.
Apology not accepted.
I don't care, Bill.
I love her.
How perfect for you...
to take whatever you want
because it pleases you.
That's not love.
Then what is it ?
Some aimless infatuation
which, for the moment,
you feel like indulging.
It's missing everything
that matters.
Which is what ?
Trust, responsibility,
taking the weight for
your choices and feelings...
and spending
the rest of your life
living up to them,
and above all,
not hurting the object
of your love.
So that's love according
to William Parrish ?
Multiply it by infinity
and take it to the depth
of forever,
and you will still have
barely a glimpse
of what I'm talking about.
Those were my words.
They're mine now.
Bill, Susan wants
to come with me.
She loves me.
She loves you ?
Mm-hmm.
Who is you ?
Did you tell her
who you are ?
No.
Does she know
where she's going ? Huh ?
You see, Susan went for
that poor son of a bitch...
whose body you took,
and everything since
has been aftermath.
You don't know
what love is.
She doesn't know
who you are.
You make a deal;
you're breaking it.
Bottom line is,Joe,
you're swindling her soul,
and you're doing it
with your eyes wide open.
I don't like what
you're saying.
I'm past
caring what you like and don't.
You're stealing my daughter,
and I'm not gonna let you.
You're not ?
No.
Are you threatening me ?
Yeah,
I certainly hope so.
Yeah.
I loved Susan from the moment
she was born, and I love her now
and every minute in between.
And what I dream of is a man
who will discover her, and that
she will discover a man...
who will love her,
who is worthy of her, who is
of this world, this time...
and has the grace,
compassion and fortitude
to walk beside her...
as she makes her way
through life.
Enough !
What I know is what I want,
and what I want is Susan.
And I will have her,
and she will have me.
And that's the way it's
going to be. And there's
nothing you can do.
Why did you
tell me all this,Joe ?
You're the big shot,
the biggest shot of all.
You don't have to ask
permission, but that's what
you're doing. Do you know why ?
Because you've somehow
developed into a good guy,
and you know this is all wrong.
I don't know
what you're gonna do,
but, uh,
how can this be love ?
She doesn't know
who you are.
Why don't you tell her,
try it out, see what happens ?
Reveal everything there is
to know about yourself and let
the chips fall where they may.
Okay ?
I've given it my best shot.
I, uh--
I wish I could tell you
to sleep on it.
::music:: [ Orchestra ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
Oh, um--
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry.
Would you excuse me ?
Sure.
Okay, nice to see you.
Nice to see you.
There's something
so indescribably sexy...
about you standing
in the middle of a crowd.
I could make love to you
right here.
You're trying to tell me
my future, you're looking
on the wrong side.
There is something
I do want to tell you.
But you can't ?
Just now when you hesitated,
I got a chill.
Remember that morning
in the coffee shop ?
When you said, ''What's wrong
with taking care of a woman ?
She takes care of you.''
Did I say that ?
Mm-hmm.
And I said you'd have
a hard time finding
a woman like that these days.
::music:: [ Ends ]
[ Applause ]
Well, you found one,Joe.
The coffee shop.
That was the place,
and you were the guy.
And you said that, uh,
that you didn't want me
to be your doctor because...
you didn't want me
to examine you.
Why, I got to examine you,
after all.
I could come with you.
You want me to wait ?
You'll come back ?
May I kiss you ?
That felt like good-bye.
What's going on,Joe ?
I feel like
we're lifting off.
I'm still here.
But you're not.
You're somewhere else.
You're someone else.
Don't you want to ask who ?
Yes, but--
''But'' ?
Joe, I'm afraid.
Afraid to find out ?
Don't be.
It doesn't matter what I am.
You know who I am.
You're--
You're Joe.
Yes, I'm Joe.
Oh.
And I promise you...
you will always
have what you found
in the coffee shop.
Tell me that you love me.
Tell me that you love me now.
I love you now.
I'll love you always.
Susan.
Yes ?
Thank you for loving me.
::music:: [ Orchestra ]
[ Chattering ]
We should think about
getting started, Bill.
Mm-hmm.
It'll just be us.
Thank you.
[ Knocking ]
Bill ?
Come in.
I got him. The helicopter
will be here in two minutes.
How are we on time ?
Okay.
Get him in here.
[ Beeps ]
May ?
Yes, sir ?
I know you're busy,
but I want you to put in a call
to Eddie Sloane for me.
At home, sir ?
No, he's at the office.
This is damn big
of Bill.
Ooh. You all right ?
Yeah.
Also smart, you know ?
Well, he had no choice.
He knows you're
a formidable adversary.
He said that ?
Yeah, I mean, you got him
by the short hairs.
Yeah, the short
and gray hairs.
We're all here, Bill.
I appreciate this, Eddie.
Members of the board, this will
just take a minute of your time.
As custodians of the company,
you may receive information
from what follows...
that will be valuable
to you or not.
Either way, thanks.
We're all ears.
[ Door Opens ]
Thanks.
Good evening, Bill.
Thank you, Quince.
I just wanted to say how
appreciative I am of this,
um, grand gesture.
Shut up and sit down.
You're a useless sack
of shit, Drew.
You played footsie
with John Bontecou...
so you could
dismember my company
to line your own pockets.
I don't know where you get
that idea. The board agreed--
The board didn't know you were
a mole who burrowed inside
so you could bury us all.
Is this Mr. Black's fantasy ?
Another one of his whoppers ?
Aren't you sick of
this asshole lurking around ?
Nobody knows who he is.
But one thing
everybody does know,
he somehow got your ear
and has been pouring poison
into it ever since.
You're the poison, Drew.
You've operated behind
the scenes to suborn
the trust of a man...
who has stamped you
with his imprimatur of
class, elegance and stature.
I've had the opportunity
to be witness to every kind
and degree of deception.
But Bill Parrish has been
on the receiving end of
machinations so Machiavellian...
that it has rarely been
my experience to encounter.
And yet, he has combatted them
stoically and selflessly,
without revealing my identity.
Had he violated
the vow of secrecy he took,
his task would
have been far easier.
He could have turned
defeat into victory.
But he is too honorable a man
to have done that.
Because of me,
he has lost his work,
his company, his reputation.
So now,
given these losses,
I'm compelled to end
the need for secrecy.
The time has come
to tell you who I am.
So tell me. Tell me.
I'm peeing in my pants.
- And you're going
to pee some more.
-Joe, don't do this.
It's okay, Bill. It's time
we put this person in his place.
It's not necessary, Joe.
Drew's gonna step aside.
- I'm not stepping anywhere.
- I appreciate your
gentlemanliness.
But what we need to do here
is drive the dagger home.
- ''The dagger'' ?
- I told you to shut up !
Prepare yourself, Drew.
I--
Joe, please.
Kindly let me
take it from here.
Am--
Don't.
An agent for the
Internal Revenue Service.
Bill ?
Huh ?
Bill.
Yeah.
[ Clears Throat ]
Yes, he's, um--
He's an agent for the
Internal Revenue Service.
Mmm, yes, we were convinced
that Bontecou, on past deals,
has structured his mergers
and acquisitions...
in suspicious and complicated
ways so as to evade paying
the taxes he is liable for.
The agency asked Bill for
his cooperation in an undercover
investigation of Bontecou.
We wanted to go after him,
and this deal gave us
that perfect opportunity.
And I offered
to cooperate.
And we're very grateful.
Uh, Agent Joe Black here--
Of course, that's not
his real name--
smelled out
your involvement, Drew.
He developed evidence you were
working both sides of the fence.
Unfortunately,
that is what is known
as a conflict of interest.
Undisclosed
conflict of interest.
An offense.
An indictable offense.
And a likely
conviction.
Very likely.
I think I'd like
to talk to my lawyer.
No lawyers, Drew.
Uh, we're gonna
offer you a deal.
Confess to the board every
detail of your participation,
then submit your resignation.
What do I get ?
You get not to go to jail.
You're talking
through your hat.
You're offering me a deal
because you've got no proof.
Proof? We've got
plenty of proof.
He's talking through his lips.
Drew, make no mistake.
Should you choose to test
my resolve in this matter,
you will be looking
at an outcome that
will have a finality...
that is beyond
your comprehension.
And you will not be counting
the days or the months
or the years,
but millenniums
in a place with no doors.
All right, you win.
Soon as I get back to the city,
I'll meet with the board.
[ Eddie ] You're meeting
with the board right now,
Drew. Resignation accepted.
Moreover, I propose
a motion to reconfirm
William Parrish...
as chairman of the board
of Parrish Communications,
as well as
a rejection of the merger
with Bontecou International.
How say you, board?
- Yes.
The motion is passed.
[ Bill ]
Thank you.
That's great.
But it's more than
I bargained for. I just wanted
to set the record straight.
You have. Sounds like
these guys want you back, Bill.
We'll get their apologies later.
Meanwhile, enjoy your party.
Celebrate. I'll attend
to the nasty details.
And, Mr. Black,
may we say thank you ?
My pleasure.
This is an I.R.S. agent's dream.
I'll be promoted
chief of section off this.
[ Clicks ]
Who would have believed it ?
You an I.R.S. agent ?
Death and taxes.
::music:: [ Ends ]
[ Applause ]
::music:: [ ''Happy Birthday'']
::music:: Happy birthday to you ::music::
::music:: Happy birthday
dear William ::music::
::music:: Happy birthday to you ::music::::music::
[ Cheering ]
Speech ! Speech !
Speech !
[ Chanting ]
Speech ! Speech ! Speech !
Thank you.
[ Sighs ]
I thought I was gonna
sneak away tonight.
[ Crowd ] No !
[ Scattered Laughing ]
What a glorious night.
Every face I see
is a memory.
It may not be a perfectly
perfect memory.
Uh, sometimes we had
our ups and downs.
But we're all together,
and you're mine for a night.
And I'm gonna break
precedent and tell you
my one candle wish.
That you would have a life
as lucky as mine,
where you can wake up
one morning and say,
''I don't want anything more.''
Sixty-five years.
Don't they
go by in a blink ?
::music:: [ Resumes ]
Hi.
Oh. What a night.
I'm having
a hell of a time.
You were right...
about Joe.
He, uh--
He is going somewhere.
I'm sorry.
You relieved ?
Yes, but--
[ Sighs ]
But what ?
I want you to know
how much I love you,
that you've given a meaning
to my life that I had
no right to expect,
that no one can
ever take from me.
Dad--
No !
I love you so much.
And I want you
to promise me something.
I don't want you
to ever worry about me.
And if anything
should happen,
I'm gonna be okay.
And everything's
gonna be all right.
And I have no regrets.
And I want you
to feel the same way.
I love you, Daddy.
That's why it's okay.
No regrets ?
No regrets.
That's a good feeling,
isn't it ?
Yeah.
Everybody's saying good-bye.
I'm still here.
Would you like to dance
with me, Susan ?
Yeah.
If you don't mind
dancing with an old fogey
like me.
Oh, Dad, you're not old.
You'll never be old.
Can I get you
anything, sir ?
No.
Do you have
any peanut butter ?
Uh, I don't think so, sir.
Mmm. Thank you anyway.
You're welcome.
What's that ?
[ Chuckles ]
The fireworks are starting.
Let's go down and watch.
[ Fireworks Popping ]
Shall we ?
You go on ahead, honey.
I'm just gonna
catch my breath.
[ Whispers ]
Okay.
Happy birthday, Bill.
Thank you.
Did you say good-bye ?
Not exactly.
I guess you have
your reasons.
Yes.
[ Popping Continues ]
Now that we have a moment,
would you mind
if I expressed my gratitude
for what you did for Susan ?
I've never heard
her speak of any man
as she spoke of you.
That's what I always
wanted for her.
But what happens
to her now ?
I wouldn't worry
about it, Bill.
These things have a way
of working out.
Would you mind if
I expressed my gratitude ?
For you,
for the time
you've given me,
for the person you are.
Don't blow smoke up my ass.
You'll ruin my autopsy.
It's hard to let go,
isn't it ?
Yes, it is, Bill.
Well, that's life.
What can I tell you ?
Should I be afraid ?
Not a man like you.
You're here.
You bet.
Well, where did you go ?
I don't know.
I don't--
I-- I don't know,
you know. I--
It's all kind of blurred up
and hazy, but--
Would you know what I mean
if I said I don't think
I'll ever figure it out ?
But now I'm back.
That's it ?
Well, I don't know
what else to say. Looks
like a hell of a party.
You think so ?
You look beautiful.
When you disappeared
around the corner,
I wasn't sure if I was
ever gonna see you again.
Hey, are you all right ?
The coffee shop.
Yep.
I asked you if I said
something wrong and you said no,
it was so right it scared you.
And then you said--
Forgive me for
saying this, but it's
been with me ever since.
What has ?
You said you liked me.
No.
You didn't ?
I said...
I liked you so much.
[ Whispers ]
Yeah.
We know so little
about each other.
But we've got time.
[ Whispers ]
Yeah.
I wish you...
could've known my father.
Me too.
What do we do now ?
It'll come to us.
Yeah.
::music:: [ Man Vocalizing ]
::music:: Somewhere
::music:: Over the rainbow
::music:: Way up high
::music:: And the dreams
that you dream of
::music:: Once in a lullaby
::music:: By, oh
::music:: Somewhere
::music:: Over the rainbow
::music:: Bluebirds fly
::music:: And the dreams
that you dream of
::music:: Dreams really do come true
::music:: Ooo-ooo
::music:: Some day you wish
upon a star
::music:: Wake up where the clouds
are far behind
::music:: Be where trouble melts
like lemon drops
::music:: High above the chimney top
::music:: It's where
::music:: You find me, oh
::music:: Somewhere
::music:: Over the rainbow
::music:: Bluebirds fly
::music:: And the dreams
that you dare to
::music:: Oh, why, oh, why
::music:: Can't I, I
::music:: Well, I see trees of green
::music:: And red roses too
::music:: I'll watch them bloom for
::music:: Me and you
and I think to myself
::music:: What a wonderful world
::music:: Well, I see skies of blue
::music:: And I see clouds of white
::music:: And the brightness of day
::music:: I like the dark
::music:: And I think to myself
::music:: What a wonderful world
::music:: The colors of the rainbow
::music:: So pretty in the sky
::music:: Are also on the faces
::music:: Of people passing by
::music:: I see friends shaking hands
::music:: Saying, how do you do
::music:: They're really saying
::music:: I, I love you
::music:: I hear babies cry
::music:: And I watch them grow
::music:: They'll learn much more
::music:: Than we'll know
::music:: And I think to myself
::music:: What a wonderful world
::music:: World
::music:: Some day I wish upon a star
::music:: Wake up where the clouds
are far behind
::music:: Be where trouble melts
like lemon drops
::music:: High above the chimney top
::music:: That's where
::music:: You'll find me, oh
::music:: Somewhere
::music:: Over the rainbow
::music:: Way up high
::music:: And the dreams
that you dare to
::music:: Why, oh, why, can't I
::music:: I
::music:: [ Vocalizing ]