- [bird screeching]
- [groans]
[screeching]
We're under attack!
Light the signal!
- [gasps]
- [grunts]
[panting]
[people shouting in distance]
- [man] Light the fire now!
- [man #2] Light the signal!
Now all of China knows you're here.
[falcon screeches]
Perfect.
Your Majesty, the Huns have
crossed our northern border.
Impossible. No one can get
through the Great Wall.
Shan-Yu is leading them.
We'll set up defenses
around your palace immediately.
No. Send your troops
to protect my people.
- Chi Fu.
- Yes, Your Highness?
Deliver conscription notices
throughout all the provinces.
Call up reserves and as many
new recruits as possible.
Forgive me, Your Majesty, but
I believe my troops can stop him.
I won't take any chances, General.
A single grain of rice
can tip the scale.
One man may be the difference
between victory and defeat.
"Quiet and demure.
"Graceful. Polite.
[mumbles] "Delicate.
Refined. Poised.
Punctual."
[crowing]
Ai-yah! Little Brother!
[blowing] Little Brother. Lit...
- [snoring]
- Ah! There you are.
Who's the smartest doggy
in the world?
- [barking]
- Come on, smart boy.
Can you help me
with my chores today?
[barking]
[growls, snarls]
[whimpers, barking resumes]
[squawking]
[barking continues]
[nickers]
Honorable ancestors,
please help Mulan
impress the matchmaker today.
[barking]
[cackling]
Please.
Please help her.
[whimpering]
[barking, growling]
Father, I brought your... Whoa!
- Mulan.
- I brought a spare.
The doctor said three cups
of tea in the morning...
- Mulan.
...and three at night.
Mulan, you should already be in town.
We are counting on you
to uphold the family honor.
Don't worry, Father.
I won't let you down.
- Wish me luck.
- Hurry!
I'm going to... pray some more.
Fa Li, is your daughter here yet?
The matchmaker
is not a patient woman.
Of all days to be late.
I should have prayed
to the ancestors for luck.
How lucky can they be?
They're dead.
Besides, I've got
all the luck we'll need.
[twitters]
This is your chance
to prove yourself.
Grandma, no!
- [screaming]
- [chicken clucking]
Yep, this cricket's a lucky one!
[chirping softly]
- [sighs]
- [horse neighs]
I'm here.
What? But, Mama, I had to...
None of your excuses.
Now, let's get you cleaned up.
# This is what you give me to work with
# Well, honey, I've seen worse
# We are gonna turn this sow's ear
# Into a silk purse
It's freezing.
It would have been warm
if you were here on time.
# We'll have you washed and dried
# Primped and polished
Till you glow with pride
# Trust my recipe for instant bride
# You'll bring honor to us all
Mulan, what's this?
Uh, notes.
In case I forget something.
Hold this.
We'll need more luck than I thought.
# Wait and see when we're through
# Boys will gladly go to war for you
- # With good fortune
- # And a great hairdo
[together] # You'll bring honor
To us all
# A girl can bring her family
# Great honor in one way
- # By striking a good match
- Huh?
- # And this could be the day
- [laughs]
# Men want girls with good taste
- Calm.
- Obedient.
# Who work fast-paced
# With good breeding
- # And a tiny waist
- [gasps]
# You'll bring honor to us all
# We all must serve our emperor
# Who guards us from the Huns
# A man by bearing arms
# A girl by bearing sons
# When we're through you can't fail
# Like a lotus blossom soft and pale
# How could any fellow say no sale
# You'll bring honor to us all
There. You're ready.
Not yet.
An apple for serenity.
A pendant for balance.
# Beads of jade
# For beauty
# You must proudly
# Show it
# Now add a cricket
# Just for luck
# And even you can't blow it
# Ancestors, hear my plea
# Help me not to make a fool of me
# And to not uproot my family tree
# Keep my father standing tall
# Scarier than the undertaker
# We are meeting our matchmaker
[townspeople] # Destiny guard our girls
# And our future as it fast unfurls
# Please look kindly
On these cultured pearls
# Each a perfect porcelain doll
# Please bring honor to us
# Please bring honor to us all #
"Fa Mulan."
- Present.
- Speaking without permission.
Oops.
Who spit in her bean curd?
Huh. Hmm.
Mmm. Too skinny.
Hmph! Not good for bearing sons.
Recite the final admonition.
- [muffled chirping]
- Mm-hmm.
- Well?
- [clears throat]
Fulfill your duties calmly and...
respectfully.
Um, reflect before you snack...
Act! This shall bring you
honor and glory.
[sighs]
Hmm. This way.
Now, pour the tea.
To please your future in-laws,
you must demonstrate
a sense of dignity...
...and refinement.
You must also be poised.
[purring]
Um, pardon me.
And silent!
[sniffs] Ahhh.
- Could I just take that back?
- [grunting]
- One moment.
- [screams]
- [gasps]
- Why, you clumsy...
- [chirping]
- Whoo! Whoo!
Aaah! Whoo! Aaah!
- [sizzling]
- [screaming]
[screaming louder]
[loud crash]
I think it's going well, don't you?
Put it out! Put it out! Put it out!
[panting] You are a disgrace!
You may look like a bride,
but you will never
bring your family honor!
[townspeople whispering]
[sighs]
# Look at me
# I will never pass
# For a perfect bride
# Or a perfect daughter
# Can it be
# I'm not meant to play this part
# Now I see
# That if I were truly to be myself
# I would break my family's heart
# Who is that girl I see
# Staring straight
# Back at me
# Why is my reflection
# Someone I don't know
# Somehow I cannot hide
# Who I am
# Though I've tried
# When will my reflection show
# Who I am inside
# Who I am
# Inside #
[Father clears throat]
My, my.
What beautiful blossoms
we have this year.
But look.
This one's late.
But I'll bet that when it blooms,
it will be the most beautiful of all.
[drums pounding in distance]
What is it?
Mulan.
Stay inside.
- [clears throat]
- [horse whinnies]
Citizens, I bring a proclamation
from the imperial city.
The Huns have invaded China.
[townspeople gasp]
By order of the emperor,
one man from every family
must serve in the Imperial army.
The Hsiao family.
The Yi family.
I will serve the emperor
in my father's place.
The Fa family.
No!
I am ready to serve the emperor.
- Father, you can't go.
- Mulan!
Please, sir, my father
has already fought bravely...
Silence! You would do well
to teach your daughter
to hold her tongue in a man's presence.
Mulan, you dishonor me.
Report tomorrow
to the Wu Zhong camp.
Yes, sir.
[Chi Fu] The Chu family!
The Wen family!
The Chang family!
[grunts]
[groans]
[thud]
[panting]
[thunder rumbling]
[thunderclap]
- You shouldn't have to go!
- Mulan...
There are plenty of young men
to fight for China.
It is an honor to protect
my country and my family.
So, you'll die for honor.
I will die doing what's right.
- But if you...
- I know my place!
It is time you learned yours.
[sobbing]
[crying]
[thunderclap]
[whinnying]
[gasps]
Mulan is gone!
What?
It can't be.
Mulan!
[groans]
No.
You must go after her.
She could be killed.
If I reveal her,
she will be.
Ancestors, hear our prayer.
Watch over Mulan.
[wind whistling]
Mushu, awaken!
[clanking]
I live!
So, tell me what mortal needs
my protection, Great Ancestor.
- Just say the word and I'm there.
- Mushu...
Let me say somethin'. Anybody who's
foolish enough to threaten our family,
vengeance will be mine!
[growling]
Mushu!
These are the family guardians.
They...
protect the family.
And you, o demoted one?
I... ring the gong.
That's right.
Now, wake up the ancestors.
[sighs] One family reunion
comin' right up.
Okay, people, look alive.
Let's go. Come on. Get up.
Let's move it. Rise and shine.
Y'all way past the beauty sleep thing,
trust me.
[ancestors yawning]
I knew it. I knew it!
That Mulan was a troublemaker
from the start!
Don't look at me. She gets it
from your side of the family.
She's trying to help her father.
If she's discovered,
Fa Zhou will be forever shamed.
Dishonor will come to the family.
Traditional values will disintegrate.
- Not to mention, they'll lose the farm.
- My children never caused such trouble.
- They all became acupuncturists.
- Well, we can't all be acupuncturists.
No! Your great-granddaughter
had to be a cross-dresser!
[ancestors arguing]
- Let a guardian bring her back.
- Yes, awaken the most cunning.
No, the swiftest.
- No, send the wisest.
- [Great Ancestor] Silence!
We must send
the most powerful of all.
[laughing] Okay, okay, I get the drift.
I'll go.
[all laughing]
Y'all don't think I can do it.
Watch this here.
Aha! Jump back.
I'm pretty hot, huh?
Don't make me singe nobody
to prove no point.
You had your chance
to protect the Fa family.
Your misguidance
led Fa Deng to disaster.
Yeah, thanks a lot.
And your point is?
The point is we will be sending
a real dragon to retrieve Mulan.
What? What?
I'm a real dragon!
You are not worthy of this spot.
Now, awaken the great stone dragon.
So you'll get back to me
on the job thing?
[sighs]
Just one chance.
Is that too much to ask?
It's not like it'll kill ya.
Yo, Rocky, wake up!
Ya gotta go fetch Mulan!
Come on, boy!
Go get her! Go on!
[whistles] Come on.
[growling]
Hello?
Hel-lo!
Hello!
Uh-oh.
Uh, Stony?
Stony? Oh, man, they're gonna kill me.
[Great Ancestor] Great stone dragon,
have you awakened?
[Mushu] Uh, uh, uh, uh...
Yes, I just woke up!
I'm... I am the great stone dragon.
Good morning!
I will go forth and fetch Mulan.
Did... Did I mention that
I was the great stone dragon?
Go! The fate of the Fa family
rests in your claws.
Don't even worry about it.
I will not lose face.
[screaming, grunting]
Oh. My elbow!
[groaning] I know I twisted somethin'.
[grunting]
That's just great.
Now what?
I'm doomed, and all 'cause Miss Man
decides to take her
little drag show on the road.
[chirping, squeaking]
Go get her?
What's the matter with you?
After this great stone,
Humpty-Dumpty mess,
I'd have to bring her home with
a medal to get back in the temple.
That's it!
I'll make Mulan a war hero.
They'll be begging me
to come back to work.
That's the master plan.
Ah, you done it now, man.
[chirps]
[chirping continues]
Hey, what makes you
think you're comin'?
[chirping]
You're lucky? [laughing]
- Do I look like a sucker to you?
- [chirps]
What you mean, "a loser"?
How 'bout I pop
one of your antennas off?
- Then who's the loser?
- [chirps]
[screeching]
[whinnying]
[both groan]
Imperial scouts.
Shan-Yu.
[screeches]
Nice work, gentlemen.
You found the Hun army.
[Huns laughing]
The emperor will stop you.
Stop me? He invited me.
- [grunts]
- [groans]
By building his wall,
he challenged my strength.
Well, I'm here to play his game.
Go! Tell your emperor
to send his strongest armies.
I'm ready.
How many men does it take
to deliver a message?
One.
Okay, okay, how about this?
[coughs, speaks in deep voice]
Excuse me.
Where do I sign in?
Ha, I see you have a sword.
I have one, too.
They're very manly and... tough.
[neighing]
I'm working on it!
Oh. Who am I fooling?
It's going to take a miracle
to get me into the army.
Did I hear someone
ask for a miracle?
- Let me hear you say "aaah"!
- Aaah!
- That's close enough.
- A ghost.
Get ready, Mulan.
Your serpentine salvation is at hand!
For I have been sent
by your ancestors
to guide you through
your masquerade.
If you're gonna stay,
you're gonna work.
So heed my word! 'Cause if the army
finds out you're a girl,
the penalty is death!
Who are you?
Who am I? Who am I?
I am the guardian of lost souls.
I am the powerful,
the pleasurable,
the indestructible Mushu.
Oh. Ha, ha.
Pretty hot, huh?
[groans]
Uh, my ancestors sent
a little lizard to help me?
Hey, dragon, dragon, not lizard.
I don't do that tongue thing.
You're, um...
Intimidating?
Awe-inspiring?
- Tiny.
- Of course.
I'm travel-size
for your convenience.
If I was my real size, your cow
here would die of fright.
Down, Bessie. My powers are
beyond your mortal imagination.
For instance, my eyes can see
straight through your armor. Oooh!
All right, that's it! Dishonor!
Dishonor on your whole family.
Make a note of this.
Dishonor on you,
dishonor on your cow, dis...
Stop. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just nervous.
I've never done this before.
Then you're gonna have to trust me.
And don't slap me no more.
We clear on that?
All right.
Let's get this show on the road!
Cri-Kee, get the bags.
- Let's move it, heifer.
- [snorts]
[men chattering]
Okay, this is it.
Time to show 'em your man walk.
Shoulders back, chest high,
feet apart, head up and strut.
Two, three. Break it down.
Hup, two, three. And work it!
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- They're disgusting.
No, they're men. You have to
act like them, so pay attention.
Look.
This tattoo will protect me from harm.
Hmm.
- [groans]
- [laughing]
I hope you can get your money back!
I don't think I can do this.
It's all attitude.
Be tough, like this guy here.
- [snorting]
- What are you lookin' at?
Punch him.
It's how men say hello.
Oh, Yao, you've made a friend.
Good. Slap him on the behind.
They like that.
Whoa-ho-ho!
I'm gonna hit you so hard,
it'll make your ancestors dizzy.
- Yao, relax and chant with me.
- [growling]
[chanting]
[Yao chanting]
- [gibberish]
- Feel better?
Yeah. Ahh, you ain't worth my time.
- Chicken boy.
- [screaming] Chicken boy?
Say that to my face, ya limp noodle!
[growls]
Oh. Sorry, Ling.
Hey!
Whoa! You're dead!
Oh, there he goes!
- [clattering]
- [chicken clucking]
[grunting]
[men groaning]
[Mulan] Hey, guys.
The Huns have struck here,
here and here.
I will take the main troops
up to the Tung Shao Pass...
and stop Shan-Yu before
he destroys this village.
Excellent strategy, sir.
I do love surprises. [chuckling]
You will stay and train
the new recruits.
When Chi Fu
believes you're ready,
you will join us, Captain.
Captain?
[gasps] This is an enormous
responsibility, General.
Perhaps a soldier
with more experience...
Number one in his class,
extensive knowledge
of training techniques,
an impressive military lineage.
I believe Li Shang
will do an excellent job.
Oh, I will. I won't let you down.
This is... I mean... [clears throat]
- Yes, sir.
- Very good then.
We'll toast China's victory
at the imperial city.
I'll expect a full report
in three weeks.
And I won't leave anything out.
Captain Li Shang.
Hmm. [chuckles]
Leader of China's finest troops.
No. The greatest troops of all time.
[chuckles]
[men yelling]
[moaning]
Most impressive.
- [whinnies]
- Good luck, Captain. Hyah!
Good luck, Father.
[yelling, fighting continue]
Day one.
Soldiers!
[together] He started it!
I don't need anyone
causing trouble in my camp.
Sorry. Uh...
[clears throat] I mean, uh...
sorry you had to see that.
But you know how it is when
you get those manly urges
and you just gotta kill something,
[groans] Fix things, cook outdoors...
- What's your name?
- [stammering]
Your commanding officer
just asked you a question.
Uh, I've got a name.
Ha! And it's a boy's name, too.
- Ling. How 'bout Ling?
- His name is Ling.
I didn't ask for his name.
I asked for yours!
- Try, uh, uh, ah, Chu.
- Ah Chu.
- Ah Chu?
- Gesundheit.
Ha, ha. I kill myself.
- Mushu.
- Mushu?
- No.
- Then what is it?
Ping was my best friend growin' up.
- It's Ping.
- Ping?
Of course, Ping did steal my...
Yes, my name is Ping.
Let me see
your conscription notice.
- Fa Zhou? The Fa Zhou?
- I didn't know Fa Zhou had a son.
Um, he doesn't talk about me much.
[chuckles]
[snorting]
I can see why.
The boy's an absolute lunatic.
[chuckling]
Okay, gentlemen,
thanks to your new friend, Ping,
you'll spend tonight picking up
every single grain of rice.
[men groan]
And tomorrow, the real work begins.
[growls]
You know, we have to work
on your people skills.
[chirping]
[squeaking]
[ringing]
Rise and shine, sleeping beauty.
- Come on. Hup, hup, hup.
- [moans]
[Mushu] Get your clothes on.
Get ready. Got breakfast for ya.
Look, you get porridge,
and it's happy to see you.
Hey, get outta there!
You gonna make people sick.
- Am I late?
- No time to talk.
It's your first day of training.
Listen to your teacher and no fightin'.
Play nice, unless one of the other kids
wanna fight.
Then you have to kick
the other kid's butt.
I don't wanna kick
Don't talk with your mouth full.
Let's see your war face.
I think my bunny slippers
just ran for cover.
Come on! Scare me, girl.
- [growls]
- Yeah!
That's my tough-lookin' warrior.
Get out there and make me proud.
[neighing]
[snorting]
- The troops just left?
- They what?
[muffled shouting]
Wait! You forgot your sword.
My little baby,
off to destroy people.
[whimpers]
[man screams]
Order. People, order.
- I'd like a pan-fried noodle.
- Oh! Sweet and pungent shrimp.
- Moo goo gai pan.
- That's not funny!
[braying]
Looks like our new friend
slept in this morning.
Hello, Ping.
Are ya hungry?
Yeah, 'cause I owe you
a knuckle sandwich.
- [men shouting]
- [Li Shang] Soldiers!
You will assemble swiftly
and silently every morning.
Anyone who acts otherwise
will answer to me.
Ooh. Tough guy.
Yao.
Thank you for volunteering.
Retrieve the arrow.
[knuckles cracking]
I'll get that arrow, pretty boy,
and I'll do it with my shirt on.
One moment.
You seem to be missing something.
This represents discipline,
and this represents strength.
You need both to reach the arrow.
[grunting]
[grunts]
We've got a long way to go.
# Let's get down to business
- [all gasp]
- # To defeat the Huns
- [all] Hoo-ah!
- # Did they send me daughters
# When I asked for sons
# You're the saddest bunch I ever met
# But you can bet before we're through
# Mister, I'll make a man
# Out of you
[Li Shang] # Tranquil as a forest
# But on fire within
# Once you find your center
# You are sure to win
# You're a spineless, pale, pathetic lot
# And you haven't got a clue
# Somehow I'll make a man
# Out of you
# I'm never gonna catch my breath
# Say good-bye to those who knew me
# Boy, was I a fool in school
For cutting gym
[Mushu] # This guy's got 'em
Scared to death
[Mulan] # Hope he doesn't see
Right through me
# Now I really wish
That I knew how to swim
[men] # Be a man
# We must be swift as a coursing river
# Be a man
# With all the force of a great typhoon
# With all the strength of a raging fire
# Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
# Time is racing toward us
# Till the Huns arrive
# Heed my every order
# And you might survive
# You're unsuited for the rage of war
# So pack up, go home you're through
# How could I make a man
# Out of you
[men] # Be a man
# We must be swift as a coursing river
# Be a man
# With all the force of a great typhoon
# With all the strength of a raging fire
- # Mysterious as the dark side
- [men cheering]
# Of the moon
# Be a man
# We must be swift as a coursing river
# With all the force of a great typhoon
# Be a man
# With all the strength of a raging fire
- # Mysterious as the dark side
- [all grunting]
# Of the moon #
[all] Hoo-ah!
[falcon screeching]
[sniffing]
[Shan-Yu] What do you see?
Black pine, from the high mountains.
White horse hair.
Imperial stallions.
[sniffing] Sulfur, from cannons.
This doll came from a village
in the Tung Shao Pass,
where the imperial army
is waiting for us.
We can avoid them easily.
No.
The quickest way to the
emperor is through that pass.
And besides, the little girl
will be missing her doll.
We should return it to her.
[stammering] No, this is not
a good idea.
What if somebody sees you?
Just because I look like a man
doesn't mean I have to smell like one.
So a couple of guys
don't rinse out their socks.
Picky, picky, picky.
Well, myself, I kind of like
that corn chip smell.
- Ahhh.
- All right. That's enough.
Get out before you
get all pruny and stuff.
Mushu, if you're so worried,
go stand watch.
[imitating Mushu] Yeah, yeah.
"Stand watch, Mushu,
while I blow our secret
with my stupid girlie habits."
- Pfft! Hygiene!
- [men laughing]
- [Yao] Me first! Me first!
- [gasps]
We're doomed!
There are a couple of things
I know they're bound to notice!
[chirping]
[men shouting]
- Whooo-ooo!
- [screaming]
[laughing] Hey, Ping!
Oh, hi, guys.
I didn't know you were here.
I was just washing. So now I'm
clean, and I'm gonna go. Bye-bye.
Come back here.
I know we were jerks to you before,
so let's start over.
- Hi. I'm Ling.
- [nervous chuckle]
- And I'm Chien-Po.
- Hello, Chien-Po.
And I am Yao!
King of the rock!
And there's nothin'
you girls can do about it.
Oh, yeah? Well, I think Ping
and I can take you.
I really don't wanna
take him anywhere.
Ping, we have to fight!
No, we don't.
We could just close
our eyes and swim around.
- Come on. Don't be such a gir...
- [crunching]
Ouch! Something bit me!
[grunts, coughs] What a nasty flavor.
Snake! [screaming]
- [whistles]
- [whinnies]
[Yao] Oooh, snake! Snake!
- Snake! Snake!
- [men continue screaming]
Some king of the rock. Aah!
Boy, that was close.
No. That was vile.
You owe me big.
I never want to see a naked man again.
[shouting, laughing]
[grumbles]
Hey, don't look at me.
I ain't bitin' no more butts.
[Chi Fu] You think your troops
are ready to fight?
Ha! They would not last
a minute against the Huns!
They completed their training.
Those boys are no more fit
to be soldiers
than you are to be captain.
Once the general reads my report,
your troops will never see battle.
Oh, no, you don't!
I've worked too hard
to get Mulan into this war.
This guy's messin' with my plan.
We're not finished!
Be careful, Captain.
The general may be your father,
but I am the emperor's counsel.
[scoffs] And, oh, by the way,
I got that job on my own.
You're dismissed.
Hey. I'll hold him, and you punch.
[chuckles] Or not.
For what it's worth,
I think you're a great captain.
- I saw that.
- What?
You like him, don't you?
- No! I...
- Yeah, right, sure.
Go to your tent!
I think it's time we took this war
into our own hands.
[cackling]
# [humming]
[inhales deeply, continues humming]
[typewriter keys clacking]
Let me see what you got.
"From General Li. Dear son,
we're waiting for Huns at the pass.
It would mean a lot
if you'd come back us up."
That's great. Except you forgot,
"Since we're out of potpourri,
perhaps you wouldn't mind
bringing some."
Hello! This is the army!
Make it sound more urgent!
Know what I'm talkin' about?
[chirping]
[clacking]
That's better.
Much better. Let's go.
Khanny, baby.
Hey, we need a ride.
[nervous chirping]
[men laughing]
Insubordinate ruffians!
You men owe me
a new pair of slippers!
[laughter continues]
And I do not squeal like a girl.
[high-pitched squeal]
Urgent news from the general.
What's the matter? You've never
seen a black and white before?
Who are you?
Excuse me?
I think the question is, who are you?
We're in a war, man!
There's no time for stupid questions!
I should have your hat for that.
Snatch it right off your head.
But I'm feeling gracious today,
so carry on before I report you.
Captain, urgent news
from the general!
We're needed at the front.
Pack your bags, Cri-Kee.
We're movin' out.
[chirps]
# For a long time
We've been marching off to battle
# In our thundering herd
We feel a lot like cattle
[mooing]
# Like a pounding beat our aching feet
# Aren't easy to ignore
# Hey! Think of instead
# A girl worth fighting for
- Huh?
- That's what I said.
# A girl worth fighting for
# I want her paler than the moon
# With eyes that shine like stars
[Yao] # My girl will marvel
At my strength
# Adore my battle scars
[Chien-Po] # I couldn't care less
What she'll wear
# Or what she looks like
# It all depends on what she cooks like
# Beef, pork, chicken, mmm
# Bet the local girls thought
You were quite the charmer
# And I'll bet the ladies
Love a man in armor
[men] # You can guess
What we have missed the most
- # Since we went off to war
- [wolf whistle]
- [Ling] # What do we want
- # A girl worth fighting for
# My girl will think I have no faults
# That I'm a major find
# Uh, how 'bout a girl who's got a brain
- # Who always speaks her mind
- [together] nah!
# My manly ways and turn of phrase
# Are sure to thrill her
# He thinks he's such a lady-killer
# I've a girl back home
Who's unlike any other
# Yeah, the only girl
Who'd love him is his mother
[men] # But when we come home
In victory
# They'll line up at the door
- # What do we want
- # A girl worth fighting for
# Wish that I had
# A girl worth fighting for
- # [whistling]
- # A girl worth fighting... #
[clanking]
Search for survivors.
- [creaking]
- [whinnies]
[horse nickers]
I don't understand.
My father should've been here.
Captain!
The general.
I'm sorry.
[nickers]
- [whinnies]
- The Huns are moving quickly.
We'll make better time
to the Imperial city
through the Tung Shao Pass.
We're the only hope
for the emperor now.
Move out!
[bell clanking]
[all gasping]
[chirping]
- [whinnies]
- What happened?
- Um...
- You gave away our position!
- [grunting]
- [battle cries]
- Get out of range!
- [shouting]
Aah!
- [whinnying]
- Save the cannons!
- [all chattering]
- Come on! Empty it! Empty it!
[Mushu] Hey!
Oh, sure.
Save the horse.
Fire!
[screaming]
[whimpering]
Fire!
Hold the last cannon.
[whinnies]
[battle cries]
Prepare to fight.
If we die, we die with honor.
[yelling]
Yao, aim the cannon at Shan-Yu.
- [Yao] Hey!
- Ping! Come back!
- Ping!
- [whinnies]
Stop!
You might want
to light that right about now.
- Quickly. Quickly!
- [falcon screeching]
Come on!
We gotta help!
- [horse whinnies]
- [Mushu] You missed!
How could you miss?
He was three feet in front of you!
[men screaming]
- [growling, yelling]
- [grunting]
[cheering]
- [cheering stops]
- [all] Whoa-ho-ho!
[whinnying]
[screaming]
[gasping, yelling]
[Mushu] Mulan!
Mulan!
- Mulan?
- [growling]
No.
Mulan!
Man, you are one lucky bug.
[gasps] Shang!
- Do you see them?
- Yes.
Perfect.
Now we'll pull them to safe... ty.
Hey, Mulan!
I found the lucky cricket!
We need help.
Ooh, nice.
Very nice.
You can sit by me.
Aah!
[Mushu] We're gonna die!
We are definitely gonna die.
No way we survive this.
Death is coming!
[blubbering] I let them
slip through my fingers.
- Aah!
- [all grunting]
Pull!
[together] Whoa!
Huh?
I knew we could do it.
You the man!
Well, sort of.
[Ling] Step back, guys.
Give him some air.
[gasping] Ping?
[gasping]
You are the craziest man
I've ever met.
And for that, I owe you my life.
From now on,
you have my trust.
Let's hear it for Ping!
The bravest of us all!
- You're king of the mountain!
- Yes, yes, yes!
- [cheering continues]
- [grunts]
Ping! What's wrong?
[grunting]
He's wounded! Get help!
- [chattering]
- Ping.
Hold on.
[whispering]
I can explain.
[gasping] So it's true!
[Mulan] Shang!
I knew there was
something wrong with you.
- A woman!
- [gasping]
- [grunting]
- Treacherous snake!
My name is Mulan.
- I did it to save my father.
- High treason!
I didn't mean for it to go this far.
Ultimate dishonor!
It was the only way.
Please, believe me.
[scoffs] Captain?
- [neighing]
- [gasps]
Restrain him!
- [together] No!
- You know the law.
A life for a life.
My debt is repaid.
- Move out!
- But you can't just...
I said move out.
[snorts]
[nickers]
[chirping, chittering]
I was this close.
This close to impressin' the ancestors,
gettin' the top shelf, an entourage.
Man. All my fine work. Pfft.
Hi.
I should never have left home.
Hey, come on.
You went to save your father's life.
Who knew you'd end up shamin' him,
disgracing your ancestors
and losin' all your friends?
You know, you just gotta...
you gotta learn
to let these things go.
[crying]
Maybe I didn't go for my father.
Maybe what I really wanted
was to prove I could do things right.
So when I looked in the mirror,
I'd see someone worthwhile.
But I was wrong.
I see nothing.
That's just 'cause this needs
a little spit, that's all.
[spits] Let me shine this up for ya.
I can see you. Look at you.
You look so pretty.
The truth is, we're both frauds.
Your ancestors never sent me.
They don't even like me.
I mean, you risked your life
to help people you love.
I risked your life to help myself.
At least you had good intentions.
[soft chirping]
What? What do you mean
you're not lucky?
- You lied to me?
- [chirping]
And what are you, a sheep?
- [grumbles]
- Ah!
I'll have to face my father
sooner or later.
Let's go home.
Yeah. This ain't gonna be pretty.
But don't you worry, okay?
Things will work out.
We started this thing together,
and that's how we'll finish it.
I promise.
[screeching]
[grunting]
[yelling]
- [yelling echoes]
- [snorting]
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[growling]
[screeching]
[gasps]
Uh, home is that way.
- I have to do something.
- Did you see those Huns?
They popped out of the snow!
Like daisies!
Are we in this together or not?
[chirping]
Well, let's go kick some Hunny buns!
Yee-haw!
[whooping]
[crowd cheering]
Make way for the heroes of China.
- Shang!
- Mulan?
The Huns are alive!
They're in the city!
You don't belong here, Mulan.
Go home.
I saw them in the mountains.
You have to believe me.
Why should I?
- [whinnying]
- Why else would I come back?
You said you'd trust Ping.
Why is Mulan any different?
Keep your eyes open.
I know they're here. Yah!
- [crowd cheering]
- Now where are you going?
To find someone
who will believe me.
My children,
heaven smiles down
upon the Middle Kingdom.
China will sleep safely tonight
thanks to our brave warriors.
[crowd cheering]
- Sir, the emperor's in danger.
- [harrumphs]
But the Huns are here.
- Please, you have to help.
- [harrumphs]
No one will listen.
Huh? I'm sorry.
Did you say something?
- Mushu.
- You're a girl again, remember?
Your Majesty,
I present to you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
I know what this means to you,
Captain Li.
Your father would have been very proud.
[screeching]
[gasping]
- [people screaming]
- [gasping]
[screeching]
[growling]
- No!
- Come on!
[cackling]
[groaning]
They'll never reach the emperor in time.
[battering continues]
[whistling] Hey, guys!
I've got an idea.
# Be a man
# We must be swift as a coursing river
# With all the force of a great typhoon
# Be a man
# With all the strength of a raging fire
# Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon #
[people exclaiming, gasping]
Boo.
Guard the door.
Your walls and armies have fallen,
and now it's your turn.
Bow to me.
Okay. Any questions?
[Yao] Does this dress make me look fat?
- [slap]
- Ow!
- [girlish giggling]
- Who's there?
[giggling]
- Concubines.
- Ugly concubines.
Oh, he's so cute!
Ohh...
[screeching]
[squawking]
Now, that's what I call
Mongolian barbecue.
[chuckling]
Shang, go!
I tire of your arrogance, old man.
Bow to me!
No matter how the wind howls,
the mountain cannot bow to it.
Then you will kneel in pieces!
Chien-Po, get the emperor!
Sorry, Your Majesty.
[grunting]
No!
Come on!
[hissing]
[grunting]
[cheering]
No.
[growling]
You!
You took away my victory!
[Mulan] No!
I did.
The soldier from the mountains.
[yelling]
- [squawking]
- [Mushu] So what's the plan?
- Um...
- You don't have a plan?
Hey, I'm making this up as I... go.
- Mushu!
- Way ahead of you, sister.
Come on, Cri-Kee.
[gasping]
[screaming]
- Citizens, I need firepower.
- [gasping] Who are you?
Your worst nightmare!
- On the roof!
- Look!
[gasping]
It looks like you're out of ideas.
Not quite.
Ready, Mushu?
I am ready, baby!
Light me.
[growling]
Huh? [gasps]
[screams]
Get off the roof, get off the roof,
get off the roof.
[grunting]
[laughing]
- You are a lucky bug.
- [squeaking]
[crowd cheering]
That was a deliberate attempt
on my life!
Where is she?
Now she's done it.
What a mess!
Stand aside!
That creature's not worth protecting.
- She's a hero.
- 'Tis a woman.
- She'll never be worth anything.
- Listen, you pompous...
That is enough.
Your Majesty, I can explain.
I've heard a great deal about you,
Fa Mulan.
You stole your father's armor,
ran away from home,
impersonated a soldier,
deceived your commanding officer,
dishonored the Chinese army,
destroyed my palace...
and...
you have saved us all.
Ah! Ooh!
[Mushu sniffles]
My little baby is all grown up
and... and savin' China.
You have a tissue?
- Chi Fu.
- Your Excellency?
See to it that this woman
is made a member of my council.
Member... what?
[stammering] But...
There are no council positions open,
Your Majesty.
Very well.
You can have his job.
What? I... Oh.
With all due respect,
Your Excellency,
I think I've been away
from home long enough.
Then... take this,
so your family will know
what you have done for me.
And this,
so the world will know
what you have done for China.
[emperor chuckles]
Is she allowed to do that?
[crying]
Um... you...
You fight good.
Oh. Thank you.
[groans]
Khan, let's go home.
[crowd cheers]
[clears throat]
The flower that blooms in adversity
is the most rare and beautiful of all.
Sir?
You don't meet a girl
like that every dynasty.
Mulan!
Father, I brought you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
And the crest of the emperor.
They're gifts,
to honor the Fa family.
The greatest gift and honor
is having you for a daughter.
I've missed you so.
I've missed you, too, Baba.
- [sighs]
- Great. She brings a sword.
If you ask me, she should've
brought home a man.
Excuse me.
Does Fa Mulan live here?
Thank you.
Whoo! Sign me up for the next war!
Honorable Fa Zhou, I...
Mulan!
Uh... you forgot your helmet.
W-well, actually,
it's your helmet, isn't it?
I mean...
Would you like to stay for dinner?
[Grandmother] Would you
like to stay forever?
Dinner would be great.
Come on.
Who did a good job?
Come on. Tell me.
Oh, all right!
You can be a guardian again.
Aah-ha!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Take it, Cri-Kee!
[whooping]
You know, she gets it
from my side of the family.
[Mushu]
Call out for egg rolls!
- [yelping]
- Guardians.
- Oh.
- Thanks, Mushu.
[barking]
- [clucking]
- [Great Ancestor] Mushu!