Mr. Lombardo, what's up?
Did you see those eyes?
Fuck off!
I appreciate you guys coming down.
All I'm going to miss is . . .
Settle down.
We've come to the halfway point
of our senior seminars.
- Beats study hall, doesn't it?
- No!
- That you, Jimmy?
- In study hall I can meditate.
- He means masturbate.
- I'm sure you know all about that.
It wasn't me, man !
We've all heard the terms
"date rape", "sexual harassment".
We've discussed
some of these issues here.
Our guests today come from
the BlLue Bay Police Department.
Detectives Duquette and Perez
will give us a fresh perspective -
- and address your questions.
Let's give them a warm welcome.
I'm out of here.
This prick can kiss my ass.
As I was saying . . . We'll start with
a question. What is a sex crime?
Not getting any.
Blue Bay, fight, fight!
Buccaneers, win tonight!
Steady.
Steady the bow, Jimmy.
That's good.
Drop the main. All right, de-rig,
and I'll see you all Monday.
The Buccaneers are number one,
and don't you forget it.
- Good work, guys. See you Monday.
- See you, Mr. Lombardo.
All right!
I could definitely party on that.
That's a stinkpot, Jimmy.
A real boatman gets one of those.
Now . . . that's a real boat.
Thank you for getting me into this
class. My old man wouldn't pay.
You're working for it.
And learning about boats.
I put myself through college
working boats.
Can I play too?
Or is it just for boys?
So, who's washing your jeep this
weekend? The senior car wash !
- That's a waste of time.
- Not at all.
- How about if Nicole and I do it?
- Tell you what . . .
I'm going to the Glades, Saturday.
On Sunday, you wash the mud off.
Deal.
My mom should give me a ride today,
but she's not here.
So I was wondering
if you could give me one?
You wouldn't want me to walk?
Something bad might happen.
- You need a lift, Jimbo?
- Yes, but I got my bike.
Hey, no problem.
Try it.
Suzie, you need a lift?
We've got room.
Jesus! Where did she get the shoes?
"Whores-for-less?"
Try it again.
Nice to see you kids getting along.
- Don't forget Sunday.
- I won't.
- Is that Sam Lombardo?
- Hi, Mom !
- Sam ! Hi.
- Hi, Sandra.
- Why don't you come in for a drink?
- Sorry, Sandra, I've got to run.
- Hi, Mr. Lombardo.
- Hi, girls.
- Look, he forgot. I knew it.
- No, I didn't. Check out my jeep.
Nice and dirty.
But wait until the other car leaves.
You mean
the Mercedes isn't yours, too?
My Benz is blue.
You know that, Nicole.
- Sam, I'm leaving.
- Where's your hose, Mr. Lombardo?
The hose, Kelly,
is in front of the jeep.
Kelly Van Ryan's
going to wash your jeep?
Come on, Barbara.
It's for a good cause.
- Sam the Philanthropist!
- Hard work never hurt anyone.
Have fun at the club.
Looks brand new.
Aren't you forgetting something?
- Your coupon. We got to have it.
- Yeah, that thing.
- Can't we just . . .
- Rules are rules, Mr. Lombardo.
- Okay, let me look for it . . .
- Mr. Lombardo? We're kind of late.
Nicole can go ahead. You can
give me a ride when you find it.
Just give me a minute.
- Go!
- Are you sure?
Frankie! Oh God !
Goddamn it!
This is Blue Bay High School. Your
son or daughter was absent today.
What?
Come on !
- That's a hell of a fish, Art.
- It's a barracuda.
If you weren't chasing booty at the
club you could have caught one, too.
- You're not going to eat it?
- Why not?
- They're poisonous. It'll kill you.
- Like most of the girls you date.
Sandra Van Ryan, for Sam.
- What's up?
- Kelly skipped school today.
- Have you heard anything?
- Not a word.
Never mind, I found her.
Pull !
Listen, Sam . . .
It was really good seeing you.
Look Sandra,
I'm real busy right now, so . . .
I haven't found anyone who can
handle my boat the way you can.
- You're fucking Barbara. So what?
- Maybe I'm a one-woman man now.
Poor Sam.
You really think a Blue Bay woman
will marry you?
- Are you finished?
- Grab a clue, Honey.
You're a hired hand, a good lay,
that's all. Enjoy it while it lasts.
Bye, Sandra.
Pull !
You seem to find guns therapeutic.
Maybe I ought to try it.
Let me guess. Some boy didn't call,
and screwed up your weekend?
So you're taking the day off.
- Which of your deckhands is that?
- Whichever one I want.
Okay, Kelly.
What's the matter?
What is it?
- I miss Dad.
- Jesus.
- I miss him too. Sometimes.
- No, you don't.
He didn't have to kill himself,
Kelly.
Kelly . . .
I . . .
I don't know why he did it.
I really don't.
Can I . . .
Can I get you anything?
Do you want a valium?
- I was raped.
- What, Honey? I can't hear you.
- I said I was raped.
- What?
I was raped . . .
. . . by Sam Lombardo.
Sam Lombardo?
- My daughter does not get raped !
- And you say Sam Lombardo did it?
That son of a bitch must be insane
to think he can do this to me.
We understand your feelings,
but we need some time with Kelly, -
- to take her statement alone.
- Are you all right with this, Baby?
- Yeah.
Would you like to take a break
for a minute?
I just want to get it over with.
We'd like to video your statement.
These are serious charges.
We must know everything
that happened. Are you ready?
He started rubbing my shoulders.
I let him.
I mean, he's a nice guy.
The next thing...
... his hand was in my shorts.
You know, from behind.
His fingers ...
- His fingers...
- Take your time.
They were in me.
Both places, you know?
- Did he put himself inside you?
- Yes.
I said "stop", I screamed. I mean,
that's how it sounded in my head.
- He hurt me.
- Did you try to fight him?
- He pinned my wrists behind me.
- Then what?
He kept saying,
"Let it happen, let it happen."
- And then he just stopped.
- You mean, he withdrew?
- It's really hard to remember.
- Try, Kelly.
I know one thing he said.
He said:
"Don't worry, I didn't come."
I can't forget that.
He said, "No little girl can ever
make me come."
"No little girl can ever
make me come." Jesus!
Too bad, we might have had
some physical evidence.
Maybe there's no physical evidence
because nothing happened.
I think she's acting.
She set it up to be alone with him,
so he could come on. But he didn't.
Maybe, maybe not. He should
never have had her out there.
Gloria, he's done half
the women in Blue Bay.
That doesn't make him a rapist.
She could take a polygraph.
And the Pope could take a piss test.
This is Blue Bay.
Ask a Van Ryan for that
and Tom Baxter will cut you off.
You're afraid of Tom Baxter now?
Or Sandra Van Ryan?
Talk to his neighbours,
his co-workers and Kelly's friends.
- This will destroy Lombardo.
- You heard her. The guy's dirty.
Bring me a case.
Good work, Jimbo.
I'll see you Monday.
That's what's left
of my sailing class.
- Talk to me, Artie.
- Kelly is accusing you of rape.
Jimmy told me.
Apparently I'm the last one to know.
Sandra Van Ryan has been ringing
every member of the school board.
- She's pushing for suspension.
- And they won't hear my side?
This is insane.
I'm innocent, goddammit!
- You've got to believe that.
- Just hang in there.
- When they clear you . . .
- You never get clear of this.
It stays with you.
It follows you around forever.
You're going to need some help, Sam.
An attorney.
And what attorney in South Florida
will go up against the Van Ryans?
Hi. I'm here to see Ken Bowden.
- Do you have an appointment?
- Yeah, Sam Lombardo.
- Mr. Bowden, your 10:30's here.
- Show him in, please.
What brings you here?
Until yesterday, I was a guidance
counsellor at Blue Bay High School.
- A student is accusing me of rape.
- Male or female?
The student is Kelly Van Ryan.
Which means, I'm fucked.
- Why don't you tell me about it?
- Shit, where do I begin?
Your relationship with the girl.
She's a student, I was her
guidance counsellor, that's all.
Then you've got nothing
to worry about.
- What happened to your neck?
- This? I don't have to wear it.
There was an insurance guy
around earlier.
Let me tell you how I charge.
Georgie!
How's the wind today?
Mr. Lombardo, I'm afraid
I can't park for you today.
I'm meeting Barbara for lunch.
- Can you park this, Georgie?
- Right away, Mr. Baxter.
You're finished here, Lombardo.
Take a hike.
Barbara, what's going on?
Maybe you didn't hear me, Lombardo.
You're finished in Blue Bay.
If you see my daughter again,
you'll be finished, period.
- Get the fuck out of here.
- Mr. Lombardo, please . . .
It's all right, George.
Sam, Honey!
Haven't seen you in a while.
- Welcome back.
- Rum and coke.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
That's too bad, motherfucker.
Sam?
Lombardo?
Whoa, man !
It's me.
Sorry, man.
Things have been a bit weird here.
I can see that.
Come on in.
You're sure this Frankie Condo
is the guy that did it?
It was him. He was driving
Sandra's Range Rover.
Tell the cops, and we can go
after Sandra Van Ryan.
- Forget it.
- The lady has deep pockets.
I know how deep her pockets are.
I thought I might save my house . . .
But guess who's on the
board of directors at the bank?
I don't need more trouble from her.
Do you think I can stop her?
With the shit I got on Kelly?
Yeah.
A year ago, when her old man shot
himself, Kelly lost it, ran away.
They found her in a fleabag motel.
Coked out of her gourd.
Meanwhile you, Sam, are voted
"Educator of the Year" or some crap.
If they put the two of you in front
of a jury, they'll look stupid.
They haven't taken your statement,
because they're looking for dirt.
And they're not going to find it.
Right?
Ken, I don't fuck my students.
He's just showing off for you now.
Good evening, Ruby.
I see you've still got Walter.
I was hoping
something had eaten him by now.
- Can I help you with something?
- Suzie called us. Where is she?
You know the way.
You won't shoot her, will you?
I don't believe she's armed.
It took you long enough !
What if I was being strangled?
Or fucked in the ass, even?
- I mean, you do sex crimes, right?
- My partner, Detective Perez.
Céline. He had a good line
on what cheap fucks people are.
Suzie, you called us, remember?
- Did they arrest Mr. Lombardo?
- No.
- Will they?
- I don't know.
That bothers you?
I want to go outside.
- When did he give you this ride?
- About a year ago.
- Was anyone else at your trailer?
- Nope.
- So you were alone?
- Yeah.
- Did he come in with you?
- I guess.
- Did he or didn't he?
- Okay. Yeah, he did.
Then what? Did he touch you?
Did you flirt with him?
Suzie, I know you feel bad.
Just tell us the truth.
I didn't say a thing to him.
He put his arm around me
and told me I was pretty.
- I could be really pretty, he said.
- Did you ask him to stop?
Shit! What difference does it make?
No one will believe me anyway.
- Did Sam Lombardo rape you?
- He did. He pushed me to the floor.
- Now, are we done?
- Almost, Suzie, almost.
Could you fight him off?
No. He stopped by himself.
Is that it?
Leave me alone.
- Don't touch me!
- All right, take it easy.
He stopped. And that was it?
He just left?
- Yeah. He did say one thing first.
- What was that?
He said, "No little bitch
can ever make me come."
Open the gate.
Look at this girlfriend.
- Counsellor, how about a smoke?
- Hello, Jinxy.
It's a bad news/good news situation.
No bail, but you get a real attorney
instead of a public defender.
I'm telling you, Ken.
I'm innocent.
You are preaching to the choir.
You're not alone.
So you're the new chicken-licker?
- Any comment on the case?
- What are your feelings?
Mr. Lombardo
will get what he deserves.
- Feeling confident?
- Yes.
The Lombardo case
has galvanised this upscale town.
Here's Sandra Van Ryan, millionaire
heiress from the Blue Bay elite.
And the girl from skid row.
The jury must choose between these
girls' stories, and Sam Lombardo's.
Live at the courthouse,
Nancy Duerr, Eyewitness News.
State of Florida vs. Sam Lombardo.
Sylvia B. Waxman presiding.
All rise.
Please be seated.
Would you like more time, Kelly?
I know this is hard, Kelly,
but I have one more question.
And even though we've been over it,
I want us all to be clear about it.
Kelly, when you saw Mr. Lombardo
intended to have sex with you . . .
. . . what were your exact words?
What did you say?
I told him, "No."
I said,
"Stop, Mr. Lombardo, please."
I screamed for him to stop.
You screamed, for him . . .
. . . to stop.
And did he?
No.
He raped me
on the floor of his shitty house.
Thank you.
On day two, the second alleged
young victim has taken the stand.
Yesterday, Kelly Van Ryan
gave an emotional account -
- and was not swayed
by cross-examination.
We'll be back later with an update.
Good morning.
Miss, when you were picked up
for shoplifting in freshman year -
- you were allowed to make one call.
You called Mr. Lombardo, correct?
Miss Toller?
And when you were expelled
for vandalism . . .
I broke a fucking window.
It wasn't my fault.
Wait until you are asked, and
don't use profanity in this court.
It was Mr. Lombardo who went with
you, in lieu of a parent conference?
Yes.
It seems to me
that Mr. Lombardo was your friend.
He was.
But all that changed, when, -
- according to your testimony,
Mr. Lombardo raped you -
- on April 23rd of last year.
Is that right?
But in May, when you were
arrested for possessing narcotics, -
- and again allowed a phone call,
you called Mr. Lombardo.
- So what?
- "So what?"
"So what?"
Oops, Suzie.
One month after you say this man
raped you, you go to him for help?
It sounds like
you still considered him a friend.
- I needed help.
- I'm sure you did. But he was gone.
And you spent six months
in a correctional facility.
Did that make you mad, Suzie? That
Sam was gone? That he wasn't there?
- Is that why you're saying this?
- I said it, because it happened.
Are you going to sit there and swear
Sam Lombardo raped you?
- I said he did.
- Let me ask you a question.
Did you enjoy
being a guest of the state?
I promise you that if you're lying,
as I believe you are, -
- you'll visit that facility again.
Which is why I'll ask you again,
under oath:
Suzie,
did Samuel Lombardo rape you?
Miss Toller,
you must answer the question.
- Miss Toller . . .
- Goddamn it!
- This was not my idea.
- Objection ! Defence is badgering.
The court will hear
what Miss Toller has to say.
Miss Toller?
Sam Lombardo didn't rape me.
He didn't rape Kelly, either.
This is ridiculous!
The witness has been threatened . . .
This court intends to hear
Miss Toller's story.
Miss Toller?
I just wanted to hurt Mr. Lombardo.
I mean, he was my friend, at first.
When I got busted he didn't help me.
I went to that hell-hole.
- First favourite, then who cares?
- Make her stop.
When Kelly said we should do this,
I thought, "Cool."
Big shots who screwed me over,
like Duquette, will get screwed.
- I'm sorry, I have to object.
- Your honour, may I be heard?
Mr. Baxter,
you are not trying this case.
Go sit down.
Kelly is pissed at Mr. Lombardo,
too. She's in love with him.
He was her fantasy, but then she
found out he was doing her mom.
Fuck!
You skanky bitch !
Get your fucking hands off me.
I'll have you fired !
Just get the hell away from me.
- Jesus, man, cut loose!
- I'm just wondering where to stay.
I've lost my house.
I'm waking up from a nightmare.
Get over it. We've got an airtight
lawsuit against Sandra Van Ryan.
- Just like that?
- These people ruined your life.
I told you they would go too far.
They went overboard !
They'll settle. Believe me,
they'll be begging to settle.
Here we go.
Wait up! Come on, girl.
Sam Lombardo was dismissed when
a victim reversed her testimony.
Excuse me, over here!
Can anybody read?
Nail that shyster's balls
to the nearest wall.
That was possible, until Miss Not
So Bright started throwing things.
Are you just going to let them
get away with this . . . shit?
On the word
of a white trash bitch.
I don't think you get it, Sandy.
Your princess committed perjury.
- I'll try to keep her out of jail.
- What are we going to do?
- Here's your coffee, Sam.
- Thank you.
Ken . . .
Sorry I'm late.
- Hold my calls, Lenore.
- Okay, Mr. Bowden.
Thank you, Sandra.
I'll be seeing you.
Okay?
Nice to see you, Tom.
Come by, we'll have lunch.
See you at the club.
See you at the club . . .
Tom, what did you shoot today?
Hey, my man.
This is for you.
You did good, Ken.
Thanks.
I know you wish it never happened.
But it did.
Take the money and enjoy yourself.
Find a happy place.
Lenore, see Mr. Lombardo out.
- Goodbye, Sam.
- Goodbye, Lenore.
Take care of my lizards.
- Hello, Kelly.
- Drop dead !
Know how my mom's paying you?
She's breaking my trust.
I can't touch it until she's dead,
and she's breaking it.
- I'm sorry.
- Why don't you spend it with her?
I hate you !
I hate you, you son of a bitch.
You see? I couldn't come back,
even if I wanted to.
Goddamn maid.
So you got my mom's money.
How much?
- How much?
- You know how much.
Your turn to pay.
It worked !
We screwed the bitch.
It worked just like you said.
- What's wrong?
- What's wrong, is you coming here.
Are you fucking crazy?
Yeah, I'm crazy.
Ask my mom.
So, how much is 8.5 million
divided by three?
Great, big joke.
You think this is fucking over?
It's a long way from over.
I'm serious.
After tonight, the three of us are
not to be seen together again.
After tonight?
Well . . . we're here, aren't we?
Maybe one celebration is okay.
If we're in agreement
that from here on out . . .
. . . you do exactly as I say.
Guidance counsellors get to find out
lots of interesting things.
Now, I want you two to kiss.
Come on. Never let the sun
go down on an argument.
I told you they would
make us look stupid.
You're right.
They did make us look stupid.
What you're wrong about, is why.
Hear me out.
Lombardo was seeing
Sandra Van Ryan.
Why not tell us?
It gave Kelly a hell of a motive.
Maybe they were saving it
for the trial.
You're Lombardo, you don't want
to sit in jail for three months . . .
- Unless . . .
- Unless what?
Unless you're setting
Sandra Van Ryan up.
Lombardo was eyeball-deep in debt.
A rich girl like Barbara Baxter
is expensive.
- But why would Kelly have to steal?
- Her money's in trust.
This guy wanted to marry money.
When that didn't work, he used
the girls to set up Sandra Van Ryan.
They chumped us.
They chumped us,
right from the start.
- Nice stroke.
- Why are you here?
- Curiosity, I guess.
- About how to improve your stroke?
About how it'll work out
for you and Sam and Suzie.
- Excuse me?
- Will you go down to the Caribbean?
- Threesomes rarely work out.
- You're out of your mind.
It's hard for three people
to keep a secret.
Especially when two of them
are in love.
You and Sam don't really want that
little pill-head around, do you?
Did Sam sell you
on the idea of whacking Suzie?
- That's murder, kid.
- Police, God ! Get a life.
You're good, you know that?
But don't think that little freak
Suzie's going to hold up.
Hello, Suzie.
Watch it with that shit,
or you'll get busted again.
Yeah, or wind up dead.
You know, I don't think I told you
how sorry I was about your friend.
What was his name?
Come on, help me out.
You know his name.
- Davy.
- I was really sorry about that.
- That is cop bullshit.
- What was that?
I don't have to listen to this.
I have friends now . . .
This is Ray, Suzie. You don't
have shit, you never will have shit.
Take a look at this.
Go ahead, it won't bite you.
Take it.
Your friend Sam
deposited the cheque.
He put the funds
into an offshore numbered account.
Cops don't know whose name's on it.
Think it's yours?
He also put a down payment on
an island property and a sailboat.
- Why are you telling me this stuff?
- Because I know what's going on.
Two's company, three's a crowd.
You don't really think Kelly and Sam
will share the money with you?
Leave me alone.
You know, I'd want a clear head now,
if I were you, -
- so I could keep a real close eye
on my new friends.
I'd hate to see you
come to a bad end . . .
. . . like Davy.
Shit!
This is Sam Lombardo.
Leave a brief message.
You called Sam?
What's the matter with you?
- There's no one to trust.
- You can trust me.
Is Suzie there?
Christ, I was afraid of that.
She left this insane message on my
machine. She's going to blow it.
- Calm the bitch down.
- Why can't you come?
Sam, I miss you so much.
I miss you too. But I can't, right
now. We've got to stick to the plan.
- If she can't get a grip ...
- Then what?
You know what. I'll handle it.
But I need you
to be there for me tonight.
Good. That's my girl.
You're the strong one.
Get Suzie.
I want you both to hear this.
Look, we've got to stay calm.
All of us.
Since the settlement, people think
I'm rich, so I act like a rich guy.
Don't let this cop
try and fuck with you.
- That's easy for you to say . . .
- Suzie, don't fall apart.
The only people
who can fuck this up, is us.
You are going to fuck me over,
aren't you?
- For Christ's sake . . .
- You are!
Are you retarded or
just brain-dead from swamp fumes?
That's what I am to you, isn't it?
Swamp trash, just like my mom.
Don't!
You stupid cunt.
You are scared, aren't you?
Jesus Christ!
- Are you crazy?
- "Sam". That was Lombardo.
- You saw the girls . . .
- The tape is unintelligible.
This shows you on the Van Ryan
property, shooting a porn flick!
They threw things at each other
in court. They were acting !
They were all acting ! They're taking
$8 million from Sandra Van Ryan.
She tried to destroy the man's life.
She thought he'd raped her daughter.
She bought the same story.
Listen, both of you.
There is no fucking case.
Sandra Van Ryan will be suing us
for invasion of privacy, so drop it.
- Am I getting through on this?
- You think it's just about money?
About us looking stupid? Question
him. He's a stone-cold psychopath.
- The girls will wind up dead.
- Give this idiot the Kennedy case.
- I understand . . .
- Next time, I'm going to sue you.
You're lucky I didn't sue you
last time. Am I free to go?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Cocksucker!
- What was that?
- You heard me, motherfucker.
- You want to say that to my face?
What are you looking at?
- I guess I kind of lost it.
- You could say that.
Have you ever seen something
coming, and done nothing to stop it?
- We all have.
- Something bad. It happened . . .
. . . and you didn't do anything.
I did that once.
I don't want to do it again.
I thought we were going to a movie.
I think we just need to get wasted.
Come on.
I want to live at the beach
some day.
Shit! I left the keys.
I'll get them.
- Kelly?
- Suzie . . .
It's me.
I was worried about you. I thought
we'd get together one last time.
- Are you mad at me?
- No, no.
I should have said more
about the part you should play.
We'll go through it all
again tonight.
This is a celebration,
not a suicide pact.
We're going to chill out,
just relax.
Have a little champagne,
watch the stars.
Kelly, have you got a blanket
in the back of your mom's Rover?
Why don't you be an angel
and run over and get it?
Good girl.
Let me tell you about this boat
I picked out for us.
You okay?
My mom would kill me
if she knew I took the Rover.
- She didn't come home last night?
- But her clothes are still here.
Walter, if you get sick,
it'll serve you right.
He found some teeth in a trailer.
He says they'll fit.
Suzie hasn't been at school
since the trial.
Now they're saying
she can't graduate.
Kelly Van Ryan got her
into this whole mess.
We'll look into it for you, Ruby.
If we find something, you'll know.
Come on.
- This is how it begins.
- We don't know anything yet.
- Put a call out on Suzie's car.
- Going somewhere?
- You got a date?
- Just check the car out, please.
It's over here, by that old boat.
- You and Suzie came out here?
- Yeah, sometimes.
A lot of the kids hang out here.
Did something bad happen to Suzie?
Did Lombardo ever come out here?
- I say something funny?
- Just the idea that he would . . .
I heard he was pretty tight
with the kids.
- You and he were pals, right?
- He got me on the sailing team.
To work my way through college,
like him.
He got an athletic scholarship.
Boats had nothing to do with it.
I'm going to be here a while, kid.
Why don't you catch the bus?
Jimmy . . .
People aren't always
what they appear. Don't forget.
They did it here. The body must be
in the swamp. But he made a mistake.
- The car was at the bus terminal.
- Couldn't Sam have put it there?
Hold on a second.
Have the car dusted for prints.
If Suzie was murdered, it was
probably Kelly. She started it all.
- How long will it take?
- We can get blood type now.
You want DNA, it could take weeks.
Poor dumb Suzie. Never had
a chance. And Kelly's next!
You get off this. Right now.
Don't even let me hear
about you bothering Lombardo.
David ! You get an ID,
you call me.
- Will you do me one favour?
- Ray, you heard him.
He told me to stay away, not you.
What if I'm right?
You got to help me out on this,
partner.
- And if the teeth aren't Suzie's?
- If I'm wrong, I'll give this up.
- Hello.
- I want to see you.
I'm in the guesthouse.
Sam, I'm really nervous.
Kelly, relax.
Take one of your mom's valiums.
In another week it's over.
We're rich.
What if they find out? They'd
put you in the electric chair.
Stay in the guesthouse.
Skip the graduation parties.
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
Be a good girl, stay where you are.
Peeping in people's windows . . .
isn't that illegal?
- Suzie Toller's missing.
- Since when?
She didn't come home last night.
We found her car.
- Ray thinks she was murdered.
- I don't know what to tell you.
- Tell me where you were last night.
- I don't have to, do I?
Come here.
I want to show you something.
Looks like goodbye . . .
Kelly's file. Read it. You'll find
an angry, sexually confused girl -
- who threatened to kill two people.
- What two people?
- One was her mother.
The other one was . . .
a female classmate -
- that she may have been
sexually involved with.
- Suzie?
- You've got the file. Read it.
It'll give you
a new perspective on things.
Why didn't you tell us about this
before the trial?
Because then I had principles
that meant a lot to me.
Now . . .
. . . I don't care.
I should probably go now.
Unless you plan
to hold me for something.
What's happening?
Where's Lombardo?
- He's gone.
- The blood type matches Suzie's.
There's more to this story
than you know.
If Suzie is dead, I think
Hunter may be right about Kelly.
Ray? Shit.
- Who is it?
- Detective Duquette. Open the gate.
- Hello, Kelly.
- What are you doing here?
Where's Kelly?
I just looked away for a second.
Just a split second.
And just like that, bingo,
she put a knee in my groin.
I didn't go down,
but it slowed me down just enough.
I couldn't get to her.
She turned on me with the gun.
Fired one shot.
I took the hit in the shoulder.
I had no choice.
I had to return fire.
Two rounds, I think. In the chest.
I went there to protect her.
Duquette, in Military Intelligence
we had a saying:
"Once is chance, twice coincidence,
three times is enemy action."
This is twice for you, Duquette.
There will be no third time.
That this was a "good" shooting,
is irrelevant.
You ignored your superiors.
Consequently, two women are dead.
You are terminated
without pension or benefits.
Duquette found Susan Toller's teeth
and blood at Stoner Beach.
Her blood was also
in the Van Ryan car.
This leads us to conclude that she
was murdered by Kelly Van Ryan.
She didn't.
Mr. Duquette . . .
This investigation is concluded.
You're dismissed.
Thank you.
Howdy, partner.
I wasn't expecting you
until tomorrow.
- Nice girlfriend !
- Why wasn't Kelly just framed?
- The bitch shot me.
- Can't cops disarm people?
Shoot them in the leg?
Did you get squeamish after
you killed Suzie with a wine bottle?
Kelly wasn't supposed to die.
It was perfect. They're convinced
Kelly whacked Suzie.
- I couldn't talk them out of it.
- I don't like surprises.
"Every cloud has a silver lining."
Now there's no loose ends. After
tomorrow, you'll never see me again.
About tomorrow . . .
I talked to the bank. They say it'll
take two days to make the transfer.
- Bullshit.
- Oh yeah? Call them yourself.
What's your hurry? Kick back for a
day or two. We'll take out the boat.
I've just had it outfitted.
I could use a deckhand.
Here's to large bank accounts.
Lighten up, partner.
You're a rich man.
To large accounts,
and no loose ends.
And no loose ends.
See that winch? Take a couple
of turns on it. She's luffing.
- You mean that thing?
- It's a winch to tighten the sails.
- Start cranking.
- This is supposed to be a vacation.
Get yourself a nice power boat.
- I'll make a sailor out of you yet.
- Or get me drowned.
- It's stuck.
- Put a little elbow grease in it.
- It's stuck, I'm telling you.
- The jenny must be caught.
Go starboard and unhook it.
I don't understand a word
you just said.
Follow this line, and see
if you can see what it's snagged on.
You're killing me.
- You mean this thing?
- That's it. See anything?
Look a little lower.
That's it.
Guess I forgot to tell you, Ray.
"One hand for the boat,
the other for yourself."
- What happened?
- Nice try, motherfucker!
You're . . . you're dead !
No, I'm not.
- Sam, for Christ's sake.
- Sorry, partner.
You shouldn't have killed Kelly.
Or that kid out in the Glades.
- What was his name?
- Davy.
That's my son, Walter. He's done
this a long time. Don't be afraid.
Thank you for coming
down to the Glades.
Did you come to watch Walter,
or is this an official visit?
- No, it's my day off.
- I thought you looked different.
- I was hoping you would talk to me.
- About Suzie?
Actually I was wondering if you
would talk to me about Ray Duquette.
He used to come here. He had
a thing going with one of the girls.
"Girls" . . . over at the Glades.
Got sort of hung up on her,
from what I hear.
- Does she still work there?
- Not after that night.
All I know is, next morning
she was gone and a boy was dead.
A Seminole kid named Davy.
He had a crush on Ray's whore.
He caught Ray slapping her around,
and tried to stop it.
So Ray killed him.
Suzie saw it, so he busted her.
Sent her up,
just to prove that he could.
That's all
there is to say about him.
To Ray.
We won, Sam. It's over.
Talk about paranoid !
Take a look around us, Sam.
You'll have to teach me to drive
this, before I can get rid of you.
Okay, Toller.
I want to trim the sail.
- Take hold of that winch.
- No, I want to drive.
You don't drive it, you sail it.
Now get on that winch.
I just want to cruise for a while.
That's one of the first things
I noticed about you.
You like to cruise.
- Suzie . . .
- Take college, for instance.
I bet you only took classes
if the finals were multiple choice.
You bought no books.
You'd borrow a girl's -
- and then you'd have to fuck her.
Is that how it went?
Yeah.
Well, I've got a good pop quiz
for you. Multiple choice, of course.
Before sailing away, Medea killed
King Creon and the princess with . .?
A rock?
A spear gun? Or . . .
- A little poison?
- Poison !
Good guess!
Nice truck.
Selling your boat?
This was Suzie's boat.
Guess she won't be needing it now.
Funny, I wouldn't have guessed
Suzie was a sailor.
The old lady had her tested once.
Her IQ was way up, around 200.
That girl could do anything
she put her mind to.
You know, when I got busted
I called you about 100 times.
I really believed that stuff
about you being my friend.
Was I naive!
What came out better?
That straw up Kelly's nose,
or that dog collar around your neck?
What do you think, Mr. Lombardo?
He seems to like the same places
you do. Funny you never met.
Real funny. You're wrong about this,
and I could get busted right here.
Trust me, the guy's dirty, he'll
love it. Especially killing me.
Get out of here,
make a new friend.
What are you drinking?
Got the pressure too tight.
You'll crush the fucking evidence.
For Christ's sake.
- Hello, Kelly.
- What are you doing here?
May I ask you a question,
Miss Toller?
Did you enjoy being
a guest of the state?
Boy, I hope I never make you mad.
The cash is just
walking-around money.
The cheque is the account, minus
a million for Ruby and Walter -
- plus my usual fee.
Case closed.
Suzie . . .
Be good.