Good piece of land.
It was.
Still is.
Travis is calling you.
Do I know you?
Well, ought to.
How did you lose that arm there, boy?
Woke up in Chickamauga
one morning without it.
Somebody deal you a losing hand there ...
... Buckaboo?
Jack?
Now tell me, you found yourself
a one-titty woman ...
... or you just take that one hand there
and whip it back and forth?
Oh, my Lord.
Get on down here!
The hero has returned!
Good to see you, Jack.
Good to see you back!
- It's me, Brian Brown.
- You remember Brian.
You got whiskers now, boy!
Ever think you'd see him again?
Whoa there, boy. What's after you?
Your husband.
Who? What did you say?
- He's coming, ma'am.
- Who?
Mr. Sommersby.
Get in the house!
Come on! Come on!
Look at you!
You old man, now look!
By God, there's another good man
the damn Yankees didn't get!
Come on over here and say hello to Will.
Look here who I got here.
Jack Sommersby.
They sent him back to me like that
from Vicksburg.
Will's a hero.
Ain't that right, son?
Well, well, well.
Welcome home, Jack.
We thank the Lord you're back.
Thank you, sir.
Is Laurel all right?
She's going to be surprised now, ain't she?
Six years is a long time without any word.
Come on, where is he now?
Look at you!
You look like a sack of bones.
Kind of hard to get Esther dumplings
where I've been.
Oh, Lord, Mr. Jack.
You're home, you're home!
Everybody here is missing somebody.
Both Ezzel boys and their daddy got killed ...
... and everybody that ain't dead is leaving.
This town finished, Mr. Jack.
Ain't nothing left here but hard ground
and nobody to work it.
Go say hello to your daddy, son.
Go on now.
Hello, Robert.
I'd forgotten how beautiful you were.
Jethro!
Hey, boy!
I hear in old town, Clemmons' pig
will be swallowing a stick tonight!
I was down there in the weeds, kind of waiting ...
... for the damn smoke
to get blowed away.
And the next thing I know ...
Thank you, darling.
Next thing I know,
there's this big old rifle butt ...
... floating down out of the sky,
just kind of taking its time ...
... like I had all day to get away from it.
When I come to, I was on my way to prison in Elmira.
I heard that was the worst one.
I couldn't even remember my name at that point.
What did you do to your hand there, Jack?
A guard stomped on it.
Don't hold things too good now.
You can still hold
a straight flush?
And other things that are important.
What did you do in prison?
Starved, froze, like everybody else.
Evening, folks.
Better take some of this while you can.
I guess you don't remember me, sir.
Joseph.
Yes, I do remember!
My daddy paid $ 100 for you.
Yes, sir.
Why don't you come on in now?
No, thank you, sir.
We just come by here
to say welcome home.
Quit wasting time! Get yourself
over here. We got a present for you.
- What do you got?
- Panther piss.
- I ain't seen you pass water all night.
- Can't do it.
One sip, I'm staggering like a new calf.
You're still a rebel, ain't you?
Best not get too friendly
with the niggers.
We had to chase some off.
That one has been
living on your land.
Next thing you know,
they'll be moving into the big house.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
You ain't acting yourself, Jack.
What'd them goddamn Yankees
do to you, boy?
Hit me on my head.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Sit down.
I'm going to dance with my wife.
Good to see you.
Welcome back!
Grab a gal here and shake a leg.
I tend to hop a little bit better
than I shake now.
Dick made me a good foot, though.
Got everything but toes that wiggle.
Ain't got no toes ...
... to worry about stomping them.
Well, be careful you don't
catch a chill, Miss Laurel.
Y'all have a good time.
Shall we?
Good night now, Buckaboo.
You know where that handkerchief is
I brought home?
It was filthy.
I told her to burn it.
Damn!
Hate to lose that thing.
Carried that nearly six years.
Why?
The last thing you gave me
before I left.
What happened here?
Yankees.
They got the silver, the carpets and
mostly anything else they could carry.
I did save Granny's brooch, though ...
... by sitting on it,
in a manner of speaking.
That's where you were sleeping
before you left.
Good night.
I swore, if I ever made it home ...
... I'd shave this thing off.
Would you do it for me?
Are you sure?
Am I home?
All right.
That's the first thing
I remember about you.
Coming back that time from
wherever you'd been, looking all ...
... brown and bearded.
Looking more like some kind
of a wild animal than a man.
Is that what you wanted?
Something wild?
Maybe.
Maybe just something a little ...
... dangerous ...
... a little different.
A little rich?
Make $900 and lose 1,000,
you are not rich.
It was never the money.
Couldn't have been love ...
... could it?
It could have been.
If you'd been the least ...
... little bit ...
... kind.
What do you think?
I'm thinking ...
... who is this man
sitting in my kitchen?
Well, good night.
Good night.
I guess we have to get used
to each other again, don't we?
I guess so.
Well ...
Good night.
You're getting ahead of me again.
Not quite.
- So where is he?
- He wanted to see the farm.
Hope he doesn't see too much.
He's liable to keep on riding.
He wouldn't do that.
But I have heard stories of men ...
... who come home, and finding
their wives married again ...
... and realizing it wasn't
nobody's fault ...
- ...she'd fallen in love with ...
- Please! I'm sorry.
I know you're hurting, and I wish ...
... that I was not the cause of it.
But we weren't married yet.
He's my husband and he's come home now.
That's right.
But if he ever ...
... lays a hand to you again,
I'll have to break it.
Orin, please.
Jethro!
Jethro?
Lord ...
... take him to that better place ...
... where the sun always shines,
and he'll have bigger fields to run in.
What're you doing?
Not too damn much.
What are you doing?
Getting a little hoeing done.
Yeah, well, you can take a break.
Not going to be any cotton
here.
I put a little bit of work
in these fields.
You and about 40 more slaves,
maybe we'll get a crop in here.
You calling me a nigger?
Hell, Orin, I ain't ...
I know what you done around here ...
... and I appreciate it.
What I've done,
I haven't done for you.
She's made her choice.
She had no choice.
If it'd gone the other way,
if she wanted you ...
... I don't think I would've hung
around here, watched.
Not me.
But you never were one
to hang around, were you?
I told Orin I'd marry him next year
if you didn't come back.
He's put a lot of hard work in here,
and we owe him.
I want you to be nice to him.
You've got to try
and put yourself in his shoes.
Shoe?
Come on, now. It's hard for him
getting this close and all ...
He ever get this close to you?
I guess he did.
Did he kiss you?
He didn't?
Did you want him to?
I don't know.
Don't know?
Did he want to kiss you?
I guess he did.
Let me get the sugar.
All right. Why didn't he?
Because I never said that he could.
You say he couldn't?
Let me get this straight.
He wanted to ...
... but you didn't know, so ...
... he didn't ask and you didn't say.
So he didn't and you weren't.
But he's not here and I am,
and I want to.
So I'm going to go ask.
- Where're you going?
- To ask Orin if I can kiss my wife.
Stop it!
You got a very beautiful
smile there, Mrs. Sommersby.
Hope to see a whole lot more of it.
Well, you will.
Where'd you find that?
It was in the trunk.
You remember?
You sewed this the whole first month
we were married, didn't you?
When I tried it on, it was too small.
You threw it in there and said ...
... you'd never sew again.
I don't think you ever did.
How'd you remember that?
Well, I forgot a whole lot
of important things.
Other ones ...
... never leave my mind, never will.
- What're you doing?
- Come on, arms up.
Been in a trunk for nine years.
It needs some washing.
You remember making our son?
The night it happened?
You were drunk.
Well, I'm sorry.
Seems like after that, you never much
wanted me anymore.
Seems a whole lot different now.
You want to sleep in the other room?
Good.
What's wrong?
I just don't remember
how I was with you.
How to be.
You don't have to remember that.
Jack ...
Say it again.
Hey, boy!
Let's go to town, get shoes!
Do I have to?
No, you can stay here and help me
shovel out the chicken coop.
Where in the world are we going?
Mama don't let me drive.
I guess we got to mind Mama,
don't we?
Say, ''hah.''
Say it louder.
Don't say it to me, boy.
Say it to him.
Say it again.
Morning!
Move around there.
You're real good, boy!
Thank you, sir.
There's a lot of dead men's
footprints on this wall.
That's the one I'm looking for.
I'm truly glad you
didn't follow them, Jack.
You'll look just fine
once you get your lips back.
Let me have that foot.
There's something about whiskers
that makes a man's lips ...
... just shrink right on up.
I'll be damned!
Your foot shrunk!
Foot's two sizes smaller now.
That ain't mine.
You must've been drunk.
See? I wrote your name
right here at the bottom.
How do you suppose
that could have happened?
You know what I see?
I see the future. Right there.
Tobacco?!
You mean smoking it, or growing it?
You can't grow it this far north.
- Too cold!
- Yes, you can. Yes, you can.
It's called burley.
They want it and we can grow it.
You ever planted anything in the field
except your foot up somebody's backside?
I don't think I have, but I didn't shoot
my first man before I had to, either.
Now, you want to hear
what I have to say?
All right.
Here's what I'm offering.
I'll give you all a piece of my land,
each and every one of you.
I'll give you tools, fertilizer ...
... and you keep half of the crop
when it comes in.
I'll take my share
and pay off the mortgage against me.
When the title clears ...
... you can buy that land you worked,
for a fair price.
Are you talking about
selling your own land?
Your daddy would've died first.
He did, didn't he?
How long you been sharecropping?
Ten years?
15 years! You ever get a chance to
buy that land you've been working?
Hell, no!
Hell, no. This is it.
This is your chance, boy.
Take it!
What about y'all? You want in?
I'm not helping niggers.
You're saying that those
who work the land ...
I can't hear you!
You're saying those
who work the land get to buy it?
Yes, sir!
That means coloreds and all?
Nobody squats on my land.
You want to stay, you got to pay for it
just like everybody else.
I ain't living next to no nigras!
You ain't, no?
No, I'm not.
Where're you going to live, then?
In the poorhouse?
I'd just as soon!
We take care of our own!
You going to take care of her?
Do that. You go work your fields
12 hours and then work hers.
- I got a question.
- Go ahead.
Tobacco seed.
We all know it's worth about
2,000 times its weight in gold.
You got no cash.
You got no collateral.
Your house, your land,
that's all mortgaged.
You don't have tools,
not even a mule.
Where you going to get money
for tobacco seed?
That's God's own truth.
Thank you for bringing that up.
Appreciate your concern and confidence.
I was getting around to that.
We're waiting to hear that.
Is the seed going to
fall out of the sky, Jack?
Hell, we're all ...
We're all sitting on
a little something.
There's nothing you
can do with that thing.
But just maybe, we put all
of those little things together ...
... we got something then.
Maybe we can get started.
All of us.
There's something we can do.
I don't know any other way to do this.
I got Confederate money
in the outhouse. You want it?
I don't see any way out of this
except what I'm saying now.
- Want me to sell my other arm?
- Buck, listen to me now.
I got a ruby brooch worth $ 1,000.
It's been in my family for 100 years,
but I can't eat it.
And neither can my family.
Anybody got a better idea than Jack's?
I'd sure like to keep my brooch.
Maybe y'all think I'm doing this
because he's my husband. You're wrong.
This is not just some idea to put
cash back in Jack Sommersby's pocket.
This is for all of us.
It sounds to me like this idea
just might go, don't you think?
I think so.
I think we don't have any other option.
Thank you, John.
- Pretty pitiful chicken scratching.
- Not bad for your left.
Well, it is me.
- I hope you can get something for it.
- We'll get a lot of seeds for that.
That's beautiful. You won't regret it.
I'm regretting this already.
All right. What we got here?
Look at that!
Never seen nothing like that before.
My grandmother's daddy gave it to her
the day she married.
He was a toolmaker for her people.
- How many acres you want to work?
- I thought about 10, sir.
- Ten. Ten, it is.
- Say there we get to buy it?
You will be coming back,
won't you, sir?
Godspeed, Jack.
Thank you, sir.
God love you.
Mind your mama.
This is real sharp.
Thank you, son.
I'll make a good trade for it.
Bye, sir.
Walk on, there! Walk on.
Home soon!
You folks will take that side.
We'll take this side.
Let's go to work!
We have two paces right here.
Mark your way down, John?
Go take it over there.
... eight, nine, ten!
Try not to be hoeing the rocks.
Make my job a little bit easier.
The ground's about ready.
We have to plant soon ...
He'll be here.
Yes, ma'am.
How do we know if something is true?
My Bible says:
"By their fruits ye shall know them."
Amen.
A good tree ...
... bears good fruit.
An evil tree, rotten.
And you don't have to
wonder which it is.
You just look ...
... and you shall know.
Good morning, Mrs. Bundy.
Go, John. Ask her.
Any news, Miss Laurel?
No, not yet.
Come on, Clarice.
Here, boy.
Where'd you come from?
Sir.
- Did you get a good price for my knife?
- Real good.
So good, I had something
left over to buy him.
Mom's going to be pleased to see you.
Hello.
Where you been?
I had to go all the way to Virginia!
But damn it, I got it!
- Let's see it.
- Look at this.
It don't look like much, does it?
The seeds or me?
Come on. Look at it.
You look at it.
Be careful now.
Where have you been?
Let's put these babies to bed now.
I'm sorry. Did I hurt you?
You all right?
- I'll be damned.
- Look at that.
Then Hector lifted ...
... stout helmet and set it on his head.
And like a star, it shone.
And forth from its stand ...
... he drew his father's spear ...
... heavy, great ...
... and strong.
When's he going to shoot some Greeks?
It's all the way back here.
That'll be a good start for you.
How you doing?
Is your back holding up?
Should be further along by now.
The ground's all give out from cotton.
We got to fertilize them, boys.
The whole damn house is falling apart.
What?
- Us.
- What about us?
I was just thinking how we used to be,
all rich and stupid.
Speak for yourself.
Now this house is falling apart ...
... we're broke
and I've never been so happy.
You certainly have changed,
haven't you?
For the better?
So much better it scares me sometimes.
You never used to read Homer.
Yeah, well, there was a ...
There was a man ...
... I was penned up with in Elmira.
He used to be a schoolteacher.
He had this old ...
... beat-up copy of Homer.
He used to read it to us.
Gave it to me.
I took up the reading when he died.
How did it happen?
He just died, that's all.
You don't have to talk about it.
Snap it.
Come here, little Jethro.
See all these flowers here?
Every one of them has got to go.
Every single one of them.
See these shoots?
You got to take them off too.
I said to use the fertilizer
in the field, Jack.
When is it coming?
September, August maybe.
Don't tell me you haven't known
about this for some time, missy.
Yeah, maybe I did.
Why didn't you tell me?
Go on now.
I need to get some rest.
Come on, Mr. Jack. Come on.
- Oh, sweet Jesus!
- What the hell is it?
I believe it's a hornworm, sir.
Hornworm?
Look at this.
Crawling all over them.
They going to eat us up, sir.
You know what to do?
No, sir.
Maybe Mr. Orin know.
- Damned if I'll ask him.
- You got to.
I said no!
Howdy. How are you?
Not too damn good. You?
Well, I think I'd be all right
if I could get some work.
We got a field full of that,
don't we?
This Jack Sommersby's place?
Jack around?
You want a piece of this?
Get out!
Who were those men?
What men?
The men in the field.
- I don't know.
- What did they want?
Trouble.
What kind of trouble?
- God's sake! How many kinds are there?
- I saw you.
- Forget it.
- But I saw you!
I said forget about it!
The goddamn worms are eating us!
You want to worry,
worry about them!
Hey, friend?
You got some fresh water around here?
- Howdy.
- Morning.
Got any water?
You look like you run into trouble.
Heard you had a problem.
You want to keep pulling them off
like you are ...
... but then just go like this.
I got a barrel at the end of the row.
Fill up from that ...
... and then when you get done with that,
I can mix you up some more.
That keeps them off?
What's in there?
- Why, it's soap, mostly.
- Soap?
Hamilton Sayer gave me the recipe.
He got that piece of land
over by the church.
Yeah, I'll have to shake his hand
next time I see him.
Why don't you take this
and I'll take that.
Job ain't done till
they're all dead and buried.
Thank you.
- What's wrong?
- You tell her to get, first.
Go on now, Esther.
Six years I've worked this place ...
... for you.
Man comes here,
says he's your husband.
You say I have to make way.
I make it.
I eat my heart like a piece
of spoiled meat, but I make way ...
... for you.
Then I run into these drifters ...
... that just been at your place,
looking for work.
And one of them has got his neck cut.
Said that somebody claiming to be
Jack Sommersby tried to kill him.
I said: "Why'd he try to kill you?"
He said because he knew it wasn't Jack.
Said he'd been with the real Jack
when he got his chest tore up ...
... and this man didn't have
a mark on him.
And just now, out in the field ...
... he didn't know who Ham Sayer was.
Best friend he ever had!
Didn't know Ham Sayer.
But you've known all along,
haven't you?
He might've fooled us,
but he didn't fool you.
Why, Laurel?
Why'd you do it?
Why'd you take him into your house?
Into your bed?
And why are you carrying
some stranger's child ...
... when all I ever wanted
was to honor you?
You are living in mortal sin,
Laurel Sommersby.
Do you hear me?
You and this child are
in danger of spending eternity ...
... in everlasting damnation!
- Get out!
- Come here.
Come over here.
See what these are?
They are a sign of the rottenness
that is eating at this place!
You get out!
Take your lies and damnation with you!
Look ...
... and you will know.
So who do you think I am?
I'd like to know one thing.
Whoever you think I am ...
... do you love me?
You're drunk.
I'm drunk. That's not the point.
The point is ...
... that I love you.
Now, do you love me?
If you loved me, you would stop
this sinning and leave me alone!
- I will not.
- Jack would.
- Sure he would.
- Did you know him?
Is he dead? For all I know,
you killed him and left him in a ditch.
He's right here in front of you.
A little banged-up maybe,
but I'm here.
Stop it!
You'll wake the boy.
You're making me crazy!
You get out of this house!
No, I ain't leaving.
I'm home now.
I ain't going to leave again.
You are not my husband.
May God strike me dead ...
... if I am not.
I'd let it burn, sir!
Who the hell are you?
We are the
Knights of the White Camellia.
We are God's hand
and He is our eyes ...
... and we are His vengeance!
Joseph!
Can you talk to me?
You all right?
Why was this man beaten?
You have broken the law,
and he has paid for it.
What law?
- A nigger can't own land.
- By law, he can own what he pays for.
Don't I know you?
You're on my land, aren't you?
Ain't you that teacher
from over in Clark County?
You better cut bigger holes
in that sheet, mister ...
... to see
who you're looking at.
Your master ain't listening, nigger.
Should I shoot you
to make him hear me?
You got the gun.
You do what the hell you like!
The war's over, boys.
Don't do it.
Stay back!
If he don't let go of it,
shoot them both!
I got him!
I didn't come to kill no white man.
Buck? What are you doing here?
Shit! I told you!
Get out of here! Get out!
Is it still my land?
You own what you pay for.
Well, I'm paying.
Go on now.
I was scared! I thought they
were ghosts. Were you scared too?
Yes, I was. I was truly scared.
But you saw them. Just men.
- Maybe they weren't even that.
- You mean they won't come back?
Why would they come back?
We're not scared anymore.
No, sir, we are not!
You want to finish this story?
It's the part ...
... where they going to
shoot those Greeks.
I like this part too.
I'll read it to you.
Now the Trojans ...
... the Trojans, like ravening lions,
rushed upon the Greek ships ...
... for the heart of Zeus
was with them ...
... and their spirits filled
like sails in the morning.
And the weariness
of their legs departed ...
... and the mighty shields
grew light on their arms.
And they knew that victory would be theirs.
You killed that dog, didn't you?
Poor old Jethro.
He knew you for a stranger.
So then you had to kill him.
Nice torch.
Save it from last night?
Who are you, you son of a bitch?
Tell me who you are or
I'll burn this place down.
I'm the man she wanted.
You're a liar.
You're a liar ...
... and a thief is what you are.
You are a goddamned yellow hypocrite
hiding under a sheet!
Sir?
Mama's having the baby.
Congratulations, Mr. Jack.
Thank you.
What happened to ...?
I fell off a ladder. I'm all right.
Can I hold her?
Let's call her Rachel,
after your mama.
So do you think she knows
I'm her daddy?
I'm sure she does.
Looks like we have a fine crop.
How's the smoke there, Reverend?
Mighty smooth.
How much you reckon we'll get?
It depends. I'll be happy with
eight dollars on a hundred weight.
Can I get you a new spire
on the church?
Verily I say unto you ...
... whosoever shall not receive
the kingdom of God ...
... as a little child ...
... he shall not enter therein.
And He took them in His arms ...
... put His hands upon them
and blessed them.
Name this child.
Rachel Caroline.
Rachel Caroline, I baptize thee ...
... in the name of the Father,
and the Son ...
... and the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
- Nothing to do with me.
- You must be proud.
John Robert Sommersby?
Yes, sir.
Federal marshals, Mr. Sommersby.
We have a warrant for your arrest.
My arrest? For what?
For the murder of Mr. Charles Conklin
of Jackson, Mississippi.
- Five minutes, Mrs. Sommersby.
- Thank you.
I want you to tell me.
I don't care what the answer is,
I'll stay by you ...
... as long as it's the truth.
Did you do this?
No, I did not.
All right, then.
I'll get our things together.
We're coming with you, Jack!
Thank you, John.
They're so afraid,
they got to handcuff me.
- I'll be back.
- You're a good man!
- We're behind you!
- Take care!
I always did have a hankering
to go see Nashville.
Proud to have you with me.
I wish I knew why you was
arresting this man!
Stand clear! Federal marshals.
God bless you, now.
You promise to come right back.
I'll be back. We'll be back!
We'll be with you in two days!
Don't you worry!
We'll see you in Nashville, Jack!
Did you bring the Acts of Assembly?
All rise, please.
Oyez, oyez. The Honorable
Barry Conrad Issacs is now sitting.
This court shall come to order!
All having suits to prosecute or
pleas to enter shall come forward ...
... and they shall be heard.
Well, we were playing
a game of five-card ...
... and Charlie, Mr. Conklin ...
... saw Sommersby slip a card
off the bottom of the deck.
He jumped up
and called him a damn cheat.
And what happened
when you got outside?
Mr. Conklin hit Sommersby
in the stomach.
He went down like a sack of potatoes.
Then Sommersby got up
with a gun in his hand.
Charlie hollered: "Don't shoot, Sommersby!"
But he shot him like a dog,
and he run off.
Now, is the man you refer to
as Sommersby ...
... here in this courtroom?
That's him.
Let the record show
witness identified the defendant.
I was standing on the corner
across the street.
I couldn't see too well
because it was rather dark.
And I saw ...
... a man lying on the ground.
And then he gets up.
And I see he has a gun in his hand.
And I heard this other man say:
"Don't shoot, Sommersby."
And he shot him.
And the man fell to the ground.
"Don't shoot, Sommersby."
Mr. Goldman ...
... did you see him sign this register?
Yes, sir.
Is that his signature right there?
Was there anything wrong with his hand?
No, sir.
The jury will observe
this hotel register ...
... and the signature of J. Sommersby,
and compare it to ...
... the signature on a bank mortgage ...
... signed by Mr. Sommersby
seven years before.
The signatures are identical.
This court is adjourned
until 9 :00 tomorrow morning ...
... when we'll hear arguments
for the defense.
All rise.
How'd we do?
Did just fine, son.
Mr. Sommersby ...
... will you come with me?
I know what you're thinking.
Orin! What are you doing here?
Watching over you.
We don't need watching.
The way things are going,
he's going to hang.
I can make sure he don't.
How?
You got to tell them who you are.
If you do, they'll have to let you go.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
Who am I supposed to say I am?
Just who you are.
Do you really want to know?
Yes.
Are you sure?
I'm ...
... Jack Sommersby.
Pleased to meet you.
What'd I do?
You stubborn fool!
I won't let you do this!
I accept your offer.
Mr. Webb?
- Is the defense ready?
- Yes, Your Honor.
The defense calls
as its first witness ...
... Mrs. John Sommersby.
Webb, what the hell is this?
Place your left hand on the Bible.
Do you swear to tell the truth
and nothing but the truth ...
... so help you God?
- Yes, I do.
- Please be seated.
- Please tell us your name.
- Mrs. John Sommersby.
Mrs. Sommersby, here are the hotel
register and the mortgage paper ...
... the prosecution has submitted
as evidence.
Do you recognize
the signatures there?
Yes, they're my husband's.
Can you point your husband out
to the court?
No, I cannot.
And why is that, ma'am?
My husband is not
in this room.
Objection!
Come here, Webb!
Your Honor, this is absurd!
Silence!
I'm talking to you!
Sit down, sir!
Don't do it.
You don't have to do it.
Sit down
or I'll have you seated.
Your Honor, this is a purely
theatrical device designed ...
... to throw these proceedings
into confusion.
Overruled, for the moment.
Mrs. Sommersby, are you saying
the defendant is not your husband?
As clearly as I can, Your Honor.
Are you saying
the defendant is an impostor?
Yes, I am.
Your Honor, this is absurd!
Quite possibly, Mr. Dawson.
However ...
... we cannot continue to try a man
for a capital crime ...
... if he is not the man in question.
Proceed, Mr. Webb.
Thank you, Your Honor.
And when did you realize
this man was not John Sommersby?
It was the little things.
At first, he looked some different.
But so did everybody back
from the war.
He couldn't remember a lot of things.
His own dog didn't know him.
A dog. It's a dog, y'all!
Sustained.
He never talked about his father,
and he'd been the world to Jack.
Your Honor, please!
Let's get our cows over their buckets.
Please, continue.
And after that, when we were ...
... together in a private way ...
... I knew it wasn't Jack.
A woman would know her own husband.
I'm sure most husbands would
like to think so, Mrs. Sommersby.
But when you realized
this man was not your husband ...
... why did you allow people
to believe he was?
People believe
what they want to sometimes.
Everybody wanted
Jack to be alive and home ...
... and when this man showed up,
looking like him, acting like him ...
... it weren't hard
just to let it be him.
But there were signs
anyone could notice.
For instance, Mr. Mead fit him
for boots and saw that his foot ...
... was smaller than Jack's.
Got them templates mixed up,
that's all.
Another thing, one day these drifters
came looking for work.
They'd been in the Army with Jack ...
... when he was wounded,
and they said this man wasn't him.
Why is she saying that about you?
I don't know, son.
Tell her it's you. All right?
All right.
You go back and sit down now.
Well, Jack, whoever he is ...
... pulled a knife on them
so they couldn't expose him.
Mrs. Sommersby, I have here
a promissory note ...
... offering an option to purchase land,
given to a Mr. Joseph ...
... signed by the defendant.
Is that your husband's signature?
No. He couldn't sign like Jack, so
he made up a story about a bad hand.
Your Honor, this witness
will say anything ...
... to save her husband.
I move we strike her testimony.
Can you offer any support
to the claims of this witness?
I can, Your Honor, and do.
The defense calls Mr. Matthew Folsom.
What is your occupation?
I have a 2,000 -acre farm
down in Clark County.
Do you see the defendant?
Yes, sir.
Can you identify him?
Yes. His name's Horace Townsend.
Horace Townsend.
How do you know the defendant?
He was the schoolteacher
in Redthorn for a short while.
He taught my children for a year.
Please continue.
I don't know where he come from, but
he sweet-talked his way into the job.
He knew a lot of fancy stuff
and Greek writing and all.
He talked us into some scheme
to build a new schoolhouse.
We gave him everything we had
and then some. More than $ 1,200.
He run off with every cent.
So, Mr. Folsom ...
... are you quite sure
that this man is Horace Townsend?
I'm sure. There's a whole bunch
of folks in Clark County ...
... be pleased to see "Yellow Horace" in jail.
Thank you, Mr. Folsom.
Your Honor ...
Heard he moved on south ...
... got some girl in the family way
and ran out on her.
Ran out on the Army too.
That's why they call him "Yellow Horace".
When our boys were in a bad fix ...
... he ran out and left them to it.
The Yankees found him behind the bushes.
We lost track of him after that.
But I knew him as soon as I saw him.
- What you're saying is ...
- What I'm saying ...
... is that man is a liar,
a thief and a deserter.
- And his name is Horace Townsend.
- Thank you, Mr. Folsom.
Your Honor ...
... I believe the defense
has proven beyond a doubt ...
... that this is a case
of wrongful arrest ...
Your Honor, may I speak?
You may not.
- I move for a mistrial.
- lf I dismiss my attorney ...
... may I then speak?
You have the right to.
- You are dismissed.
- You don't need to.
On the basis of that man's testimony,
I'm about to rule on a mistrial.
Mr. Webb is trying to prove
I'm not who I am.
I don't see how I could win
anything that way.
You could win your life.
Without my name,
I don't think I have a life ...
... Your Honor.
Very well.
Continue, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Webb.
I said, thank you.
- Mr. Folsom.
- That's me.
You testified that you knew me
as soon as you saw me.
Did we ever meet ...
... since the time you said
that I lived in Redthorn?
I don't believe so.
I do believe so.
But the last time we met,
you were sitting on a horse ...
... dressed up like a bed.
Didn't you and your White Knights
burn a cross in front of my house?
And beat a black man half to death
because he tried to farm for himself?
I did not!
Didn't your leader
point a gun at me ...
... and say that you and your Knights are
"the only true law in Tennessee"?
You don't recognize the authority
of this court at all, do you?
Which is why you can lie about me.
You are the liar!
The real reason you are here is ...
... to stop me from selling land
to a colored man ...
... who'd then be a landowner
on a level with yourself.
You may go to hell!
You will watch your tongue
in my court.
And you will watch your tongue
in my presence!
You sit up there
in judgment of nobody!
In two years,
when the Yankees are gone ...
... you will be back in the field
where you belong!
Quite possibly, Mr. Folsom.
But in the meantime, you are
in contempt of my court ...
... and I sentence you to 30 days
in county jail.
Sentence me?
You nappy -headed son of a bitch!
Sixty days!
Show Mr. Folsom the way
to our uncomfortable facilities.
You're a dead man!
The jury will disregard
the testimony of that witness.
Mr. Towns ...
How shall I address you?
Jack Sommersby.
Can you offer evidence to that effect?
How many of y'all are here
from Vine Hill?
How many willing to swear
I'm Jack Sommersby?
- I will!
- I'll swear!
We could bring them all up here
one by one, Your Honor.
Or what we could do,
if you want, is ...
... bring Mrs. Sommersby back up here,
find out how this all got started.
Now, Laurel, you really believe
I'm not your husband?
Yes, you are not.
But you let everybody
believe that I was.
Why is that?
Because I wanted you to be him
as much as they did.
Why?
I was worn out from work and lonesome.
- I didn't want my son ...
- You mean, our son?
I didn't want my son growing up
without a father.
I see. So even when I first come home,
from then, you had doubts about me?
Because I was mean to you?
That's where you went wrong.
Jack Sommersby never said a kind word
to me in his life.
Objection, Your Honor!
Is this a court of law?
May I humbly remind you
that this is a murder trial?
And may I remind you this court
will not try a man for murder ...
... as long as his identity
is in question.
Now please sit down.
- Continue, sir.
- Thank you.
But I must warn you,
you proceed at your own jeopardy.
I think all these people
are flat stumped now.
These people have known you
since you was born. Haven't you?
They may not know everything
that you'd do ...
... but they'd know what you wouldn't.
They know you wouldn't let a man
sign contracts with them ...
... if he wasn't Jack.
It wouldn't be worth the paper
it's printed on.
Meaning ...
... they wouldn't own anything.
You thought of that?
What about our children?
What about them?
If I wasn't Jack Sommersby ...
... what would that make them?
What about our little Rachel?
"Bastard" is not a very pretty word.
Is that what you want?
And you?
You think you can just go home now
with your illegitimate child ...
... and your thief lover?
Just tell all these good folks ...
... you've been lying to them
for a year?
They know you better.
Maybe they don't know me that well.
Now nobody knows either one of us.
You can twist it around all you want,
but we both know you're not Jack.
Everybody here knows who I am.
I know who I am. The only people
who don't are you and Orin.
You make some kind of a deal?
With Orin?
Don't be ridiculous!
This man shows up here ...
... with a skunk in a sheet ...
... telling everyone I'm not who I am.
What does he expect in return?
Stop this.
No. Tell me,
what did you promise him?
That everything would be the way it was
before you came.
Everything would be
the way it was before.
Except you'd be promised to a man ...
... you don't love.
And I would be some piece
of scum named Horace Townsend ...
... serving a few years for fraud.
At least you wouldn't hang.
I wouldn't have to.
I'd be dead already.
You care for me?
Of course!
Then why are you doing this?
Because you are not Jack Sommersby!
- How do you know?
- A woman knows her husband.
- You've got no proof.
- I don't need any!
- Nobody believes you!
- I don't care. I know how I feel.
That's all that matters?
You're a hardheaded woman!
You're a stubborn idiot! You're not
Jack, so why do you pretend you are?
How do you know?
- I know because ...
- How do you know?
I know because I never loved him
the way that I love you.
So tell me, Laurel, from your heart ...
... am I your husband?
Yes, you are.
Thank you.
No more questions, Your Honor.
Mr. Dawson?
You may step down, Mrs. Sommersby.
Do you have any more witnesses,
Mr. Sommersby?
No, sir.
Kindly approach the bench, sir.
You've argued most effectively.
Your identity not being in question
leaves little doubt about your guilt.
Don't you have anything else to say?
What's it say?
How much did we get?
I said eight, hoped for 10 ...
... got 12?
Now, how much we get
for the whole crop?
Just over $ 10,000.
God Al mighty!
Come on, woman.
Come here. Dance around!
Jump around!
We did it! We did it!
You and me.
How are the kids?
They're fine.
Rachel's all fat and sassy.
Robbie?
He's having a hard time of it.
He don't understand.
I don't understand.
What am I supposed to tell him?
You tell him his daddy
never killed anybody.
What about Horace Townsend?
Horace Townsend.
I knew Horace Townsend.
Very well.
Everything they said about him
in the courtroom there ...
... it was true.
I hated the bastard!
The only piece of luck
he ever had was ...
... being locked up.
Some man looked just like him.
Could have been brothers.
Probably were.
After spending four years
in that cell together ...
... they knew all there was
to know about each other.
Anyway, he's dead now.
Who?
Horace.
You didn't kill him?
No, he got stabbed ...
... that night he killed Conklin.
Bled to death.
I buried him on a hill ...
... under some rocks.
You mean you buried Jack, don't you?
I mean I buried Horace.
For good, Laurel.
You've got to tell them.
You've got to tell that judge.
- He'll understand.
- Don't do this.
No.
You want to hold me, then hold me today
and every day after that!
You say that you love me, then show me!
Be a father and grow old with me.
That's what love is!
- You think I don't want that?
- Then come home.
You don't understand.
If I'm Horace, we got no home.
I don't care.
I do care!
I will not be Horace Townsend again!
You'd rather die?
I would rather be home.
If you know some way for Jack Sommersby
to walk out of here, I'll do it.
There's nothing I can say, is there?
Do you know ...
... how many nights I stayed up
in our bedroom ...
... just looking at you?
Thinking ...
... what a miracle it is to be here.
I used to wonder
what I'd ever done to deserve ...
... being there in a room with you.
I still do.
Being your husband ...
... has been the only thing
I've ever done that I'm proud of.
We don't have much time now.
You bring it?
Yes, it's right here.
Oh, God!
I ironed this thing four times.
- It's fine.
- It's all wrinkled up.
It looks terrible.
My fingers are shaking.
Let me help.
You know, I feel that ...
... if I know you'll be there with me,
I can do this thing right.
Please don't ask me that. I can't.
I will not watch you die!
- It's time.
- You wait a minute!
I'm sorry, sir.
You keep that for me ...
... for better or for worse.
Forgive me the worse.
It was always you!
I knew the first moment I saw you ...
... it was always you, my love.
- Company!
- Attention!
God bless you, Jack!
You, John Robert Sommersby ...
... having been found guilty
of the murder of Charles Conklin ...
... are hereby sentenced
to be hanged by the neck until dead.
Sentence to be carried out immediately.
May God have mercy on your soul.
Because he hath set his love upon Me ...
... therefore will I deliver him.
I will set him on high
because he hath known My name.
He shall call upon Me,
and I will answer him.
I will be with him in trouble.
I will deliver him ...
... and honor him and show him My salvation.
God bless you, Jack.
No, don't. I'm not ready yet.
No, don't, not yet!
Please! Let me through!
Don't, please!
Jack! I'm here!