Leave me alone, will ya?
You think you're so smart.
Would you stay still already?
What a geek!
- I'm not a geek!
- You're doing it wrong!
- Shut up!
- You're doing it wrong.
- It doesn't go like that.
- Who asked you?
- Who's your brother?
- You are, Stevie!
You do it like this,
it'll open up in a fire,
you'll get burned and die.
Let's go!
What d'you got, Adcox, a big deal?
Medium deal, Captain.
Hey, Brian, want to come along?
- Dad...
- Stephen, you've come a dozen times.
Give your brother a chance.
What d'you say?
We'll be back in a minute.
How about it?
- Sure!
- Come on!
- Pull the cord, Brian!
1545 Idylwild.
- Give it a yank, a good pull.
You've gotta get
these cars outta the way.
- Give it another yank!
Well, there it is,
right over there. See it?
Okay.
You stay
near the truck now.
That doesn't look too bad.
Drop two lines
and hold the squad.
Everything I own in the
whole world is up there.
All my stuff's up there!
Adcox! Ladder up!
Hey, that's your
old man up there, Brian.
Nice grab, Captain!
Take it easy.
You'll be okay.
We got it!
Come on.
Dad!
Hold on, Adcox.
Is that a gas line?
- Dad!
Hey, Brian!
Brian McCaffrey, got some I.D.?
Hey, Willie!
I'll give you I.D.!
- The littlest McCaffrey!
- How you doin'?
Hot off the presses, boys!
Station assignments!
Hey, McCaffrey!
Why don't you hold onto
that for me, huh?
Something wrong
with my eyesight?
You really trying
this fireman thing again?
- Quitting once wasn't good enough?
- It's in the blood.
- Is that right?
- Willie, you owe me a brew!
Hold on!
I'm talking to the fire chief!
Let's look and see
what else was in your blood.
I always looked forward
to getting these.
- You hold onto those, huh?
- Whoa! I got station 17!
"Aspen Snowmobile Tours.
Brian McCaffrey, Sales. "
It didn't offer the growth
and challenge that I needed.
"Cattle Drive Mobile Log Cabins. "
- That was in your blood six months?
- The coffee sucked.
"Brian's Sound Spectrum,
Direct Hi-end Stereo Sales. "
This is your own company.
This was a big step, huh?
I was ahead of my time, Willie.
McCaffrey!
What's the matter with you?
Aren't you even curious?
Engine 115, right?
How'd you know, you prick?
These are supposed to be sealed.
Lucky guess.
And a case of Scotch to the captain
at station assignments.
You crooked son-of-a-bitch!
Make us proud, guys!
McCaffrey, that's
my cousin's company.
Come on!
Calm down, Mrs. Vaitkus.
Mrs. Vaitkus, please, calm down.
McCaffrey, I think it's a box,
or a 211, at least.
- Just give me one minute.
- Hurry, we can't miss this one!
- Hey.
- Hi, Jen.
- I see your grandma's still-
- Yeah, she still hates you.
- You look great.
- Thanks. How long you been in town?
Four months.
- Oh, really.
- But I, uh...
I've been really busy
at the academy.
I graduated today.
I can see that.
So what have you been up to?
Well, uh...
I work at city hall, actually.
No kidding? That's great!
So...
I don't know what-
Maybe you and I could...
could get together for a beer.
A beer?
Beer... that's-
It's funny. You're acting
like I just saw you last week.
When I haven't seen you
in what... six years?
You son-of-a-bitch!
Don't want ya overheatin', Brian!
I'll give you overheatin'!
Easy, man. I don't have
time for this bullshit.
Well, you've certainly matured.
Well, it's nice to know
we can still be friends.
Come on, Brian.
We got a fire to go to.
Engine 17,
your pressure's fine.
Get out of the way here,
please.
Officers, you're standing around
with your thumb up your asses.
- Where you going?
- I'm a fireman.
Go!
Need a second lead-out?
What the fuck are you
talking about?
- Get out of here!
- Brian!
This is the
real shit, man!
The real thing!
Well, what do we got here?
A fireman's costume, huh?
Where'd you rent it?
Thanks for coming to
my graduation today, brother.
You're a real
inspiration to me.
I'm sorry, man.
You're really ready to fight
fire this time, huh, Brian?
It just doesn't work on you,
little brother.
- I'll see you around.
- Not likely.
You see, that's where
you're wrong already.
I talked to
Chief Fitzgerald.
He decided maybe you shouldn't be
way on the other side of town...
where I'd never
get to see you.
Starting tomorrow,
you're going to be...
with the toughest company
in the city.
17... my company.
One case of Scotch, Brian?
Man, you're gettin' cheap
in your old age.
Get outta here, girls.
You should learn not to box
when the 17's on the job.
Hey, Inspector Rimgale,
she's all yours.
Hey, give me a shot
of that, will ya?
Hey, Shadow.
So, you got a cause there?
Mice with matches.
Well, the glory boys
are going to have to...
wait a few days on this one.
Sean?
Sean!
Hey, buddy.
What's goin' on?
It's Uncle Brian.
You'll remember this.
Spinach?
We don't need no
stinkin' spinach!
- Mom! Mom!
- Hey...
Hey, what's-
Come here. It's okay.
- Hello?
- Yeah?
- Brian...
- Hey, Helen.
God, I'd about
written you off.
I know, well-
So, uh...
What's goin' on?
- Can I come in for a second?
- Sure.
- How you doin'?
- Okay.
Good to see you.
So that's Sean, huh?
Geez, he's a little giant now.
You'd be surprised
what a few years can do to a kid.
- Remember your Uncle Brian?
- No.
You don't remember him?
Hey, Sean-man.
Where's your daddy today?
Uh... Stephen's not
staying here anymore.
He moved out last April.
I'm sorry, Helen, I, uh-
You guys should try picking up
the phone once in a while.
Hey!
Hey.
I, uh...
talked to Helen.
I thought Dad's boat
was finally retired...
to the old family graveyard.
Don't you worry about
falling out of this thing?
I've gotta tell you,
I love what you've
done with the place.
Yeah, it's comin' along.
You want a beer?
Yeah, why not?
What, you been rippin' off
fire stations again?
Just some old stuff...
that Adcox gave me that
the department was gonna throw out.
But it's good enough
for this tub.
What is this?
"Iron Butterfly,"
"Cream"?
You gotta be kidding! This isn't
an actual operating 8-track!
What do you want, Brian?
What are you doin' here?
I wanna know why you messed
with my station assignment.
I mean, does this
really have to be...
one of those big brother,
little brother...
you broke my G.I. Joe and
I'm still pissed games?
Man, how do you do it, huh?
How d'you keep
coming up with...
new and amazing ways
to fuck up?
I mean, that Scotch bullshit?
Am I really supposed
to believe you came home...
because you felt heartstrings
moan for the family biz?
You were bankrupt!
The scary thing is...
you probably coulda
got away with it for awhile.
Hang back a little bit
at the fires-
You know the drill.
The only problem is,
that in this job...
there's just no place to hide.
It's not like having
a bad day selling log cabins.
You have a bad day here,
somebody dies.
And that's just not
fucking good enough.
You know something?
I must've told myself
a million times...
I didn't even want
to be a damn fireman.
Look, I know I quit
the academy before.
- And I know how you must've felt.
- Oh, you do?
You know how I felt?
I gotta do this, Stephen.
I need to know.
Yeah, I think you're
going to find out, Brian.
Try not to be late
tomorrow, huh?
Give me a break, huh!
Shit!
Come on, damn it!
Oh, shit!
- My car wouldn't start!
- What are you doin', man?
Atta boy!
Damn!
Come on, man.
You can make it!
Well, Baby McCaffrey,
how you doin'?
How you doin', John?
Hey, Axe,
you know this rug rat?
Know him?
I practically raised him.
He never calls.
He never writes.
I'm Brian.
I'm sorry.
All right!
Garment factory.
Shake and bake, boys!
I think we got a barbecue.
Got yourself a hot one
first time out, kid.
Oh, yeah, this is
gonna taste like shit.
- All right, let's go!
- Shit!
I hate it when we gotta
fucking go look for it.
Call in a box, Otis.
We're gonna need some back-up.
Brian, inch-and-a-half.
Get the high-rise jet.
- These moments do try me.
- Be gentle now, Axe.
Holy shit!
Coming through!
Hey, Probie,
how about it, huh?
- You ready?
- Yeah.
You're doin' it wrong.
Stay beside me.
I mean, right beside me.
Come on, man.
Kick it in.
Get down!
Show time!
Got it!
- Let's take it from the side.
- No, let's hit it head-on!
It's gonna flash on us, Bull.
We gotta back out!
She'll steam on us a little,
but she won't flash.
Here comes your water.
Here it comes!
All right,
let's go for the throat!
Hey, Nightengale!
Save your fucking air, man.
Pull down that wall!
I gotta ventilate this heat.
All right, hook us up to a standpipe!
Come on, Brian, hustle!
Shit!
It's in the walls!
- How about it, Probie?
- Coming!
Come on, Brian.
We're going to lose this!
Shit!
Charge it!
- Hey, Otis, is it-
- It's jumpin' floors.
So where's the second-in
companies, huh?
Sorry, man, John Wayne time.
You're on your own, boss.
- No back-up.
- Shit!
Dig in.
- Dig in, goddamn it!
- All right, come on!
What the hell's goin' on?
What was that, goddamn it?
Slow down,
it's jumpin' floors to us.
Relax, put your mask on.
It's gonna be the real deal.
Down!
Cover up, Lieutenant!
Jesus Christ!
I'm burning up!
Put him out!
Bull!
All right, go get it!
Hey!
Sorry, kid.
I thought you were dead.
We got it. Let's go!
Oh, shit!
Man down!
Look out!
I'm going!
You go, we go!
Come on!
Pull!
Brian, let's go!
Hey, Stephen!
The chief thinks we got one left
behind downstairs, a civilian.
Axe!
Take-
Down to two probies, perfect!
- Take Tim and do a search!
- Let's go, kid!
- Stay with him.
- Okay, I will.
Come on. Let's move it, Brian.
Stay on this line.
Ow! You son-of-a-bitch!
More line!
Shit!
Help!
Stephen! Over here!
Someone's over here!
Help!
- Where's my brother?
- I don't know. I ain't seen him, Bull!
Is anybody in here?
My God!
I got one!
Somebody, give me a hand!
Is she going to be
all right?
I'm afraid you're a little
too late with this one.
Sorry to hear about the mannequin.
I heard you two were close.
You all right?
You didn't get burned,
did you?
Look, I'm a little
busy right now.
You've got an awful short memory
for direct orders.
- I told you to stay beside me.
- I heard somebody call.
What was that bullshit
with the standpipe?
The cap was stuck!
I told you to stay right
be-fucking-side me, Brian!
Hey, look, I was doing it!
I was up there doing it!
You don't know, man.
You don't know what I did!
What you did was
drop the ball, Probie.
You split the team up.
Get that part right...
if you wanna.
- Let me get one of those.
- Here you go.
I don't know, Axe.
I don't know.
That Stephen, man.
What goes through
that guy's head?
Never wears his mask.
Making us take it on
in the first room like that.
This shit's happening
too often, man.
- Could've flashed. Should've flashed!
- Yeah, but it didn't.
- Stevie knows.
- The guy's lucky.
- Alderman.
- Inspector Rimgale.
- I... need to get in that trunk.
- Oh, excuse me.
Thanks.
Pretty fancy shoes you're
wearing for a fire scene.
Guess you haven't been
to many fires.
We wanted to talk to you
about Alan Seagrave's death.
We still haven't gotten
a fire report.
You'll get that answer
as soon as I do, ma'am.
A man gets stuffed through
the windshield of his own car.
Is that an accident or arson?
People are asking me.
I gotta tell 'em something.
We're starting to get the feeling
your office is dragging out this case...
to embarrass the Alderman because
of his fire department cutbacks.
I have an uncomplicated job:
to decide if a fire is arson.
If so, to catch
the son-of-a-bitch doing it.
If my investigative methods
happen to muck up...
the campaign of
certain mayor wannabes,
I gotta tell you,
I'm not going to lose
any sleep over it.
I'm sure you're gonna have that report
on my desk as soon as it's ready.
- You'll have it.
- Thank you.
That guy better not make any rights
on reds in my district.
Hey, Swayzak?
You missed it.
Get over there.
Keep 'em busy.
You should've been there.
It was fucking great!
We almost lost a whole
goddamn company for you.
Since you shut down 33,
there's no fucking backup.
We appreciate it.
I don't know about the rest,
- but you got my vote for mayor.
- If you have a problem, help us.
- Work with the task force.
- The task force?
Three guys have died because of cuts
made by your fucking task force!
Know that little glow that's starting
to blink in the corner of your eye?
That's your career dissipation light.
It went into overtime.
- Come on, man.
- No.
If anybody's lights
are about to go out,
believe me, they're yours.
Thanks a lot, fellas.
You did a great job today,
by the way.
Alderman, will this affect
your task force findings?
No more today.
Good-bye.
So this is that big city job
you were talking about.
Yeah. Welcome home, Brian.
Where's that fucking guy
buy his shoes?
Did you check those out?
They're like fucking butter.
Hey, G-man!
Get outta here.
Do you have to do that?
Yeah. Could you
believe that fire?
There we were,
Adcox and me...
pulling that lady right out
of the fire's fucking throat.
We saved a life, man!
I love it here!
Fighting 17th!
Goddamn!
Stephen's amazing.
You see how he took that fire?
By the balls!
I'm gonna be
that good someday.
You watch.
You'll see.
You know what Stephen said to me?
When the shit
was coming hard,
he said,
"You never know...
till the moment
the fire stares you down...
- if you're just gonna do this job-"
- Or be great at it, right?
He using that line of shit
on you now?
You think he made
that little gem up?
My old man used to use
that line every other day.
It's no line, man!
That's no line.
Hey, kid,
we ain't waitin'!
Go, go, go!
Let's go!
No, no, not that way!
What's going on?
Come on. Let's go!
It's lunch, Probies!
Let's get started!
Ooo, caw, caw!
A couple of crows, man!
That money will probably
end up coming from-
- This better be good.
- Or we feed you to the thing.
Shut up. You got something
against Dalmatians?
Accident or murder?
That's the question arson investigators
are struggling with...
after a freak explosion known
by firefighters as a backdraft-
Hey, Pengelly, you're on TV.
- I saw you too!
- Look, that's me.
He's been identified as Alan
Seagrave, a prominent Chicago C.P.A.
Despite pressure
from the city council,
fire officials refuse
to speculate on the cause,
saying only that
their investigation is continuing.
- Gentlemen, gentlemen.
- Here he goes again.
As 17th's official toastmaster-
- And bullshitter.
- Thank you, Santos.
Did I mention you were
cut out of my will?
I think it appropriate...
that we recognize the two asswipes...
probationary firemen,
among us today,
who were officially baptized...
into the world of old man fire.
First, to Tim.
Despite the fact he was born
with a dull expression...
and a really hideous
pair of ears,
he not only took on the beast,
but pulled from its clutches,
assisted by a more famous and
brilliant firefighter... me,
a kicking and
screaming civilian...
who'll probably wind up suing us
for breaking her fingernails.
And to Brian.
Help me, Santos.
Whose own contribution...
was both more beautiful
and less likely to sue us.
Son-of-a-bitch.
When I heard that both
McCaffrey brothers...
were being assigned here
at this station at the same time,
my heart was filled with a...
sudden desire to transfer.
So raise a glass, lads,
to funny-looking Tim
and the McCaffrey brothers.
For despite the fact...
they've gotten on each
other's nerves for years,
have managed with great effort to still
be pissed off at each other.
Gentlemen...
Fuck you!
Thanks for the ride.
Hey, Brian.
I'll see you tonight, huh?
Yeah, I'll see you tonight.
I've known Jack Fitzgerald
since he was a candidate.
They had fire engines then?
- Get that man's name!
- I gotta say, he was just as ugly then.
Can I have a beer, please?
- Hey. How you doin'?
- Hey.
- ... home of the real firemen.
Enough of us stroking each other.
Here's the man
we're here to honor,
- Chief Jack Fitzgerald.
I know I speak
for everybody here.
It's about time you retired...
and made a promotion
for somebody else.
Think I oughta change the view.
I couldn't have
wished for a better life.
Thank you much.
- I don't believe this shit!
- Pretty boy, get a load of this.
Bull, wait'll
you listen to this shit.
- Let me see.
- Hey-hey-hey.
"Probationary Fireman,
Brian McCaffrey,
on his first fire, showed the bravery
and courage of a veteran...
when he risked life and limb to...
- double-check a burning floor, alone.
Emerging victoriously
with Anna Rodriquez,
a seamstress for the
North Shore Clothing Company. "
Axe, get a load
of this shit!
"McCaffrey first gained
prominence as the subject...
of a 1972 Pulitzer
Prize-winning photograph taken...
- at the scene of his father's death. "
- That's me.
What are we gonna do
about this?
- Hey, 17, what's going on?
- Well...
I think that
it's union bylaw...
that if you get your picture in
the paper, even if it's bullshit,
- you buy the whole company a drink.
- All right!
I know I'm gonna have
another double... on the hero!
- Give him a hand over here.
- What's this?
Leave 'em alone.
Good job.
Brian McCaffrey, huh?
Brian, this is my boss,
Alderman Swayzak. He wanted to meet you.
You should be proud of helping
to save that woman's life.
- That was a hell of a job.
- Don't believe everything you read.
Don't be so modest, Brian.
See that?
That's a mannequin.
Look, Brian,
let me just get down
to it, okay?
I've been checking you out.
Jennifer can't say enough.
I need your help.
- I'm gonna offer you a job.
- I've already got a job.
The great thing about this job,
it's still with the fire department.
One of your best investigators, Don
Rimgale, is working a really tough case.
He needs an extra pair of hands.
If that name is gonna
come from my office,
- I want it to be you.
- Why is that?
I want someone from a real traditional
fire-fighting clan.
Yeah, we got
all kinds of traditions...
like dying young.
Thanks anyway.
Took you all of 30 seconds
to blow that off.
Brian, I know it's not
my place to say this,
but I think you're passing
on a great opportunity.
- You're smarter than that.
- Look, Jen.
I'm trying to do something here.
Can't you see that?
I'm trying to be a fireman,
not some kind of poster boy
for Swayzak.
There's gotta be at least
500 other smoke eaters here...
that do that shit
for real every day.
Why don't you tell Swayzak
to talk to one of them?
Hey, Bull, slow down.
Helen, can I talk
to you for a minute?
- What about?
- It's about Sean.
Right here, right now,
you wanna talk about Sean?
- How you doin', Stephen?
- Hey, Jackson.
You don't have
to stop dancing.
It's only our son,
for Christ's sake.
- Stephen, you don't have to remind me.
- Stephen.
- What about your dumbass brother?
- Wait a second.
Saving a mannequin.
How fuckin' stupid can a guy get?
- Stephen, relax.
- Let go.
Stephen!
You got anything else you want
to say about my brother?
Goddamn you, McCaffrey!
Atta boy, Brian!
Take it outside!
- Knock it off!
- Come here, you son-of-a-bitch!
Ow-ow-ow.
Oh, I'm bleeding.
Jesus!
Knock it off.
Come on, eh?
Hey! Knock it off.
Hey, hey, I'm fine.
Jesus, Stevie, you never
know when to quit, do you?
Do you ever wonder why...
you're stuck a fucking lieutenant
for life?
No.
Come on.
Let's get a drink.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
Hey, whoa!
- Get him outta here!
- I just wanna get a drink.
You need to get the hell
outta here. Let's go.
The whole family's crazy.
You nailed him.
He's all right.
He said something.
- What'd he say?
- I don't remember.
Listen, I can walk by myself.
Ow! I hurt my ankle, man.
Don't stand and laugh.
Get me up!
Yeah. Oop. Photographer.
-Think I can get on the cover of "Life"?
-Let's go.
- Is Axe a great guy?
He doesn't know shit
about what I want.
I've got news for everybody.
I'm not my old man.
A fire won't get me.
I know more than he did.
I know more about fire
than all of 'em.
Time for bed, Sugar Ray.
Let me get those for you.
Get outta my way.
I can get my shoes off.
You're such
a pain in the ass.
You always were.
What are you talkin' about?
I saved your ass tonight.
Why don't they trust me
anymore, huh, Brian?
Really, the guys just
don't trust me anymore.
Hey, this boat could
be great, don't you think?
Maybe I'll just...
just take it out
on weekends.
Sean and me.
We could just float.
Get it on your shoulder,
Probie. It's not a football.
You're not breaking
any records, Brian.
Goddamn it!
Get it on your shoulder!
All right, Stephen.
Come on, Stephen!
Come on, Brian.
Kick that old man's ass!
Run, damn you!
I'm comin'. I'm comin'!
Aw, shit!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Run, damn you!
Oh, shit.
Okay, roll the hose.
- Are you kidding me? By myself?
- You heard me.
- What about Tim?
- Aw, shit. What about Tim?
For Christ's sake.
Next time I'll let you win.
You got a problem
with drilling, Probie?
- Is that it?
- No! I don't have a problem with it.
But let's just have
one drill, Lieutenant,
-not one for the company and one for me.
-Roll the hose now!
I'm not gonna quit, Stephen.
You hear me?
I'm not gonna quit.
My baby!
My baby is still up there!
- Please, somebody!
- Where's your baby at?
How many men
you got in there?
My baby is still up there.
Please help me!
Hold on, Steve.
Don't go up there.
- Wait for the hose line.
- Brian!
Hey, don't take that kind
of shit from it!
Don't let it know
you're scared!
-Stephen, we gotta wait for a hose team.
-No time.
Come on!
- You ready?
- We gotta wait for a hose team.
Jump when I say.
It won't get us.
Now! Hold your breath!
Stephen!
- Steve, Steve.
- All right.
- You kicked ass, Bull.
- Way to go, Bull.
Thanks.
Man, that was
pretty crazy, huh?
I waited.
I would've waited.
- Come on. Don't worry about it.
- But you did it, man.
You did it all the way.
You were really a hero.
Brian...
it's not about being a hero.
I went in because
there was a kid up there.
I do what I do because that's my way.
And it was Dad's way.
- Maybe it's not everybody's way.
- Dad's way?
He tell you that in
a fucking séance, huh?
You said you needed
to know something.
What did you learn today, huh?
What if there had been
another kid up there?
Oh, I don't know.
What do you think, Brian?
Time to move on?
You're right.
You win, Stephen.
You're the best.
Hey, Brian?
Brian.
Hi.
Listen, Jen, I-
I've been thinking
about what you said.
If the offer's still on the table,
I'd like to talk about it.
Well, great!
That's great,
really great news.
The alderman will be thrilled
that you're working with us.
Marty's a good man, Brian.
Yeah.
So stop me if I got this wrong.
The fire's almost out, you're upstairs
on the unburned floor...
- checkin' for heat. Correct?
- Yes, sir.
- Messages for you.
- Thank you.
You've been told by your
battalion chief, your captain...
and by me not to
do nothin', right?
- Do nothin' until ordered, correct?
- Yes, sir.
Now the itch starts.
The glory boy flash starts.
"I'm a hero.
Heroes don't stand around. "
- You can tell me. That's what it was?
- Yes, sir.
So you punched out
a window for ventilation.
Was that before or after you noticed
you were standing in a lake of gasoline?
Was that before
or after you noticed...
you were standing in a lake
of gasoline, you idiot?
Before, sir.
You could have burned, killed,
or crispered half that company.
You wrecked the physical evidence that
I use to prove that it's arson.
You know how goddamn hard
it is to determine the cause.
Now go home and you
think about that.
- I'll have to call him back.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah?
- Brian McCaffrey, your new assistant.
Oh, Dennis' kid. Why don't you
go find a corner to hide in?
I'll get to you later.
I don't wanna deal with you now.
Great.
You still standing there?
I think we should get
something straight here now.
I was assigned to
this office by the city.
- You better get used to me.
- I know who you were assigned by.
I knew your father too.
He was a hell of a fireman.
He had a hell of a reputation.
But it don't cut slack here
as far as I'm concerned.
Swayzak sends you here, fine.
I gotta eat you? Those are the rules.
I got nothin'
to say about that.
Swayzak or no,
you work for me now.
Step outta line, make one false move,
you're outta here.
Don't think
you're the first.
- Let's go.
- Where we goin'?
Pest control.
Shadow, Shadow
Hi, Shadow.
Hi, Ronald. How ya doin'?
Stayin' comfortable?
- I didn't think you would make it.
- I wouldn't miss this.
- Who's that?
- He works for me.
Is he a fireman?
I like firemen.
You like everybody, Ronald.
Brian McCaffrey. Yeah, sure.
No, that's Stephen.
He's the little one
with the hat.
Oh, what a treat!
- Hey, do I know you?
- Your dad did.
- Who the hell is this guy?
- Nah, put it away.
Come on, Shadow. He lost
his dad to the animal and...
you didn't even tell him who
he was coming to see? Tell him.
Let me tell you about Ronald.
Ronald likes telephones.
Likes to tape wooden matches
to the bell strikers...
and then wrap it
in cotton with gasoline.
Had a whole little thing goin', huh?
And when you got bored?
What'd you do?
- He started makin' calls.
- Never proved.
Tell him about us
down on State Street.
Nah. Nobody cares
about that one.
It was your basic warehouse torch
I was doin' for the owner.
I mean, they were a cakewalk.
I just-
I just lost my concentration
and my animal turned on me.
Got the whole place
going like hell.
My hair was on fire, my hands.
Everything.
I was dead.
Then suddenly I was alive.
I was pulled out of there...
by my hero, my Shadow here.
Except, he didn't see this big tub
of phosphorous, did you?
Explosion lit him up so bright,
left his shadow on the wall.
Still shy about rolling up
your sleeves, Shadow?
Show him your stomach.
The funny thing
about firemen,
night and day,
they're always firemen.
Ronald Bartel.
All right, the parole board
has received...
Mr. Bartel's fitness report,
his I.D. 44,
endorsement from his section warden.
Dr. Norris?
As supervising psychiatrist,
I would describe...
Mr. Bartel's
progress as remarkable.
Taking into account
his disability and the six years...
he's already served,
I recommend a parole.
Mr. Bartel,
do you regret your crimes?
Yes, and-
and I'm aware
of the pain that I have caused.
If released, will you
commit these crimes again?
No. No, I won't.
Do you consider yourself
ready for society?
Yes, I do.
Yeah, right, Ronald.
You're ready, all right.
- Excuse me.
- Shadow.
- Remember this?
Remember this, Ronald?
- Remember who it belonged to?
- Mm-hmm.
What did you do to
that little girl?
It's not fair, Shadow.
What did you do
to that little girl?
I burned her.
You burned her.
What do you do to
old ladies, Ronald?
Burn them.
And what about the world, Ronald?
What would you like
to do with the whole world?
Burn it all.
See ya next year, Ronald.
We figured the body's
the owner, some guy named Cosgrove.
Weird blast, though,
like that other guy...
who went through
the windshield of his own car.
Explosion blew out the flame
before the engine got here.
Good for us;
not too good for him.
Bring the toolbox.
Tim, get the hot spots.
You in the cheap seats,
watch it.
There's Brian.
Well, let's go.
Hey, McCaffrey,
need a special invitation? Come on.
Charge the line, Axe.
- What do you want me to do with this?
We got heavy smoke stains
observed in entry room.
Smoke demarcation line
is very low.
Fire never got hot enough
here to cook the soot off.
Come on, you sneaky
little son-of-a-bitch.
Come on. Tell me
where you came from.
Point me where you started.
Come on.
Burn indicators distended
toward northern wall.
Less soot here, more heat.
Lack of discoloration
in shattered glass...
indicates slow burn
before explosion.
There's some little
dead rat critters here.
Fire originated in this room.
Took its time.
Hung out.
The air ran out. It couldn't breathe.
It was snuffed.
But it wasn't dead.
Must have been all that
trapped heat lying low,
waiting for some sucker
to give it one big gulp of air.
Another backdraft.
This is our point of origin.
Let me have a crowbar.
No sign of accelerants.
Well, if it's arson,
somebody figured a new way to hide it.
Okay, we got Alan Seagrave...
and Donald Cosgrove.
Both deaths due
to close encounters...
with stationary objects.
We have an office door for Cosgrove...
and, oh, an '87 Porsche for Seagrave.
No nonrelevant traumas.
No significant
blood toxicology.
Attitude of both trajectories
are consistent with explosion.
They ran the residue you scraped
from both front doors.
It's a combination of plumber's putty
and rayophene gum.
It burns almost completely
away when you light it.
- So it was on both doors?
- Yeah.
Something else I want to show you.
You're gonna have to help me.
McCaffrey, why don't you
come over and help us?
No, I don't think so.
Not in my contract.
I just rewrote your contract.
Come on over and help us.
- Anyway, we're gonna have to lift him.
- Great.
Christ, he's not gonna sell
you insurance. Just lift him up.
Hold on.
You see that patch
of shirt right there?
We wondered about
the discoloration.
So I scraped a piece off
and ran a spectro on it.
On a lucky shot,
they picked up traces of something.
What was it?
Ah, trychtichlorate.
Nobody around here
ever heard of it.
Yeah, trychtichlorate.
It eats magnesium.
It's an absorption catalyst
used in toxic waste accidents.
It's rare. They stopped making it
a couple of years ago.
We figured it got in his clothes
in a gas state from the fire.
What was it doing
in the fire?
That's your job. Okay!
Stephen, what-
What are you doing here?
Just fixin' my roof.
You've gotta stop just showing
up on the roof like this.
Look, I just- I wanted to,
I don't know, not exactly...
apologize for the other night,
especially since...
- I don't remember much.
- You remember.
Yeah, I know. I just wanted to say,
I don't know, something.
The great communicator.
So what's going on, Stephen?
You only bang on the roof
when you got something on your mind.
How's Brian doing?
- He's out. He quit.
- He just up and quit for no reason?
I don't care what you heard, Helen,
I treated him better...
than any other probie I ever had.
All right?
He probably
hates my guts...
but at least he finally
took a look in the mirror.
So once again, Stephen's right
and somebody else is wrong.
You always gotta be right.
- That's such bullshit.
- Yeah? Why?
Because I'm the first
to admit it when I'm wrong.
Yeah?
How often does that happen?
In a fire? Never!
He would have
bought it, Helen.
I'm telling ya, maybe not today,
maybe not next year;
but it would have happened.
All right? He's my brother.
I couldn't just-
You just couldn't
live with that.
McCaffrey.
Yeah?
Take the top off.
Holy shit!
That's it.
Son-of-a-bitch! This guy is different.
He don't love fire.
- Who?
- The killer.
He used magnesium to make
it look like an accident.
I got it after
we went to see Ronald.
Torchers want to fry
the whole goddamn world.
But the fires that killed those guys
never burned up that much.
The trychtichlorate hid the magnesium
in the plug, but it burned slow.
And he made
his burns backdrafts.
- But he killed these guys.
- Could have killed everybody.
Backdraft blew out the flame.
That's it. That's the reason.
- What reason?
- Why backdrafts.
Whoever fried
Seagrave and Cosgrove...
went to a hell of a lot of trouble
to make sure they died by fire.
They also made sure that
the fire blew itself out.
So that's why they used
the putty in the doors.
What do we got?
A torch with a conscience?
No. We got a stone killer
trying to make a point.
You can make the call now.
It's arson, right?
I'm not calling anyone yet.
You can't rush this.
I've seen it too many times before.
I wanna make sure
this torch doesn't walk.
We're gonna wait.
Well, well, Mr. McCaffrey.
- Welcome aboard.
- Nice boat you got here.
What?
You mean mine?
Well, not yet. Glad to have
you as part of the team, Brian.
Let's get a picture with
Mr. McCaffrey and myself.
You look good.
Yeah, there you go.
Thanks. Hi.
Yeah, have fun now.
Great night, isn't it?
Who is that?
- Larry Dewaay.
- Come on. Larry, how are ya?
Hey.
- Yeah.
- How's the job going?
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Is Rimgale getting any better?
- Rimgale's Rimgale.
-He's just doing his job.
-Doing his job? He hasn't done anything.
At this rate, he won't declare
it's arson before he retires.
Will you get me out of here?
Otherwise I'll have to go pick her up.
This is it, one of the oldest
fire stations in the city.
What do you think?
- It's homey.
The guys are sleeping upstairs.
You're gonna get me in trouble.
This is my office.
Impressive, huh?
Yes, it's very nice.
Lot of tradition locked up
in this old house.
See those doors?
They lead to the hay loft when they used
to have the old horse-drawn engines.
Lot different then.
But kind of the same,
you know?
Do you miss it?
You seem like you do.
Well, when I came back,
I, uh- I knew.
I knew that I really
wanted to be a fireman.
Then why'd you quit?
Well, I should have said
I wanted to be a good one.
So show me
your fire truck.
Mask up, lads.
Bring that sledge.
Where is it?
I don't know. There's alarms
goin' off on three floors.
This alarm system's been
screwing up since they built-
- 10? 29?
- Yeah.
How do we know if the floor's
gonna be on fire?
Well, when the doors open,
if it's hot,
- don't get out.
We're gonna start on this side.
I'll meet you down at the end.
- All right, come on. Come on.
- High-rise gigs give me the creeps.
Bull, we're early
on this one again...
and it ain't even broke out yet.
We're one short with Brian gone.
- Wait for the next-in engines.
- Let's catch it before it breaks out.
- You want to learn something?
- Yeah, I do.
Axe, go with Pengelly.
Take the other side.
-Don't split us up again. It ain't safe.
-I haven't got time for this.
- Then let me take the lead.
- Do your job; they need a line.
Come on.
Come on, Axe.
Oh, you're so very sly;
but, so am I.
She's hot and smoky...
but she's not rollin' yet.
- Shit!
Hello, 51.
You follow 17 in the truck.
11201 South Clark.
It's a cancel.
11021 South Clark.
- South Clark.
- What time is it, anyway?
All right, take it.
Wait, wait.
Make sure you check it first.
Oh, yeah.
- Howdy, boys.
- Brian!
- Here we go. Now get that mask back on.
- Right.
Clear!
Stay here.
Check that door for heat, Tim?
Tim!
Watch out, Steve.
I got him. Move off.
Put it out!
Stretcher!
Get the goddamn stretcher.
Everybody over here.
Through here. Through here.
Get that stretcher over here.
What the hell happened?
Oh, my God! Tim!
Tim! How'd it happen?
Breathe, Tim, breathe.
Get him in there!
Come on!
- You're all right.
- Come on! Hang on, kid!
- Hey, Shadow, I got one here.
- Oh, Christ.
Some guy named Holcomb.
Steve.
Steve, you all right?
- How is he?
- He's alive.
- Is he gonna make it?
- They're not saying.
He's in there.
I'm sorry.
You can't come in now.
Please stay outside.
I should have been there.
None of us should
have been there, Brian.
Don't tell me
about the chance I'm taking.
- You were costing me time.
- You didn't wait for back-up.
- You were wrong.
- What the hell is your problem?
- This part of your investigation?
- You had to do it.
You had to be myth man,
taking another fire bare-handed...
-instead of looking out for your probie.
-We need space.
- Is that what happened?
- I had that fire. He didn't listen.
He's a candidate,
your responsibility.
You shouldn't have had him
up there in the first place.
You burned him, Stephen.
- Fuck you.
- Don't you walk away from me.
Yo, Brian. Let's go.
Goddamn it!
Get him off!
Come on!
Easy, man.
Loosen up!
You're just making things worse.
- Relax. Forget about it.
- Come on. Come on.
- Inspector.
- Alderman.
Chinese sponge cake?
When are you gonna catch
the prick that's doing this, Don?
- Don?
- Don't you have any leads?
No, Marty, I don't.
We haven't found any connection
between the victims at all.
Jesus Christ.
Open your eyes.
You got Seagrave, Cosgrove...
- and now Holcomb.
- Holcomb?
Put 'em together.
It's a goddamn list.
I didn't know the name of
that victim had been released.
- Hey, John.
- Morning.
I'll do whatever
you want me to do.
I want to help you nail
that son-of-a-bitch that burned Tim.
Show me how.
Thought old Marty was
acting a little strange.
He's right.
There's residue.
Holcomb is the third victim.
The backdraft was set up
somewhere in there.
Fried Holcomb
when he opened the inner door.
But the outer door held
and it waited for Tim.
In a word, Brian,
what is this job all about?
Fire.
It's a living thing, Brian.
It breathes, it eats,
and it hates.
The only way to beat it...
is to think like it;
to know this flame will spread
this way across the door...
and up across the ceiling;
not because of the physics
of flammable liquids,
but because it wants to.
Some guys, fire owns 'em.
Makes 'em fight it on its level.
But the only way to truly kill it...
is to love it a little,
just like Ronald.
- Hi.
- I heard your friend's gonna be okay.
- Thanks.
We checked and your boss
was partners...
with all the murder victims
in a company called Lakeside Dynamics.
He's keeping that a secret.
I wanna know why.
- I don't know anything about that.
- You might be able to find out.
- Get me his files.
- Do you know what you're asking?
Yeah.
Four years ago I was punching
a cash register.
Two years ago, Marty Swayzak
didn't even know my name.
I was bringing
the guy coffee.
I practically run
that office now.
And Marty-
He believes in me.
I just don't-
You're asking me to
throw that all away.
Your boss is a liar.
Stephen?
I'm sorry, Helen.
I just couldn't sleep.
Well, what's wrong?
It used to be real clear.
When I was a kid,
what meant most to me
about this job was...
no "ifs. "
Somebody called
the fire department, we came.
We just showed up.
Those guys, they just don't know
how much I love 'em.
You don't leave people hangin'.
It holds everything up,
doesn't it?
Loyalty.
I don't get it.
"Till death do us part. "
Isn't that what you heard, Helen?
You go, we go.
It's all the same...
piece of shit without that,
isn't it?
It's the end of everything.
I'm sorry I came.
There's just nobody
I can talk to.
I really miss you.
You sure you really want
to put grape jelly in the eggs?
Yeah, it's part of my formula.
It's an experiment.
- It's an experiment?
- Yeah.
Let's get these eggs going.
- Hey, I want to do that.
- Can you do it?
That's good.
I'll put that in the formula.
- You gonna leave the shells?
- Yeah.
- They're part of the formula?
I guess you know
what you're doing.
- I know what I'm doing.
Mom!
I didn't know
you'd be up so early.
Mom, go back to bed.
We're making you breakfast in bed.
- Stephen, can I talk to you a minute?
- Yeah.
You keep going there.
You're doing good.
He knows what he's doin'.
He told me he likes those piano lessons
you got him taking.
It's just I don't want
to confuse him, you know.
I knew who you were
when we got married.
I knew how you did things.
And-
I mean, you haven't-
I just can't anymore.
I just- you know,
I gotta worry about Sean.
- Yeah.
- I mean, you're the best.
You really are.
But the chances
that you take just-
You scare me now.
Sean.
Listen, I, uh-
I blew it.
I forgot that
I gotta work this morning.
So, um-
That's all right.
We'll just do it again next Saturday.
- All right?
- Mom's crying.
The latest polls came in, Marty.
Marty?
Jesus Christ, Marty.
What's going on?
We have a city planners
meeting in 15 minutes.
Marty.
You've gotta level with me, Marty.
Is there something about
these deaths you're not telling me?
No.
- What's this?
- Just take it.
Rimgale's gonna wanna
talk to Swayzak about this.
I'm sorry.
- That's a dumb thing to say.
- You're right.
Good-bye, Brian.
What the hell you do
with this thing?
What do you mean?
I drove it, Joe.
This is a copy of Swayzak's report
that we know is bullshit;
but we could never argue with
the numbers because they're airtight.
This file she gave you
proves it's phoney.
I checked on the firm that recommended
the cuts to Swayzak's task force.
They've done exactly one job,
a manpower study.
I checked further and it's not even
a company. No employees... nothing.
- Just a P.O. box.
- I wonder who wrote that report.
- Someone who knows how to work numbers.
- Exactly.
Like a bunch of
dead financial wizards.
- Seagrave, Holcomb, Cosgrove-
- And Swayzak.
Why did he go through
this trouble to cut firehouses?
When a firehouse closes, Swayzak
converts it into a community center.
- That's sweet.
- Lakeside Dynamics, remember them?
They get all
the expensive construction work.
I'm telling you,
this is a total scam.
These guys were
making a ton of money.
It's time we had a little talk
with Mr. Swayzak. Let's go.
Mr. Swayzak?
Gas. Check in there.
Come on. Come on!
- Let's go. Come on!
- Hey, kid.
I think I've got
a problem here.
Is it true that you were rescued
by the fire department's arson team?
That's quite a bunch
of guys, huh?
I'm so goddamn helpless here.
I can't do a fucking thing.
- What do you want me to do?
- I've been lying here thinkin'.
For hours... thinkin'
and thinkin' and thinkin'.
We're close.
But we're not lookin'
in the right place,
not in the right place.
So, you've come to pick
Ronald's brains...
because nobody knows
the animal like Ronald.
It must've looked like
it was going to be...
a medium deal, didn't it,
when your father bought it?
What?
Did you watch him when he made
that ballsy jump and saved-
I didn't come to talk
about my father.
I sent away for a copy of that "Life"
with your picture on the cover.
It's a collectible.
- Who's doing this, Ronald?
- Wrong question.
Who isn't?
It isn't a spark, is it?
Because there isn't enough damage...
and he wouldn't
have had any fun.
It isn't an insurance pro
because there isn't any profit.
- Who does that leave us with?
- What's his tool?
How does he do it?
How does he talk to the fire?
- The outlets.
- No.
That's a probie.
That's beneath you, Brian.
Trychtichlorate.
Very good. Very good.
You still haven't
put it together?
- I have.
- Then who, Ronald?
You wanna know who?
I wanna know...
if this kid
really wanted to be...
just like his dad.
Did he?
Okay.
I'm outta here.
All right!
I wanted to be him, okay?
I wanted to be him
more than anything.
You loved him.
Yeah.
You watched him dance with the animal.
You saw your dad burn.
Fuck you, Ronald!
Who the hell's doin' this?
Did it look at you?
Did the fire look at you?
It did.
Our worlds aren't
that far apart, are they?
So...
whoever did this really knows
the animal well, don't they?
They know him real well
but they won't let him loose.
They won't let him have fun
so they don't love him.
Who doesn't love fire...
and is around trychtichlorate
all day long?
Oh, my God!
That wasn't such a long walk
after all, was it?
Oh, my God.
Goddamn it, Stephen.
Hey, what's goin' on?
I just came by to see
how you were doing.
How am I doin'?
Well, I'm sellin' Dad's boat.
Guy comin' by in a few minutes
to take a look at it.
What are you gonna do?
I mean, where you going?
I didn't say I was goin' anywhere.
Look, I gotta-
I gotta get back.
- There's somethin' I'm supposed to do.
- What?
What do you gotta do?
Look at you.
Look at your face!
All the things you must be thinkin'.
You really hate my guts,
don't you?
You know something, Brian?
That's all right.
- Maybe we should talk about it-
- You don't like me...
because I was no genius in the way
I raised you. Is that it?
Dad was gone!
What was I supposed to do?
- You tell me.
- Forget it. It's okay.
I tried. I wanted so
many things for you...
that I couldn't even hope for.
Because after that,
I had no choices!
Well, I'm not your father.
You got somewhere to go, go.
People change, huh, Brian?
Sometimes right
when you're lookin' at 'em.
What's going on with you?
I don't know.
Do you?
I gotta go.
Attention,
all units responding.
This is gonna be a hazardous materials
response at a chemical plant.
- Stephen? Has Stephen gotten back yet?
- He just pulled up.
- Is it Adcox?
- How do you know?
I didn't until you came to the boat
lookin' for those chemicals.
- Lookin' for me.
- What were they doing on the boat?
Axe gave 'em to me.
They're cleaning shit.
- We gotta roll!
- I'll be there in a minute.
I gotta go to Rimgale
with this.
- They're pullin' a box.
- I'll be there!
- Stephen!
- Wait! I'm his lieutenant.
I'll handle it.
Stephen?
Are you a part of this?
No.
You're sure?
That's the only thing
I am sure of anymore.
Bull, we need you.
Jesus Christ!
Stephen!
Shit!
Get out of the way!
- You all right?
- You all right, Peng?
- Everybody all right?
- You okay?
Yeah. Help me out.
Where's 17?
- I don't know.
- Shit!
Stephen!
- Where's 17?
- 17's on the roof.
Mask up.
We got a chemical fire.
We're pullin' the plug.
Everybody off the roof, now!
- Jesus Christ, Axe.
- You don't understand.
My cousin, Sally,
used to work at Swayzak's office.
She saw the files.
She saw what he did.
- You set me up with those chemicals?
- I'm tryin' to explain.
- Stephen.
- You back off!
- Axe.
- Somebody had to stop these pricks.
- Are you thinkin'? You burned people!
- You didn't see.
- You're a fireman.
- When Sally showed me Swayzak's files-
- I should've let you in on it.
- In on murder?
Those assholes were closin' firehouses,
gettin' our friends killed for money.
- I had to do it for the department!
- For Tim?
- That was an accident.
- Did you start that fire?
Why'd you have to go
in there so fucking early?
That's why you
wanted me to wait.
- Let me finish Swayzak!
- No. It's over.
Your dad would puke if he saw
how you shit on his department.
- What would he say about what you do?
- Your dad died...
saving my life, and these people
were killin' firemen for money.
- Swayzak.
- He killed our friends for money.
What the fuck would you do?
You're his lieutenant.
You've gotta handle this.
It's going!
Get to the side!
It's gonna go!
17! Somebody!
I'm in the elevator shaft.
Help me!
Help, somebody!
17, help!
- Brian!
- Stephen!
I'm burning up in here!
- You all right?
- Yeah. You all right?
Come on.
We gotta go get him.
We gotta get outta here.
The whole place is goin' up.
Look out!
Come on. This way.
Wait a minute. Brian!
Jesus!
I just couldn't
let it go, Bull.
Yeah.
- I got ya.
Let me go, Bull.
You go... we go.
Stephen!
Nooo!
Don't move.
Don't move, damn it.
- What?
- Just lie down.
Oh, shit!
Pengelly, up here!
Did you hear somebody?
Stephen!
- Pengelly!
- Up here!
- Where's he at?
- Over there!
Pengelly!
We're gonna get you outta here.
Lay down. Don't move.
Get goin'!
Pengelly, I lost the line.
I'm going for the hose.
Brian!
- Go!
- All right, move it!
Come on.
Look at him.
That's my brother,
goddamn it.
How is he?
Is he okay?
- Let's move it. Let's go.
- Hang on.
Let's move it, now!
- Up with him!
- Come on.
- All right, Bull.
- He's gonna make it.
I gotta get this collar on.
Come on. Help us out.
I don't want it.
Brian?
Don't tell them about Adcox.
Don't let them.
- It'll hurt the department.
- I won't.
- Monitor on.
- I'm sorry. I thought-
90 over 60.
I'm sorry
I ever thought you-
I know.
- I- I beat it.
- Blood pressure: 80 over 60.
The fire never got me.
Hang in there.
- You're gonna make it!
Lidocaine, now!
- Is he going to be all right?
- He's spiking!
Who's your brother, Brian?
You are, Stephen.
Lidocaine in.
I'm tired of hearing
the sirens.
Turn... turn the siren off, Brian.
Turn the siren off.
You're gonna be all right,
goddamn it!
Hang in! Let's go!
Move this thing.
Don't you die on me now.
You hear me?
Hang in there.
We're almost there.
It's not your time now.
I need you.
You're gonna make it.
Clear!
Starting compression.
One, two, three, four, five.
One, two, three,
four, five.
One, two, three, four, five.
One, two-
In the Chicago fire department...
the alarm code 3-3-5 signifies...
that the company has
returned home to quarters.
We will now ring out
that code to welcome home...
Firefighter John Adcox and
Lieutenant Stephen McCaffrey.
Honor guard,
hand salute!
Honor guard, dismissed!
Gentlemen, can we help you?
Police. We have a subpoena
for Alderman Swayzak.
- Ah, Inspector-
- Alderman Swayzak, how are you doin'?
- This will only take a minute.
- I'm in a press conference.
These detectives would like to
question you why you secretly paid...
Donald Cosgrove, Jeffrey Holcomb,
and Alan Seagrave...
to create a phoney manpower study.
Ask him who made money
off firemen dying.
You see that glow flashing
in the corner of your eye?
That's your career
dissipation light.
It just went into high gear.
I'll have my aides look into it
as soon as they can. Thank you.
Mr. Alderman has no further comment.
This conference is over.
...1718 West Maplewood.
1718 West Maplewood.
Got it, Cap?
Okay, into the truck.
Code 32.
Nightengale!
We're gonna be damn busy.
Salsa!
You're doin' it wrong!
Thanks.
All right.