What are you doing?
We don't stop here.
Get out of the car.
The boys found this on the floor,
in the back of the Caddy.
Yeah, they showed me.
Could be unrelated.
Could be.
Any of those dead kids
wearing pearl earrings?
No.
Could be someone's missing, maybe.
That’s what I'm thinking.
Just one more bag after that.
I just wanted to come here.
To Winkie's?
This Winkie's.
Okay. Why this Winkie's?
It’s kind of embarrassing.
Go ahead.
- I had a dream about this place.
- Oh, boy.
See what I mean?
Okay, so you had a dream
about this place.
Tell me.
Well...
it’s the second one I've had.
But they're both the same.
They start out that I'm in here but...
it’s not day or night...
it’s kind of half-night, you know?
But it looks just like this.
Except for the light.
And I'm scared like I can't
tell you.
Of all people...
you're standing right over there.
By that counter.
You're in both dreams
and you're scared.
I get even more frightened when
I see how afraid you are, and...
then I realize what it is.
There's a man...
in back of this place.
He's the one who's doing it.
I can see him through the wall.
I can see his face.
I hope that I never see that face
ever outside of the dream.
That’s it.
So... you came to see
if he's out there.
To get rid of this
god-awful feeling.
Right then.
It’s around the back.
Dan! Dan, are you all right?
What is it, Dan? Dan?
Hello?
The girl is still missing.
- Talk to me.
- The same.
I can't believe it.
Well, it's time to say
good-bye, Betty.
- It’s been so nice traveling with you.
- Thank you, Irene.
I was so excited and nervous. It was
sure great to have you to talk to.
- I'll watch for you on the big screen.
- Okay, Irene.
Won't that be the day?
Good luck, Betty dear.
- Take care of yourself and be careful.
- I will.
Thanks, again.
Betty, it was so nice meeting you.
All the luck in the world.
Thank you.
- My bags?
- Where to?
1612, Hayvenhurst.
Got it.
- Ten bucks says you're Betty.
- Yes, I am, Mrs. Lenoix.
- It is Mrs. Lenoix, isn't it?
- In all my living glory, baby.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Call me Coco. Everybody else does.
- Wait there and I'll go get the key.
- Okay, Coco.
Wilkins!
If that damn dog craps
in the courtyard one more time...
I'm just gonna bank his little butt for
breakfast! You don't have any pets?
- No, I don't.
- They're allowed.
I just don't like them
in here for obvious reasons.
There was a man that lived here once
that had a prizefighting kangaroo.
You just wouldn't believe what that
kangaroo did to this courtyard.
Let’s go see your aunt’s apartment.
It’s a good one.
I can hardly wait.
- It’s unbelievable!
- I told you.
You and your aunt probably have
an understanding, so here's the key.
And if you need anything,
just give a holler.
Everybody in this building is pretty
much okay with me...
or they wouldn't be here.
If you like, later on
I'll introduce you around.
Well, no hard feelings if you don't.
I'm sorry. My aunt Ruth didn't tell
me someone was gonna be here.
- I'm so sorry.
- It’s okay.
I'm Ruth's niece. My name is Betty.
I'm sure she told you I was coming.
There was an accident.
I came here.
I understand. I saw the dress.
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
What happened?
A car...
a car accident.
Are you okay?
I think so.
I was just...
taking a shower.
Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
I'll let you get back to that.
I'm gonna get unpacked.
What’s your name?
I'm sorry, I'll get out of here.
We can talk later.
My name is...
Rita.
Do you work with my aunt?
- No, I...
- I'm sorry...
it 's none of my business.
She has pretty red hair.
She's letting me stay here while
she's working on a movie...
that 's being made in Canada,
but I guess you already know that.
I couldn't afford a place like this
in a million years.
Unless, of course, I'm discovered
and become a movie star.
Of course, I'd rather be known as
a great actress than a movie star...
but sometimes people
end up being both. So...
that is, I guess you'd say,
the story of why I came here.
I'm sorry. I'm just
so excited to be here.
I just came here from Deep River,
Ontario, and now I'm in this...
dream place!
Well, you can imagine how I feel.
Sit down.
Where were you hurt?
- We should call a doctor.
- No.
- But this could be serious.
- No, I need to sleep.
If you have a concussion,
you shouldn't sleep.
I'll be okay if I sleep.
I just need to lie down
here and sleep.
You see, Adam, there
are some suggestions...
that ought to be brought forward.
And I know you said you would
entertain suggestions.
And that 's all anybody
here is asking you to do.
- What are you talking about?
- An open mind.
You're in the process of recasting
your lead actress, and I'm...
we are asking you to keep
an open mind.
What was it the last time?
- Okay, lets try the next one.
- He's not gonna like it.
We'll see.
Castigliani brothers!
Let me introduce you around.
Please...
take a seat. This is Mr. Darby,
whom you know.
And this is the director,
Adam Kesher.
And his manager,
Robert Smith.
She's very pretty.
May I offer you gentlemen anything?
- Espresso.
- Nothing.
- What 's the photo for?
- One espresso.
No, that 's it.
I think you're going to enjoy
your espresso this time.
I've done quite a bit of research...
knowing how hard
you are to please.
This one comes
highly recommended.
- What 's the photo for?
- It 's a recommendation.
A recommendation to you, Adam.
- It 's not a recommendation.
- This is the girl.
What girl? For what?
What is this, Ray?
We'd be happy to put her on the
list for considerations.
You'd be pleased to know, there's
quite a bit of interest in this role.
Interest? There's six of the top
actresses that want this thing.
This is the girl.
- Ray, take care of this.
- Hold on, hold on, Adam.
Hold on?
There's no way!
Napkin.
Pardon?
Of course.
Excuse me.
Is that all, sir?
- Shit.
- Sorry. That was highly recommended.
That is considered one of the finest
espressos in the world!
What 's going on here? There is
no way that girl is in my movie!
- This is the girl.
- Hey, that girl is not in my film!
It 's no longer your film.
This is the girl.
Castigliani brothers get out
of that limo?
- The two guys in dark suits?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
- Leave that door open.
Castigliani brothers?
Beat it, pal.
Good afternoon, Mr. Roque.
Her name is Camilla Rhodes.
The director doesn't want her.
Do you want him replaced?
I know they said...
Then?
Then...
that means we should...?
Yes?
Shut everything down?
Is that something that...
Do you want us to shut
everything down?
Then we'll shut everything down.
Oh, man, that 's unheard of.
An accident like that, who could
have foreseen that, man?
- It 's unreal, right?
- Yeah.
Unbelievable, man.
So, bro? God, you look good.
- What have you been doing?
- You know, just...
doing some stuff
for this guy.
Are you making ends meet?
Hardly.
I know, man, look at my digs.
Times are tough, bro.
Hey... man, it 's not that bad.
I hope you're not gonna
get in any trouble.
That was just a thing, man.
That story? That made you laugh!
- That was a funny story, man.
- Fucking car accident!
Hey, so that 's... that 's it, huh?
That 's Ed's famous black book.
The history of the world...
in phone numbers.
Oh, man!
Something bit me bad!
Hey, man!
She's hurt real bad! Could you come
here and call on the phone, please?
She's hurt real bad! You gotta
come in here and call the hospital!
Come on, man! I'm serious about this!
I can't do everything by myself!
Hey, man.
Oh, man!
Aunt Ruth, I'll try. I'm gonna study
those lines until I know them...
inside out.
Either right here on
this fabulous leather couch...
or I'll take them with
a coffee into the courtyard...
like a regular movie star.
I got a real shock to find your
friend Rita here.
She was in the shower
and I opened the door!
Rita!
What do you mean?
She was in an accident.
Rita. Your friend.
No, Coco unlocked the door.
No, she didn't see her.
She's sleeping.
I'm sure there's some explanation for
this. I don't think we have to do that.
Please, don't worry. Aunt Ruth,
we don't need the police.
You're awake.
I think I misunderstood.
I thought you knew my aunt
and that 's why you were here.
I just talked to my aunt on the phone
and she wants me to call the police.
Rita?
I'm sorry, I...
What is it, Rita?
I thought when I woke up...
I thought sleep would do it.
What 's wrong?
I just don't know who I am.
- What do you mean? You're Rita.
- No, I'm not.
I don't know what my name is.
I don't know who I am.
This is your purse.
Your name must be in your purse.
You wanna know, don't you?
- Yes, but...
- Open it.
- Sure you don't want anything?
- Not here.
- Thanks.
- A drink or something?
No. Thanks, though.
I'll take a cigarette,
if you have one.
Yeah, just reach inside my
shirt pocket there.
Any new girls on the street lately?
No.
I haven't seen any.
A brunette?
Maybe a little beat-up?
No.
- Keep your eyes open for me, okay?
- Sure.
You bet you will.
That money...
you don't know where it came from?
When you think of them,
the money and the key...
does it make you
remember anything?
There's something...
something...
there.
What did you say?
- They fired everyone.
- Who fired everyone?
Ray did!
Wait! I'm talking on the phone.
They closed the set. Everybody's
gone. You'd better get down here.
No.
You've gotta talk to Ray.
You've gotta fix this.
I'm going home.
Home?
Meet me at the office, we gotta do
something. You gotta do something!
- I'm going home, Cynthia.
- Adam, this isn't like you.
Please, come to the office. There's
gotta be something we can do!
I'm going home.
I wonder where you were going.
Mulholland Drive.
Mulholland Drive?
That 's where I was going.
Mulholland Drive.
Maybe that 's where
the accident was.
There must be a police report.
We could call.
We could call anonymously just
to see if there was an accident.
It'll be just like in the movies!
We'll pretend to be someone else.
I wanna walk around, anyway.
I'm in Hollywood and
I haven't even seen any of it.
Come on, Rita,
do you feel up to it?
Okay.
But just...
just to see.
Just to see if there was
an accident...
on Mulholland Drive.
Lorraine?
You're home?
Now you've done it!
Just forget you ever saw it.
It 's better that way.
What the hell are you
even doing here?
What are you doing?
That 's my jewelry!
- That bastard. You bastard!
- He's probably upset, Lorraine.
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Adam, stop it!
You're hurting me! Gene!
You're hurting me!
That ain't no way to treat your
wife. I don't care what she's done.
Throw him out!
Damn you, Adam!
Get out!
Let 's hide it.
There's one.
- Los Angeles Police Department.
- I'm inquiring about an accident...
...last night on Mulholland Drive.
- I'll connect you to Traffic.
- Sergeant Baker.
- Hi, I'm inquiring...
I heard a sound last night that
sounded sort of like a car crash.
I want to know if there was an
accident on Mulholland Drive.
Yes, there was.
- Can you tell me what happened?
- No, I can't.
- Was anyone hurt?
- May I have your name, please?
There was an accident.
He wouldn't tell me anything else,
but that was your accident, Rita.
Maybe there's something
about it in the papers.
Come on, I'll buy you a cup of
coffee and we can see.
Maybe it happened so late it 's
not in today's paper.
There's nothing?
Not that I can see.
That 's okay.
Thanks.
Diane.
Will that be all?
Would you like your check?
Rita, you want something?
- No, just... just the coffee.
- We'll take our check.
What is it, Rita?
I remember something.
I remember something!
- What is it?
- Diane Selwyn.
Maybe that 's my name!
"D. Selwyn." It 's the only one.
I'm gonna call.
- It is strange to be calling yourself.
- Maybe it 's not me.
Hello, it's me.
Leave a message.
That 's not my voice.
But I know her!
Maybe that isn't Diane Selwyn's
voice. Maybe that 's your roommate.
Or if it is Diane Selwyn,
she could tell you who you are.
Maybe.
Maybe, maybe...
Adam Kesher?
- Adam Kesher?
- Get lost!
- This is Adam Kesher's house.
- Like hell it is! Get out now!
Get out!
Adam Kesher?
Get out of here!
He's never coming back! Ever!
- Bastard.
- I guess you don't understand English.
She said leave. Here's the door.
Gene!
Get out!
Adam Kesher?
- Yeah, what is it, Cookie?
- I'm sorry, Mr. Kesher...
but there seems to be some
problem with your credit cards.
What? I pay you cash, Cookie.
Listen, two guys from
your bank came by.
My bank?
- How'd they know I was here?
- I don't know.
What 'd they say?
They said to tell you that you're
maxed out at your bank...
and that your line of credit
has been canceled.
That 's unbelievable.
Well, look...
I don't know what 's going on.
That is so much baloney.
- I got enough cash for you, Cookie.
- I know, I know. Don't worry.
But I'm sorry, it 's my duty
to inform you...
listen, man,
whoever you're hiding from...
they know where you are.
Right.
I'm sorry.
Hello?
- Someone maybe shut off my money.
- I know. Where are you, Adam?
- Sorry, what do you mean you know?
- Somebody called...
they told me you were as good as
broke. So I made a few calls.
- And?
- You're broke.
I'm not broke!
I know, but you're broke.
Where are you?
- I'm at Cookie's, downtown.
- Do you know somebody called...
"The Cowboy"?
- "The cowboy"?
- Yeah.
"The Cowboy". This guy,
the Cowboy, wants to see you.
Jason said he thought
it would be a good idea.
Jason thought it would be a good
idea for me to go see the Cowboy.
Should I wear my 1O-gallon hat
and my six-shooters?
Something tells me that this guy
is connected to what 's happening.
Adam, I think you should do it, and
you should do it right away.
- What 's going on, Cynthia?
- It's been a very strange day.
And getting stranger.
Where do I meet this Cowboy? Do you
have to ride out to the range?
Sort of, funny boy.
If I tell him the meeting's on...
you'll go to the top of the Beachwood
Canyon, there's a corral up there...
...where he'll be.
- You've gotta be kidding me.
Will you meet with him?
Yeah.
Sure. This has been
that kind of a day. When?
I'll call him right away
and then I'll call you back.
You know, you could stay at
my place, if you wanted.
- I don't think that 'd be a good idea.
- I was just offering a place to stay.
Yes, and I appreciate the offer,
Cynthia. I'll find a place.
Just go on and give that cowboy
a yodel and get on back to me.
Okay. But you don't know
what you're missing.
Just get along, little doggie.
And call me back.
It 's right about here. Sierra Bonita.
It 's not too far away.
What 's wrong with that?
I'm not sure about this.
I know you're afraid of something.
We'll be careful. I promise.
Tomorrow. We'll go over there...
and we'll find out.
It'll be okay.
It 's probably Coco.
- Yes, may I help you?
- Someone is in trouble!
Who are you?
What are you doing
in Ruth's apartment?
She's letting me stay here.
I'm her niece. My name's Betty.
No, it 's not!
That 's not what she said.
Someone is in trouble!
Something bad is happening!
I'm sorry, but I don't know
who you are and...
Louise?
What are you doing, Louise?
I've been trying to get hold of you
since 3 o'clock this afternoon.
That one is in my room and
she won't leave!
I want you to get her out.
I want you to get her out now.
This is Louise Bonner.
I'm sure she meant well.
Louise, this is Betty,
this is Ruth's niece.
I was on my way over here to see
Betty. Betty is a young actress.
I was delivering some faxed pages of
a scene for a big audition tomorrow.
- Well, here they are, honey.
- Thank you.
Come along now, Louise.
I'll take you home.
I'm sorry.
It happens sometimes. Come on.
No, she said it was someone
else who was in trouble.
Stop it, Louise!
I'm taking you home. Come on.
- Good night, Betty.
- Good night.
Good night.
Cowboy...
- Howdy.
- Howdy to you.
Beautiful evening.
Thank you for coming all the way
up here to see me from that...
nice hotel downtown.
No problem.
What 's on your mind?
Well, now. Here's a man who
wants to get right down to it.
Kind of anxious
to get to it, are you?
Whatever.
A man's attitude...
a man's attitude goes some ways
the way his life will be.
Is that something
you might agree with?
Sure!
Did you answer because that 's what
you thought I wanted to hear...
or did you think about what I said...
and answered 'cause you
truly believe that to be right?
I agree with what you said. Truly.
What 'd I say?
That a man's attitude determines to
a large extent how his life will be.
So since you agree...
you must be a person who does not
care about the good life.
How's that?
Well, stop for a little second...
and think about it.
Can you do that for me?
Okay. I'm thinking.
No, you're not. You're too busy
being a smart aleck to be thinking.
Now, I want you to think
and stop being a smart aleck.
Can you try that for me?
Look, where's this going?
What do you want me to do?
There's sometimes a buggy.
How many drivers does a buggy have?
One.
So let 's just say
I'm driving this buggy.
And if you fix your attitude,
you can ride along with me.
I want you to go back
to work tomorrow.
You were recasting the lead actress.
Audition many girls for the part.
When you see the girl that was shown
to you earlier today, you will say:
"This is the girl."
The rest of the cast can stay.
That 's up to you.
But that lead girl
is not up to you.
Now, you will see me one more
time if you do good.
You'll see me two more times
if you do bad.
Good night.
- You're still here?
- I thought that 's what you wanted.
- Nobody wants you here!
- Really?
My parents are right upstairs.
They think you've left!
- So? Surprise.
- I can call them. I can call my dad.
- But you won't.
- Lf you're trying to blackmail me...
it 's not going to work! You're
playing a dangerous game here.
You know what I want.
It 's not that difficult.
Get out!
Get out before I call my dad!
He trusts you!
You're his best friend.
This will be the
end of everything.
What about you?
What will your dad think about you?
Stop! Just stop it! That 's what
you said from the beginning.
If I tell what happened, they'll
arrest you and put you in jail.
Get out of here before...
- Before what?
- Before...
...I kill you.
- Then they'd put you in jail.
Then I cry, cry, cry,
and then I say with big emotion...
"I hate you! I hate us both!"
- Such a lame scene.
- But you are really good.
Thank you, darling.
Hi, there. Who are you?
Betty?
Betty, can I see you outside
for a minute?
What is it, Coco?
Your aunt called.
I was afraid of that.
She wants to know who's
staying in her apartment.
It 's just for a night or two.
Until she finds her own place.
I tried to explain that to aunt Ruth
but the connection was bad...
and her plane was leaving,
and she got it all mixed up.
I kept telling her
that it was my friend Rita...
and she kept saying
she didn't know any Ritas.
- Look at me straight, sweetie.
- Coco, she's very nice.
Honey, you're a good kid...
but what you're telling me is
a load of horse puckey.
Even though it
comes from a good place.
I'm gonna trust you
to sort this thing out.
- Thank you.
- Don't make me out to be a sucker.
Louise Bonner said there is trouble
in there, remember last night?
Well, sometimes she's wrong...
but if there is trouble,
get rid of it.
Is everything all right?
- Is it bad for you that I'm here?
- No, no, everything is A-Okay.
Now, I've gotta fix that sandwich.
And my audition is in one hour!
I hope I'm back
in a couple of hours.
- And don't drink all the Coke.
- Good luck.
When I get back, I'll keep the
cab waiting, so be ready to go.
"Voilà!"
Betty Elms, I would
like you to meet...
Jack Tutman, my assistant.
Woody Katz, who we have
cast in the part of Chuck...
and will do the scene with you.
Bob Rooker, our director...
and Julie Chadwick.
Now, our surprise guest,
Lynne James.
Alas, we can't afford her to
cast our show but...
well, as casting agents go,
she is the best.
Why, thank you, Wally.
Hello, Betty.
- Very pleased to meet you.
- This is my assistant, Nikki.
And the ever lovely Martha. Martha
Johnson, whom you met out front.
Hi.
So, shall we give it a go?
Would you like a water,
a coffee before we begin?
No, I'm fine.
Well then,
let 's everyone take a seat.
Betty, why don't you join Woody
over there and we'll play the scene.
Bob, do you have anything
you wish to say?
Something to Betty
before we begin?
No. It 's not a contest.
The two of them...
with themselves.
So don't play it for real...
until it gets real.
Okay.
Just tell me where it hurts, baby.
What?
I wanna play this one nice and close
like we did with that other girl...
what 's her name? With the black
hair. It felt good, what do you think?
That 's good, Woody. Just don't rush
that line again. I told you...
the line where you say:
"Before what?"
Bobby, acting is reacting.
I just play off them. They all say:
"They're gonna arrest you", like
that, and: "They'll put you in jail."
They say it the same way.
So when they say it, I just react.
- What 's your name?
- Betty.
Betty, look. You don't rush it,
I don't rush it, okay?
Now, we're gonna play this nice and
close just like in the movies, okay?
Dad's best friend goes to work.
Bob?
And...
action!
You're still here.
I came back.
- I thought that 's what you wanted.
- Nobody wants you here.
Really?
My parents are right upstairs.
They think you've left.
So, surprise!
- I can call them, I can call my dad.
- But you won't.
You're playing a dangerous
game here.
If you're trying to blackmail me...
it 's not gonna work.
You know what I want.
It 's not that difficult.
Get out.
Get out before I call my dad.
He trusts you. You're his...
best friend.
This will be the end
of everything.
What about you? What'll
your dad think about you?
Stop.
Stop it.
That 's what you said from
the beginning.
If I tell them what happened, they
will arrest you and put you in jail.
So get out of here...
before...
Before what?
Before...
I kill you.
Well, then they'd put you in jail.
I hate you.
I hate us both.
- I'm gonna take her over there.
- Yeah, big time.
Well, there it was.
Yeah, there it was, all right. Baby,
you got a way with you. Really.
Bob?
Very good. Really.
I mean, it was forced maybe,
but still humanistic.
Very good. Really!
Really.
Oh, I thank you, Betty.
And I really mean that, sincerely.
I mean, it was...
extraordinary.
You've done your aunt proud today.
I'm going to tell
her that first chance I get.
Now, you and I are going
to speak again very soon.
- Thank you, Mr. Brown.
- Thank you, Wally.
I'm sure you all have a lot to talk
about. We'll walk Betty out.
Yes, indeed.
And it was our pleasure, Lynne.
Don't you be a stranger around here.
We'd love to have you here.
- Come on, Betty.
- Thank you again, Mr. Brown.
And it was nice meeting
all of you.
Bye.
Bye!
She's a slam-dunk! Where
the hell did you find her?
God, that was awful!
Not you, Betty. You were stellar,
and I mean that. But poor Wally.
He'll never get that picture made.
Wally's days were up 2O years ago.
You know Woody Katz
is only doing it for a favor.
And the cast they have
so far is terrible.
Oh, God, terrible!
That poor old fool Wally.
He was very nice
and he seems so sweet.
And Wally... Mr. Brown is a very
close friend of my aunt 's.
Don't get me wrong, I love Wally.
I ought to, I was married
to him for 1O years.
And I love actors. All actors.
We just get a little catty sometimes.
We want to take you across and
introduce you to a director...
who's a head above the rest.
He's got a project
you will kill for.
Knock right out of the park!
Sixteen reasons
Why I love you
- One
- The way you hold my hand
- Two
- Your laughing eyes
- Three
- The way you understand
- Four
- Your secret sighs
They are part
of sixteen reasons
Why I love you
- Five
- The way you comb your hair
- Six
- Your freckled nose
- Seven
- The way you say you care
- Eight
- Your crazy clothes
That's just half
Of sixteen reasons
Why I love you
- Nine
- Snuggling in the car
- Ten
- Your wish upon a star
- Eleven
- Whispering on the phone
- Twelve
- Your kiss when we're alone
- Thirteen
- The way you thrill my heart
- Fourteen
- Your voice so neat
- Fifteen
- You say we'll never part
- Sixteen
- Our love's complete
Those are all
Of sixteen reasons
Why I love you
Sixteen reasons
- Cut it! Thank you very much, Carol.
- Checking the gate?
Checking the gate! Thank you.
We'll tell you what happens next!
Thank you very much for coming in.
I know how busy you are.
Are you kidding me? I loved the script.
Just show me where to sign.
I love you, but there's no way they're
gonna let me cast this thing...
until I've seen everyone. I'll let
you know as soon as I can.
I know you will. Because my manager
is gonna be bugging you. And me!
- My pleasure. Now get outta here.
- You're so cruel to me.
- I'm the girl who's playing this part.
- I'll see you later.
Hank? Where's Hank?
- Who's next, Hank?
- Camilla Rhodes.
- Is she ready?
- All ready.
- Bring her in.
- Camilla Rhodes, next.
"Sylvia North Story".
Camilla Rhodes, take one.
Okay, here we go.
Let 's lock it up, please.
- Roll sound, please.
- That 's fit.
Playback and action.
Why haven't I told you?
Oh, baby, I told
Every little star
Just how sweet I think you are
Why haven't I told you?
- Get Jason over here.
- Cindy, Adam wants to see Jason.
Made my heart an open book
Why haven't I told you?
Friends ask me
Am I in love
I always answer “yes"
Might as well confess
If the answer's yes
Maybe you may love me too
Oh, my darling, if you do
- Why haven't you told me?
- Did you want to tell something?
This is the girl.
Excellent choice, Adam.
Oh, my goodness.
I have to be somewhere.
I promised a friend.
- I'm sorry, I must go.
- Now?
Should be around here.
259O. That 's it.
Up there!
Does it look familiar?
- Don't stop!
- What is it? What do you see?
- Those men, in front, in the car.
- Do you know them?
Keep going.
Go around to the back.
Selwyn, number 12.
Now you got me scared.
You see?
I told you there was nothing
to be afraid of.
Betty, wait. Wait!
Don't.
No one's home.
Yes?
Diane?
Number 17.
But it said number 12.
I switched apartments with her.
She's in 17.
It 's down at the end, on the left.
But she hasn't been around
for a few days.
We'll leave her a note.
I'll go with you.
She still got some of my stuff.
You go ahead.
I gotta get that.
- Guess you're not Diane Selwyn.
- Guess I'm not.
There's still no one home, I guess.
- What are you doing?
- Come on, help me in.
Come on, I'll open the front door.
No!
Come on.
Come on!
I know what you're doing.
I know what you have to do.
But let me do it.
Let me do it.
You look like someone else.
Good night, Betty.
You don't have to wear
that in the house.
What?
The wig!
I was just looking at myself again.
I'll take it off to sleep.
You don't have
to sleep on that couch.
- No, it 's okay.
- No, it 's not. This is a huge bed.
Come on, just get in
and get a good night sleep.
It 's more comfortable than
the couch, isn't it?
Thank you, Betty.
It 's nothing. I shouldn't have let
you sleep on the couch last night.
No, I mean...
thank you for everything.
You're welcome.
Good night, sweet Betty.
Good night.
Have you ever done this before?
I don't know.
Have you?
I want to with you.
I'm in love with you.
Silence.
There's no band.
There's no orchestra.
Silence!
- Rita?
- There's no band.
Rita, wake up!
It 's okay. It 's okay.
No, it 's not okay.
What 's wrong?
Go with me somewhere.
It 's two o'clock. It 's two
o'clock in the morning.
Go with me somewhere.
Sure.
Now?
Right now.
There's no band!
There is no band!
This is all...
a tape recording.
There's no band, and yet...
we hear a band.
If we want to hear
a clarinet...
listen...
A muted trombone.
A muted trumpet.
It 's all recorded.
There's no band!
It is all...
a tape.
It is an illusion.
Listen!
Ladies and gentlemen,
let Club Silencio introduce to you...
"La Llorona de Los Angeles".
Rebekah del Rio.
I was all right
For a while
I could smile for a while
But I saw you last night
You held my hand so tight
As you stopped to say hello
You wished me well and you
Couldn't tell
That I've been crying
Over you
Crying
Since you said “so long"
I've been miserable and alone
Lonesome and crying
Crying
It's hard to understand
That upon seeing you again
I'd be crying
I thought
That I was over you
But it's true, so true
I love you even more
Much more than I did before
But darling, what can I do
You don't love me anymore
And I will always be
Crying over you
Your love has captured
The whole of my heart
That was left crying
Crying
Betty?
Where are you?
Hey, pretty girl.
Time to wake up.
- Where have you been?
- What do you want?
My lamp and dishes.
Come on, Diane,
it 's been three weeks.
I put your dishes in that box.
- That 's my ashtray.
- Take it.
- Anytime.
- I'm just making sure, Diane.
This is it?
By the way, those two detectives
came by again looking for you.
Camilla!
You've come back.
What was that you were saying,
beautiful?
I said...
you drive me wild.
We shouldn't do this anymore.
Don't say that.
Don't ever say that.
Don't, Diane!
Stop it!
Diane, stop!
I've tried to tell you this before.
It 's him, isn't it?
I'm not trying to show you how
to do the scene, but just...
watch me and I think you'll
understand what I'm getting at.
Don't sit so rigid, just...
just relax.
Now, the two of you are alone
and it 's real comfortable.
Like you've known
each other forever.
Even if you don't say anything,
it 's real comfortable.
Hank, can you just clear the set?
There's too many people around here.
- Let 's get this worked out.
- Clear the set!
Everyone have a cup of coffee.
- Everyone, please!
- Can Diane stay?
Yeah, sure, Diane can stay.
Hank, let Diane stay!
Diane!
Now, when she starts to cry,
don't pull her towards you.
Let her fall into you.
Just let her fall.
And when you kiss her...
it 's just a continuation
of that move.
There's no break.
Kill the lights!
Don't be mad.
Don't make it be like this.
Oh, sure, you want me to make
this easy for you.
No fucking way!
It 's not gonna be!
- It 's not easy for me!
- Diane!
Hello, it's me.
Leave a message.
Diane?
- Hello?
- Diane?
Camilla.
Diane, the car's waiting.
Are you okay?
You coming?
Good. It means so much to me.
Go on. The car's right
outside your house.
It's been waiting, okay?
Okay.
It's 698O, Mulholland Drive.
Mulholland Drive.
What are you doing?
We don't stop here.
A surprise.
Shortcut.
Come on, sweetheart.
It 's beautiful.
A secret path.
Perfect timing.
Welcome, Diane.
Well...
Here's to love.
Here she is!
I don't believe
you met my mother.
Hi. I'm Diane Selwyn.
Just call me Coco, everybody
does. Pleased to meet you.
Well, let 's eat!
I'm starving!
I'm sorry I was late.
I'm from Deep River, Ontario.
- A small town.
- So you rolled in here from Canada.
I always wanted to come here.
I won this jitterbug contest.
That sort of led to acting.
You know, wanting to act.
When my aunt died...
Anyway, she left me some money.
- She worked here.
- In the movies?
Yes.
How did you meet Camilla?
- On the "Sylvia North Story".
- Camilla was great in that.
I never went to
Casablanca with Luigi.
- What a pity!
- Then go!
I wanted the lead so bad.
Anyway, Camilla got the part.
The director...
Bob Rooker?
Yes.
He didn't think so much of me.
Anyway, that 's when
we became friends.
She helped me...
getting some parts in some
of her films.
I see.
So I got the pool,
and she got the pool man.
I couldn't believe it. I wanted
to buy that judge a Rolls Royce.
Sometimes, good things happen.
So I guess we've saved
the best for last.
- Do you want to tell them?
- No, you tell them.
Camilla and I...
are going to be...
Sorry about that.
No, I'm fine.
This is the girl.
Don't show me this
fucking thing here.
It 's just an actress' photo
resume. Everybody's got one.
You got the money?
I sure do.
Okay, now, once you hand that over
to me, it 's a done deal.
You sure you want this?
More than anything in this world.
When it 's finished, you'll find
this where I told you.
What 's it open?
Silence!
Silêncio.