Police found her in the street.
Looks like she was bitten.
Some kind of an animal.
Jesus! Her water`s broken!
She`s going into
uterine contractions!
We`ll have to do a C-section!
What you got down there,
little man?
Oh, that`s my heatseeker.
I`ll bet it is.
So, where are we going?
It`s a surprise, baby.
Yeah, I like surprises.
Oh, my God!
What the fuck are we doing here?
Look at all that.
What the fuck is that?
What did you just say?
Wow.
What`s up?
Man!
All right.
What`s happening?
Whoa!
Man.
Fuck.
Fuck. I need a drink.
What`s wrong, baby?
Is that him?
Jesus, that`s him.
It`s Blade. It`s the daywalker.
Come on, daywalker!
I`m gonna rip
your fucking head off!
That`s him! Get him!
Fuck him up!
We`re gonna jack you up.
Make him hurt bad.
Quinn...
I`m getting a little tired
of chopping you up.
Thought I might try fire
for a change.
Give my regards to Frost.
Please don`t!
Put him out.
-Yes, sir.
-Paramedics.
Got a charred cadaver for you.
Still warm, too.
1, 2, 3.
Oh, Jesus, that`s rank.
He was still screaming
when they found him...
stapled to a wall.
That`s very pretty.
Did you check the chem count?
His blood sugar`s
3 times norm...
phosphorus and uric acid
are off the charts.
You took this off a DOA?
But this doesn`t make any sense.
The red blood cells are
biconvex, which is impossible.
Look at the polys,
they`re binucleated.
Curtis,
it`s 3:00 in the morning--
This is not a joke.
I`ve got the body
in the morgue right now.
I thought you promised
to give me some distance.
I just want you to come down
and take a look.
Show me the body.
And I don`t want to hear
a word about us.
Done.
We`ve had that conversation.
You haven`t started
on the internal organs yet?
Just a blood sample
for the pericardium.
The maxilla
looks a little deformed.
There`s some odd muscle
structure around the canines.
I`m going to start the "Y"
and check the tracheal mucosa.
Let me ask you something.
Honestly...
you ever have
second thoughts about us?
Sometimes.
But then I remember
how much of an asshole you were.
Want to cut me some slack here?
You asked for some time off,
I gave you some time off.
-Look, Curtis--
-l`m trying.
It`s over.
Call security!
Came back to finish you off.
Get out of my way, you freak!
Freeze!
Motherfucker,
are you out of your damn mind?!
Hey, you! Freeze!
Hold it right there!
My shoulder--
it`s dislocated.
Whistler.
Bringing home strays now?
She`s been bitten.
Should`ve killed her, then.
Yeah, I know...
but I didn`t.
You watch her close.
If she starts to turn,
you finish her off.
Or I will.
She`s borderline.
Another hour,
she`d be well into the change.
Dr. Karen Jenson, listen close.
I`m going to inject you
with allium sativum--
garlic.
This is going to hurt--a lot.
It was Quinn.
Frost`s little errand boy?
You get a lead on him?
Too bad.
Hold her.
I give her fifty-fifty...
if she makes it
through the night.
Blade...
the daywalker--
still pursuing
his ridiculous crusade.
How many died?
We don`t have an exact count.
Apparently,
he used a lot of silver.
We`re having difficulty--
Send in Frost.
Deacon Frost.
You can come in now.
These nightclubs of yours
are dangerous.
Are they?
They draw needless attention
to our kind.
You know our policy.
Your policy, not mine.
Our livelihood...
depends on our ability
to blend in...
and our discretion.
Maybe it`s time
we forgot about discretion.
We should be ruling
the humans...
not running around making
back-alley treaties with them.
For fuck`s sake,
these people are our food...
not our allies.
You`re out of line.
Am l?
Or maybe l`m just
the first to say out loud...
what we`ve all been thinking.
We have existed this way...
for thousands of years.
Who are you
to challenge our ways?
You`re not even a pureblood.
Like it matters.
I was born a vampire...
as was every other member
of this house...
but, you, Frost...
you were merely turned.
The world belongs to us...
not the humans.
You know that.
Do we have
any other business to discuss?
Well, there`s the matter
of our offshore accounts.
We`re having difficulty--
And have you made
the transfer to the--
Gitano...
you may wake up one day
and find yourself extinct.
You`re a week early.
Whistler says l`m building up
a resistance to the serum.
I figured that might happen.
You take care, all right?
Imust be getting soft
in my old age...
Ietting you bring home
a stray like that.
It was damn stupid of you.
Might`ve lucked out, though.
I checked her background.
It turns out
she`s a hematologist.
She might be useful to us.
I doubt it.
I`m serious.
I took a look
at that notebook of hers.
She`s onto something.
I had to increase the dose.
It`s over 50 milligrams now.
That`s getting dangerous.
Just do it...
old man.
Wander off the beaten path,
doctor?
Who are you people?
My name`s Abraham Whistler.
You`ve met Blade.
So, am I a prisoner here?
Not at all.
We just had to take
certain precautions...
before we let you go.
You got to understand...
they`re everywhere.
Vampires--
the hominus nocturna.
We hunt them, you see--
moving from one city
to the next...
tracking their migrations.
They`re hard to kill.
They tend to regenerate.
And l`m supposed
to believe all this?
You already met Mr. Crispy
at the hospital.
What do you think?
So, what do you use, then?
Stakes? Crosses?
Crosses don`t do squat.
Some of the legends
are true, though.
Vampires are severely allergic
to silver.
Feed them garlic and they go
into anaphylactic shock.
Then, of course,
there`s always sunlight...
ultraviolet rays.
I got this sucker running.
You want to give it a try
tonight?
It`s still heavy.
Well, you`re so big.
If you want to live
to see another day...
you`ll be out of town
by nightfall.
So where am I supposed to go?
You`ve been exposed to them.
One way or another, somebody`s
going to take you out.
There`s a war going on
out there.
Blade, myself, a few others...
we`ve tried to keep it from
spilling over onto the streets.
Sometimes, people like yourself
get caught in the cross fire.
I have blood samples.
I can go to the police.
They own the police.
You have to understand,
they`re everywhere.
Chances are you`ve seen them
yourself and didn`t know it--
on the subway or in a bar.
So that`s it?
You guys just patch me up
and send me on my way?
Here.
Vampire mace--
silver nitrate,
essence of garlic.
You keep your eyes open.
Be careful.
One other thing--
buy yourself a gun.
If you start getting
sensitive to daylight...
If you find you`re thirsty...
regardless of how much
you had to drink...
then I suggest you take that gun
and use it on yourself.
Better that
than the alternative.
You have been warned before.
These archives are restricted
to the members of the house.
You are wasting your time.
It`s a dead language.
The ancient texts
can never be translated.
You wouldn`t even
understand them.
Damn it, Frost!
I`m talking to you!
Keep your voice down, Gitano.
We`re in a library.
You don`t need to shout.
What are you up to?
What are you going to do?
What?
You bore me.
Remember what we told you.
You keep your eyes open.
They`re everywhere.
But it`s daytime!
How you doing?
Hi, there.
I`m sorry. Whoa! Hold on.
Police officer. I`m sorry, OK?
Police officer.
I didn`t mean to scare you.
The front door was open.
What are you doing in here?
I`m just here
on a routine check.
Look, l`m Officer Krieger,
42nd precinct.
You`re Karen Jenson, right?
Your coworkers
at the hospital...
said that you were kidnapped
last night.
Are you OK?
What happened
to the other doctor I was with?
Curtis Webb? He died.
Don`t worry about that
right now, OK?
Why?
Because you`re dead, too,
you bitch.
Bitch! What is it?
What is this, garlic?
Yeah. He said it would work
against vampires.
Vampires?
Who said I was a vampire?
Nobody.
He`s a familiar--
a vampire wannabe.
If he`s loyal...
and he proves himself,
maybe his master will turn him.
Wait a minute.
You used me as bait?
Get over it.
Is all that necessary?
That`s a glyph--
a vampire cattle brand.
It means that Officer Krieger
is somebody`s property.
Another vampire tries
to bleed this little hooker...
then they have to answer
to his owner.
We`ve been tracking him
for a long time.
All right.
Officer Krieger...
you going to be
a good little bloodhound, huh?
Tell us what your master`s
been up to.
Great, now you robbing him.
You going to rob me, too?
How do you think
we fund this organization?
We`re not exactly
the March of Dimes.
It`s fake.
Looks like our friend here
has been blood running.
Hillbarn clinic.
I know this place.
It`s a blood bank.
Owned by vampires,
and there`s one in every city.
And they always deliver.
So, where were you taking it?
I don`t know
what you`re talking--
Look, take it easy.
I`m only going to ask you
one more time.
Where were you taking it?
Go fuck yourself.
Fuck me? No, you fuck this.
You better wake up.
The world you live in
is just a sugar-coated topping.
There is another world
beneath it--
the real world.
And if you want to survive it...
you better learn
to pull the trigger.
Wait a minute.
I`m coming with you.
You`re useless.
I have to stick with you.
It`s the only way
l`ll stay alive long enough...
to find a cure for myself.
There is no cure.
He`s not going to come back.
Nobody`s that stupid.
When you understand
the nature of a thing...
you know what it`s capable of.
It`s Krieger. I`m at 16-0-0-9.
Get me through.
I got a delivery
in progress here...
and I just had a run-in
with Blade.
I got to clear out
that clinic on Hillhurst now!
Looks like we hit pay dirt.
That`s a vampire mark.
It means there`s a safe house
around here somewhere--
a place they can go
with donors coming.
See the valets over there?
They`re vampires.
So is the doorman...
and the whore on the corner.
How can you tell?
By the way they move...
the way they smell.
It`s like a bad dream.
There are worse things
out tonight than vampires.
Like what?
Like me.
OK, vampire anatomy 101.
Crosses and holy water
don`t do dick...
so forget what you`ve seen
in the movies.
You use
a stake, silver, or sunlight.
You know how to use
one of these?
Nope, but l`ll damn sure
learn quick.
The safety`s off,
rounds already chambered--
silver hollow point
filled with garlic.
You aim for the head
or the heart.
Anything else is your ass.
Do you have an invitation?
Kenji!
Where`s the entrance?
I can`t tell you that, man.
I`m going to ask you
one more time.
Where`s the entrance?
OK.
It`s in the freezer.
Come on, man! I told you!
It`s in the fridge!
You give Frost
a message from me.
You tell him it`s open season
on all suckheads.
Some kind of archive.
This must be where they keep
most of their records.
Isn`t this just a little
high-tech?
They`ve got their claws
into everything--
politics, finance, real estate.
They already own
half of downtown.
Frost throws a good party.
Yeah...
but where is he?
Come on, baby.
Don`t keep everyone waiting.
Deacon, there`s someone here
to see you.
I got to talk to you, Frost.
I`m sorry. I had to come here.
It`s a mistake going to Pearl`s.
I know that. Dumb fucking me.
I know you`re disappointed.
Am I that transparent?
You want to meet him?
I can get you guys
in with him...
because we`re tight.
We`re like brothers.
Fuck.
Aw, fuck. Frost.
I`ve been telling these bitches
all about you.
They`ve been dying to meet you.
They are so psyched.
Bad ass bitches. They--
Frost, it`s about Blade.
Aw, he`s busy, you know?
Because when he`s focused
on business...
Frost, this is important.
Blade was waiting for me...
using the girl as bait.
And you were stupid enough
to take it.
Shut up, bitch.
I didn`t know
he was going to be there.
It was a trap, see?
But don`t worry about it.
It`s no problem.
We can still get the girl.
Forget the girl.
-I want Blade.
-I know you do.
You hear me, Quinn?
I want him alive.
What?
Wait a minute, man.
You want him alive?
What`s that smell?
...image carefully, Frost.
You will need 12 purebloods
to make the ritual work.
Krieger, is that you?
He`s here!
This must be Pearl...
the record keeper.
He`s going to kill me!
You need me, Frost!
Pearl, you`re history.
Have the good grace to die
with some fuckin` dignity.
Ruthless bloodsucker.
Congratulations, Blade.
I hear you`ve been lookin`
for me.
-l`m flattered.
-lt`ll pass.
Fuck.
What is that?
That, biscuit boy,
is a U.V. Lamp.
We`re gonna play a little game
of 20 questions.
Depending on how you answer...
you may walk out of here
with a tan.
What`s that?
That? Oh, it`s nothing.
It`s routine research.
Actually, it`s a video game.
That must`ve hurt.
It`s a fragment,
a piece of the prophecy!
What prophecy?
Oh, l`m not really sure.
There are so many out--
And there is nothing you can
do about it, daywalker!
Is that so?
Well, that`s what Frost says.
Then you won`t mind me
borrowing this, will you?
If he moves, fry him.
What`s in here?
Nothing. It`s a storeroom.
But you`re wasting your time.
There`s nothing
of importance to anyone.
Then you won`t mind
if I take a peek.
He moved.
What is this?
These are the pages
from The Book of Erebus...
the vampire bible.
It contains everything...
their entire history.
La Magra
must be one of their legends.
Why is Frost so interested
in La Magra?
-Give me your hand.
-Hola, amigo!
Do you remember me?
Give it to him!
Nice one.
Well, well, well.
You took my arm, man.
Remember?
But it`s cool.
I got a new one.
Think l`ll ever play piano
again?
You can slice him,
you can dice him...
but the Quinn man
just keeps on comin`!
Check it out.
I`ve got his pigsticker.
You`re a fuckup, Crease!
You`re just full of surprises...
ain`t you, chief?
Stay with me, sweetness...
`cause l`m not finished
with you yet.
Ah, looky here.
Silver.
Nice craftsmanship, huh?
Probably cost you
a pretty penny.
This here is a man
who takes his job...
just a little too seriously,
don`t you think?
Come to think of it, Blade...
I owe you one.
Actually, if you want
to get technical...
I owe you two.
What`s so funny, bright eyes?
I`m expecting company.
Catch you fuckers at a bad time?
No! No guns!
Fuckin` this way!
Drop the guns!
I need him!
He wants Blade alive! Go!
You`ve been listening in
the whole time?
Keeping radio contact.
Think l`d let him run loose
without a chaperone?
Christ! I`m too old for this.
Somebody get me
a goddamn wheelchair.
He can take care of himself.
Jump!
What are you gonna do?
Oh, my God.
What`s wrong?
It`s dislocated.
Let me help you.
Let me give you--
No! Get away.
You`re one of them, aren`t you?
I`m something else.
I found him when he was 13.
He`d been livin`
on the streets...
feedin` off the homeless.
His need for blood
had taken hold at puberty.
I took him for a vampire
at first.
Almost killed him, too.
Then I realized what he was.
Blade`s mother
was attacked by a vampire...
while she was pregnant.
She died, but he lived.
Unfortunately, he`d undergone
certain genetic changes.
He can withstand garlic,
silver...
even sunlight...
and he`s got their strength.
This time tomorrow,
all his wounds will be healed.
He still ages like a human,
though.
Vampires age slower than us.
Unfortunately...
he also inherited their thirst.
I thought the serum
was supposed to suppress that.
Time`s runnin` out.
His body`s
startin` to reject it.
So far, all my efforts
to find a cure have failed.
Why do you hunt them?
I had a family once--
a wife and 2 daughters.
Then a drifter
came callin` one evenin`...
a vampire.
He toyed with `em first...
tried to make me decide...
which order they`d die in.
We kill as many of `em
as we can find...
but it`s gettin` worse.
Because of Frost.
There`s somethin` happenin`
in the vampire ranks.
It`s somethin` big...
and l`d stake my life...
that son of a bitch
is at the center of it.
Whistler told me what happened.
He told me what you are.
You don`t know me.
You don`t know
anything about me.
I`m not human.
You look human to me--
Humans don`t drink blood.
That was a long time ago.
Maybe you should let that go.
I have spent my whole life...
Iooking for that thing
that killed my mother.
It made me what I am.
And every time I take
one of those monsters out...
I get a little piece
of that life back...
so don`t you tell me
about forgetting.
He took us by surprise!
Two of them against
your entire security force?
Don`t put that shit on me,
`cause you were there, too!
I`m sure Deacon will
appreciate--
...stabbed in the balls for it,
all right?
You little skeez!
Don`t see the lifestyle
really suits you.
I should put this stump through
that shit-eating grin of yours.
Face it. You were sloppy.
You got what you deserved.
Deac, let me take this guy out.
Look what he fuckin` did!
He took my hand again!
Listen to me. I want him alive.
What the fuck are you talk--
You want him alive?
We`ve been tryin` to kill
this motherfucker for years.
Are you
out of your fuckin` mind?
Big guy, relax.
Be patient.
Now, we got a lot to do here.
I need you, man.
Morning.
How you feelin`?
Look at that.
Whew. Gettin` a little toasty
out here, huh?
When was the last time...
you stopped to appreciate
a good sunrise?
Oh, that`s right.
You were born a vampire...
so you never had
the pleasure, have you?
That`s OK. It`s all right.
Least we`re here together.
Share the moment...
which means a lot to me
by the way, really.
I mean that.
`Cause actually,
when you get to know me...
I`m a fairly
sentimental type of guy.
Bit of an innocent,
you might say.
Do what you want, Frost.
Doesn`t make any difference.
You just don`t fuckin` get it.
You`re never gonna be
a pureblood.
Hold him.
You will never rule us!
Jesus Christ.
Have a nice day.
Sorry, you old dog.
You just got a little too long
in the tooth.
What, man? That was funny.
"Long, tooth." Funny.
Did I tell you the one about...
What have you done
with Dragonetti?
Let`s get down to business,
shall we?
I need 12 volunteers.
What is this?
Smells like a vampire
wiped his ass with it.
I took it from the archives.
It`s written in blood.
It`s from The Book of Erebus.
I think it`s what Frost
has been workin` on.
It`s somethin` about
the Blood God...
the Spirits of the Twelve.
I don`t know.
I can`t make out the rest of it.
Maybe this`ll help.
I`ll figure out something.
So what`s all this?
Took a trip
to the hospital last night...
borrowed some equipment.
For your miracle cure?
This is E.D.T.A.
It`s an anticoagulant.
We use it to treat blood clots.
Now look what happens
when I introduce it...
onto a sample of vampire blood.
Take a step back.
The reaction`s energetic.
Some cure.
I didn`t say E.D.T.A.
was a cure.
But maybe you could use it
to explode some vampire heads.
Wait a minute.
I need a sample of your blood.
Later.
Gotta go downtown.
Need some serum.
Serum can wait.
This is important.
Is he sick?
Cancer.
You have a lot of love for him,
don`t you?
We have a good arrangement.
He makes the weapons.
I use `em.
My mother used to say...
"a cold heart is a dead heart."
You don`t look so good.
I`m just a little tired.
You know we`ve been...
workin` all night.
I guess we didn`t catch it
in time.
You got another day...
two at the most.
For what it`s worth, l`m sorry.
You make it sound like
l`m already dead.
How you doin`, chief?
Easy.
Wouldn`t want
our little friend here...
to wind up on the back
of a milk carton, would we?
It`s nice to finally meet you.
Had my eye on you for years.
I know all about you--
your serum, Whistler--
everything.
Sunblock.
Hey, it`s a start, right?
The goal, of course,
is to be like you...
the daywalker.
You got the best of both worlds,
don`t you?
All our strengths...
none of our weaknesses.
Maybe I don`t see it that way.
Oh, so it`s back to pretending
we`re human again?
Come on. Spare me
the Uncle Tom routine, OK?
You can`t keep denying
what you are, man.
You think the humans will ever
accept a half-breed like you?
They can`t.
They`re afraid of you.
And they should be.
You`re an animal.
You`re a fuckin` maniac.
Look at `em.
They`re cattle...
pieces of meat.
What difference does it make
how their world ends?
Plague, war...
famine.
Morality
doesn`t even enter into it.
We`re just a function
of natural selection, man...
the new race.
Looks like
your mascara`s running.
I`m offering you a truce.
I want you with us.
What do you think, l`m stupid?
You`re familiar
with the Blood God.
You`re nothing to me...
but another dead vampire.
You`re an idiot. You know that?
I came down here
offering you an easy way out...
and you spit it right back
in my fuckin` face.
Careful.
What do I care?
They`re nothing but cattle...
just like you said.
If you wanna take the hard road,
be my guest...
but I promise you,
by the time this is over...
you`re gonna wish they never
cut you from your mother`s--
Go home.
It was simple.
Why do vampires need
to drink blood?
`Cause their own blood
can`t sustain hemoglobin.
Right. It`s a genetic defect,
just like hemolytic anemia.
That means that we have
to treat it with gene therapy...
rewrite the victim`s DNA
with a retrovirus.
They`ve been using it
on sickle cell anemia.
Are you sure that`s safe?
I have no idea,
but I don`t have a choice, do l?
You actually think
this could work?
On me...
On Blade, l`m not so sure.
He didn`t contract vampirism
from a bite like I did.
He was born with it.
It`s part of his DNA.
I`m sure I can cure
his thirst...
but it`s gonna take time.
Ah, we`re out of time.
You saw what was on that disk.
Damn.
Get out of here.
I said get out of here!
Nice place.
Took us a while to find it!
Bite me and get it over with.
I ain`t gonna bite you.
Do your thing.
Frost took her.
Listen to me.
The disk.
He decoded it.
Frost is trying to...
trigger
a fuckin` vampire apocalypse.
There`s some kind of...
vampire God
he`s trying to resurrect.
La Magra.
You`re the key.
He needs your blood...
the blood of the daywalker.
You`re the chosen one.
Listen to me, Blade.
You can`t go after him.
Bullshit.
If Frost gets his hands
on you...
it`s all over.
There`ll be armies
of the motherfuckers.
Shit.
You`re gonna have
to finish me off.
Don`t want me coming back.
We can treat the wounds.
It`s too far gone.
You know that.
Give me your gun.
Give me the goddamn gun.
Now walk away...
you stupid son of a bitch.
Walk the fuck away.
By the time you watch this...
your friend Whistler
should be dead.
If it makes any difference
to you...
he put up quite a fight.
You can find us
at the Edgewood Towers.
You seem a bit tense.
A bit pent-up maybe...
Like you need
to release something.
You know?
Blade not...
givin` it to you maybe?
I don`t know. I just...
I see such a beautiful woman.
Great skin.
I`d like to see you happy,
that`s all.
Is this the part
where you offer to turn me?
It`s either that or a body bag.
Go ahead.
Bite me.
I`ll just cure myself.
I did it before,
and I can do it again.
There is no cure, baby.
There is
if you`ve been bitten...
if you were once human.
How`d you get that scar, Deacon?
A born vampire
would have the power...
to regenerate from birth.
You must`ve gotten scarred
before you were turned.
Isn`t that right?
Vampires like you
aren`t a species.
You`re just infected--
a virus,
a sexually transmitted disease.
I`ll tell you what we are,
sister.
We`re the top
of the fuckin` food chain.
The Blood God`s coming,
and after tonight...
you people are fuckin` history.
He`s a hurricane...
an act of God.
Anyone caught in his path
will instantly be turned.
Everyone you`ve ever known...
everyone
you`ve ever fucking loved.
It won`t matter
who`s pureblood and who`s not.
How are you gonna cure
the whole fuckin` world?
And Blade`s blood is the key.
We got an intruder.
I don`t think you understand.
This dude is fuckin` bad.
He had 20 guys around him--
and he`s got shit
he throws at you--
Yeah, the swords.
Throw it in the air,
catch it underneath.
Yeah. Shut the fuck up!
There`s no intruder
where we are.
Look, make it happen, all right?
It`s one guy on foot.
That`s him! Get him!
Why am I hearing gunfire?
Did I tell anybody
to start shooting?
I need him alive.
Please!
I just work for them!
Jesus Christ.
Lock this place down.
Yes, sir!
Eric?
But you died.
I came back, Eric.
That very same night...
when Deacon welcomed me
into his arms.
Jesus Christ.
I thought you`d be happy.
You`re finally reunited,
and you act like this?
Blade, give it up. It`s over.
She belongs to me, buddy.
Don`t look so surprised.
You spent your whole life...
Looking for the vampire
who bit your mother.
Well, here I am.
Who would ever guess you`d
survive your mother`s death?
But you did.
And here we are--
one big happy fuckin` family.
I need my serum.
Maybe when we get outta this...
I`ll take that miracle cure
of yours.
There`s one catch.
If it works...
you`ll lose your strength...
and your ability to regenerate.
You`ll be completely human.
Glad you could make it.
Thanks for the shades.
Our ancestors
called this place...
the temple of eternal night.
Nice, isn`t it?
Apparently, these geniuses
forgot it ever existed.
Fortunately for us...
I`m what you might call a...
student of history.
Why are we here?
This temple was built
for one glorious moment--
this night, for the Blood God.
Thanks.
Let`s see this sword of yours.
Well.
Titanium, right?
Acid-etched?
I`ll get used
to a weapon like this.
What? You look surprised.
I told you, Blade,
I know everything about you.
Hold out your arm, Quinn.
Why, man?
They`re, like, all better.
Hold out your arm. Now.
Deac, l--
Just kidding.
He was fuckin` with me.
He can`t hear you, honey.
The thirst has got him now.
What do we have here?
The precious serum.
How long`s it been
since you shot up?
12, 13 hours maybe?
I bet you`re just dying
for a drink, aren`t you?
What`s it feel like?
Is your blood on fire?
Try some.
You might like it.
Thanks, but I prefer
the real thing.
In any event...
I don`t think you`ll be
needing these anymore.
It`s a shame, you know?
When I think
of what you`ve become...
what you should have become.
I guess I don`t blame you.
I mean, with everything
that`s happened...
it`s the human side of you
that`s made you weak.
You should`ve listened
to your blood.
Say what you want...
but, I promise you,
you`ll be dead by dawn.
Get him outta here.
Get these fucks downstairs.
Now.
Come on. Let`s go.
Don`t worry, sweetheart.
We haven`t forgotten about you.
Oh, no, baby.
We got something real special
planned for you.
That surfer boy had a nice ass.
I sucked him dry.
And you`d figure he`d turn, man.
Yeah, but he didn`t turn,
did he?
No. He turned into
some kinda zombie.
It happens sometimes, cutie.
He was fuckin` tripped out.
Pathetic.
These guys are complete scum.
They`ll eat anything--
animals, rodents, corpses,
and sometimes...
they`ll even eat vampires.
That`s a plus.
And bearing that all in mind...
I`d like you to meet
an old friend of yours.
It`s too bad.
I kinda liked her.
What a waste.
I don`t know
what`s happening to me.
No pulse.
And, of course...
there`s the question
of lividity.
I never thought
I would see you again.
Tell me, Karen...
do you ever have second thoughts
about us?
Poor child.
You`re so sick.
So thirsty.
Don`t touch me.
Eric, look at me.
Vampires are my people now.
I`m one of them.
Can`t be.
Yes, it can.
Try to understand, Eric.
Your mother
died a long time ago.
I`ve hunted...
I`ve killed...
and l`ve enjoyed it.
Haven`t you?
I know you have.
Sooner or later,
the thirst always wins.
Come on.
Spread them out.
One on each glyph,
under the towers.
Make it perfect.
Bring the elevator up.
You stupid girl.
What do you think
is going to happen?
La Magra? The Blood God?
That`s a fairy tale
for pretty little vampires.
Then why are you sweating,
pureblood?
You`re afraid
we`re gonna steal your soul...
your pureblood spirit?
You should be.
Read the prophecy.
It`s time you fucks contributed
something to the cause.
Even if Frost is right...
you really think he cares
about you?
You`re gonna die
just like the rest of us.
Tonight, the age of man
comes to an end.
No more compromises.
We`re gonna be gods.
Of course we are.
I`m gonna be naughty.
I`m gonna be
a naughty vampire god.
Gotta stop...
Save your strength.
Blue.
You`re hypovolemic.
You`re bleeding to death.
Need...
serum.
Listen to me.
I want you
to take some of my blood.
Look, just do it.
Is everybody thirsty?
I hope you`re all
very fucking thirsty.
Don`t stop.
How was it?
I`m your mother.
You wouldn`t hurt your mother...
would you?
Come here.
I must release you.
Fuck!
Not anymore.
Kill him.
Wait! I owe you, man.
I got two new hands, Blade.
I don`t know which one
to use to kill you with!
I`m really going
to enjoy this now.
Let`s do this.
You`re too late, Blade.
My turn.
Look at you.
You`re a little bitch.
What, your serum?
It can`t help you now, stud.
Nice shot.
Some motherfuckers are always
trying to ice-skate uphill.
Let`s get out of here.
I need to get back to the lab...
if l`m going to cure you.
It`s not over.
You keep your cure.
There`s still a war going on...
and I have a job to do.
You want to help...
make me a better serum.