(EERIE RUMBLING AND ROARING)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
DEIRDRE: Thank you so much.
That looks fabulous.
DEIRDRE: Thank you, Geoffrey.
GEOFFREY: You're welcome.
DEIRDRE: We'll also take
a bottle of red as well.
Thank you.
GEOFFREY: Certainly.
DEIRDRE: Right, now...
Thank you, Barry.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
DEIRDRE:
That looks wonderful.
Beautiful day.
DEIRDRE:
Where are you going?
CATHY: To eat my sandwich.
DEIRDRE: You'll ruin
your appetite for prawns.
I don't like prawns.
DEIRDRE: Darling,
don't wander off.
For God's sake,
leave her alone, Deirdre.
DEIRDRE: Go play
with your ball.
Don't be so annoying!
Darling, what about snakes?
There aren't any snakes
on the beach.
Just let her enjoy
herself for once.
DEIRDRE: Edward?
EDWARD: Yes, ma'am.
(HUMMING CHEERFULLY)
(WILD PURRING
AND CLICKING)
(BRANCHES RUSTLING)
Hello, there.
What are you,
a little bird or something?
(TRILLING SHRILLY)
Are you hungry?
Take a bite.
It's roast beef.
It's good. Come on.
I won't hurt you.
Mommy! Daddy!
You've got to come see this!
I found something!
(DINOSAURS TRILLING
AND SQUEAKING EXCITEDLY)
(SQUEAKING INTENSIFIES)
(POUNDING SURF)
Cathy, darling,
lunch is ready!
(DINOSAURS SQUEAKING)
Are you looking at this?
I'm afraid there
isn't enough to go around.
(CATHY SHRIEKS)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Paul?
Cathy?
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC SWELLS)
DEIRDRE: Will you hurry up?
Hurry up!
(SUBWAY CAR BRAKES
SCREECHING)
You're him, right?
Excuse me?
The scientist? The guy?
I saw you on TV.
I believed you.
(CHUCKLES)
(ROARS)
(PIANO PLAYING
CLASSICAL MUSIC FAINTLY)
Who shall I tell
Mr. Hammond is calling?
IAN: Ian Malcolm.
I've been summoned.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(PIANO MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Dr. Malcolm!
IAN: Oh, my God.
Hello, Dr. Malcolm.
Kids, kids.
It's so great to see you.
It's so great.
Look at you.
You came to see Grandpa?
Yeah, he called me.
Do you know what
it's about?
I don't, either.
This joint's kind
of creepy, isn't it?
Is everything okay?
Well, not exactly.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Dr. Malcolm.
Here to share a few campfire
stories with my uncle?
IAN: You can convince
The Washington Post
and Skeptical Inquirer
of what you want
but I was there.
I know what happened
and so do you.
Do you actually believe
that everyone who chose
discretion did so
for a nefarious motive?
Even Lex and Tim?
IAN: Leave them out of it.
It's not a game.
No. You signed
a nondisclosure agreement
before you went
to the island
that forbade you
from discussing
what you saw.
You violated that agreement.
I did. And you lied
about the deaths
of three people.
You misinformed
the public,
which made me
look like a nut.
Hasn't been so good
for my livelihood...
We made a generous
compensatory offer
for your injuries.
A payoff and an insult.
When you spin reality,
cover up evidence,
it hurts more
than my reputation.
As I recall,
your university
revoked your tenure
for your selling
wild stories to the press.
I didn't sell anything.
I never took a cent,
and I told the truth.
Your version of it.
There aren't "versions"
of the truth.
InGen can't keep
spewing out...
InGen is my
responsibility now.
I will jealously
defend its interests.
IAN: Your responsibility?
What about Mr. Hammond?
It is our board of directors
I must face, not my uncle.
Trust me,
your problems are about
to be rendered moot.
LUDLOW: In a few weeks' time,
they'll be long forgotten.
Not by me.
Careful.
This suit cost more
than your education.
HAMMOND: You were right
and I was wrong. There!
Did you ever expect
to hear me say such a thing?
Thank God for Site B.
Site B?
Isla Nublar was
just a showroom,
something for the tourists.
Site B was
the factory floor.
That was on Isla Sorna,
80 miles from Nublar.
We bred the animals there,
and nurtured them
for a few months,
then moved them
into the park.
Really? I did not know that.
After the accident
in the park,
Hurricane Clarissa
wiped out our facility
on Site B.
Call it an act of God.
We had to evacuate.
The animals
were released
to mature on their own.
"Life will find a way,"
as you once so
eloquently put it.
By now we have a complete
ecological system
on the island
with dozens of species
living in their own
social groups
without fences, boundaries,
or constraining technology.
And for four years
I've tried to keep it safe
from human interference.
That's right. Hopefully,
you've kept the island
quarantined and contained.
But I'm in shock
about all this.
I mean, that they're
still alive.
You bred them
lysine-deficient.
Shouldn't they have
kicked after seven days
without supplemental enzymes?
Yes! But, by God,
they're flourishing.
That's one of
1,000 questions I want
the team to answer.
Team?
Yes.
I've organized
an expedition to go in,
thank you,
and document them.
To make the most
spectacular living
fossil record
the world has ever seen.
Go in and document?
You mean with people?
Yes, the animals
won't know they're there.
Very low impact.
Strictly observation
and documentation.
HAMMOND:
Our satellite infrareds
show the animals
are fiercely territorial.
The carnivores
are isolated in the
interior of the island
so the team can stay
on the outer rim.
Don't worry. I'm not making
the same mistakes again.
No, you're making
all new ones.
John! So, there's
another island
with dinosaurs,
no fences this time,
and you want to send
people in,
very few people,
on the ground, right?
Who are the four lunatics
you're trying
to con into this?
It was difficult
to convince them as to
what they would see,
in the end had
to use my checkbook
to get them there.
But there's Nick Van Owen,
who is
a video documentarian,
Eddie Carr,
who's a field
equipment expert.
We have
our paleontologist
and I was hoping
that perhaps you might
be the fourth.
We've been on the verge
of Chapter 11
ever since that
accident in the park.
There are those
in the company
who wanted to
exploit Site B
in order to bail us out.
They've been
planning it for years,
and I've been able
to stop them until now.
But, a few weeks ago,
a British family
on a yacht cruise
stumbled across the island
and their wee girl
was injured.
She's fine.
But the board
has used the incident
to take control
of InGen from me.
Now it's only a matter
of time before this
lost world
is found and pillaged.
Public opinion is
the one thing I can use
to preserve it,
but to rally that support
I need a complete
photo record
of those animals alive
and in their
natural habitat.
So you went from
capitalist to naturalist
in just four years.
That's something.
It's our last chance
at redemption.
John,
no.
Of course, no.
And I'm going to contact
the other three members
of your team
and stop them from going.
Who's the paleontologist,
by the way?
She came to me,
I want you to know this.
Who did?
Leave it to you, Ian,
to have associations,
affiliations,
even liaisons,
with the best people
in so many fields.
Not Sarah.
Paleontological behavior
study is a new field,
and Sarah Harding
is on that frontier.
Her theories on
parenting and nurturing
amongst carnivores
have framed the debate.
What are you doing?
Where's your phone?
HAMMOND: It's too late.
She's already there.
(PHONE BEEPS OFF)
The others are
meeting her in three days.
You sent my girlfriend
to this island alone?
"Sent" is hardly the word.
She couldn't be restrained.
She was already
working in San Diego,
doing some research
at the animal park.
It's only a couple
of hours' flight from there.
She was adamant,
absolutely adamant about,
here you are,
about making the initial
foray by herself.
She thinks
she's Dian Fossey.
"Observation
without interference,"
she said.
She went on and on.
You know how it is.
After you were
injured in the park,
she sought you out.
Then she went all
the way to a hospital
in Costa Rica
to ask somebody
who she didn't even know
if the rumors were true.
If you want
to leave your name
on something, fine.
But stop
putting it on other
people's headstones.
She'll be fine.
She's spent years studying
African predators.
Sleeping downwind and all.
She knows what she's doing.
And, believe me,
the research team will...
It's not a research
expedition anymore.
It's a rescue operation
and it's leaving now.
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
EDDIE: You can't
shave three days off
my deadline
and expect to be ready.
I'm not supplied.
I haven't tested
any of this.
IAN: Why give her
a satellite phone
if it doesn't work?
Why doesn't it?
EDDIE: Could be solar flares,
the satellite, or maybe
she turned it off.
EDDIE: I need
half air on the tires.
We're flying pressurized.
IAN: Does she know
how to use it?
EDDIE: You kidding?
She's faxed me refinements
on 50% of the plans
for this stuff.
Don't do that. You got
to baby it a little bit.
Love it.
I'll love it
when it works.
It'll work
when you love it.
You coming along?
I don't usually,
but I can't resist.
Thanks for
the two-minute warning.
Nick Van Owen,
this is Ian Malcolm.
Nick's our
field photographer.
IAN: How do you do?
You do
wildlife photography?
Wildlife, combat,
you name it.
When I was with Nightline,
I was in Rwanda,
Chechnya, Bosnia.
I do volunteer
work with Greenpeace
once in a while.
Greenpeace?
What drew you there?
Women.
NICK: 80% female,
Greenpeace.
Noble.
NICK: Noble was last year.
This year I'm getting paid.
Hammond's check cleared,
or I wouldn't go on
this wild-goose chase.
You're going to
the only place in the world
where the geese chase you.
KELLY: Dad! Dad!
IAN: Kelly,
my honey, you found it.
What took you so long?
Sorry, I couldn't
get a cab.
IAN: Sweetie, that's okay.
Listen, I've got to
tell you something.
I've got to talk to you.
I don't even know
this woman.
IAN: You've known Karen
for 10 years.
She doesn't even have Sega.
She's such a troglodyte.
Cruel, but good word use.
KELLY: Why can't
I stay with Sarah?
She's out of town.
Karen's fantastic.
She'll take you places.
You'll have a fantastic time.
Stop saying "fantastic."
Where are you going, anyway?
It's only for a few days.
I wouldn't be going if it
wasn't really important.
I'm your daughter
all the time.
You can't
abandon me whenever
opportunity knocks.
That hurts my feelings.
Your mom tell you
to say that?
EDDIE: Dr. Malcolm,
downstairs, please.
I know we've had
some hard going.
But in the last few years,
we've started to work
things out.
Yeah, but crack
on me a bit.
Ground me or something.
Send me to my room.
You never do
any of that stuff.
Why would I?
You turned out so
beautiful, brilliant,
powerful, funny,
and generous.
The queen, goddess.
My inspiration.
EDDIE: Dr. Malcolm.
KELLY: I could come
be your research assistant,
like I was in Austin.
This is nothing
like Austin.
Anyway, you have
your own stuff.
Your gymnastics competition.
You've been training
for months.
Gymnastics?
I scrubbed out, Dad,
I got cut from the team.
Thanks for knowing.
I'm sorry, honey.
I know how much
that meant to you.
You like to have kids.
But you just don't
want to be with them,
do you?
It wasn't me who dumped you
and split for Paris,
so don't take it
out on me.
EDDIE:
Dr. Malcolm, downstairs!
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You want some
good parental advice?
Don't listen to me.
MAN: How are
we doing here?
(MEN CHATTERING)
The specs say it can't
deform at 12,000 PSI,
so we just have to test it.
Let's clear.
Are we clear?
What's this?
A High Hide.
You know, you go up
and hide, high.
It goes up to where
the trees are
and keeps the researchers
out of harm's way.
Actually, it puts them
at a very convenient
biting height.
What's the time?
Do you have the time?
Do I have the time? Why?
We're leaving
in three hours.
This is so cool.
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Lindstradt air rifle.
Fires a subsonic Fluger
impact delivery dart.
It works better than
your satellite phone?
That's funny.
I loaded it with
the enhanced venom of
Conus Purpurascens,
South Sea cone shell.
Most powerful neurotoxin
in the world.
Acts within 0.002
of a second.
Which is faster than
the nerve-conduction
velocity.
So the animal's down
before it even feels
the prick of the dart.
Is there an antidote?
Like if you shot
yourself in the foot?
Don't do that.
You'd be dead before
you even realized
you had an accident.
(SPEAKING SPANISH ANGRILY)
He says
he's unloading us here.
He won't go
further up the river.
He's heard too many stories
about this island chain.
He'll drop us off
and anchor offshore.
What kind of stories?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Stories of fishermen
that came too close
to the island
and never returned.
He has a radio.
He has a satellite phone.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
When you need him,
call and he'll be here
in two hours.
But he will not stay here.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He won't stay anywhere
near these islands.
They call the islands
"Las Cinco Muertes"?
What does that mean?
"The Five Deaths",
he says.
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
EDDIE: I put
a location sensor in
Dr. Harding's phone,
so we should get a reading.
IAN: I'm so relieved.
EDDIE: Don't push my buttons.
We're almost
on top of her dot.
She should be around here.
Over there.
(ADVENTUROUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Sarah!
Sarah Harding!
How many Sarahs do you think
are on this island?
(BUSHES RUSTLING)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
What?
Something big.
(RUMBLING)
(EXCLAIMING SOFTLY)
Wow.
(GROWLING)
This is magnificent.
Yeah. "Ooh, ah,"
that's how it
always starts.
But then later there's
running and screaming.
Wow.
Nick!
(LAUGHING)
I guess you got
the jump on us,
didn't you, Sarah?
SARAH: Yeah.
(SARAH STOPS LAUGHING)
Ian, I never thought
in a million years
Hammond could get you
to come here.
SARAH: Hi, Eddie.
Hi, Sarah.
Got a granola bar
or something? I'm starving.
Did you see those animals?
A family group,
a pair-bond and
a sub-adult,
long after the juvenile
was nest bound.
Every egg clutch
I've seen has crushed,
trampled shells.
Hatchlings stay in
the birth environment
a long time.
That's conclusive.
I can put that controversy
to rest if I get a shot
of the nest.
Have you been attacked?
No, that's my lucky pack.
That's how it always looks.
Okay, Sarah...
SARAH: Is that a Nikon?
Can I borrow that?
I'll be right back, baby,
I promise.
IAN: When Hammond
called you,
why didn't you say
something to me?
I knew you would
have stopped me
from coming.
IAN: I would have
tied you to the bed.
I know how they
survived without lysine.
I don't care.
The herbivore species
that are thriving
eat mostly agama beans, soy,
anything lysine-rich.
(GROWLING)
And the carnivores
eat the herbivores, so...
Wait.
Stay there. Be quiet.
I'll be right back.
No!
Stay there.
(STEGOSAURUS HOWLING)
(STEGOSAURUS GRUNTING)
IAN: She's much too close.
What the hell is she doing?
Too close.
(STEGOSAURUS SNIFFING)
(MAGICAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(STEGOSAURUS GRUNTS SOFTLY)
She has to touch it.
She can't not touch.
She's going
right up to it.
Once she sees something,
she has to...
(STEGOSAURUS HOWLING)
Is this even possible?
What?
This? What did you
think you'd document?
What did you think
you'd see?
Animals. Maybe,
big iguanas.
Fruitcakes.
(WHIRRING AS CAMERA
REWINDS FILM)
(STEGOSAURUS HOWLING)
They get very angry
when you run out of film.
IAN: Sarah!
(STEGOSAURUS HOWLING)
IAN: Shoot them!
They're just
protecting their baby.
So am I!
(STEGOSAURUSES HOWLING)
(THRILLING
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
I think they're leaving.
(THRILLING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC SLOWING)
Wow.
These images are incredible.
Legendary.
Guys shoot their whole life,
they never get stuff
half this good.
Just give me
the Pulitzer right now.
Today, please.
The competition's over,
close the entries,
I'd like to thank
everyone who lost.
SARAH: Don't light that!
Dinosaurs pick up scents
from miles away.
We're here to
observe and document,
not interact.
IAN: Which, by the way,
is a scientific
impossibility.
Heisenberg
Uncertainty Principle.
What you study,
you also change.
SARAH: I'll risk it.
I'm sick of scratching
around in rock and bone
making assumptions
and deductions about
the nurturing
habits of animals
that have been dead
for 65 million years.
I'm sick of it, man.
Then you fill my head
with stories for four years.
Of course I came down here.
IAN: Stories of
mutilation and death.
Weren't you
paying attention?
SARAH: Please!
Don't treat me like
I'm a grad student.
I've worked
around predators since
I was 20 years old.
Lions, jackals,
hyenas, you.
(WILD SQUAWKING AND CHIRPING)
Where's the fire?
I'm trying
to change 100 years
of entrenched dogma.
Dinosaurs were
characterized very early on
as vicious lizards.
There's great resistance
to the idea of them
as nurturing parents.
Robert Burke said
the T. Rex was a rogue
who abandoned its young
at the earliest opportunity.
I can prove otherwise.
Fire! Dr. Malcolm,
fire, base camp!
SARAH: No! Water makes
the smoke billow. Use dirt!
Who started the fire?
I just wanted
to make dinner.
I wanted it ready
when you guys got back.
Do you see any family
resemblance there?
You practically
told me to come here.
I... What?
You said,
"Don't listen to me."
I thought you were trying
to tell me something.
Kelly, you knew
exactly what I meant.
You have no...
You want to lock her up
for her curiosity?
Where do you think
she gets it?
KELLY: Thank you, Sarah.
IAN: Don't start
the teaming-up thing.
Out of the conversation.
Please. Really.
Eddie?
What?
Why in the hell doesn't
this thing ever work?
It's not a landline.
You're not in a phone booth.
You got to wait
for a decent signal.
Violence and technology,
not good bedfellows.
Hammond wants
your equipment as close to
the animals as possible.
Great idea.
And why don't you smear
on a little sheep's blood?
Eddie, is there
any reason to think
the radio in
the trailer might work?
Don't tease me.
If you feel qualified,
try flicking
the switch to "on."
Okay, I'm taking
my daughter out of here.
Anyone coming with me,
this is your last chance
to get out.
When you're out
in the field...
Nick, if you're staying,
I'll gladly deliver
a letter to your wife
or loved one
so you can say goodbye.
Eddie, if you have
any personal effects
it's the least I can do.
I'll be in there, guys.
Our presence needs
to be 100% antiseptic.
If we so much as bend
a blade of grass...
Dad, are you mad?
No, I'm not mad.
I'm furious.
What is this?
This looks like your room.
I was going to clean it up.
Right now.
What is this?
There are 100 switches!
Don't be mad. I was
going to call to let you
know where I was.
I always do, don't I?
I'm the best kind
of girlfriend there is.
One who travels a lot.
You like that, right?
You love your independence.
I've gotten used
to being apart,
but that's not
how I want to live.
Kelly, this is tall talk.
Just for a minute.
It's like
a height restriction
at an amusement park.
If you wanted to rescue me,
why didn't you
bail me out from
that museum
fundraiser three weeks ago,
like you said you would?
This is a slightly
different situation.
What about
the dinner with your parents
you never showed up for?
Why not rescue me
when I really need it?
Be there when
you say you will?
I have made a career
out of waiting for you.
You know,
Sarah has a pretty good...
It's so important
to your future that you
not finish that sentence.
Please, outside!
Ian, come on. Look.
I love that you rode
in here on a white horse.
I really do.
It's very touching,
very dramatic.
I just need you to
show up in a cab every
once in a while, too.
What are you doing?
Don't go out there.
It's not safe.
Stay in here. Come back.
Shut the door.
Okay.
I know what I'm doing.
You guys should
definitely go.
But I'm going to stay.
I love you.
I just don't need you
right now.
What you need is
a good anti-psychotic.
I'll be back
in five or six days.
No, you'll be back
in five or six pieces.
What bothers you is that
I'm not afraid of this place,
and you are.
IAN: Of course I am.
That's the whole thing.
All I want is...
What's that sound?
(RUMBLING)
IAN: Here we go.
I'll get you out on
one of these, now.
Hello! Over here!
I don't get it.
It says InGen on the side
of that chopper!
I don't get that.
Why would Hammond
send two teams?
KELLY: Cut the
umbilical, Dad!
Doesn't he trust us?
We haven't even started.
PETER: This is as
good a place as any
for base camp.
That's first priority
after we're finished.
I want it up
and running in 30 minutes.
That's half an hour.
Understood? Over.
Cancel that order.
What? Why?
This is a game trail,
Mr. Ludlow.
Carnivores hunt
on game trails.
You want to set up
base camp or a buffet?
Let's find a new spot,
shall we? Over and out.
Peter, if I run your
little camping trip,
there are two conditions.
First, I'm in charge.
If I'm not around,
Dieter is.
You just pay us,
tell us we're doing well,
and serve us Scotch
after a good day.
Second condition, my fee.
You can keep it.
All I want for my services,
is the right to hunt
a tyrannosaurus.
A male. A buck only.
How and why are my business.
If you don't like
those conditions,
you're on your own.
So go ahead,
set up base camp here,
in a swamp, or in
the middle of a Rex nest
for all I care.
I've had too many safaris
with rich dentists
to listen to any more
suicidal ideas.
Okay?
Okay.
Cycle, break off
the stray from the herd
and flush him to the right.
Snaggers, stay ready.
He's bringing them out
to you. It'll be a
Pachy... Pachya...
Oh, hell.
The fat head with
the bald spot. Friar Tuck.
(ROARING)
Stop.
Pachycephalosaurus.
Carnivore?
No, herbivore,
late Cretaceous.
(ROARING)
See the distinctive
domed skull?
Nine inches of solid bone.
Now, careful.
See, the Pachy's neck
attaches at the bottom
of its skull,
not at the back
of its head.
When it lowers its head,
its neck lines up
with its backbone,
which is perfect
for absorbing impact.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Snagger, Friar Tuck's
on the loose,
just about to cross
your path.
(SCREECHING)
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
ROLAND: Dieter,
get in the outrigger.
You're closing in
on a carina...
DIETER: Say that
again, Roland. A what?
ROLAND: The one
with the big red horn.
The pompadour. Elvis.
Take me out.
Okay, Carter, reel me in.
Easy!
(ROARING)
DIETER: Not too close.
Go for the legs!
The legs! Watch the tail!
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(MELANCHOLY
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
ROLAND: Burke!
Come here.
Recognize this trackway?
Yes, I do. Tyrannosaur.
LUDLOW: Roland.
Where do you think
you're going?
To collect
my fee, Mr. Ludlow.
To collect my fee.
(SQUELCHING)
(DINOSAUR CHITTERS)
(HISSING)
Oh, my God.
Procompsognathus triassicus,
found by Frass in Bavaria
in 1913.
Is it dangerous?
No, I wouldn't think so.
The Compy's been presumed
to be a scavengers,
like jackals.
It gives me the creeps.
It's like it's not scared.
There haven't
been any visitors
to this island.
There's no reason
for it to fear man.
Now it does.
(INSECTS BUZZING)
ROLAND: It's the Rex nest.
Infant's probably only
a couple weeks old.
Never left the nest.
Offspring that young,
the parents won't leave him
alone for too long.
AJAY: Make your blind here,
wait for the buck to return.
No. If the nest is upwind,
then so are we.
When he comes back,
he's gonna know
we're here without us
having a chance.
The trick is to get him
to come where we want him.
(HOWLING IN PAIN)
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
This is why Hammond
was in a hurry to
get you here.
He knew they were coming.
My God,
they are well-organized.
Those are some
major-league toys.
IAN: Maybe I should ask
to use their phone.
Their dish is bigger
than yours.
So they actually want
to build another park here?
After what
you said happened
on the other island?
They're not
building anything.
They're taking these
animals out of here.
Back to the mainland.
I think I should tell you.
Hammond told me these people
might show up.
He thought we'd be finished
by the time they started,
but if they weren't
he sent a backup plan.
What backup plan?
Me.
LUDLOW: InGen is seeking
limited partners
to defray some
of our expenses.
LUDLOW: The prospectus
you've been given
by the board details
our projected hardware
and construction expenses.
As you can see
by my two friends here,
the software is
already fully developed.
One might say,
"It'd be up and running."
In a moment,
I'll take you on a stroll
through the camp
and you'll see some larger,
more impressive specimens.
Wow.
(DINOSAURS GROWLING
AND GRUNTING)
(DINOSAUR HOWLS)
You don't bring people
halfway around the world
to visit a zoo.
You bring the zoo to them.
San Diego is
the perfect setting.
People already
associate our beautiful city
with animal attractions:
San Diego Zoo, Sea World,
San Diego Chargers.
(DINOSAURS
HOWLING AND ROARING)
LUDLOW: Mr. Hammond
knew this.
Before he ever
dreamt of an island
he began construction
on an amphitheatre
very near to where
you're sitting now,
the InGen Waterfront Complex.
But he abandoned it
in favor of something
far grander
and ultimately impossible.
And so,
the facility sits
unused, unfinished,
when it could be
completed and ready
to receive visitors
in less than a month.
(ROARING)
(ALL SHOUTING IN PANIC)
(DINOSAURS
ROARING AND GRUNTING)
ROLAND: Ajay,
look out! Jump!
(FAST-PACED
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(BABY REX WAILING)
That's the last time
I leave you in charge.
(WATER SPLASHING)
(BABY REX WAILING)
SARAH: Oh, my God.
Are you out of your mind?
NICK: She's got
a broken leg.
Let's get in the car
before they hear us.
You have any idea
what that is?
Come on,
open the door.
You're nuts.
Man, Ian's not
going to like this.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
What's going on?
Isn't it obvious?
We're not alone
on this island.
IAN: It's not set
to the frequency.
Look here.
What the hell is that?
IAN: It's right here.
Hello?
(WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING SPANISH)
No, not Enrique.
Ian Malcolm.
Are you on the boat?
No, is this the boat?
(WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING SPANISH)
We're on Isla Sorna.
We need to talk to
the boat, Mar del Plata.
NICK: I'll get him.
All right. That's it.
I got you.
Hurry up.
Let's go. Go. Come on.
Watch his tail.
Get the door.
(WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING SPANISH ANGRILY)
Boy, is she mad at you.
I feel sorry
for that guy, Enrique.
No lectures, please.
Honey, stay back.
Don't stand up, okay?
I got it!
Watch his head.
Ian, he's hurt!
No, honey, no.
SARAH: I'm going
to get the table.
He'll snip at you.
Watch his tail,
he's swinging his tail.
Set him down.
All right?
Okay, I got him.
Got him?
Yeah.
(BABY REX WAILING LOUDLY)
It's okay.
There you go.
IAN: What must I do,
hit her with a stick?
No, don't get close, honey.
Watch out!
Don't stand too close.
He smells.
(WOMAN ON RADIO
SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BABY REX WAILING)
No, lady, enough!
Wrong frequency. God.
SARAH: Nick, don't let him
get those things around you.
(BABY REX WAILING)
Hello,
it's Ian Malcolm.
SARAH: Okay,
let's take a look at this.
Easy, easy.
Just calm down now.
SARAH: Okay,
here are the metatarsals.
Tibia, fibula.
There it is.
There's the fracture.
Right above the epiphysis.
NICK: How bad is it?
If we don't set it,
he'll die. It won't heal.
He won't be able to
pivot on his ankle.
He won't be able
to run or walk.
A predator
will pick him off.
Carlos, come in.
God damn it,
you bastard, listen...
Other animals
are going to hear this.
Come in, please.
Can you hear me?
I've got to get out of here.
I want to leave.
I'm calling the boat.
I want to go someplace else.
I don't want to be here.
I want to be somewhere safe.
IAN: Isn't it safe here?
I want to be
somewhere high.
What? What is it?
What's going on?
Information, please. What?
IAN: You're much
happier not knowing.
Get us up. Here we go.
There we go.
KELLY: I'm so stupid.
I shouldn't have
come along with you.
Can you set it?
Yeah, I just need
something temporary
to break apart and
fall off as he grows.
Whenever you're ready.
He's fighting, Dr. Quinn.
What's the frequency
for the boat?
EDDIE: 15888.
It's third from the top.
Okay, we're high.
This is the safest
place you can be.
Like Sarah said,
the plants make it
so the animals
won't know you're here.
KELLY: You're just trying
to make me feel better.
I remember the stories
you told.
This is nothing like that.
We're in a completely
different situation now.
(LOUD ROARING)
IAN: Is there any
way we can communicate
with the trailer?
He's moving again,
more morphine.
SARAH: We have no idea
what his metabolism is.
We'll kill him with too much.
(PHONE RINGING)
I need your hand here.
Put some pressure there.
No answer.
What a surprise.
How do I get down?
Tie this belt around you.
Where are you going?
Stay here. Come on,
stay here. Please!
Squeeze this rope hard.
The harder you squeeze,
the slower you go.
If you don't
squeeze at all...
I get the idea.
Dad, please stay here.
Stay here, please.
Honey, the queen?
The goddess?
Your inspiration?
Now you're talking.
IAN: Now you're talking.
All right.
I'm coming right back.
I give you my word.
But you never
keep your word!
(IAN CRASHING TO THE GROUND)
I would have squeezed
just a little bit harder.
Okay, I'm almost finished.
Damn it.
I need another adhesive.
Something pliable
that I can...
Spit.
Your gum.
(MOANING SLEEPILY)
(HEAVY CRASHING
IN THE FOREST)
(HIGH-PITCHED SCREECHING)
(EARTH-SHAKING REX
FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
SARAH: Get the amoxicillin
and fill a syringe.
Quick injection
of antibiotics and
he's out of here.
(PHONE RINGING)
For once in your life,
would it kill
you to pick it up?
Help me get it out of here.
No, we just set its leg.
(EARTH-SHAKING REX FOOTSTEP)
Mommy's very angry.
(REX ROARING)
(ALL PANTING IN TERROR)
This isn't
hunting behavior, Ian.
They're searching.
They came for their infant.
Let's not disappoint them.
Let me get his head, okay?
Careful. Be careful.
SARAH: I got him.
NICK: Muzzle off.
(GROWLING AND
ROARING CONTINUES)
(PHONE RINGING)
IAN: Yes, Eddie?
They're going
back to the jungle.
IAN: I know. I see.
How's Kelly?
She's fine.
She's right here.
Hello?
Kelly, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm good.
Stay there. Don't move.
I'll be right back up.
Understand?
Yeah, I understand.
(PANTING)
I beg people
to listen to me.
I use plain,
simple English.
Shut up.
That should make
an interesting chapter
in your book.
The debate over
the parental instincts
of the T. Rex
is now academic.
Hang on.
This is gonna be bad.
(ALL YELLING)
(REX ROARING)
They're pushing
us over the cliff.
Oh, my God.
Come on, come on.
Once we're out of here...
Into the woods.
Straight into the woods.
Come on!
This is where they hit us.
Hang on to something!
Sarah!
(GLASS CREAKING AND CRACKING)
SARAH: Oh, God, please!
Don't move!
I'm coming down for you.
Here I come. Stay still.
Here I come, Sarah.
The satellite phone,
get it!
NICK: Okay.
(SUSPENSEFUL
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(GLASS CRACKING)
Give me your hand, honey.
NICK: Heads up!
(SARAH SCREAMING)
(SURF CRASHING AND POUNDING)
Your lucky pack.
I got her.
(HORN HONKING)
(CALLING THE OTHERS)
EDDIE: Nick?
NICK: We're in here.
Hold on!
I'm coming.
God damn it!
What did this?
Kelly. What'd you
do with Kelly?
She's okay.
She's in the High Hide.
Who's hurt?
What do you need?
IAN: We need rope.
Rope. Anything else?
Three cheeseburgers
with everything.
NICK: No onions on mine.
SARAH: And an apple turnover.
(SUSPENSEFUL
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
EDDIE: Hold on.
I'm coming!
IAN: Bring the rope.
Let's go.
I'm coming.
IAN: Now, now.
NICK: Eddie, you all right?
EDDIE: Yeah. I'm coming.
We need the rope.
Throw it down here.
Hurry up!
Good throw.
Did you tie this
to anything?
NICK: We're sliding down!
IAN: Up you go.
(SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
Eddie! Hey!
(SARAH GASPING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(TRIUMPHANT
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Go.
Increase your rate of climb.
(SARAH SCREAMING)
(EARTH-SHAKING
REX FOOTSTEPS)
(MOTOR REVVING)
(EDDIE SCREAMING)
(TRIUMPHANT
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
ROLAND: Our communication
equipment's been destroyed.
And if your radio
and satellite phone were
in those trailers...
They were.
Then we're stuck here.
And stuck together,
thanks to you people.
We came to watch.
You came to
strip-mine the place.
Back off.
At least we came prepared.
Five years of work
and electrified fence
couldn't prepare
the other island.
You think your
Marlboro men will help?
You're looters.
You came to take.
You have no rights.
An extinct animal brought
back to life has no rights.
It exists
because we made it.
We patented it. We own it.
You looking for a problem?
And I found you, didn't I?
Stop!
Come on!
I know you.
You're that
Earth First bastard.
What's Earth First?
Professional saboteurs.
Environmentalists!
Criminals.
Knock it off!
Listen to me.
Moving the baby to
our camp may have
changed the adults'
perceived territory.
LUDLOW: Their what?
That's why they
attacked the trailers.
They're defending
this entire area now.
We have to move now.
To where? Our boat
and their airlift
are waiting for
orders we can't send.
All right.
There's a communications
center here near the old
operations building.
Everything ran on
geothermal power.
It was never meant
to need replenishing.
If we can get here,
we can send a radio
call to the airlift.
You know the frequency?
Here in this book.
We'll mind those.
How far is the village?
A day's walk, maybe more.
LUDLOW:
That's not the problem.
ROLAND: What is?
What is the problem?
Velociraptors.
Their nesting sites are
in the island's interior,
which is why
we were keeping
to the outer rim.
Wait. What's a Veloc...
Velociraptor.
Carnivore. Pack hunter.
Two meters tall,
long snout,
binocular vision,
strong dexterous forearms,
killing claws on both feet.
The Rexes
may track us, too,
if they feel
we're a threat to them
or their infant.
No, we'll lose them
once we leave
their territory.
Don't bet on it. Tyrannosaur
has the largest proportional
olfactory cavity
of any creature in
fossil record, except one.
Right.
The turkey vulture
could scent up to 10 miles.
Right. This is all
very thrilling,
but I say we should
head for the village.
We could head back
down to the lagoon.
And sit out in the open,
next to a heavily
used water source
hope that your
captain comes back?
He won't.
He knows better.
Then we head
for the village,
we might find shelter
and we can call for help.
Rex just fed, so he
won't stalk us for food.
Just fed? You mean Eddie?
Show some respect.
He saved our lives
by giving his.
Then his troubles are over.
My point is
predators don't hunt
when they're not hungry.
NICK: No, only humans do.
You're breaking our heart.
Saddle up! Let's get this
moveable feast underway.
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
NICK: Excuse me, cowboy.
You want some gum?
You seem like you
have common sense.
Why the hell are you here?
Somewhere on this island
is the greatest predator
that ever lived.
The second greatest predator
must take him down.
You going to use that?
If he doesn't
surrender, yes.
Let me see it.
No.
The animal exists
for the first time
in tens of
millions of years
and the only way
you can express yourself
is to kill it.
Remember that chap
about 20 years ago?
I forget his name.
Climbed Everest
without any oxygen.
Came down nearly dead.
They asked him,
"Why did you go
up there to die?"
He said, "I didn't.
I went up there to live."
I didn't wish you luck
on your new venture.
You're off to
a promising start.
My team is intact.
I'm sorry for
the loss of your man.
It's easy to criticize
someone who generates an
idea, assumes the risk.
When you try to
sound like Hammond,
it comes off as a hustle.
It's not your fault.
They say talent
skips a generation.
I'm sure your kids
will be sharp as tacks.
Hammond's reach
exceeded his grasp.
Mine does not.
Taking dinosaurs
off this island
is the worst idea
in the long, sad history
of bad ideas.
And I'll be there
when you learn that.
(ADVENTUROUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ROARING)
Go.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Take a break. Five minutes.
Are you injured?
No, it's the baby's.
I set its broken leg.
It won't dry
in the humidity.
LUDLOW: Roland, a word?
I'd love to know
where we are.
Making friends with Ahab?
(MEN CHATTERING)
DIETER: Carter, I'm going
to the ladies' room.
Wait for me here. Okay?
(MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
(SINGING IN SPANISH)
(WARBLING)
(SHRIEKING)
It's not polite to
sneak up on people.
(ELECTRIC ZAPPING)
Carter! Where are you?
I got turned around in here.
Shit!
Carter, let me
hear from you!
(MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
Hey, Carter!
(CHIRPING)
(CHIRPING CONTINUES)
Hey, Carter!
(EERIE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Carter!
(COMPIES CHIRPING
AND TRILLING)
Roland!
Okay, break's over.
Moving on!
Carry me.
I got it.
Carter.
(MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
(SOLEMN INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(DIETER YELLING)
(COMPIES CHIRPING
AND TRILLING)
Get off!
(CHIRPING AND TRILLING)
(DIETER SCREAMING)
When did you last see him?
10, 15 minutes.
Come with me. And you.
If he's alive,
we'll find him.
The rest of you
keep right on.
Ten minutes,
you'll reach the ridge.
Wait for us there.
No one tells
the little girl.
Right. Let's carry on.
Everybody up.
Come on. Up, up.
All right, guys,
let's get the hell
out of here.
Come on.
(SUSPENSEFUL
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(WHISPERING) Roland?
AJAY: Did you find him?
ROLAND: Just the parts
they didn't like. Map.
The operations building
is right down in there
about a mile and a half
from the base
of these cliffs.
How do you know that?
I've seen it.
The climb down
won't be easy.
We'll let them sleep
one more hour.
Then we hit it.
(DISTANT EARTH-SHAKING
REX FOOTSTEP)
(EARTH-SHAKING REX
FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, no.
(EARTH-SHAKING REX
FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(DISTANT TRILLING
AND CHIRPING)
(EARTH-SHAKING REX FOOTSTEP)
(PANTING)
(REX SNIFFING AND GROWLING)
(REX GROWLING SOFTLY)
What is that?
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
(SARAH SHUSHES KELLY)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Kelly.
(SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Stay down! Don't move!
IAN: Don't run!
IAN: Don't look,
just run! Run!
(MEN YELLING)
(GUN CLICKS)
Bastard!
(REX ROARING)
(THRILLING
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(REX ROARS THUNDEROUSLY)
(EARTH-SHAKING REX FOOTSTEPS)
You son of a bitch!
He can't reach you!
Stay back!
He can't reach us!
No!
Oh, my God!
A snake! Help me!
Stay back!
It's okay.
It's coming back!
KELLY: Dad!
IAN: Thank you.
(MEN SHOUTING)
Don't go
into the long grass!
Not into the long grass!
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
MAN: Move it.
Keep moving.
Move it!
(MAN YELLING)
(SHRIEKING AND YELLING)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
BECOMES MORE RHYTHMIC)
Hey, hey!
Look at this.
What is it?
I think it's Ajay's bag.
(LOW TRILLING AND GROWLING)
Go, as fast as you can.
Go!
(IAN MOANS IN PAIN)
I see structures there.
They said the communications
center is in the
operations building.
I'll get in there
and send the radio call.
See you there.
Wait for us.
Every second counts.
If you can keep up,
you're welcome to try.
Okay, here we come.
No! Rest.
(SUSPENSEFUL
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
Oh, man.
(SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Damn it!
(RADIO WHISTLES AND HUMS)
Be there.
CQ, this is InGen Operations
Harvest Leader
to Harvest Base.
Repeating, I'm calling
for InGen Operations
Harvest Leader
seeking InGen Harvest Base.
Go ahead, Harvest Leader.
The operation has suffered
severe casualties.
The survivors are now
in mortal danger.
I need you to send
rescue immediately.
Our co-ordinates
here are
9 degrees 58 minutes north,
85 degrees...
(ENORMOUS MUFFLED BREATHING)
IAN: Nick!
(IAN CONTINUES CALLING)
IAN: Nick Van Owen?
(ROARING)
Here, here!
Inside! Anywhere!
Come inside!
(SHRIEKING)
(SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(RAPTOR SHRIEKING
AND GROWLING)
(TREMENDOUS
THUDDING AGAINST DOOR)
(THUDDING INCREASING
IN FEROCITY)
(RAPTORS GROWLING
AND SNARLING)
(PANTING)
Go.
KELLY: Where do I go
when I'm out?
I'm right behind you...
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
INTENSIFIES)
SARAH: Look out!
KELLY: Watch out!
Up here!
(RAPTOR SNARLING AND HISSING)
Kelly, no!
KELLY: Hey, you!
The school cut you
from the team?
Get out of here! Go!
(SUSPENSEFUL INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(RAPTOR GROWLING
AND SNARLING)
Come on. Let's go!
(HELICOPTER ROTORS WHIRRING)
Let's go!
(TRIUMPHANT
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
NICK: Let's go!
IAN: What about
the other survivors?
NICK: Another
chopper's coming.
(TRIUMPHANT INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
IAN: It's okay.
It's over now.
That's one souvenir
they won't be taking
with them.
LUDLOW: Find
the infant tyrannosaur.
Roland can
show you where
the nest is.
I want it on my jet.
I'll take it directly
to the infirmary
in San Diego.
Hurry. I want
to be airborne
before the female
knows we're here.
LUDLOW: Roland?
You probably saved InGen.
We lost everything
we came after on this trip.
But this animal
and its infant
will bail us out.
Congratulations.
You've got your trophy!
A buck only.
But it's alive!
Everyone will line up
and appreciate it and
what you did for us.
What's the matter?
He didn't make it. Ajay.
I'm sorry.
Really, I am.
I remember the people
who've helped me.
There's a job
for you in San Diego,
if you want it.
No, thank you.
I've spent enough time
in the company of death.
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Oh, my God.
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
LUDLOW: Fifteen years ago,
John Hammond had a dream.
Like John himself,
the dream was grand.
It was outsized.
It was bold.
It was impractical.
It was not to be.
But half an hour from now,
John Hammond's dream,
re-imagined, will come true.
For.01 of the cost of
building a destination
resort thousands
of miles away...
IAN: Is this
the Ludlow affair?
It's private property.
We're on the list.
Turn around,
get back in your car.
This is Dr. Harding,
I'm Dr. Malcolm.
We have Mr. Ludlow's
test results.
There's good and bad news.
LUDLOW:
Tonight we will christen
Jurassic Park, San Diego,
with a mega-attraction
that will drive
turnstile numbers
to rival any theme park
in the world.
I want to thank each
one of you for coming
in these wee small
hours of the morning.
The ship is here.
It's early?
You better come now.
It's so exciting!
See that couple?
Sir, you need
to look at this.
Let them see this up close.
Yes, sir.
Let me check.
MAN: I want a direct
line to the Coast Guard
right now.
Look. That's their
transponder signal,
Venture 5888.
They're coming in,
but I can't raise them.
LUDLOW: Try again.
Skipper, SS Venture,
this is InGen
Harbor Master.
Do you copy? Over.
Skipper, SS Venture,
you are approaching the
breakwater at flank speed.
Reduce at once. Over.
(DISTANT LOW RUMBLING)
SS Venture,
reduce your speed at once.
SS Venture, this is
InGen Harbor Master.
You are entering
a docking area.
SARAH: What's everybody
looking at?
We should've stayed
in the damn car.
(RADIO STATIC)
(LOW RUMBLING GROWING LOUDER)
(CONFUSED
SHOUTING AND TALKING)
You okay, Mr. Ludlow?
I don't know.
How do I look?
MAN: Go up this one.
Oh, my God.
Where's the crew?
All over the place.
WORKER: I smell a fuel leak!
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
Check the cargo hold!
There may be crew
down there.
Everybody off the boat!
No! Get away from that!
(REX GROWLING)
Now you're John Hammond.
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
SARAH: Why wasn't
it tranquilized?
MAN: It was, with two
darts of Carfentanil.
It was over 10 milligrams.
SARAH: That'd put it
in a coma.
It stopped breathing.
We gave it naltrexone
to counteract.
But we didn't know
how much.
You gave an antagonist
without knowing the dosage?
You put it in
a narcoleptic state.
It's a locomotive now.
We're prepared here.
Any more dinosaurs
on the boat?
No, we brought the infant
back on the plane.
We had this
to tranquilize it.
Do you have
the infant?
(FAINTLY) It's safe.
Ian.
The animal's dehydrated.
First, it'll go to
a water source
then look for the next
thing its body needs.
All the containment
equipment is here.
We got to get it
to the dock.
The boat might
be seaworthy.
I know what
you're gonna say.
When we brought the baby
to the trailer, it came.
There's no
reason why it won't do
the same thing here.
Yep.
Where's the infant?
In a secured facility. Why?
Where's the facility?
(EARTH-SHAKING REX
FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
There's a dinosaur
in our backyard.
Benjamin,
what are you doing?
What are you doing?
What?
Come on. There's a dinosaur
in our backyard.
The problem is,
you need to read to him.
No.
I will tell you
what it is.
You have to serve him dinner,
he won't be up all night.
It's the stupid fish tank!
He needs
a proper nightlight.
Put something over it!
It may as well be daytime.
Just turn it off.
Slow down. Slow it down!
(FAST-PACED
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
SARAH: There it is.
He's sedated.
Really heavily.
Give me a hand.
When the adult
sees us again
with his baby,
isn't he going to be like:
"You!"
There may be some
angry recognition.
Who knows?
He may be just
happy to see us.
What the hell
are you doing?
We're taking the kid.
If you really want
to stop us, shoot us.
How will we find
the adult?
Follow the screams.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Get to the other
side of the bus!
There.
Oh, my God.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
SARAH: It's too drugged.
He won't know we have it
unless it makes some sound!
Wake up. Come on.
He knows.
Ian, slow down a little.
IAN: I don't think so.
(SIRENS BLARING)
This guy's
almost fully awake.
You know
where you're going?
Yeah, the waterfront's
on the other side
of these warehouses.
Is there a way through?
God. There could be.
IAN: There we go.
You have to follow me now.
There we go.
SARAH: Got him?
IAN: Yep.
Here we go.
Ready?
Where's the Rex?
Is it behind us?
There's the water.
Shoot it.
Tell them to shoot it.
(BABY REX WAILING)
No, you idiot, the adult.
Shoot the adult.
I want the baby back alive.
(ADVENTUROUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(BABY REX WAILING)
Dr. Malcolm!
What have you done with it?
I want that infant!
(MUFFLED BABY REX WAILING)
(MUFFLED BABY REX CHORTLING)
Are you there?
(MUFFLED BABY REX GROWLING)
There you are.
Wait.
(ADVENTUROUS
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(CARGO DOORS CLOSING)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(TRIUMPHANT
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
TV REPORTER:
There's a first-rate shot
of the ship's deck
and the cargo hold that,
for the moment,
contains the animal itself,
presumably with
the infant alongside.
By our calculations,
they should be nearing
the halfway
point of this trip.
Jim, can you
still hear me there?
JIM: Yes, I can, Bernard.
We are halfway to the island.
It is 206 nautical miles
from our present location.
The ship is moving
at 20 knots
which will put it in
at about 11:30 a.m.,
Eastern time.
One of the Navy's
primary concerns
has been safety.
If we look at
the ever-growing escort
around the ship
they're taking no
chances of a repeat
of the San Diego incident.
TV REPORTER:
Let's take a moment
to run the tape
of our interview
earlier today
with John Hammond.
He's the former head
of InGen Bio-Engineering,
the man who is
now spearheading
this movement
not only to
return the animals
to their island
but to keep
the island itself intact.
It is
absolutely imperative
that we work
with the Costa Rican
Department of
Biological Preserves
to establish
a set of rules
for the preservation
and isolation
of that island.
These creatures
require our absence
to survive,
not our help.
And if we could
only step aside
and trust in nature
life will find a way.
(DINOSAURS ROARING)
(PTERODACTYL SHRIEKING)
(TRIUMPHANT
INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(MAGICAL INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)