Why don't you, like,
ever realise the truth, Vince?
I ate nine pies and a Meatball Hero
in one hour. That's a record.
It wasn't nine pies.
It was eight.
You left two slices of mushroom
on the last tray.
- Violet?
- You guys, it was six pies. No Hero.
I had to call the paramedics
to pump your stomach,
and it was three and a half years ago.
When are you gonna talk
about something else?
When someone comes through
that door and breaks the record,
then we'll stop talkin'
about the subject.
Enjoy your pie, guys.
- It's the last one I'll ever serve.
- Aren't you forgetting something?
Quit it, Pete. I'm not doin' that.
It's a tradition. Sign the card.
I got it, folks.
I got the first autograph.
- Hey, Violet. All right.
- Violet's on her way to the wall.
That's 20 years
of girls leaving town.
That wall is jinxed.
I won't sit near that wall.
Let's hope you have better luck
than they did.
Ladies and gentlemen.
As you all know,
my best friend, Violet Sanford,
has decided...
has decided to leave
South Amboy tomorrow,
and travel the 42 miles
to New York City.
So... OK, come on.
Bring her up here, girls.
Come on, Violet.
Come on, Vi.
Come on, everyone.
Violet, come on.
Come up here.
- Come on, honey.
- You guys.
Now, I think it's only fair
that tonight,
on her last night here with us
in Jersey,
she grace us with a little tune.
- No way.
- Go, go, go, go, go.
Look at this.
Four people killed last night
in New York.
No reason at all.
Police have no leads.
- Tragic.
- Dad, what are you doing?
I guess four out of seven million
ain't so bad.
Headline should read,
"Millions Survive Night in New York."
Dad, stop. I get the point.
Here. Eat your eggs.
They're not eggs. They're egg whites.
And I'd rather eat the carton.
You've already lost six pounds.
You're staying on this diet.
No fast food. No sausage.
And I bought you some of those Lean
Cuisine meals, and I put 'em in the freezer.
- My mouth is watering already.
- And your vitamins are on the counter.
- I don't take vitamins.
- You do now. Just take them.
And I put fresh batteries in
the TV remote and set the VCR timer, so...
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Am I missing something here?
I'm the parent. You're the child
running away to live by herself.
I should be tellin' you
how to live.
- Fine. How should I live?
- Simple. Don't go.
I got that Irish Spring you like.
And, Dad, whatever you do,
- don't do the laundry.
- Don't do the laundry.
Just leave it by the dryer, and I'll do it
when I come home every Sunday.
This is interesting. They say
the handrails on the subway system
could one day
lead to an outbreak of plague.
Dad...
Look, you said I could be
whatever I wanna be.
I never said "song-writer in New York City".
That's the exception.
You said anything,
and I believed you, so...
I'm not leavin' this house
without your support.
That's Gloria. What's it gonna be?
Violet, I saw how hard it was
for your mother when she didn't make it.
But if she was here,
she'd tell me to shut up,
wish you luck
and give you a big hug.
I'm not gonna give you a big hug,
and I'm not gonna wish you luck, but...
I am gonna shut up, sit here with my coffee
and pretend to be mad. Is that OK?
This is the last of it.
- Honey, are you OK with that?
- Yeah, I got it, I got it.
Wait. All right.
- That's everything.
- Let's hit it.
Good luck.
There, I said it.
- Love you.
- I put some pepper spray in your purse.
Even if you're not sure, just start spraying.
You know, you're not alone, Mr Sanford.
You know, me and you
should have dinner sometime.
I'm lockin' the doors.
All right. This is it.
What do you think?
I had a feeling
you were gonna need this.
- What are you doing?
- It's just some emergency cash I saved up.
Honey, from the looks of this place,
I'd say this is our emergency.
Well, I'm not takin' it.
Fine, then.
I'm freezing your assets.
So, thanks for everything. I'll call ya.
- What is this?
- It's just that all our lives, you know,
we always had one thing in common,
you and me.
What are you talking about?
It's like, you know we said
we wouldn't lose our virginity
until we got married,
and that didn't happen.
And then we said
we'd go to college or junior college,
or dental hygienist school,
you know.
And that didn't happen.
We've never followed through
on a single thing, you know.
And I think that's
what makes us so special.
And this is why you're crying?
Well...
A long time ago you told me
that you were gonna move to New York.
But everyone thought you'd just
stay in Jersey and get married,
like me and Danny are gonna.
You know, and look at you.
No matter what,
you really did it, Vi,
and I'm so proud of you.
Turn that down. You hear me?
You be quiet. It's not fair.
Hi. I'm Violet Sanford.
I just recently moved to New York,
and I was wondering if you would
give my tape to one of your artists.
Violet, that is so cute.
Now, let me tell you about me.
My name is Wendy,
and I first moved to New York when I was
21 to be a dancer, but I broke my big toe.
And then I got knocked up by this actor
who dumped me to join the Peace Corps.
So for the last 16 years I been
raisin' my daughter all by myself.
And then two weeks ago
she tells me that she is a bisexual,
and that she hates me more
than any person on this planet.
Now, tell me
how I can help you, please,
because I am dying
to make your dreams come true.
You don't take the tape
unless it comes from an agent,
but I can't get an agent
until I get published?
If we were to listen to that tape,
that would give you grounds
for a copyright or plagiarism lawsuit.
It's just a little tape.
All I want is someone to sing my songs.
Welcome to the music business.
- Good evening. I.D., please.
- Hi. Sure.
- What can I get you?
- Let me ask you something.
I'm a song-writer. Is there someone
here I could talk to about my songs?
I've been a struggling
sax player for 12 years.
- What can I get you from the bar?
- Pepsi and some crackers.
Hey. How are you doing?
Excuse me.
Who's that guy?
That would be Mr O'Donnell.
Mr O'Donnell.
He's the manager or something?
Yeah. He's the music manager.
He's in charge of finding bands and...
booking new talent.
Where the hell were you, O'Donnell?
I got 15 orders stacked up here
and nobody to run the grill.
15 orders, Walt. Is that all?
Gimme ten minutes,
I'll catch us up. Go on. Lie down.
Relax.
You look tired.
We can talk about my raise later.
You think this is Australia?
There's no raise. I'm about to fire you.
Excuse me. Mr O'Donnell?
Mr O'Donnell, my name is Violet Sanford.
I'm a song-writer.
I just wanted to give this to you.
I know it's not the most professional
way to submit a tape,
- but this is all pretty new to me.
- It's pretty new to me too.
I just figured as the manager
of a club like this,
you must know
every band on the East Coast.
The manager? Of this club?
- You guys go ahead. I'll catch up.
- Sure thing, Mr O'Donnell.
I don't usually do this, Violet,
but I have a feeling about you.
So I'm gonna take your tape,
and I'm gonna see what I can do.
Thank you.
I can't believe how easy this was.
Neither can I.
You wanna go for
some coffee or something?
O'Donnell, who do I look like?
Your goddamn maid?
That's Mr O'Donnell,
but I'll let it slide this time.
I told you to take your stuff home
and wash it.
You got cow grease caked on the front.
Walt, I've warned you
about your attitude...
- You're fired.
- You better not push me, kid.
I could find a hundred other little punks
like you who can burn a turkey burger.
Minimum-wage punk.
Maybe we should start over.
I'm Kevin O'Donnell, and I work the grill
here at the Fiji Mermaid Club.
I just made a complete fool of myself.
I was gonna tell you.
I'm almost sure I would have told you.
I just want you to know
I'm not following you home.
I'm just walking myself
26 blocks in the wrong direction.
- I asked you to leave me alone.
- Did I mention how sorry I am?
I mean, not that it's all my fault.
You did throw yourself at me.
I didn't throw myself at you.
I was pretending to be sweet
and innocent so you'd give me a break.
- Can I ask you a question?
- What?
Is there a reason we just walked
in a circle? Are you lost?
I'm not lost.
Somebody just moved my street.
You wanna play a game?
- I bet I can guess where you're from.
- I'm about to get out my pepper spray.
I reckon you're from a big city.
And there's no sign from here
of a bellybutton ring or a tongue piercing.
- I gotta go with Chicago.
- OK.
I've never had anyone stare at my ass for
half an hour, so I'm gonna say good night.
And I'm hoping
you're gonna say it back.
OK. I can take a hint.
I really do know a lot of people
in the music business.
You just don't give up, do ya?
Well, it was the sweet and innocent thing.
It did me in.
Good night, Kevin.
Just for the record, I was only staring
at your ass for the first 15 minutes.
- William Morris.
- I don't mean to interrupt. I just want to...
I'll transfer.
- William Morris. Please hold.
- It's a demo. I'm a song-writer.
William Morris.
I'll be right with you.
I just want to leave this
for Whitney or Mariah.
I'm sure they're personal friends of yours.
I'm sure it sounds great in your shower,
but karaoke ended a half-hour ago.
So if you'd like to get your songs heard,
you're gonna have to take them to
an open mic night just like everyone else.
William Morris.
I'll transfer.
You're not getting validated.
Can I help you?
Yeah, hi. I'm sure all your spaces
are filled for tonight.
I just wanted to come down and check out
what this whole open mic thing was about.
I can squeeze you in in ten minutes.
A couple of my regulars, they called in sick,
so I've got some spaces to fill.
I need you to sign your name in here
and get yourself ready.
Bathroom's around the corner
if you want to throw up.
Next up we have a young lady
named Violet Sanford.
So let's put our hands together
for New Jersey's own Violet Sanford.
- Come on up, Violet.
- There we go. Yeah.
Go, Violet.
- I'm a little nervous.
- So are we, honey.
Don't tease me, honey. Sing.
Come on, give her a break.
I'm sorry.
Hello?
You gotta cheer up. You look like
somebody ran over your dog.
How much is a slice of pie?
We happen to have
the best French apple in town.
And it's on the house.
- It's enough to shut up.
- Sit up and pay attention, OK.
- Twenty says it's Prett
- I will raise you ten,
- because it is Home Alone.
- You guys have to read the signs.
I call with Saving Private R
- What?
- Let's flip this over,
and Miss Jennifer from Austin
says her favourite movie is...
No way. There's no way.
You already saw this one.
- You are such a cheater.
- Hello. A naked girl in army boots?
Easy play to call.
- Thank you.
- Those boots are kinda cute.
I'm gonna have to get me some of those.
Wait, wait, wait. Romero.
You gotta turn that up, baby.
That is the jam. Turn it up.
- There you go, there you go.
- Oh, no.
- Girl, what are you doing?
- Remember this? Remember this?
Here's my belly dance shimmy, girls.
Do you know those girls?
Yeah. They're here every morning
around this time.
- Winding down.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- They have to, in their line of work.
- Are they hookers?
No.
Coyotes.
All right.
You guys? You guys wanna see
what Al gave me for my birthday?
- This.
- You let him brand you?
- Isn't it cute?
- She let the man brand her.
Check it out, ladies.
We each made 300 bucks tonight.
You sure you wanna be
goin' off to law school?
- Let's make a toast.
- Yeah.
To Zoe's last week as a Coyote.
She's gonna be impossible to replace.
I just wanna tell you both
that I will never, ever forget you.
Who's up there?
- I'm looking for the owner.
- Come on down.
Bring a case with you.
What are you doin' here?
I'm gonna drop this case.
Where do you want me to put it?
That depends. What do ya want?
Well, I heard you might need a new...
That there might be a job opening.
Put it right there.
Let me take a look at ya.
Let me guess.
Piedmont, North Dakota.
- South Amboy, New Jersey.
- Same thing. You do any drugs?
Just coffee.
That's all I can afford right now.
- Let me see your arms.
- Are you kidding?
Do I look like I'm kidding?
Where'd you get that scar on your wrist?
Pizza oven. It's a permanent burn
from pulling slices for four years.
That could be the saddest thing
I've ever heard.
- What's next? You want a urine sample?
- I prefer blood.
Look, are you really the owner?
'Cause I've had a rough couple of days,
and so the last thing I need is some
waitress on a power trip wastin' my time.
You start Friday night. Be there at 11.
That's when we get busy.
- You're givin' me a job?
- I'm givin' you an audition.
- Don't be late, Jersey girl.
- I don't mean to press my luck,
but would you mind telling me
why you're hiring me?
Because the average male
is walking around with a toddler
inside of his pants.
A two-year-old
right there inside his Dockers.
Men have two-year-old children in
their pants? That's why you're hiring me?
You look like a kindergarten teacher.
The kids'll love it.
Sorry I asked.
- I.D., please.
- I'm supposed to start work here tonight.
Go ahead.
You picked a good night to start.
It's a little slow right now,
but it should pick up.
OK.
Is this a church meeting
or is this a bar? Make some noise.
Yeah.
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
- I don't think so.
Just in time. Where you goin'?
- I was looking for you.
- Good. Let's go.
- Really love your top.
- Thanks.
I got it on sale down...
OK. Hair.
Let's see your moves.
That's Rachel.
You can learn a lot from her.
She just cut some guy's ponytail off.
Yeah. The court ordered her
to take anger management classes
after she pummelled a customer
for grabbin' her ass.
He pressed charges,
I gave her a raise. Cheers.
There is only two rules, OK?
What do you want?
Two beers.
- Don't date the customers.
- OK.
Second, don't ever bring your boyfriends
into my bar.
As of this moment you are to appear
available, but never be available.
Break my rules,
I fire you on the spot.
- I understand.
- Jesus.
Everybody.
Shut up.
I'd like you to meet my new girl,
whose name is...
Violet.
...Jersey.
Jersey is an ex-kindergarten teacher,
and a former nun who just escaped
from the convent,
and is tired of being the only virgin
in New York City.
Would anyone like
to buy her a drink?
- Come on, move. I'm workin' here.
- Sorry.
- Four Margaritas with salt.
- All right.
Got tequila.
No mix, no salt, no blender.
- OK, how about a Black Russian?
- Got vodka, no Kahlúa.
- White wine.
- Never carry the stuff.
- So basically you have...
- Jim, Jack, Johnny Red,
Johnny Black and José.
All my favourite men.
You can have it any way you like,
as long as it's in a shot glass.
OK, I'll take a beer.
- Four dollars.
- I'm Cammie, the Russian tease.
Violet, the Jersey nun.
That one's Rachel,
the New York bitch.
We all play our little parts,
only Rachel really is a bitch.
And I really am a tease.
Cammie, you can only be a tease
if you stop sleepin' around, babe.
Yeah. I keep forgetting that part.
I'll have a shot of tequila, and don't
forget one for your pretty little self.
Thanks, but ever since
I got really drunk on tequila,
I never drink the stuff any more.
Lil, your new girl's
refusing your good booze.
No. I was suggesting
this gentleman buy me a double.
That's more like it.
I need eight shots.
Four Canadian, four South of the Border,
a six-pack of MGD,
and a double-blended back.
- You want eight shots of what?
- I got it.
Forty-six even, honey.
- Lil.
- Yo.
Your Jersey girl can't quite keep up.
Gimme a Scotch and water.
- OK, you got it.
- Lil, do we serve water with our whiskey?
Only water I serve's
got barley and hops in it.
Everybody.
Do we serve water in this bar?
Hell, no H2O! Hell, no H2O!
Sink or swim time, Jersey.
Get up there.
I can't do that dance.
OK.
Here's some cash.
You did OK for a nun.
- You're firing me?
- I told you this was an audition.
Thanks for comin' in.
Now, get outta here.
No. Please.
Back off.
Guys. Guys, back off.
Look, the way I see it,
you got two choices.
You can start a fight here,
throw some punches, get a bloody nose,
make complete fools of yourselves, or you
can take this ten bucks I got right here
and buy these two pretty ladies
a round at the bar.
- Come on. What do you say?
- Let's go to the bar. Party.
Hold it, Jersey. I'm just dyin' to know
where that came from.
Try serving beer and pizza
on Monday nights
when the Giants play the Cowboys
in November.
I'm giving you a second audition.
There's a store at the corner of 6th and Hill.
Be there at noon tomorrow.
I'm sending my fashion coordinator there
to take you shopping.
Now go home
before I change my mind.
And Jersey. I'd be shocked
if you survive another night.
Yeah.
- Hey, honey. How are you?
- All right. I miss you.
- I miss you too.
- What are you eating?
One of those Lean Cuisine meals.
Rice and vegetables. Delicious.
- See, they're good. Right?
- Yum.
So, tell me more about this bar.
What kind of place is it?
I don't know. It's just a bar, Dad.
Hold on a second.
- Hi.
- What's going on with your song-writing?
Song-writing.
He still has my tape.
I want my tape.
I had a feeling you'd be back to see me.
- No dates in the kitchen, O'Donnell.
- I'm not staying.
I just want my tape.
Please.
- Thanks. Bye.
- Did you really write all those songs?
You listened to my tape?
No, of course not. I mean,
that would be invasion of privacy.
Go ahead. Laugh it up.
'Cause there's nothing you can say
that's gonna bother me.
I'm just trying to tell you
I like your music.
I mean, do you always
take compliments so well?
- I gotta go.
- Wait.
I wanna see you again.
Where are you workin'?
- I'm a Coyote.
- Good. And what the hell is that?
If you wanna see me again,
you'll figure it out.
Was that good?
Sorry I'm late.
Al and I had a big fight.
And then we made up.
Twice.
You're the fashion coordinator?
Lil told me to get you something
that would make the kiddies drool.
Trust me, Violet.
I have a serious shopping problem.
No. Forget it, honey.
That's a church dress.
Nobody wears leather in church.
You sure we're going in the right direction?
Try this one. It's very tasteful.
- It has a zipper in the crotch.
- Yeah.
- Who would wear that in public?
- Actually, I have it in blue.
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
Here I am.
Yeah, baby.
Come on. Knock it off.
Lil. The ice.
How do you like that, huh?
I don't know how you guys do it.
I can't have another drink.
Next time that guy buys you a shot...
That's on me, honey.
...chase it with a beer.
- I don't get it.
- I don't swallow it.
I just spit the shot back into the beer bottle.
They'll never know.
You try it.
Just keep an eye on your spittoon bottle.
Once Rachel served hers to Lou
by accident. Huge drama.
Cammie, I think I just fell
in love with you.
Violet. I'm not a lesbian.
I've played in the minors,
but never went pro.
- That's not what I meant.
- What are you doing?
Lil's starin' straight at you. Come on.
Grab this guy. Make yourself look busy.
- Hi. You look like you could use a shot.
- No, I'm waiting on Lil.
Sorry. It's a no-parking zone. If you
wanna sit here, you gotta order a drink.
- OK. Gimme a glass of water.
- OK.
- He just ordered water?
- Yeah.
You know what to do.
Testing.
Everybody, this guy just ordered water.
Do we serve water in our bar?
Hell, no H2O. Hell, no H2O.
Jersey. No.
It's OK, Lil.
Nobody orders water in your bar.
He can order whatever he wants.
He's the fire marshal.
Mike, I'm so sorry.
She's new.
I'm OK.
Let's step outside.
Nice knowin' you, Jersey.
Come on, you guys. Let me hear you.
You OK?
- Who am I kidding? I can't do this.
- Of course you can.
Now cheer up, because there's
a really cute guy at the bar asking for you.
Somebody's asking for me?
He says his name is Mr O'Donnell.
He's hot.
You all right, mate?
Jersey. The fire marshal
threatened to shut me down.
- He let me go with a $ 250 fine.
- Lil, I'm really sorry...
I'll make you a deal. You figure out
a way to make me 250 tonight,
I'll let you come back tomorrow.
Great.
- So much for sweet and innocent.
- So, you found me.
Some guys at work told me
where I could look for Coyotes.
Well, take a good look,
because tonight's my last night.
- I think I'm gonna get fired.
- Why?
'Cause I have to make $ 250 in two hours.
It's completely impossible.
Here's nine dollars,
just to get you started, OK?
I always like to help a friend in need.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Kevin, I don't want your money.
All right, listen up.
Ladies, the bidding will start at $ 25.
For one night only,
you get this purebred, housebroken,
fully trained, young stud.
- No way.
- That's pretty cheap.
- Violet, what are you doing?
- You said you wanted to help, so...
Turn around, sir.
Let 'em take a look at ya.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- It's payback time, Mr O'Donnell.
Now, turn around.
No. God, no. Don't do this.
Go on. Show 'em what you've got.
- Do you wanna do this?
- All right, ladies. What'll you give me?
I've got 20 bucks.
I've got $ 25 right here.
Make it 35.
Thirty-five dollars.
- Forty dollars.
- Get... What are you doing?
- Come on, girls. Fifty?
- Fifty.
- Sixty-one dollars.
- I've got 70.
- Come on, girls. Seventy-five?
- Seventy-five dollars.
- Eighty.
- Eighty dollars.
- Come on, girls. Do I hear 85?
- Ninety. Ninety-five dollars.
One hundred dollars.
- That's it.
- You wanna come home with Mama?
Yeah. That's my boy.
- Yeah. Shake it, shake it.
- $125 back here.
$140, right here.
Come on, come on.
My goodness, girls, come on.
One-fifty and you'll see the butt.
Come on, girls.
You can do better than this.
One-seventy-five.
Yeah.
There we go.
Two hundred dollars.
- You've got 250 right here.
- Two hundred and fifty dollars.
Sold, for $ 250.
- No.
- Come on up, honey. He's yours.
Damn you.
The blonde would have gone to 275.
Come with me.
You're gonna owe me big-time for this one.
That's 250 even.
We're closin' up, girls.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
What does "Coyote Ugly" mean?
Did you ever wake up sober
after a one-night stand,
and the person you're next to is layin'
on your arm, and they're so ugly,
you'd rather chew off
your arm than risk wakin' 'em?
- That's coyote ugly.
- Let's go, ladies.
But why would you name
your bar after something like that?
Because "Cheers" was taken.
Cabs are out front.
- You're rich, Jersey.
- Yeah.
Good night.
The woman who purchased me
is named Sandy Rosenfeld,
a divorcée with three grown kids,
a passion for long walks and short-haired
hunting dogs and Italian opera.
Her ex-husband is a C.P.A.
Her favourite artist is Van Gogh,
and her New Year's resolution is to lose
15 pounds, and to see Barbra in concert.
OK. I owe you.
What do you want?
Well, it's 3:30 in the morning.
I want what every man wants.
Breakfast.
And that's it? I go to breakfast
with you, and we're even?
No. We're not even close to even,
because I danced on a bar,
I took off my shirt,
and I unzipped my pants.
OK. Let's make a deal.
Breakfast and lunch.
- Breakfast, lunch and two dinners.
- That's four dates.
Yep. Which would make it the second
longest relationship I've ever had.
Get in the car.
I hate to spoil your evening, but
it looks like we're not gonna go anywhere.
Oh, my God.
It's hard to find parking in New York.
You ever eaten Turkish?
This is the place.
- Hey. How you doin'?
- Hi, Kevin.
- Four of the regular?
- Sure, yeah.
- How you doin'?
- How are you?
Here it is, man.
Flown in from Miami.
- Check out the merchandise.
- Hey, man, no. I trust you.
All right, all right.
Look, I don't know what you're into, but...
The Amazing Spider-Man.
Number 129, mint condition.
- Worth a thousand bucks.
- A comic book.
No, it's not just a comic book. This is
the first appearance of the Punisher.
This is the Holy Grail
of comic books.
You collect comic books. That's so cute.
It's not cute.
It's very rugged and manly.
- It's just a bit geeky. Huh?
- I think it's sweet.
So, do you always eat breakfast
on the hood of your car?
What can I say? I'm a romantic.
You think this is romantic?
Well, you may not be feeling it now,
but I think one day
you'll be on stage singing
a song about this very night.
"When We Were Downwind
From a Trash Barge."
Yeah. Catchy title. Hum a few bars.
Sorry to disappoint you,
but I'm a song-writer, not a singer.
When I get on stage, I freeze.
What if the fate of the free world
rested on your voice?
OK. If the fate of the free world
depended on me singing, maybe.
All I ever really wanted
is to sit in the dark
and hear someone great
singing my songs.
I wanna be the one
who writes the music.
I remember the first time my mother
played me "Bridge Over Troubled Water",
by Simon and Garfunkel.
I remember exactly what she was wearing,
I remember exactly how her hair smelled,
and I remember exactly how I felt.
And every time I hear that song,
I remember exactly
what she was wearing,
and exactly how her hair smelled,
and exactly how I felt.
'Cause the great songs last forever.
- So what's the problem?
- Well...
now they're telling me
the only way to get my songs heard
is to go out there
and sing 'em myself.
So we're gonna have to try and fix
this little problem straight away.
And how do you propose we do that?
Well, is there any place
you feel comfortable singing?
- The shower.
- We'll start there.
I don't care how long it takes, how many
hours we have to spend in that shower.
- Let's get to it.
- OK. Before we hit the showers,
maybe you could tell me
a little something about yourself.
Really?
What do you wanna know?
What part of Australia are you from?
I'm from all over.
My family moved around a lot.
So the rest of your family
doesn't live in New York?
Do you always ask
this many questions?
Do you always dodge
You could at least tell me where you got
all the moves you pulled on the bar tonight.
Well, if I told you,
I'd have to kill you.
That's original.
The sun's coming up.
We're gonna be late.
Late? Late for what?
This is incredible.
- Look at that fish.
- All right. Put this on.
- You're gonna need it.
- Why? What are you talking about?
You're gonna help me
unload the next bin.
- You're joking, right?
- No. It's not that bad, Vi.
- I do it all the time.
- Exactly how many jobs do you have?
Tuesday through Saturday,
I'm at the club.
Sunday and Monday,
I park cars at the Plaza.
I've been a telemarketer.
"Would you like to switch to AT&T?"
And for six terrifying hours
I delivered phone books in Queens.
Don't forget your extensive work in fish.
This is an expensive city,
and these guys pay cash.
I don't care if they pay in lobster.
I'm not sticking my hands in that fishy bin.
I was gonna split the money with you.
- A hundred bucks apiece.
- A hundred bucks?
- Wait, wait. Why didn't you say so?
- Thanks, Dan.
- You're not ready, are you? Fifty bucks.
- Wait. No.
- Twenty-five, ten.
- OK. OK.
Ready?
That's disgusting.
You'll hurt their feelings.
OK. Just on top of the other fish.
So, I know I just met you a few days ago,
but there's something I have to tell you.
You smell really bad.
Well, so do you. I mean,
I was gonna kiss you goodbye,
- but I thought I might gag.
- You're a real charmer.
OK. Good night.
Good morning.
Don't look at me like that.
Spend it.
- What are you doing here?
- I changed my mind about this kiss.
I think we should give it a shot.
Well...
Have a nice day.
"Have a nice day"?
Yeah. I panicked.
I didn't know what else to say.
Have a nice day.
- I wanna get in, I wanna get in.
- All right. Back of the line over here.
Yeah.
Come on.
- Yeah, I like it.
- Yeah.
- Hey, baby.
- Make a hole. Make a hole.
- Lou. Nobody else gets in here.
- Shit, the cops are here.
- Look at this place.
- Wait a minute.
I'm sorry. There's nothing we can do.
You're 50 people over max.
If you try to shut us down,
they'll tear the place apart.
Let's go outside and talk.
I'll take care of it.
This is not a gas pump, son.
Wait your turn.
- No pictures, man.
- I'm a reporter from The Voice.
What are you doing?
Put me down.
- Put me down.
- Cammie.
- Help.
- Come on. Let her go.
Rachel. Help.
Sailor boy. Come on. Break it up.
- Lou, where's Rachel and Cammie?
- I don't know.
Let me go.
Jersey. They're tearing this place apart.
Rachel. Rachel.
I'm talking about that.
- Great. Yeah.
- Last call, Lil.
- Start clearin' 'em out.
- You got it.
Let's go.
Did you see their faces?
I mean, wow.
They all wanted you, honey.
Even the girls.
Not a dry seat in the house.
You guys, that was, like,
a one-time performance,
that I have to repeat, like, every night.
She sang along with a jukebox.
Let's not start polishing a Grammy.
Come on, Rach.
She saved your butt. Admit it.
No. She saved me from kicking the shit
out of a couple of drunks.
That's it.
Dunk 'em good.
- Where you goin'?
- I don't know.
I gotta walk or celebrate
or pass out or something.
Ladies and gent.
How about a big round of applause
for the singing Coyote from Jersey?
- So I'm a Coyote?
- Five nights a week.
- What is it? What's wrong?
- Why would anything be wrong?
You called me in the middle of the night
and said there was an emergency.
What was that for?
I had a good night.
I wanted a good-night kiss.
Well, wait a second.
Where are you going?
Have a nice day, Mr O'Donnell.
"Have a nice day"?
What's going on?
Why do I need my guitar?
You'll find out soon enough.
No. This way.
OK, now there's a seat.
Just there.
OK?
Take a look.
Your fans wanna hear you sing.
I told you. I can't sing my own songs.
I never could.
Well, that's too bad, because
they've requested to hear your songs.
Be gentle on the keyboard.
I borrowed it from the club.
You did all this
just to help me sing?
I thought maybe we could cure that
stage fright I've heard so much about.
Kevin, I wish you could.
Come on. Let me try.
Tell me what it feels like.
You really wanna know?
Yeah.
You asked for it.
What are you doing?
The only way I can show you...
is to make you...
really nervous.
The first thing that happens...
is my heart starts to race.
Good.
Racing heart. Yep.
- Got it.
- And then...
my entire body starts shaking.
Shaking body.
I'm getting that. Yeah.
And...
then everything gets...
a bit...
cloudy.
Clouds are definitely rolling in.
Then I start...
Iosing control.
Well, how long does this usually last?
It's been known to last all night.
- That must be horrible.
- It's excruciating.
I think that audience
got more than they paid for, really.
What's "LMS" stand for?
Lynn Marie Sanford.
It was my mom's guitar.
She died five years ago.
She moved to New York to be
a singer when she was my age.
She came pretty close
to the big time.
What happened?
She hated the stage. She said
it was the scariest place in the world.
Sounds familiar.
You really want me to sing?
Just tell me what I have to do.
Disappear.
All right. No problem.
If you wanna write songs, if you wanna be,
like, a serious song-writer,
you've simply gotta go with the Mac.
Laptop. You can lay your tracks down
on a blank CD, and you're done.
Do you have a payment plan?
Rachel.
Good work.
What a babe there. What a babe.
All right, that's two now, guys. Two.
Come on, Cammie.
- Come on, Cammie.
- Go, Cammie.
- Lil.
- Yeah?
- I tell you what.
You're two out, bases loaded.
How about we double the bet?
Forget it, Earl.
Cammie's my worst hitter.
I know that. Why don't we triple it?
- All right.
- All right?
All right.
Let's go, toots.
Cammie.
- Yeah?
- Sure is a beautiful day out here.
Be a shame to waste it, don't you think?
Sure is.
Yeah, Cammie.
Get the ball over the plate, Earl.
OK, boys. Show me those balls.
Five, and there's your six hundred dollars.
Yes, sir. Thanks, Earl. We'll be sure
to put you on the schedule for next year.
- Yeah, you do that.
- Yeah, Coyotes.
What are you doing?
What are you, brain-damaged?
You know what kind of maniacs
we got driving through here?
They don't stop for nothin'.
- Whose boat?
- I borrowed it from a friend.
- Yeah? Looks like a guy's car to me.
- How can you tell?
I've been staring at cars
every day for the last 16 years.
- Who is he?
- He's a friend.
Look, I brought you a turkey sandwich,
no mayo, extra sprouts.
Thank you. Great.
I'm starvin'.
Now, tell me about this bar.
Is it a bunch of bankers
havin' martinis after work?
I gotta go.
Look, I love you.
I love you too. Be careful.
Do I come to your office and honk?
Come on.
I got you a gig.
There's this club where a lot of music
people hang out called the Elbow Room.
My friend's the manager. He owes me a
favour, and you're it, next Thursday night.
Are you forgetting
about the stage fright?
What about the bar?
Come on, Kevin. All I do
is sing along with the jukebox.
See? You're making progress.
A few more nights at my place,
and you'll be cured.
I hate to burst your bubble,
but I'll never be cured. It's genetic.
Stage fright DNA.
Yes, I saw that on E.R. last week.
OK. Laugh all you want, but my mom
couldn't do it, and neither can I.
So was your mother afraid to try?
Look, I just wanna be a song-writer.
Why won't you give up on this?
Because I've been giving up on people
my entire life, and it's a nasty little habit.
So, you're gonna sing
at the club, or I'II...
Or you'll what?
I'll never kiss you again.
That sounds like a threat,
Mr O'Donnell.
Well, let's just say
it's gonna be quite a long, cold winter.
- That's supposed to convince me?
- It's working, isn't it?
Your knees are getting weak.
- I'll think about it.
- Try again.
- I'll see if I can get off work.
- You're gettin' warmer.
All right. You win.
- I'll do it.
- I love winning.
We have a special treat for you tonight,
boys and girls.
Look who dropped by for a visit.
- Zoe.
- No.
I'm a paying customer tonight. I have
class in the morning. What are you doing?
- Come on, Zoe.
- No.
Zoe. Zoe. Zoe. Zoe. Zoe.
Time to get wet, girls.
Excuse me,
does Violet Sanford work here?
- She's on the bar.
- She's on what?
- What do you guys say?
Yeah.
Dad.
Wait.
Dad. It's not as bad as it looks.
I just sing here every night.
People come here to see me.
Say something.
The guys are putting your picture up
in their booths.
- I gotta go, get up early.
- Dad, it's just a bar.
- You can trust me.
- But you're my daughter.
Hi, you've reached Bill Sanford.
Please leave a message
when you hear the beep.
Dad, you can't avoid me
for the rest of your life.
I have to come over and do your laundry.
We both know
you're running out of clean shirts.
I bet the one you're wearing
stinks pretty bad.
I'm not gonna apologise, because that
would mean I'm doing something wrong.
And I'm not sure I am, so...
I'm playing at a club tonight. A real club.
Someone important could hear my song,
and next month somebody
might be singing it on the radio.
- So wish me good luck.
- Good luck.
Anyway, I'll call you
and tell you how it goes.
Take care of yourself, old man.
"Old man."
All right. You should be dancing
on the floor. I wanna see your bras.
I'm in heaven. I'm in heaven.
- Do you think this muff's been waxed?
- I hope so.
Is this the greatest party
we've ever been to or what, man?
Lil, I can only stay two hours.
- What are you talking about?
- I gotta leave early tonight, remember?
Bourbon.
Maybe you haven't noticed all the bodies
you had to crawl over to get in here tonight.
Lil, I told you I gotta leave
by 10:30 no matter what.
- Here.
- I got it. I got it.
Seven.
- Here you go.
- What are you doing?
I gotta go. It's half past.
Can you have Lou call me a cab?
Listen, Jersey. You're not
going anywhere. Not tonight.
This place is out of control.
But, Lil, I told you.
I'm only working two hours...
You wanna sing? Sing for them.
These people dragged
their asses out here to see us.
This is New York, and there's a line
halfway around the block.
That's something, Jersey,
whether you believe it or not.
And if I go?
If you were goin',
you would have left by now.
- Where are you?
- Lil won't let me go.
Violet, just walk out.
She doesn't own you.
You can still make it here.
I'm sorry.
- I'll call you tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
Violet...
- What's the story?
- She's not coming.
So what am I supposed to do, Kevin?
I got a whole spot to fill.
I'm sorry, Richie.
I made a mistake.
This doesn't change
anything with us, Kevin.
A deal's a deal. Am I right?
I'm the guy. Me.
Zach, who said
you could be up here?
You're not supposed to be up here.
All right.
Take it easy, Zach.
Zach, take it easy.
- Knock it off.
- Kevin.
Lil.
- Break it up.
- Kevin, that's enough.
Lou.
Kevin, that's enough.
- Kevin, that's enough.
- Get off me.
Kevin, Zach's a regular,
and he was just having fun.
- Having fun with my girlfriend.
- Lou, get him out of here.
You're gonna chill outside,
or I'm calling the cops.
- Out of my way. Move.
- Let me go.
Get the hell outta here.
Everybody, free drinks on the house.
I'm paying. Get up here.
Kevin?
Kevin, what is your problem? Look,
I'm sorry about tonight, but look at this.
There was no way
Lil was gonna let me out.
This is not about Lil.
This is about you and this place.
- This is my job.
- It's a goddamn sandbox
for you to stick your head in.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- The place is a joke.
All right?
They don't come to watch you sing.
They come to watch girls
shaking it on a bar.
And what would you have me do?
Sing for quarters in the park?
At least you'd be singing your own songs.
I told you I can't do that,
so stop pushing.
I'm just asking you to try,
but I guess that's asking a bit too much.
Right. It's so easy to be you,
isn't it?
You have no dreams, no hopes,
no chance of getting hurt.
When was the last time
you took a chance on something?
- Some of us don't have that luxury.
- Why is that?
Right. We don't talk about you, right?
It's a big secret.
Come on, Kevin.
Let's play a game.
I'm gonna guess why
you left Australia.
- Doesn't matter.
- You were in jail.
No, that's not it.
You have a wife and four kids in Sydney.
Come on. Am I getting warm?
Come on, Kevin.
I don't have a lot of time.
Why'd you run away from home?
I didn't have a home.
Is that what you wanted to hear?
I don't have a family.
I mean, that's the big secret.
Are you happy?
Are you gonna feel sorry for me now?
You gonna hold me close while I tell you
I had to change homes every two years?
I had a bad childhood. Big deal.
I don't need your sympathy,
'cause I'm here,
and I'm living on my own two feet
like I wanted to.
That was my dream.
And at least I did it
with a little bit of dignity.
And I didn't. That's it?
Well, just unbutton the blouse
a little and unzip the pants,
show a little bit of flesh -
I think you can figure it out.
Go on in. Your fans are waitin' for ya
to crawl on the bar.
- I told you not to break the rules.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about you and your boyfriend
making a scene in my bar.
I'm talking about a friend of mine
inside with a broken nose.
The rules were simple, Jersey.
I've fired girls for a lot less.
What, so I can't have a boyfriend now?
What kind of stupid shit is that?
This place is my home,
and I'm not willing to risk
everything I have on your personal life.
It's business, plain and simple.
This is not business.
I work my ass off for you,
- and you're supposed to be my friend.
- I never said I was your friend.
I'm your boss, and you knew
the rules like everybody else.
Will you stop with "the rules"?
It's a bar, for Christ's sake.
Then what are you so upset about?
Oh, my God. Gimme a bite. I'm starving.
- Thank you.
- How does it feel to be Mrs Molinaro?
You know, I think he was the perfect choice
for my first marriage.
Hey, Gloria.
Thanks for inviting me.
I gotta go to work.
I'm on graveyard tonight.
- Thank you, Mr Sanford.
- Yeah, well, it's not worth a hug, dear.
It's only 50 bucks.
- Your old man's a ten, Vi.
- Eleven. Some days a twelve.
- Well, it's a beautiful wedding.
- No, you can't go.
I just want one picture of you and Violet
dancing together. Come on.
OK. Come on. Smile.
Are you really working,
or are you just leaving because of me?
You know I don't like to wear a tie.
So this is how it's gonna be?
You're not gonna return my phone calls?
If you needed money,
you should have come to me.
I would have found a way
to take care of you.
Dad, you can't even
take care of yourself.
I am doing just fine on my own,
thank you very much.
Really? So how come
you're not wearing any socks?
I had a minor disagreement
with the clothes dryer.
Look, just face it, Dad.
You need me.
And I moved out,
and that's what bothers you.
No.
No, what bothers me...
is for the first time in my life...
I was ashamed of you.
I would have never thought
that would have ever been possible.
It's me.
Leave a message after the beep.
Violet? I've just finished work,
and in a few hours
I'm going to unload
three disgusting fish trucks.
I thought maybe you'd like
to come and give me a hand.
- But you're not in.
- OK. I'm coming. I'm coming.
Or you're not picking up.
So, I'll call back,
because I'm hoping
one day you will wanna talk.
Kevin? Hello?
Kevin? Hello? It's me.
I'm here.
- Is this Violet Sanford?
- Yes.
I'm calling from
Riverview Medical Centre.
We have a patient here by the
name of William James Sanford.
Is that your father?
Violet Sanford?
- Yeah?
- Your dad's in recovery right now.
The car struck him on his right side
when he was walking to the booth.
His right leg is broken,
and there was some arterial damage
we had to go in and repair.
But other than that,
it's just a lot of bumps and bruises.
I'd say he's a pretty lucky guy.
Violet?
I told you, don't come down here.
It's your wedding night.
Are you kidding? Danny's been
in my family for five minutes.
You've been in my family
my whole life.
I'm sorry.
I love you so much.
I never did thank you for the dance.
That's OK.
It's all right.
My tapes.
Come on. Just call him.
Just pick up the phone and call him.
Don't call him.
I told you, this place is a palace.
It's pretty late.
Are you sure you wanna do this now?
Well, here's my door.
No turning back now. Come on in.
Oh, you're so right.
This place is a palace.
- Would I lie to you?
- This is a great idea. I'm so glad...
Nice strong pulse.
Don't look at me like that.
I'm a sick man.
You can eat whatever you want now,
but when we go back home,
it's egg whites and Lean Cuisines.
- I'll see you later, Bill.
- Wait a minute.
What do you mean,
"until we go home"?
I'm moving back.
I couldn't do it.
I couldn't sing my songs.
I was afraid.
Do you know why Mommy quit?
Yeah, she told me.
'Cause she couldn't do it.
No, that's not it.
She wasn't afraid, Vi.
Your mother on stage...
She was amazing.
Then why did she quit?
Because of me.
Right after you were born,
she told me she wanted to quit,
and I let her.
See, I knew how good she was,
but I never told her.
I loved her...
more than anything.
And I just went on and pretended
that there was no other choice.
- Dad, it's OK.
- No, it's not OK.
I'm not gonna make
the same mistake twice.
You're not goin' back to work for Pete.
I don't care what it takes. I don't care
how many bars you have to stand on.
You are not comin' home.
I'm not letting you back in the house.
Forget it.
Are you wearing cologne?
No.
Well, it's just a splash of Old Spice.
Where did you get Old Spice?
That nice redheaded nurse
gave it to me as a gift.
Then she asked me out for coffee.
I'm scared.
- Are you gonna go on a date?
- God, a date.
I'd better buy a pair of socks.
OK. Come on in here.
Watch out for the... OK. OK.
OK if I eat here at the bar?
- Do you have a reservation?
- Yeah.
It's under "cast-iron heartless bitch".
Could it be under
"stubborn and pigheaded"?
Yes. That's the one.
I'll have a double water
on the rocks, please.
- How'd you find me?
- Cammie.
She told me about your pop.
I'm sorry to hear about that.
He's OK.
Good.
- So am I.
- Yeah. Yeah, I can see that.
What's good to eat here?
Lil, you didn't come here to eat.
What do you want?
OK.
I just wanted to let you know you can
come back to the bar whenever you want.
I appreciate the offer,
but I'm OK here.
I figured that.
You were never a lifer.
I'm married to that bar.
Hell, I'd...
I'd sleep there if I had the guts
to walk around barefoot.
But that's me, you know?
I'm the original Coyote...
Just a small-town gal trying
to make it in the big bad city.
"Small-town gal"?
Piedmont, North Dakota.
You ever tell anyone that,
I'll kill ya.
Take care, Jersey.
You have one new message.
I have one message in eight hours.
How pathetic am I?
Violet, this is Lyndsey Morgan
from the Bowery Ballroom.
Listen, we loved your CD,
and we want you to play in our
song-writer's showcase next Sunday night.
You're on at 10:00 sharp.
So drop your music by the club,
and the house band
can learn your song.
Now, if you have any questions,
don't be afraid to give me a shout.
See ya Sunday.
- Here are the keys to the apartment.
It's all yours.
I can't thank you enough
for subleasing me this place.
- You don't know how long I looked.
- And when is your boyfriend moving in?
He's actually coming in
tomorrow from Boston.
It's historic, guys. This is the first night
I've closed early in three years.
Ta-da. Will you hang that outside for me?
- Lou, you got that number I asked about?
- Yep.
So why are you moving to Chicago?
I'll figure that out when I get there.
Hello.
Do yourself a favour
and look at page 137 of The Voice.
I can't believe your name is in the paper.
I'm gettin' this framed.
Dad, if you're not ready in five minutes,
I'm gonna leave without you.
Keep your pants on, will ya?
I'm physically challenged.
I only got three rolls of film.
I hope that's enough.
Dad, I'm only singing one song.
Right. Better go get another one.
Bill.
My kid's singing tonight
at some club in the city.
She's a little nervous. Hey, maybe you
can give us a one, two, three for luck.
You got it. All right, let's give it up
for Bill Sanford's daughter.
Light 'em up. One, two, three.
Look, Vi.
I can't do this.
Jesus.
Did I mention to you that I was
recently in a horrific car accident?
I can't do this.
I gotta go back.
- Violet, listen to me. Are you listening?
- Yes.
You have nothing to be afraid of.
You're already a star.
Dad, what are you talking about?
I'm a nobody.
If you're such a nobody, then why did
I buy this off Pete for 20 bucks?
Why do you have that?
I saw it on the wall,
decided I wanted the first autograph.
I figured it'd be
a damn good investment.
Now what are you waiting for? I didn't
spend three months in physical therapy
just to take a ride
to the state line, you got me?
- Yeah, I got ya.
- So what do you say, Vi?
How about another U-ey?
You guys call that a one, two, three?
Now, let's do it again.
This time I wanna feel chills.
There goes Bill again.
He's back for seconds.
Come on now. Let's give him all we got.
Let's go.
The only reason why I came down here
tonight is to see her fall on her face.
Take it easy, Rachel.
It's supposed to be a fun night out.
- Excuse me.
- I'm cool. OK? Don't worry about me.
Hi. Good evening, ladies.
Can I help you?
No.
It's packed, Lyndsey. The house band
has been on for 15 minutes.
If she's not here in five,
she's bumped.
Jesus.
Now that we're here,
I'm feeling a little nervous.
Thank you, Mr Sanford.
Probably just carsick.
Forget I mentioned it. I'm fine.
Have a great show.
Vi.
Get your butt in there.
Come on. We're right behind you.
Break a leg, sweetie.
Ladies and gentlemen,
making her Bowery Ballroom debut,
Miss Violet Sanford.
I'm sorry.
Violet.
- Come on, baby. Shake it.
- Hey, pinhead.
Shake it.
Don't do it, Rach. He's a big guy,
and you're still on probation.
Don't worry. Those classes
are really paying off.
OK. Let's give a big Coyote welcome
to LeAnn Rimes.
So tell me, what do you do when you
realise all your dreams have come true?
You pay off old debts.
Volume 129, the original appearance
of the Punisher.
The one I cost you.
Thank you.
Lil, I don't think
your new girl's gonna hack it.
Jersey. Jersey. Jersey. Jersey.
OK. In true Coyote tradition,
I'm gonna make every woman's night,
and auction off the most
handsome little hottie in the place.
Violet, come on.
You can't do this to me again.
Here he is, girls.
Come on, Dad.
OK, ladies.
The bidding will start at 25 dollars.
Nobody wants this.
What are you getting me into, Violet?
25 dollars.
You said you wanted
a more active social life.
Come on, girls. There's a lot of miles
left on these tires.
- Fifty dollars.
- Come on, Dad. Strut your stuff.
Seventy-five.
Take some of it off.
OK, put some of it on.
Yeah, baby!
- Ninety.
- Ninety-five.
Ninety-eight fifty.
A hundred.
- A hundred and fifty dollars.
- Sold.
I'm a Coyote.
Your father has no problem
with stage fright.
So tell me, what do you do when you
realise all your dreams have come true?