[Thunder rumbles, crashes]
[Sea gulls crying]
...Come on, Jake.
...Slow down!
...Hurry up, Jake!
...Melanie!
I gotta get home.
My mom's gonna kill me.
Wow, did you see that?
1,001... 1,002...
...Well, answer the question!
...No!
No, you won't answer,
or no, you won't marry me?
Jake Perry,
I'm 10 years old.
I got too much to live for.
...[Lightning crashes]
...Ahh!
Not that way, you dolt!
Come on!
...Wow!
...Cool!
It's hot.
Don't touch it.
We'll be safe here.
Says who?
Everybody.
Lightning never strikes
the same place twice.
Why would you want to
marry me for anyhow?
So I can kiss you
any time I want.
[Thunder rumbles]
...[Gasps]
...[Rumbling, rain falls]
Woman:
I need more coffee, guys.
I'm gonna switch...
It's a warning!
Oh, my God.
...Hey.
...Hi.
You know,
that accent of yours
is a whole lot thicker
when you're dreaming.
...[Laughter]
...[Sighs]
All right, how come
y'all let me sleep?
Oh, calm down.
It was 5 minutes.
What did I say?
We're all getting big, fat
raises when you become somebody.
[Light laughter]
Oh, did they kill
Badgley Mishka!
Okay, laugh now, but
tomorrow it could be us.
Not us... you.
I just make the coffee.
Thank you.
# Well, I'm feeling
like I'm fallin' #
...# But I'm still on my feet #
...I'll see you at the show.
...# Reality is coming #
...Bye, Mel.
# But that don't bother me #
# 'Cause I'm on my way #
# And I'm okay #
# Hey, hey #
# Come on, bring on the day #
# 'Cause I just might
get everything I need #
# Hey, hey #
# I'm givin' what it takes #
# I'm ready as
I'm ever gonna be #
# So bring on the day #
# Day #
# Bring on the day #
# You gotta keep on
keepin' on #
# You gotta keep on keepin' on #
# You gotta keep on
keepin' on #
[Breathes deeply]
Andrew!
There's a rose for every moment
I thought of you last night.
God, you must be exhausted.
Listen, knock 'em dead.
I'll see you at the show.
...[Giggles]
...It's gonna be great.
I love you.
I can't wait to see you.
Goodbye.
[Dial tone, beep]
# This one's going out
to all the people #
# That work hard all week #
# Weekend come...
it's your song, song, song #
Okay, people,
we are officially late!
Pan: Melanie!
Yes?!
This top is supposed
to be neon aubergine,
but it's all wrong!
It's all wrong!
Okay, don't panic.
That's my job.
Um... okay.
Put her on after Anoke.
The third light cue is yellow.
She'll look eggplant.
Pan, uh, the reason it's all
wrong is it's on backwards.
[Effeminately] Ooh,
Miss Vixen, I'm scared of you.
Frederick, what are you doing
here? You're the competition.
Competition? Please! Our
design's for plumes and pearls,
and nothing is going to come
between me and my protege.
And this is, after all,
all about me.
Oh, I love this. Stella
McCartney's gonna kill herself.
Then why do I feel like
I'm in Times Square buck naked?
Baby doll, you're
gonna be just fine.
Seven years ago, you were this
debutante off the plantation,
and now you're
my steel magnolia...
with her very own show.
Okay, get out of here
before you make me cry.
Bonne chance!
Big smile!
Great! Thank you!
# The waves keep on crashin'
on me for some reason #
Good to see you.
Secretary Hennings,
do you have a moment
for a few questions?
Andrew, are you excited
about the show?
Uh, of course,
I'm very excited.
Did you get to
see the models?
The models? Why, uh...
Please tell me
he has a flaw somewhere.
He asked me to go to
Ireland for Christmas.
He's gonna ask you
a lot more than that.
...You think so?
...Mm-hmm.
...Hey, let's go!
...Let's do this!
All right, we gotta go.
Places, everyone!
...Come on, let's go, line up.
...Have a good show.
Okay, no smiles,
no smiles, just smirks!
# Keep on dancin' #
# You hold me like you should,
so I'm gonna keep on dancin' #
# Keep on dancin' #
Ohh!
Honey!
...[Shrieks]
...Oh, congratulations.
You're amazing.
Those flowers were insane.
Oh, well, I just want
this day to be perfect.
[Sighs] Oh, God, honey,
what if they hate me?
Oh, they're critics, Mel.
They hate themselves.
That's easy for you to say.
I wasn't born with
that thick Hennings skin.
No, you weren't, and that
is what I love about you.
Mmm.
Ah, honey, I'm sorry, I got
a meeting in the Bronx.
But you go and enjoy, and
I'll see you later. Okay?
Oh, and, hey, we've got that
thing tonight at Lincoln Center.
What thing?
Fund-raiser thing.
[Sighs] Right, the thing...
with your mother.
That's tonight.
I'm afraid so.
Okay.
I am so proud of you.
Thank you.
...Okay?
...I love you.
I love you, too.
Congratulations.
[Horn honks]
His meeting's running
a little late.
He told me to take you inside
so you wouldn't have to wait.
Where are we?
[Horn honks]
...I'm so tired, Jimmy.
...Yeah.
I've just had it.
Well... he shouldn't be
too long.
Miss Carmichael,
won't you come in?
So... have you made a decision?
A-bout what?
Ireland.
Ireland, honey, [Scoffs]
that's four months from now.
I was thinking maybe
2... 300 guests, tops.
For Christmas?
Andrew, are you on
some sort of medication?
What's going on?
Where are we?
[Gasps] Oh, my God.
O-Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Melanie Carmichael...
will you marry me?
Are you sure?
I mean, a-a-are
you really sure?
Because if you're not sure, we
could just go back to the car.
...Mel, Mel, Mel, Mel...
...It's only been 8 months.
You know I never do
anything rash.
And I usually never
ask a question
I don't already know
the answer to,
so... at the risk of
being rejected twice,
I'm gonna ask you again.
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
[Both laugh]
Yes!
Pick one.
Mayor, just one shot!
One shot!
Can you comment on
the Watson bill?
Over here, Mayor, please!
Over here!
Thank you.
Where is he?
He's running late.
No doubt thanks to
that Carbuncle girl.
Carmichael...
designer, Southern.
Right, whatever.
Right here, Mayor!
...Please, Mayor!
...Miss Mayor, over here!
Your Honor,
how do you answer those
who are opposed to
the street-improvement project
you put before
the city council today?
I suggest they take a drive on
some of the streets in Brooklyn.
Maybe they'll disappear
into a pothole.
Your son's relationship
with Melanie Carmichael...
sources say they're engaged.
Do you have a comment?
Trust me, if my son were
engaged, I'd have a comment.
I thought you were tired.
Jimmy, can you excuse us
for a second?
[Chuckles]
I've been planning
this for weeks.
I knew your show would be great,
and tonight is perfect.
Oh, God, I can't wait to see
the look on my mother's face.
Come on,
let's call your parents.
No!
l-I mean...
[Chuckles nervously]
n-not right this second.
What I mean is, uh...
Honey, would you
mind terribly
if we just kept this to
ourselves for a few days?
Mel, it's gonna come out
sooner or later.
No, l-I know,
I know, but, um,
it's just, I haven't seen
my folks in about 7 years,
and I just feel like I should
probably tell them in person.
Of course.
And, um... l-I think
I should do it alone.
Mel, I'm gonna have to
meet them eventually.
l-I know, I know, and
they will love you...
eventually.
Is it because
I'm a Yankee?
Well, that...
and a Democrat.
Okay... mum's the word.
...No one will know.
...Thank you.
Secretary Hennings,
will you comment...
Secretary Hennings...
Okay. [Laughs]
Hello.
Why haven't you told your
mother you're engaged?
Have you thought
about children?
I'm sorry we're late.
That shade of lipstick does
nothing for you. What kept you?
Oh, it's none of your business.
Ah, you know I hate surprises.
What's going on?
Oh, Tom, always a pleasure.
Good to see you.
...Melanie, darling.
...Hi, Your Honor.
So good to see you.
Look at you... always
the belle of the ball.
I hear very good things
about your new line.
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
Always a pleasure.
Um...
...Andrew?
...Yes?
Seems Melanie is wearing
a skating rink
on a very important finger.
Um, Your Honor, I'd
really like to keep it...
Oh, my God,
you're engaged?!
[Indistinct shouting]
Quiet.
Tabatha: Bloody hell, Mel,
I'm your first New York friend,
and I have to read about it
with 12 million other people!
Sorry, honey,
she just grabbed my hand.
What was I supposed to do?
I know...
we read all about it.
...So, did you cry?
...Wouldn't you?
One man for the rest of my life?
I'd bawl my bloody eyes out.
So why don't you meet us?
We're just around the corner.
[Sighs] Can't.
I'm in Alabama.
Oh... my God.
Yeah.
[Birds chirping]
[Barks]
[Barking slowly]
Aw, he's loud,
but he don't bite.
Come on, shut up, hound!
Lie down.
Go on, stay.
Now, how can I help you?
Well, for starters, you can get
your stubborn ass down here
and give me a divorce.
...[Thud]
...[Groans]
[Sighs] Come on,
Jake, I mean it.
The joke's over.
Let's just finish this.
I've got a plane to catch.
You're shittin' me, right?
You know, I've never actually
understood that expression,
but, no,
I'm not "shitting" you.
Look, it's even got
these idiot-proof tabs
to make it easy.
There's one copy for me,
one copy for you,
and one copy
for the lawyers.
[Exhales sharply]
What? Speak!
[Slow barking resumes]
You show up here
after 7 years
without so much as a "Hey,
there, Jake, remember me...
your wife?"
Or a "Hi, honey.
Lookin' good.
How's the family?"
You expect me to tell you
you look good?
Did they run out of soap down at
the Piggly Wiggly since I left?
[Slow barking continues]
They laugh at that up north
or wherever it is you been?
You knew where I was.
And don't even pretend you spent
all this time missing me.
Oh, I missed you,
all right.
But at this range,
my aim is bound to improve.
Is that a threat?
I've got a lawyer
who charges $350 an hour.
He billed me every time
you sent these papers back.
Well, I'm glad to see
you finally got the message.
...Shut up, Bear!
...Shut up, Bryant!
[Barks, groans]
What happened to Bear?
He died.
You weren't here.
What are you doing?!
Leavin'. You done it.
You should recognize
the gesture.
Could we just try to keep this
as civilized as possible?
Please sign these papers
so I can go home.
What do you know from home?
Hell, I bet your folks don't
even know you're in town.
That's my business.
Honey, those people are
the only family you got.
Don't you "honey" me,
honey!
Get your butt back in that car,
you drive over and see 'em,
and then maybe we'll talk.
[Screen door slams]
Jake! You dumb, stubborn,
redneck hick!
The only reason you
won't sign these papers
is 'cause I want you to!
Wrong! The only reason
I ain't signin'
is 'cause you've turned into
some hoity-toity Yankee bitch,
and I'd like nothin' better
right now than to piss you off!
[Grumbling]
Unh!
What are you doin' with
Mose Plydell's plane anyhow?!
That's my business!
...Fine!
[Door locks]
[Groans]
Divorce, my ass.
[Groans softly]
Hey, genius...
[Sighs]
Next time you lock somebody out,
make sure they don't know
where the spare key's hidden.
Well, see, that's the thing
about Hide-A-Keys...
it'd be nice if your wife
told you where it was!
I'm not your wife, Jake.
I'm just the first girl
that climbed
in the back of your truck.
But you're right...
I have changed.
I don't even know
that girl anymore.
Well, then...
allow me to remind you.
[Door slams]
"Born into one of the wealthiest
families of Greenville, Alabama,
her daddy's in cotton and
all that that implies."
There's no listing for an
Earl Carmichael in Greenville.
How about her local high school?
No record of a Melanie
Carmichael attending... ever.
Jesus! Whatever happened
to responsible journalism?
There's something
wrong here.
Why would my son
do this to me?
Maybe he, um, loves her.
Oh, please!
This is classic rebound.
He's still wounded from...
who was his last girlfriend?
Whitney Truesdale,
lawyer, San Francisco.
Yeah, well, there was
a match made in Heaven...
society, political family,
California...
all those electoral votes.
Get Andrew on the phone.
Since we have a small window
for the Secretary of Housing,
please hold your questions
until after the presentation.
Gentlemen.
Did you see the look
on my mom's face?
I thought her head
was going to explode.
Yeah, what did she say?
That I should date women
like Melanie, not marry them.
...That's harsh.
...That's Mom.
...Thank you.
...Thanks a lot.
We hope to have
the Bronx Children's Hospital
...open by fall 2003.
...[Cellphone ringing]
Oh, speak of the devil.
Hello?
So, have you two lovebirds
set a date?
I'm pleading the Fifth.
Okay, fine, just try to keep
your secrets. I dare you.
Oh, at least you sound like
you're in a better mood.
My approval rating
went up 2 points.
It seems the public likes
being reminded I am a mother.
God, always running for office.
I'm only thinking of you.
Say, um...
do you happen to have
the Carmichaels' number
down there in Greenville?
I thought perhaps
I should introduce myself.
I would like to meet them first,
if you don't mind.
You do realize the press
is going to be all over this.
Happy couples don't sell.
So if there are any skeletons
in her closet, Andrew,
we need to know about them.
[Indistinct talking
on police radio]
You make clothes, right?
I design them.
There's a big difference.
Did you design anything
with stripes?
...[Knock on door]
...You called the sheriff?!
You know that old bastard
hates me!
For good reason!
Well, hell's bells, if
it ain't Felony Melanie.
Wade!
Hot damn, girl,
do we miss you around here!
Hey, I think I saw poor, old
Fuzz just the other day.
Oh, God,
you had to bring that up.
I can't believe
you're the sheriff!
Yep, I get to frisk pretty
little things like you all day
and get paid for it.
Wade, can you try and be
a little more professional?
We got us a crime suspect here.
Now, Melanie, you can't just go
breaking into people's houses.
I didn't break in, Wade.
I used a key...
my key.
Well, it still ain't
your house, darlin'.
I'm gonna have to
escort you out.
Use the cuffs, Wade, please?
If you get him to sign these,
I'll let you run me out of town.
Now, that's none
of your concern.
Well, what do we got here?
...A bill of divorcement?
...Mm-hmm.
Hell, boy, I thought you said
you took care of this.
And I thought I had.
Obviously not.
Well, if you two are still
married, it's her house, too.
This here ain't nothin'
but a domestic dispute.
He didn't hit you, did he?
If he took a swing at you,
I'll take him in right now.
We take that stuff
pretty serious nowadays.
No, Wade,
Jake's never hit me.
You know what?
I don't have a single
childhood memory
that doesn't have
you two in it.
And that includes the night
I lit my ass on fire. Remember?
Wade...
Memory Lane is closed.
Ah, boy, you two got a whole lot
of catchin' up to do...
so I'm just gonna
leave you to it.
Man, I set you up with
your wife. You owe me one!
Why won't you just
sign the papers?!
Hey, there is
nothin' I can do.
The law is the law,
and she has done nothin' wrong.
I suppose shoplifting steaks
at Winn-Dixie's okay.
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
I took 'em back,
and you know it!
You remember that vandalism out
at the stockyard? Totally her!
Like I could tip a cow
by myself.
Hmm.
Wade... isn't there
some outstanding warrant
for whoever dumped your mama's
tractor in the fishpond?
[Gasps]
[Sighs deeply]
We only have 10 of these, and
it's gonna be gone for good.
So if you are loving
this monster...
...[Snoring]
...[Telephone rings]
We have eight only?
If I knew how to say that in
Italian, I would, but I don't.
Um, if you love this...
9: 15? Honestly.
Who could be callin'
at this hour?
Hello?
Hel-lo?
Melanie: Hey, Mama.
Melanie? Is that you?
Oh, it's so late.
Are you all right?
I, uh... um...
I just thought
I'd surprise you.
Well, this certainly is a fine
surprise, hearing from you...
you know,
being such a busy girl and all.
Of course, I call people
while I'm doin' the dishes
or shellin' peas.
Oprah calls it
"multitasking."
Mama, the call
isn't the surprise.
l-I'm in town.
Oh, Lord, love a duck!
Ha!
Oh, my baby girl
has finally come home.
Earl, she's in town.
Earl: You gonna repeat
everything she says?
...If you are, get off my chair.
...Mama...
I'm just sittin' here, is all.
What happened to the sound?
I turned it down
so I could hear the phone ring.
...Mama!
...What, are you a clairvoyant?
It was so loud,
I couldn't hear myself think.
...Mama...
...They could have heard it
at Joe and Lurlynn's house.
...Hello?
...I only get 3 minutes.
Oh, honey, you didn't need
to call, then. Just come on by.
Uh... well, that's the thing.
I was sorta hoping
Daddy could come get me.
Earl: So, what put you
in jail this time?
Melanie: Jake and
his big, fat mouth.
It's just a misunderstanding,
that's all.
Yeah, kinda like that
weddin' I paid for, huh?
I would hardly call that
a wedding.
Boy was nervous.
He was still drunk
from the night before.
Can you blame him?
Yes, I can!
I went to the reception
by myself with puke
all down my dress while he slept
it off in the Travelodge,
and you're still
siding with that...
I'm not sidin' with anybody.
...[Sighs]
The boy's changed, is all.
Can we just
not talk about Jake, okay?
l-I know he's the son you never
had, but I'm your only daughter,
and maybe you want to know
what's new with me.
[Sighs] Okay, shoot.
I met somebody...
and he's quite a catch.
H-He's really a great guy.
And I'm happy... really.
Come to Mama, sugar!
Hey, Mama.
Oh, good land of the livin',
you are skin and bones.
Well, don't I get a smile?
I know you got one
in there somewhere.
Come on, come on, let's not
let all the bought air out.
Well, are you hungry, sweetie?
Do you want me to reheat you
some chicken-fried steak?
Oh, no, Mama, I'm fine.
Sweetie, you look tired.
Are you tired?
Oh, you know what?
Maybe it's the way
you're wearing your hair now.
[Sighs]
You guys have really done
a lot with the place.
Lord, would you listen
to that accent?
Why don't you sit
in my good chair?
Now, your mama got me this
Christmas before last.
Oh, you mean the one where you
were supposed to come visit me?
I told you time and time again,
it just didn't suit.
Let me... let me get
you those tickets.
Sit down in it.
Sit down.
[Chair squeaks]
Now, watch this.
[Clicking]
...Ahh!
...[Springs boing]
...Oh! Oh!
...[Squeaking]
I mean, isn't that
quite the deal?
There are hardly words.
Now, how do I get
out of this thing?
...Oh...
...[Clicking]
...Oh, my God!
...[Springs boing]
Jake tell you
he's thinkin' of gettin' one?
...[Sighs]
...Oh, I see your priorities...
Jake, jail, and then home.
Mama, it was just unfinished
business, is all.
Jake's doin' all right.
Boy's goin' places.
Once upon a time,
you were goin' places, too.
Here are your tickets.
These were a gift.
I'd rather you guys
just use them.
You know what I can't understand
is how y'all will visit
every stupid battlefield
in the continental U.S.,
but you can't manage
to visit your only daughter.
Well, the door swings
both ways, sweetie.
Anyway, don't get me started on
the things I don't understand.
Here we go.
Your dream for me was to get out
of this place and be somebody.
You shoved me in every beauty
pageant in the state.
I'm just sayin', is all.
What?! What are you
trying to say?!
l-I mean, just tell me what
I can do to make you happy!
Just make yourself happy,
darlin'.
Done.
We're there, all right?
You know, I've really
made something of myself.
I have a career. People
actually want to be me.
And somebody loves me,
and I love him.
Pearl, why don't you get us that
baloney cake out the icebox?
Your mama's a complex woman.
[Sighs] I'm going to bed.
Good night, darlin'.
Kate:
But you know nothing about her.
Are you even sure who she is?
I love her, Mom.
That's nice,
but you have to be careful.
You and I are different.
We're not better, not worse...
we're just different.
We're in public life to serve,
and to serve
to the best of our abilities,
we have to set good examples.
Do you have to control
everything?
I've put a hold on the Plaza
for the second weekend in June.
That should give you
a nice, long engagement.
We were thinking
Christmas in Ireland.
[Silverware clinks]
If you think
I'm going to let some girl
talk you into getting married
...She is not "some girl."
...any place but New York City.
She's my fiancee,
for Christ's sake.
[Exhales sharply]
You are just
like your father.
One minute you're brilliant,
controlled, steadfast.
The next you're
throwing it all away
on some young piece of ass.
Those are your issues, Mother.
[Clears throat]
Not mine.
[Birds chirping]
[Dog barking]
Melanie: Okay...
Hold on.
You know what? Uh...
How long does
a contested divorce take?
18 months?!
Mr. Buford,
I don't have 18 months.
I don't have 18 days.
Okay, well, that's just
not gonna work for me.
...U- Uh, ye-yes.
...Man: Whoo-hoo!
Don't see the likes of you
around these here parts much!
Mr. Buford,
that's not gonna work.
Lady, you look like
sex on a stick in that
...Frederick Montana getup!
...I have to call you back.
Listen, bubba,
why don't you just kiss my...
...ass!
Oh, my God!
Get in the truck, there, missy,
'cause I don't do that sort
of thing on the street.
I guess your mama
raised you right.
Whoo! What is that? [Sniffs]
Calvin Klein? That's very nice.
Very good.
l-I better back off.
Don't want to get you in trouble
with the little lady.
There is a little lady,
isn't there?
I can hardly afford me, much
less some high-maintenance babe.
What about
Cindy What's-her-name?
You guys were real hot
and heavy in high school.
She's a women's softball coach
up in Nashville.
...Mm-hmm. [Chuckles]
...Oh...
Well, that explains some
lingering questions that I had
about a game of post office
we played one time.
...[Laughing] No!
...[Laughs]
I guess we all have our little
secrets, don't we, Bobby Ray?
Yeah, we sure do.
'Course, I read about
yours on the Internet.
What?!
Oh, I know all about
the cocks in your henhouse.
Oh, God!
Bobby Ray!
You sure do know how
to make a girl blush.
Well, I gotta get back
to the factory,
but are you in town
for a while?
Oh, God, I hope not. No,
I'm just hitting the bank.
Well, I better scram.
Ha ha. Very funny.
...Been really good to see you.
...Good to see you, too.
[Smooches]
Bye.
[Door opens]
Oh... hi, Eugene.
How's your leg?
Oh, it don't give me too much
trouble, Miss Melanie.
Dorothea, I'm gonna
take my lunch.
[Telephone rings]
Well, look what
the cat dragged in.
Dorothea?!
Oh, my God, you've...
Lost 110 pounds,
I know.
[Exhales sharply]
Well... congratulations.
Thanks.
Uh... I noticed that you
don't have an ATM.
Oh, them things.
Russ don't want to put one in
on account of you lose personal
contact with the customers.
Yes, that would be tragic.
Wade said you and Jake
had quite the reunion.
But that's just
pillow talk talkin'.
A-Are you and Wade...
Goin' on three years.
'Course,
it ain't Tiffany's.
But then again,
you can't believe
everything you hear on TV.
Uh, l-I need to make
a withdraw from my...
Joint account?
My what?
with Jake.
From what I hear,
y'all are still married.
Why, yes.
Yes, we are.
# I got a little change
in my pocket #
# Goin' jing-a-ling-a-ling #
# Want to call you on
the telephone, baby #
# And give you a ring #
# But each time we talk #
# I get the same old thing #
# Always
"No huggy, no kissy #
# Until I get a wedding ring" #
# Oh, my honey, my baby #
# Don't put my love
upon no shelf #
# She said,
"Don't hand me no lines #
# And keep
your hands to yourself" #
# B-Baby, baby, baby #
# Why you treat me this way? #
# You know I'm still
your lover boy... #
[Groans]
Hi, honey.
Lookin' good.
How's the family?
Cut the shit.
Where's my stuff?
Now, what kind of wife
would I be
if I didn't pick up
after my husband?
The kind that
don't live here.
Now, I'm gonna ask you
one last time.
Where is the Hide-A-Key?!
I had the sweetest chat with
Wade's mama about her tractor.
Nice to see you got
your accent back.
Oh, I stumbled across
a few things today.
Holy shit!
What happened to the stove?!
Oh, and where are
them little magnets
I had over here, huh?!
What the hell is this...
chick food?
Light beer... less calories.
I tried to pick out
a new bed,
but have you been to
the Sit 'n Sleep lately?
Yuck. I'll just have to order
something from New York.
Whatever blows
your dress up, darlin'.
You go right ahead
and spend your money.
Oh, but, darlin'...
I thought you said we should
think of it as...
our money.
Just a guess,
but I'm thinking the words
"joint checking"
are flashing in your head
right now.
How much did you take?
All of it.
Son of a bitch!
You want a wife,
you got a wife.
And what are you doing
with all that cash?
Why don't you invest it?
Don't you know anything?!
I know if you don't get out
of this house right now...
Sign the papers, and
I'll give it all back.
...Fine!
Give me the pen.
Hold on. What are you doing
with all that cash saved up?
And since when did you
quit the tire factory?
You're not doing anything
illegal, are you, Jake?!
Maybe I am. So what?
I don't ask you about
your boyfriend,
you keep your nose
out of my life... deal?
Who told you?
Honey, just 'cause I talk slow
doesn't mean I'm stupid.
Look, Jake...
Nobody finds their soul mate
when they're 10 years old.
Yeah, I guess.
I mean, where's
the fun in that, right?
I can't believe you kept
this thing all these years.
Mm-hmm.
Most people don't know that
lightning does that to sand.
Oh, hey, Mel,
you know what?
[Chuckles]
I just remembered
I got myself a hot date.
You don't mind if I have
my lawyer take a look at these.
What?!
Hell, I'm just a
simple country boy.
There's words in there
I can't even pronounce.
You might be takin' me to
the cleaners for all I know.
The cleaners? You?
Say, what did this set
you back, anyhow?
More than you
make in a month.
Just sign the damn papers!
Nah...
But...
thanks for stoppin' by.
Oh! God.
# Bright lights, big city #
# Gone to my baby's head #
# Bright lights, big city... #
[Cellphone rings]
I love you, I love you,
I love you.
Andrew:
Are you sitting down?
Melanie: Why? Bad news?
Just picked up the "New York"
magazine, and I quote,
"That cool breath
of fresh air
"blowing through the tents
at Fashion Week
"was the soon-to-be household
name of Melanie Carmichael.
Fashion insiders have labeled
her 'the next big one."'
[Gasps]
Oh, my God,
"the next big one"?
Oh, God, honey, I needed that
almost as much as I need you.
What is that noise?
[Sighs]
The sound of my past.
Have fun.
[Giggles] Okay, bye.
...# Bright lights #
...# Big city #
# Gone to my baby's head #
...# Yeah, bright lights #
...# Bright lights #
...# Big city #
Batten down the hatches,
boys!
Trouble done just walked
back into my life,
disguised as my favorite
daughter-in-law!
Honey, drive that pretty face
over here and give me a hug! Oh!
Soon-to-be
ex-daughter-in-law.
Ooh, whoo!
Who's the lucky guy?
His name is Andrew.
He's in politics.
Well, you got my vote.
Good to see you,
baby girl.
Hey, you give this lady
whatever she wants.
...I'll catch up with you later.
...All right.
I'll have a Gray Goose martini,
two olives, dirty. Thanks.
# Well... #
Oh... my... God!
Melanie?!
Lurlynn?
Yes! Oh, my God!
L-Look at you,
all fancy.
You look like you just
stepped out of a magazine.
Oh, well, thank you.
Um, look at you.
You have a baby...
in a bar.
Hell, I got three
more at home.
This one's still on the tit,
so I can cart him anywhere.
...[Baby gurgles]
...Right.
I almost bought that exact same
top the other day.
But Clinton'd kill me
if I spent 30 bucks
on a sweater thing.
Ah, that Jaclyn Smith
knows what she's doin'.
Actually, it's mine.
Bergdorf's just picked it up.
I design clothes now.
Oh, mmm, now that
you mention it,
I'm... I'm pretty sure
I heard that. [Chuckles]
...[Cheers and applause]
...So, do you know Jaclyn Smith?
Mind if I join you?
Actually, we do.
You must be Jake's hot date.
I'm Starr.
Hi, I'm Melanie, Jake's
snotty Yankee-bitch wife,
whom he refuses to divorce,
even though
I'm engaged to another man.
Hot dog, Jake, look at
the size of that thing.
...Honey?
...Huh?
Why don't you get us
a couple drinks, all right?
Okay. [Giggles]
Is that a martini?
Not "me and her" us.
"You and l" us.
Why do you make me
be mean to you?
Is that what you want...
to be humiliated in front
of all of your friends?
Oh, come on, Mel,
we were your friends, too.
Well, looky, looky there!
Well, well, well,
if it isn't the two
groomsmen of the apocalypse.
...Hey, Eldon!
...Yep?
Are you hungry?!
Starved!
No, no, no!
No, don't you dare!
I could use a Melanie
sandwich!
Just seems like old times,
doesn't it?
Get off me!
Ugh!
No, not like old times,
all right?
Times have changed.
No more Melanie sandwich,
no more Melanie taco,
and no more Melanie
corn dog, all right?
...Sure... sorry.
...Just playin' with you.
Come on, guys,
just grab a stick.
Let's play some pool,
all right?
And if you can't find a cue,
just pull the one
shoved up her ass.
[Laughter,
cheers and applause]
Eldon, you're still wearing
that same old stupid hat.
Well, I... just about
got it broken in.
Now, you sit your
bony ass down there
and watch and see me
teach Jake here
how to lose at pool.
Well, see, that's the thing.
I'm not really a watch-and-see
kind of girl...
am I, Jake?
Woman: Come on, now,
Bobby Ray, you got it.
[Drunkenly] Bobby Ray...
...[Laughs]
...[Laughs, snorts]
Don't blow this one,
okay?
All right, baby?
You can take the girl
out of the honky-tonk,
but you can't take the
honky-tonk out of the girl.
[All groaning]
Eldon: So, Jake...
are you going to divorce
this girl or what?
Well, she waited 7 years.
A couple more days
won't kill her...
unfortunately.
Like it's gonna
make a difference.
You never know.
You might be interested to learn
Jake has this whole...
Hey, hey, let her think
whatever she wants, Clinton.
She made up her mind
about me a long time ago.
Some things never change.
[All groaning]
Like Eldon here!
He never could get
his balls in the right pocket.
[Laughter]
Okay, Jake,
it's you and Mel.
Clutch time, man.
It's just like
state playoffs.
We're down by 6,
7 seconds to go.
We need that big, beautiful
52-yard bomb!
[Cheers and applause]
Do you remember that,
Mel?
How could I forget?
That was the night
Jake got me pregnant.
All: Ooh.
Why don't you just go
public with that shit?
Oh, come on.
It's not like anybody can
keep a secret around here...
except for Bobby Ray.
Now, what did I
ever do to you?
You never did anything
to me, darlin'...
or any other girl in town.
[Laughter]
Melanie, what is
the matter with you?
...What do you mean?
...Oh, she's just unhappy.
Well, of course,
I would be, too,
if "Women's Wear Daily"
called me "less than mediocre."
[Laughter]
Why don't you just
go to a gay bar?!
...Ooh!
...[Light laughter]
[Laughing] Now, what would
"B" Ray do at a gay bar?
Well...
[Pool cue clatters]
I think I had about
enough fun for one night.
Oh, come on,
I was just kidding.
Hey, Stella!
How 'bout another round of
drinks for my friends here?
Honey, I think you've
had about enough.
You know what?
I think you're right.
I have had enough.
I mean, how do you people live
like this, anyway?
All right, that's it,
that's it. Come on.
Did you know that there's
a great, big world out there?
It has absolutely nothin'
to do with chitlins
or children or beer!
I liked her better
when she was crazy.
[Sighs] Jake!
What makes you think
you can treat them
like somethin' you stepped in
in them fancy shoes, huh?!
...You asked for it!
...I asked for it?!
You show up here,
you steal my money,
you rearrange my house, and
then you insult my friends,
actin' like you're
better than 'em!
I am better than them!
And you stole my pen!
That's all that matters
to you, isn't it?
...Jake...
...The money...
the labels, the shoes...
you're pathetic!
Oh, like you're
goin' places!
Well, I am as soon as I
get my keys out of here.
Oh, no, you don't.
No, you don't, Mel.
...Give me my purse!
...You want to kill yourself?
You want to kill yourself,
you do it somewhere else.
At least I'm doin'
somethin' with my life.
So what if you can't
play football anymore?!
...Get a new dream!
...Get in the car.
...Get in the truck, Mel.
...I did.
All right!
So, I... guess
the date's over, huh?
Do me a favor.
...Hmm?
...Follow us home.
...[Gagging] Blah!
...[Vomit splashing]
[Sighs deeply]
[Melanie snoring]
Earl.
Evening, Jake.
Pearl.
Jake.
Oh!
[Dog barking, children shouting
playfully in distance]
Mmm...
Earl:
My battle's in the day
and runs on into
tomorrow morning.
Pearl: Be still.
I can't fasten this.
If we win, I might stick around
for old Billy's rabbit stew.
If we lose, I'll be home.
Tomorrow, then, sweetie.
Now, listen, Pearl,
you go easy on her.
There.
Oh, we were wondering when
we were gonna see you.
Christ Almighty, Daddy.
How am I gonna explain you
in New York City?
History's history.
No use sweepin' it
under the rug.
Wish me luck.
Go get them Yankees.
People need a passport
to come down here.
[Door closes]
[Birds chirping]
Hey, Bryant, where is he?
[Barking]
Jake: Come here.
Come on, come on.
There you go,
there you go.
...[Groans]
...Look good? Come on!
Bryant, Bryant,
come on! Come on!
What's she doin' here,
huh?
I thought you'd be gone.
Bryant,
there you go, boy.
I put the money back
in your account.
There you go!
Thanks.
Saves me from bouncin'
a lot of checks.
Can he swim?
Doesn't look like it.
I like what you did, though...
to the house.
Should help it sell quicker.
Are you movin'?
Well... I been spendin'
a lot of my time
up around Tuscaloosa,
so...
[Snorts]
How deep is that water?
About 8 feet.
[Bryant groans]
Look, Mel...
I signed your papers.
Jake, I never
meant to hurt you,
or anybody else,
for that matter.
And I just came out
here to say...
thank you.
You might want to find yourself
a place out of the way.
You can't just leave!
[Chuckles]
Sure I can.
You want to come?
Where you goin'?
Well...
I want to show you
somethin'.
I can't.
Can't or won't?
Both.
The girl I knew
used to be fearless.
The girl you knew
didn't have a life.
Well, I... guess you better
get on with it, then.
Come on, Bryant!
Come on, boy,
get in here.
E-Excuse me, do you know
Bobby Ray Bailey's address?
8 13 Lafayette.
You don't remember me,
do you?
Oh, I remember you
just fine.
You used to steal
catfish from my pond.
Yes, sir.
I did that.
I'm sorry.
'Course, on the weekends,
Bobby Ray goes over to
the Carmichael plantation...
visits with Colonel Murphy...
it being tourist
season and all.
Thank you.
[Birds chirping,
dog barking]
Yes?
Oh, hi! [Chuckles]
I'm Melanie Carmi...
um, um, Melanie Smooter.
I'm... I'm here
to see Bobby Ray.
[Cannon fires]
...Oh.
...Yee-haw!
If he's alive,
he's out back.
Come on.
They're out here somewhere.
Watch your step.
Bobby Ray?
Bobby Ray: Melanie?!
Don't move!
Yee-haw!
[Cannonball whirring]
Hot damn!
Hold your fire, sir.
I'll be right back.
We weren't aimin' for ya,
but I doubt I would have
gone to your funeral.
I guess I wouldn't blame you.
Forgotten how beautiful
this place was.
Guess it doesn't take much
to forget a lot of things.
Bobby Ray,
it's not like that.
You know what? I'll tell
you what it's not like.
It's not like Jake's the only
one that you run out on.
I'm so sorry I outed you.
I guess I figured
if I was pointing at you,
then... nobody would
see through me.
Bobby Ray,
I can't find the fuse!
I should go
before he kills himself.
Bye.
Afternoon.
Can I help you?
Barry Lowenstein,
"New York Post."
Ho-ho, boy,
am I glad to see you.
I'll tell you, it's, uh...
definitely, uh,
another world down here.
Uh, did you say
the "Post"?
Yes, I did.
l-I was hoping
to get an interview
with you and your family...
maybe, um, a few pictures
if you don't mind?
No.
I mean, uh, yes, I do...
mind.
They're not here.
Oh... wow.
This is just
as you described it.
It must have been amazing,
huh, growing up here?
Like a fantasy.
Would you mind if I take
a quick look inside?
Actually,
I'm on my way out.
I'll come back, then.
Uh, uh, okay,
but just a peek.
[Chuckles]
This is it...
home sweet home.
Wow!
How old is this place?
Uh...
it was built by my, uh,
great-great-great-grandfather,
Charles Carmichael,
in 1853.
Oh, boy, I bet you slid down
this banister a time or two.
Oh.
And over here we have
the, um...
[Maid humming]
...kitchen, but who hasn't
seen one of those?
Let's start over here.
[Door knob rattles]
[Humming continues]
[Gasps] Oh.
[Whispering] Now, this is
my favorite room.
It was part of the, um,
Underground Railroad.
[Whispering]
Why are we whispering?
The whole place
is haunted...
by ghosts of, um,
the Civil War soldiers.
[Door hinges creak]
[Creaking]
Jake! [Muttering]
...buttons.
No wonder we lost the war.
Was that one of 'em?
Melanie?
What are you doin'
in a closet?
Hi. Barry Lowenstein,
"New York Post."
Miss Carmichael is just showing
me around the plantation.
Uh, Mr. Lowenstein is writing
a piece on the family,
you know, since I'm marrying
the mayor's son and all.
I had no idea.
Isn't that something?
Yeah.
Well, a plantation by any
other name is just a farm.
But it does roll off the tongue
a little sweeter, doesn't it?
Huh.
Well, I do believe Miss Melanie
forgot her manners.
I'm Bobby Ray...
her cousin.
[Sighs]
Charmed.
See, when the Yankees
marched through Alabama,
they tried to destroy
our metal-formin' capabilities
by placin' barrels of powder
underneath the anvils.
Of course,
all that managed to do
was blow 'em sky-high
for a few seconds.
So... in honor
of that act of stupidity,
we all... we get together to
re-create it for the tourists.
...[Cannon fires]
...Aah!
...Yee-haw!
...What the hell was that?!
[Cannonball whirring]
Hey, Grandpa!
This here's Barry!
He's doin' an article
on Melanie's weddin'!
Never heard of her.
Thanks!
[Tires screeching]
Well, aren't you
just a big, fat liar.
Bobby Ray!
Oh, go back to New York.
[Both laugh]
# If fear's
what makes us decide #
# Our future journey #
# Well, I'm not along
for a life #
# I'm not along for a life #
# 'Cause I'm still yearning #
# l-l-I am falling down #
# Try and stop me #
# It feels so good
to hit the ground #
# You can watch me #
# I fall right on my face #
# It's an uphill human race #
# And l-I am falling down #
Hmm. Hello.
I'm sorry about what I said.
Really sorry.
Melanie, forget it.
Boy:
She was not sharing.
Okay, y'all, you need
to eat and be quiet.
We're gonna have us
a little visit.
# Ye-a, ye-a, ye-a, yeah #
# Oh, l-l-I am falling down #
# Try and stop me #
# It feels so good
to hit the ground #
You know, he went up there.
Who?
Jake? When?
About a year after you left.
He doesn't know I know,
but Clinton let it slip once.
Jake was in New York?
He told Clinton he'd never
seen anything like it.
He realized straight off
he'd need more than
an apology to win you back.
He needed to conquer
the world first.
He's been tryin' ever since.
That's why he kept
sending the papers back.
Yeah.
Hmm. It's funny
how things don't work out.
[Baby gurgles]
It's funny how they do.
[Cheers and applause]
# Now, listen here #
# Well, I tried to tell you,
baby #
# But that don't make
no sense #
# Now you got me, baby #
# Up against that fence #
...# Ain't that a shame? #
...# Shame #
# Shame, shame
the way you do #
Man: Ha-ha! Ha!
Hey, look who I found
hangin' out by the parkin' lot.
Hesitant to join us.
# Shame, shame,
shame on you #
Jake: Anybody think
of anything in here
that, uh, might bother
Bobby Ray?
...Uh, Clinton's breath?
...Ha!
You still the same Bobby Ray
from last night?
Last time I checked,
yeah.
Well, then, I'm gonna
buy you a drink.
Well, you're really not
my type, I mean...
[Laughter]
Oh, honey, you...
you drink that from the top.
I'm just lookin' to see who
makes this Deep South Glass.
I wonder if you can get it
in New York.
It's beautiful.
Hey, Jake,
Mel would like to know
where she can find some of
that snooty-faluty glass.
Why ask me?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe because you're...
[Clears throat]
You're all spiffed up
and... and all.
...["Sweet Home Alabama" plays]
...Am I missin' somethin'?
...[Cheering]
...Let's show some respect.
Jake...
When was the last time you
pushed me around the floor?
Clinton here has got
two left feet.
Well, Ms. Taylor,
I'd be honored.
Let's do it. Come on.
Come on, Mel,
get on out here!
Well, aren't you
the Lord of the Dance?
I ain't as clumsy as I look.
She just can't keep time.
You might have to
prove that to me.
Woman: Whoo!
# Now, I heard Mr. Young
sing about her #
You know, he's pretty good.
It might be you.
Oh, the hell you say.
Let me at him.
# I hope Neil Young
will remember #
Aw, look at them two
welded together.
Why do they fight it?
# Sweet home Alabama #
Maybe we could just talk.
# Lord, I'm comin' home
to you #
[Crickets chirping,
dog barking]
[Train whistle blows]
Come on, let's go
to the Roadhouse.
Nah.
What do you say we drive
out to Fairview and bowl?
I don't think so.
Do you want to go
harass somebody?
...[Chuckles]
...Unh-unh.
Hey, I know this great
place where we can...
All: No!
Y'all, I think I'm gonna
call it a night.
[Thud]
[Sighs]
[Crickets chirping]
[Indistinct shouting
in distance]
Hi, there, boy.
Sorry it took me so long.
I would have come sooner
if I'd known you were sick.
Actually, that's
probably not true.
[Exhales sharply]
I've been pretty selfish lately.
Dogs don't know anything
about that, do they, though?
You were always
like a big old pillow.
Like when everything
went pear-shaped...
[Voice breaking]
you never left my side.
And then I just left you.
[Crying] I bet you sat there
wondering what you'd done wrong.
I told him
it was my fault.
[Sighs]
[Sniffs]
Quit bein' so nice.
It's the truth.
How come it has to be
so complicated?
What?
Truth...
[Sniffs] life...
this.
He was one hell
of a good dog, wasn't he?
[Sighs, sniffs]
Yeah.
You looked like you were
having fun out there tonight.
I'm happy
in New York, Jake.
[Sighs]
But then I come down here
and...
this fits, too.
Since when does it have to be
one or the other?
You can have roots
and wings, Mel.
Maybe I could just fly south
for the winter.
Look.
What?
There.
Do you see 'em?
[Chuckles]
Lightning bugs?
Only you.
[Sniffs]
[Chuckles]
You know, I still go
out there sometimes.
I see those big thunderheads
rollin' in.
It's like a religion.
[Chuckles]
I had a dream about it
the other night.
You ever wonder
what would have happened
if we hadn't have gotten
pregnant?
Jake...
Just...
let me get this out
before I can't.
I thought that baby
would be an adventure.
And it took me a while
to realize
it would have been
your only adventure.
I just guess Mother Nature
knew better, huh?
I was so ashamed...
...'cause I felt...
relieved.
And all of a sudden, I just...
needed a different life.
You done real well
for yourself.
I'm proud of you, Mel.
I'm just sorry I never danced
with you at our weddin'.
I'm sure this next one's
gonna go better for ya.
Jake, I can't do this.
Hey...
I know.
Go home.
Well, I'm just sayin',
is all.
I mean, I... I saw
the way you two
were lookin' at each other.
Will you just shut up
about it, Mama?!
I can't help
the way Jake feels about me!
He hasn't done
anything wrong!
He hasn't done anything right
either!
I can't believe I'm even
having this argument!
I'm leaving! I'm gone!
I'm marrying another man!
Yes, that's right, you get
a second chance, so please
don't mess it up!
For who?
For me or for you?
Don't sass me, okay?
Don't you dare sass me,
'cause I have put up
with an awful lot from you
over the years.
Like what?! L-Like me quitting
your precious pageants?
I didn't want you to
end up like me! Damn it!
Now, you need to stay as far
away from here as you can.
That boy is quicksand.
What's so wrong
with being you, Mama?
I just think that you
deserve better, that's all.
I know you do.
You always have.
I'll see you in New York,
all right?
Mm-hmm.
You'll like it.
I promise.
Now, don't you forget to
say goodbye to your daddy.
[Drumroll]
...Fire!
Fire!
[Cannons fire]
Melanie: Daddy?
[Firing continues]
Daddy?
Daddy!
Who ya lookin' for,
darlin'?
Earl Smooter.
5th Regiment?
[All groaning]
Anybody seen Earl Smooter?
He's about to surrender!
Thank you!
[All sigh]
[Tires screech, horn honks]
After you.
Afternoon.
...How are ya?
...Good, thanks. Yourself?
No complaints.
That's a beautiful house.
Sure. Yeah.
You, uh, you here
to see Bobby Ray?
Actually, I'm, uh,
hoping to surprise Melanie.
...Melanie?
...My fiancee.
You got the wrong house,
don't ya?
This is, uh,
the Carmichael place, isn't it?
Are we talkin'
about the same girl?
...Melanie Smooter?
...Melanie Carmichael.
Oh, well,
that explains it.
That sure does.
Andrew Hennings.
Nice meeting you, Jake.
[Doorbell rings]
Hey, Jake.
What's goin' on?
Oh, you know,
I'm just, uh, talkin'
to Mel's fiance here.
Wonder if you might know
where she is.
Andrew Hennings.
You must be...
l-I'm Bobby Ray...
her, uh, cousin?
I see you've already met
Jake... her, uh...
...Other cousin.
...[Laughs]
Family! God, it's great
to meet you both.
I think Melanie said
somethin' last night
about, uh, visitin'
her daddy
u-up at the...
up at the battlefield.
...The battlefield?
...You know us Southerners.
I mean, the minute
the Confederacy died,
it became a moral issue.
Come on, I'll, uh, I'll
give you a ride up there.
That's great. Thank you.
All right. Nice meeting you.
# What this world needs
is a few more rednecks #
# So people ain't afraid
to take a stand #
So, who's...
Melanie... Smooter?
Local hero around here.
Why is that?
She blew up the bank.
And that made her a hero?
Well, notorious, anyway.
She was 10.
Oh.
Fortunately, nobody was hurt...
except, maybe, the cat.
What cat?
The one with the dynamite
on its back.
She blew up a cat?
...He was scheduled to die.
...From dynamite?
The vet said it had cancer,
so Eldon thought it'd be put
in one of those chambers,
you know, the ones
that suck their lungs out.
Little Mel, she couldn't bear
the thought of that.
She, uh, she wanted
somethin' more humane.
Yeah, sure.
So, they were doing some
blastin' out by the new highway.
So, we, uh, we took
old Fuzz up there,
taped him up.
Used about 30 feet of fuse
just to be on the safe side,
said our prayers,
and ran like hell.
Of course.
So, there we were,
sittin' in Virgie's Diner,
feelin' pretty blue.
When Mel looks up and sees
that damn cat,
trottin' down the road,
searchin' for Eldon.
No shit.
Yeah, and we
would have caught him, too,
but once that fuse hit his tail,
boom, he took off like a shot.
And into the bank.
Well... the theory is,
he probably wriggled loose
from the explosive.
'Cause, uh, people still
see him from time to time,
scorched tail and all.
He's a little skittish
around humans.
That's quite a story.
She was quite a girl.
# A little less talk
and a little more action #
Whatever happened to her?
# And a few more rednecks... #
Oh, you know...
wound up pregnant,
married some loser
right out of high school.
[Trumpet playing "Taps"]
["Taps" ends]
[Whistling,
cheers and applause]
Are you surprised?
What are you doing here?
Well, I came to deliver
your fiance.
I think
she was talking to me.
Jake...
Must be exhaustin'.
...What?
Livin' a lie.
What's he talking about?
You and I are in love
with two different people.
Is he a second cousin?
He's my husband.
Your what?
I mean my ex-husband.
You married your cousin?!
No, I came down here
to finalize my divorce.
Hey, darlin',
thought that was you.
Must be your new someone.
Earl Smooter...
glad to meet ya.
Melanie Smooter.
Andrew, wait.
Wait!
Andrew! Wait!
I just...
Please.
Let me try
and explain myself!
You don't understand!
This is not
who I am anymore!
Look, I don't know who you are
or what else you lied about,
but I know one thing...
there is a Lear Jet
in Mobile, and I am on it.
[Sighs]
I know you're thinkin'
I spoiled things good
this time.
Oh, hon, don't go accusin' me
of thinkin'.
I ain't done
anything of the sort.
Anyway, spoiled's in the eye
of the beholder...
...like these plums here.
Some people might
call them "spoiled"...
but I think that, um,
these almost-ruined ones
sometimes make
the sweetest jam.
Do you need any help?
It was kind of fun,
seeing Daddy up there,
surrendering.
Yeah.
He sure does have
a flair for the dramatic.
You certainly don't get it
from my side of the family.
Hey, y'all.
Look who I found
walkin' down l-58.
Hi.
I thought you'd be
halfway to New York by now.
So did I.
Ooh, if I'd known
company was comin',
I'd have put on the dog.
This is my mama.
Hi.
She makes the best jam
in three counties.
[Scoffs] Oh.
And my dad...
you... you already met him.
Yeah.
And this is our home.
This is where I grew up.
Well, it's a pleasure
meeting you both.
I'm... Andrew Hennings...
Melanie's fiance...
well... that is... if...
if she'll still have me.
Look, Mel...
I really don't care
what happened down here.
So... you have a past.
I mean, who doesn't?
What I need to know
is if there is a place for me
in your future.
Oh, good Lord.
That is the sweetest thing.
Well, go on.
Oh! Hello, New York City!
Woman, what the hell
you gassin' about?
Well, sir...
my mother happens to be
the mayor up there,
and, uh, she'd like
nothing better
than a big, snazzy
New York wedding.
Well, uh...
yeah, I suppose
I can take off work.
Andrew, I, um...
actually, I was thinking,
maybe we could have
the wedding here.
Here.
In my hometown.
Look, Mel, if you're worried
about the money, don't.
It's not about
the money, Andrew...
not down here.
You know...
a lot of people
are expecting us
to get married in the city,
but I think a nice,
quiet, country wedding
is just the ticket.
Earl...
Pearl, if you...
if you folks could
take care
of the rehearsal dinner,
I'd really like
to take care of the rest.
Well, I think
we could cover that.
Heck. [Chuckles]
How many times does
your only daughter get married?
[Chuckling]
Other than before.
Felony Melanie?
She was never convicted.
Oh-ho.
I don't know
which is worse...
child cat killer
or sons of the Confederacy.
What would you suggest I do...
dump her for being poor?
You're supposed to be
a Democrat, remember?
There is nothing wrong
with being poor.
I get elected by poor people,
and I'm a big enough person
to commend her
for making something of herself.
What upsets me
is that she lied to you.
So what? She was ashamed
of her background.
Who hasn't been embarrassed by
their parents at one point?
I'm going to assume that
was a rhetorical question.
Assume away.
[Sighs] No one is going to
change my mind about this...
not you, not the media,
not anyone.
Fine...
but admit it...
I was right.
Yes... you were right.
There is a wedding
in your future,
whether you like it or not.
And how, exactly,
does Little Miss Alabama
plan to accommodate
500 people?
I suppose she has connections
at the jail.
Well, there are
several excellent choices...
the Travelodge,
Days Inn, a Motel 6,
oh, and
the Golden Cherry Motel,
where we will be.
Laugh now,
but if this gets out...
It won't.
The press expects
the Plaza in June.
# Something's #
# Been creepin' into my head #
# Turnin' my thoughts #
...[Telephone ringing]
...# Into a dizzy red #
Now, let's talk
about your wedding.
This place is gorgeous,
and we can control
the security.
...[Ringing continues]
...The Carmichael plantation?
It did inspire your identity,
did it not?
...You thought of everything.
...Yeah, well, I always do.
Been great.
Keep in touch.
# Now you have come #
...[Ringing continues]
...# To get some lofty role #
# Oh, you got me walkin'
backwards #
# You got me thinkin'
sideways #
# You got me talkin' circles #
# You got me losin' my way #
# You got me crossin'
every line #
[Ringing continues]
# You got me just in #
# Time #
[Ringing stops]
...You guys remember the sheik.
...Yeah.
Well, he proposed to me,
and I think I loved him,
despite his billions.
Then why didn't you say
"yes"?
Because I hesitated
long enough to realize
my head and my heart were saying
two different things.
...It's this way.
...Yeah.
Well, it's a big decision.
Well, it's supposed to be
the easiest one you ever make.
Wasn't it?
Hey, Tabby, this is it...
this is the stuff
I was telling you about.
"Deep South Glass."
Oh, yes. Let's.
What's the matter?
Oh, my God.
Do we know...
Mo'?
Mel?
Wow. Look at these.
It's what happens to sand
when it's struck by lightning.
She's pulling your dick.
No, really.
I've seen it.
You just have to dig it up.
Huh.
Oh, hey, Bryant.
Friend of yours?
Hey.
I saw him first.
I, uh...
think he's already taken.
I, um...
I tried to call you
a couple of times.
Listen, since you're here,
you and your friends should,
you know, look around,
and have some lunch.
Y'all should sit
on the deck. It's nice.
Jake...
Come on, Bryant,
let's, uh...
let's leave this lady alone.
Come on.
Come on, boy.
Yes, sir.
Can we help you?
l-I'm... I'm looking
for a Melanie Carmichael.
Anybody here
recognize that name?
Man: No.
What business
you got with her?
I'm afraid
that's a private matter.
[Chuckles]
Well, then, I'm afraid
we can't help you.
Damn reporters.
Like the first ant
at a picnic.
Mm-hmm.
Now... this one here's
from Louisiana.
See? It's got
a little alligator on top.
How sweet. I can see where
your daughter gets her taste.
Ohh.
[Chuckling]
[Sighs]
This is one of those disasters
waiting to happen.
You know, one of the big ones
that only cockroaches survive.
It's going to be fine.
[Sighs]
[Insect buzzing]
[Buzzing stops]
One down...
7 million to go.
Careful.
You just smashed
the state bird of Alabama.
...Ohh!
...[Laughs]
Pearl? Oh, Pearl.
Hi!
...Well, finally.
...Hi! How are you?!
...Hey, buddy.
...Hello, sir.
Well, I can see
why Melanie is so adorable.
...I'm so happy to be here.
...Hey!
[Groaning]
Hi, Earl.
[Laughing]
We're so happy
to have you here.
I'm sorry the place is
such a mess, Mrs. Hennings...
Mayor... ma'am!
No, no, no, no, no...
don't you dare. It's "Kate."
You know, I've been
tryin' to get Earl
to weed these shrubberies
and repaint the trim.
And... oh, my God,
Iook how pretty she is,
Earl.
Yeah, I'll bet Kate
could use a drink.
Kate could, indeed.
...[Chuckling]
...Well, just come right on in.
I've got some fried pickles,
...hot right out of the grease.
...Yum!
Kate: . . Had a lot of trouble
getting my house painted, too.
Oh, well...
i-it's a lovely chair,
Earl.
Earl: Yeah, but to get
the full effect,
you got to pull
this here handle.
Daddy, no!
Earl: Now, you hold onto
your drink, Kate, and watch.
...Aah!
...[Clicking, springs boing]
[Indistinct shouting]
...We're so sorry, Kate!
...We'll get you up.
# He's gonna marry me #
# And we're gonna go to town #
# We're gonna buy
some real good car #
# And we're
gonna drive around #
# We'll hold hands,
touch, and hug #
# He talks so sweet to me #
# 'Cause he knows a lot
about love and stuff #
# And he's gonna marry me #
Name?
Uh, Buford...
Wallace Buford.
I'm not on that list,
but I've got some urgent
business with the bride.
Not today, you don't.
Trooper?
All right, sir, let's get it
turned around here.
# Yeah, he's gonna kiss me
on the mouth #
# And he's #
# Gonna marry #
# Me-e-e #
[Birds chirping]
[Clanging]
[Thunder rumbling]
Hey...
there's a weddin'
goin' on.
Yeah, I heard mention of it
a time or two.
I sure hope
this weather cooperates.
It's supposed to be
a big one.
...[Clanging]
...You know, Jake...
You're my only son...
and I love you,
but sometimes...
you are too much
like your daddy.
She made her decision,
Mama.
For somebody who's been holdin'
onto somethin' so hard,
you're pretty quick
to let it go.
You know,
I can't control her
any more than
I can control the weather.
It's just nerves.
You're doin'
the right thing.
Am I?
When I married
your daddy...
oh, Lord, but I was
a fool for that man.
I couldn't put one foot
in front of the other.
I remember standin' there,
thinkin',
"Oh, preacher, hurry up
before he changes his mind."
[Laughing]
Look where it got me.
[Inhales deeply]
Sometimes
that man makes me so mad,
I could just wring his neck.
But you still love him.
God knows I do.
[Laughing]
And only he knows why.
Mama... I think I...
He can give you a life
that we never dreamed of.
And he adores you.
[Thunder rumbling]
He does, doesn't he?
[Rumbling continues]
["Here Comes the Bride" plays]
Well, even if he is a Yankee,
at least he's sober.
Buford: Ms. Carmichael!
...Man: Hey!
...Ms. Carmichael!
...Get him!
Get back here!
Uh!
Uh, uh, uh, uh! Aah!
...Ugh!
...[Guests gasping]
...Ms. Carmichael!
...[Indistinct conversations]
Mr. Buford?
Ugh!
Get your hands off me!
Wait! Let him go.
Melanie?
[Breathlessly]
You are one hard woman
to get in touch with.
[Rumbling continues]
Mr. Buford,
he signed the papers.
What are you doing here?
He did... you didn't.
What?
You mean I'm still married?
[Guests murmur]
Well,
not unless you want to be.
Oh, for God's sakes,
Melanie.
I thought
you took care of this.
It's an honest mistake,
Andrew.
Well, then, can we fix it
before we all get soaked?
Does anybody have a pen?
[Indistinct conversations]
...Mom?
...Oh, yeah, sure.
Man:
Go on, check your purse.
Darlin'...
[Clears throat]
These things don't
just happen, you know.
[Sighs]
Can't ride two horses
with one ass, sugar bean.
[Thunder rumbling]
[Sighs]
Andrew...
You don't want
to marry me.
I don't?
No.
No, you don't...
not really.
[Sighs]
[Voice breaking]
You see, the truth is...
I gave my heart away
a long time ago...
My whole heart...
and I never really
got it back.
And l-I don't even know
what else to say,
but I'm sorry.
I can't marry you.
[Guests murmur]
And you shouldn't want
to marry me.
Wow. [Chuckles]
So this
is what this feels like.
That's it?!
You're just gonna
let her humiliate you
with some bullshit
about an old husband?!
Yeah.
I think I am.
Excuse me.
[Thunder rumbling,
indistinct conversations]
...You...
...[Door closes]
In my entire life...
I have never met anyone
so manipulative,
so deceitful!
And I'm in politics!
[Sighs] I'm just
trying to be honest.
I will not allow
the future President
of the United States
to be dumped at the altar
by some psycho Daisy Mae!
You go after him,
you little bitch!
...[Guests murmur]
...Wait just a minute, missy.
Uh, there... there's no need
for name-callin', now.
Now, she spoke her piece,
and that's all there is to it.
Oh, go back
to your double-wide
and fry something.
[Guests gasp, murmur]
[Guests gasp]
Nobody talks
to my mama like that!
Praise the Lord!
The South has risen again!
Whoo-hoo!
[Cheers and applause]
Hey, y'all!
If you're friends of the bride,
stick around!
I'm gonna go find me
a groom!
[Cheers and applause]
[Rumbling continues]
[Clanging]
Hey, cowboy...
You owe me a dance.
Nice dress.
Where's your husband?
I'm lookin' at him.
Apparently,
you and I are still hitched.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell me
you came to New York?
I needed to make
somethin' of myself.
About done?
What is it
about you Southern girls?
You can't make
the right decisions
'til you tried
all the wrong ones?
At least I fight
for what I want.
Oh, what do you want,
Melanie?
I don't even think
you know.
You're the first boy
I ever kissed, Jake,
and I want you
to be the last.
Maybe you and I
had our chance.
Fine!
Have it your way,
you stubborn ass!
Oh! [Chuckles]
Whatcha want to be
married to me for, anyhow?
So I can kiss you
any time I want.
[Rumbling continues]
What the hell are you two
tryin' to do...
get yourselves killed?!
[Both laugh]
What seems to be
the trouble, officer?
I'm here to bring you in,
young lady!
What did she do
this time?
Well, the way I hear it,
seems she run out
on a perfectly good cake.
# Riot in the streets #
# The touch
beneath the sheets #
# It's only gonna make you
love me more #
# The cops, they got the guns #
# The night destroys the sun #
# It's only gonna make you
love me more #
Woman: You're gettin'
a little light-headed.
# This here world, well,
it was mine to take #
# Faith can keep you warm #
# But I'll teach you
how to shake #
# And I'll come to you
like a little girl #
Well, folks, look who finally
made it to their reception...
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mrs. And Mr. Jake Perry!
[Cheers and applause]
# Moonlight on the beach,
sweet amphetamines #
# It's only gonna make you
love me more #
# This here world, well #
# It was mine to take #
You might want to keep those
for the honeymoon.
# And I'll come to you
like a little girl #
Speech! Speech!
[Barking]
Well... I do believe I owe
this lady a dance.
You sure do!
[Barking]
...[Indistinct shouting]
...Come on!
[Barking]
...Shut up, Bryant.
[Groans]
Look at this.
Hey, Stella...
Make it a slow one.
[Chuckles]
[Introduction to
"Sweet Home Alabama" plays]
[Whistling,
cheers and applause]
...# Wheels #
...# Big wheels keep on turnin' #
# Carry me home to see my kin #
...# Singin' songs
about the Southland #
...[Cheers and applause]
...All right, wait.
# I miss Alabamy once again #
# And I think it's a sin #
Woman: Hi!
# I heard Mr. Young
sing about her #
# I heard ole Neil
put her down #
How are you?
# I hope Neil Young
will remember #
# A Southern man don't need him
around anyhow #
# Sweet home Alabama #
# Where the skies are so blue #
# Lord, I'm comin' home
to you #
# Ohh #
All right,
just stand right here.
# You don't got to be
from down here #
# To get along just fine #
# Bein' silent
is a state of mind #
# Sweet home Alabama #
# Oh, so sweet #
# Where the skies are so blue #
# So blue #
# Sweet home Alabama #
# Sweet home, oh, yeah #
# Oh, my sweet home # #
[Intro to Shannon McNally's
"Now That I Know" plays]
# Now that I know what I know #
# I know I'll always love you #
# Now that I see what I see #
# I see it'll always be #
# Now that I got what I got #
# I know I had it all along #
# Midweek, mornin' time #
# I wake up next to you #
# With your head on my pillow #
# And your arms around me #
# Oh, baby, it's so warm #
# And I've looked
all around #
# Seen nothin' but big mouths
with somethin' to prove #
# They've never come close
to havin' anything on you #
# No, babe, not even close #
# Still
I lay here thinkin' 'bout #
# The way
I thought it would be #
# But all my plannin' aside #
# Now that I know what I know #
# Yeah! #
...# Now that I see what I see #
...# Now that I know, whoa #
# Who-a-a-a-a #
# Now that I know #
# Now that I know what I know #
# Now that I see what I see #
# Now that I got what I got # #
[Introduction to SHeDAIS Y's
"Mine All Mine" plays]
# He-e-e-y #
# The sun kisses
the windowsill #
# And I am still #
# On my second cup
of pity me #
# Yeah #
# It's been a long night
chasing ghosts #
# But at the most #
# It's been a rude awakening #
# That all too late
I finally see #
# I finally see #
# I see that it's #
# My loss #
# My lonely #
# My mistake #
# Mine only #
# Mine all #
...# Mine all mine #
...# Mine #
# Ohh #
# And it's my bad #
# My broken #
# All my should have's
left unspoken #
# Mine all #
# Mine #
# Always thought
I'd get to sorry #
# But the chance
has come and gone #
# So if it finds
its way back in #
# I'll hold on, hold on #
# Hold o-o-on #
...# My loss #
...# It's my loss #
...# My lonely #
...# It's my lonely #
# My mistake #
# Mine only #
# Mine all #
...# Mi-i-i-i-ne #
...# All mine #
...# Yeah, it's mine all mine #
...# Mine, all mine #