Pretty windy out
That better not be the one
where you blow people up
It's not, Mom
Mm-hmm
Dad, look what I can do
I've been practicing
That's spectacular, kiddo
Cool
You're inside out
Oh... I knew that
Doesn't work for you?
Can't believe you taught him that
I didn't... He did it on his own
Charlie, did you brush your teeth?
- Yes
- Charlie...
I brushed them
Let me see
Look at this, Con...
Let's go. I'm serious
You're driving me bonkers, Mom...
Let's go
Con, remember when we
were gonna buy Omnidel
you said no?
You remember what
the price was?
Uh, 1.50 $
Close. 61 $
I'll do it, Mom
No, I'm gonna do it
You know what it's
going for now, Con?
- Say, "e"
- Eeeee
Guess, Con
Edward, I don't know, all right?
All right, now rinse
74 $
Really rinse. And pee
I should've bought it. Shit
So buy some
Too late, Con. Too late
Lift the seat, honey
Don't forget to put it down!
When you finish...
Do you really need all that stuff?
Mom... no one wears these dorky hats
Well, you do, and you're not a dork
How do I look?
Very handsome
Love you... Ok. Come on, let's go!
Whoa. Jesus!
Come on
Whoa!
Maybe you shouldn't go in today
I promised I'd do that
stuff for the auction...
And someone's got
a birthday coming up
Latrell Sprewell jersey, Mom
Don't forget
He's on the Yankees, right?
Mom...
You're driving me bonkers
You're driving him bonkers
Jesus...
...it's a holiday there
Well, I'll just keep talking
No, no, that's ok.
But in order to pick up...
Taxi!
Shit!
Taxi. Taxi!
Oh... Shit!
I'm so sorry!
- Oh, putanne! Mes bouquins!
- I'm so sorry
Putanne! Mes bouquins!
I'm sorry
I'll get your things
Aw, shit!
Taxi! Taxi!
My books! Putanne!...
I need a taxi!
Could you help me get a taxi?
Ok
I'll watch your books
- Thanks
- Thank you
Hey. Hey!
Hey!
Bad day for taxis
It's this horrible wind
Yeah. You shot down
there like a bullet!
If you flapped your arms,
you'd be home by now
I'll remember that next time
That's not good
I know
Listen, that's me up there...
the flower pot
I get you a band-aid, ok?
Hold on to something.
Don't blow away
Or... you can come on
up and clean it off, no?
Come on!
I'm not an ax murderer. I promise
Oh, shit
Fucking elevator
Ne marche pas jamais cet ascenseur!
Ascenseur de merde!
Allez! One more!
Pardon the mess
You a writer?
I'm a book dealer
Oh...
Uh... bathroom's right
down there, on the left
Go ahead
There's a medicine cabinet
You can sneak a peak
at my prescriptions
Hello
I made you some tea
Thank you
Do you box?
I used to... when I was young
Hmm
This is an amazing place
Uh-huh
Yeah, but it's not mine
No?
The owner is a friend, a sculptor
and he's living in Paris,
so... that's cool
We can stay here, me and my books
Hmm
Um, I... can I use your phone?
I have to call home
Oh, sure, sure. There's
a phone just behind you
Thank you
Gloria? Hi, it's me
Good, good
How's Charlie?
Hi, honey. How was
your day at school?
Yeah? What was the best part?
Guess what. Can you believe
that mommy missed her train?
Um...
Ice
Uh... about an hour
You should start your homework
No. I promise to tell you
all about it when I see you
I love you. Bye
That was my son Charlie
He's 8. He'll be 9 next week
I'm Paul Martel.
I'll be 28 in July
I'm Constance
And I'm late. I have to go
Before you go, take your book... no?
Oh, no, I... I couldn't. I don't...
Sure, you can
A souvenir
Go down there
You know, like before
Ok
Keep going...
Stop!
Now right
No. Right
Ok, now... the second
shelf from the top...
Take the fourth one
from the left
Got it?
Think so
Open to page 23
"Drink wine
This is life eternal
"This, all that youth
will give to you
"It is the season for wine
roses, and drunken friends
"Be happy for this moment
This moment... "
is your life"
I have to go
Thank you
Can you find your way out?
I hope so
That's my bedroom
It was nice meeting you, Constance
Hey, come back if you need more
books or... medical attention
A perfect 10 there!
Oh, my! Did you see that?
Hey, Glo, hey
That wouldn't be
the TV on, would it?
I was just turning it off
Sure you were
The wind knocked me down today, Glo
Oh, yeah? You all right?
Do you need anything?
Gross!
- Were you in a fight?
- No, just fell over
Does it hurt?
A little bit
Cool!
Where are you going?
To get the camera!
- Try this
- Thank you
What do you need a camera for?
It's for school.
We're doing blood and stuff
Ok, now look like it really hurts
- Ready?
- Yep
This'll be great
The wind blew her down...
She bled and everything
Everybody's hats blew off
Look who's the worid photographer
You ok?
Yeah... It took me
down like an old lady
- Honey...
- It's humiliating
Dad, look at the pictures
At least we got the evidence.
Anyone we can sue?
- Whoa!
- No
There was this nice
guy who helped me
It was like this, Dad. It was a twister
Dad, look!
It was like this. This is a tornado
He lived around there. He got me
some Band-Aids and put me in a taxi
Is he good-looking?
I feel sick
Did you do your homework, Charlie?
I can't. I don't know how to do it
Well, come on. I'll help you
You can help me with mine
Did you get his name? This guy?
You can send him a bottle a wine
Cheap wine
Con, stand there a second.
Con, wait a minute...
Just stay there a second. I'm just
trying to figure out how to do the...
The thing I can't
figure out is the, um...
...zoom thing here
There it is. Ok, hold on. Stay there
The zooming thingie... zooming in
Stay there. No, come on. I'm just
trying to figure this thing out
I want to see if it focuses...
Hold on. Come here
Cool. Very cool
So beautiful
If you only knew... Look at you
God, what a beauty
Something the matter?
Nothing
Nothing at all
Good
Come here
- This is really good
- No, it isn't. Go away
- Come here
- This is major
I think it really is zooming in
I found the zoom
Found it
Dad!
Mom!
Shit! Ok...
I can't sleep!
- That camera...
- Jesus!
I'll be back. I'll be back...
Don't fall asleep
It works!
Mom, are you nuts?
You forgot my lunch
I did not
It's by the door.
Come with me
What are you chew...
what are you chewing?
Nothing
Spit that out. What is that?
Oh...
That's lovely
- Mom?
- Yes?
I don't want to be a dumb bunny
Honey, it's a play
There's lots of other bunnies
It would be cool
to be a bunny
- You're bonkers, Mom
- That's what you tell me
- Love you
- Love you, too. What's that?
Oh. Thank you
Bye
Shit
Hi, this is Paul Martel
Leave a message after
the beep. Thanks.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
- Hello
- Hello!
You're... you're there
This is Connie Sumner
The one from the really windy day
Oh, that one!
How's the knee?
Did you ice it?
Yes, I iced it and
I elevated it and...
...you name it, I did it,
and it's much better and I...
And I... I just wanted to call and
I wanted to thank you and, um...
I wanted to ask for your address
because I wanted to
send you a bottle of...
- Where are you?
- What?
I said where are you?
I'm in Grand Central
It's really hard to hear you
Come and see me
What?
Yeah, take a break
I'll make you some coffee
Coffee...
Um...
Uh... ok
Ok
See you. Bye
Fuck
Ah, no permanent damage, I see
We take Medicaid, Blue Cross...
I'm uninsured
No, I'm afraid we don't
take charity cases here
It was a joke
Oh, look at this...
Jack London
First edition of "White Fang"
In the original dust jacket.
And you know what?
I got it for a buck & 50
What's it worth?
About 4,000 times more!
Those are in French
I took it in school
Ah. Uh... "Tu veux
enlever ton manteau?"
Do I want to take off something?
Um... your coat
Would you like to
take off your coat?
Yes, my coat...
Thank you
But I can't stay very long.
I have some errands I have to run
- I'll get the coffee
- Ok
Shit
It's in Braille
Braille
No, no. Braille.
He was French
Close your eyes
What?
"My mother makes me chicken"
"Her chicken makes me cough"
"I wish that when she made it"
"she took the feathers off"
It doesn't say that
I had better go
- Huh?
- I got to go
Uh... take care. Don't fall
Thanks for the coffee
You didn't drink it
Hi
Lindsay, hi
Ah, Connie...
- Let me buzz him
- Thanks
Hey, what a surprise
Look at you!
- Hi, Bill
Hi, Connie
Am I interrupting?
- No, no
- I was just leaving
All right, I'll, uh, I'll get you
the budget for those trucks later
All right. Thanks
Would you like a coffee?
No, thank you
Mmm
- Ah, that's nice
- Mmm. Mmm
You know, I didn't know
you were coming in today
I could've given you a ride
You're freezing. What is that?
Well, I was around the corner,
and I brought you a present
Wow. What's the occasión?
Nothing. I don't know
It's a medium, but
they said it runs large
Look at that!
You don't have to try it on
I'm the boss. I can do
whatever I want
What do you think?
Hold on just a second
Yeah?
Oh, all right, but
hold the other calls
You're busy. I'll go
- I'll go
- No. Sit. Sit. Sit
Hello, Henry...
Yeah, so what is this
suspensión problem?
No, I never received it
Well, all right.
Well, get it to me
Henry, this... No,
it's not good enough
I'm sitting here with 200
trucks that I can't use
All right. Well, set up a meeting
Yeah, and I want
Frank Burnbaum there
'Cause I don't feel
good about this guy
When I tell someone to do
something, I want it done
I'm sure you will
Anyway...
So, what else you up to?
- Auction
- Yeah?
Who'd you hit on?
The usual suspects...
Who?
- Bob Gaylord
- Bob?
You get a pledge out of Bob, they
should send you to the middle east
So, tell me...
What?
What do you think?
It's a keeper!
Jeez
Hello
Here I am again
I brought muffins
"Tu veux enlever ton manteau?"
What is this music?
You like it?
Yes
Do you want to dance?
Now?
Yeah
Ok
I have to warn you,
I tend to lead
Of course. You are American
You've done this before
Uh, what?
How many girlfriends
have you had?
Um... two
Really?
Would I lie to you?
I don't know, would you?
Your eyes are amazing,
you know that?
You should never shut them.
Not even at night
You should learn to sleep
with your eyes open
I'll work on that
Will you?
Hang on
I think this is a mistake
There's no such thing as a mistake
There's what you do
and what you don't do
I can't do this
I forgot my coat
I can't. I can't
What? What's wrong?
I can't. I don't know
how to do this
- This is wrong
- Hit me
I don't want to
Hit me
Say, Ed!
- Hey, Bob!
- Haven't seen you in a while
No. No. I've been
working late this week
How's the boy?
He's a pistol of a kid.
He's gonna have a birthday
- Really? How old?
- 9
So, uh, any major armed robberies?
No. No, not this week
Speaking of armed robberies...
...you better watch out for Connie
She's gonna get you to
sign over your mortgage
What do you mean?
Did she try to hit
on you for some money?
No
I thought she talked
to you about this...
...uh, school auction... or whatever
Not me
But I've been out of town. Maybe
she talked to Maggie about it
Yeah. Yeah, I guess I got it wrong
Anyway, we owe you a dinner
Yeah
He's out
Mmm
Can I get
you anything?
No. No, I'm fine. Thanks
Tough day?
Mmm, not really
How about you?
How was your day?
It was good
You know, the usual stuff
Sure you don't want anything?
No
Con?
Yeah?
Do you love me?
Of course I love you
What a silly question
I guess... I'm just feeling silly
I'll be up in a minute
Ok
Sorry
What are we doing here?
Having lunch
I shouldn't be doing this
What, you shouldn't be having lunch?
Not with you
I think we should leave
Listen...
see those guys over
there paying the check?
- Yes
- Ok
If the guy on the right pays,
we'll leave right now
If the guy on the left pays, we stay
And... I kiss you
No. No
No. No. No
Ah. Ah...
Hey, you're kidding me, man
I win
No
- C'est la vie!
- No
Don't do it. Don't
Room for two?
Of course
Nice music
What is it?
It's, um...
African, I think
I like it
Here
Let's go to bed.
Come on
Stay here with me
I'm cold
- Stay here
- I'm cold
Stay here with me
I'm cold
Come on, let's go
How about lunch today?
You free?
I have all this fund-raiser
stuff Auction things to pick up
We can do an early one, if you want
How about 12:00?
12:00?
Yeah
Will I be hungry at 12:00?
We could go in together
I'll wait for you
I'm not gonna be ready
to go for at least an hour
That's all right. I'll wait
- Oh, shit
What?
I just remembered...
I have a facial at 12:30
at Georgiana's today
Oh, well...
You gotta stay beautiful, right?
Georgiana's, huh?
Waste of money
Yeah, Manhattan
Uh, beauty salon called, uh, Georgina
Uh, yeah, right. Yes. Yes.
Georgiana's. That's right
Thank you
Hello, I'm calling to confirm
an appointment today, 12:30
Sumner. Connie Sumner.
S- u-m-n-e-r
Could she... could she
be down for another time?
No, thank you
Connie!
Connie! Connie...
- Tracy! Hi!
- Hi
I was gonna call you
That's what they all say when
I call about bunny costumes
You know Sally
from Planned Parenthood?
Hi. It's been a while
Well, too long. Too long
You look amazing
So where you headed?
Oh, I was just going to, um...
go look at some window
shades for the kitchen
Well, we're gonna go
and have coffee
Why don't you join us?
Oh, I'm gonna be late
For window shades?
Come on!
Ok. Ok
Hi, how are you?
I'm just going to make
a phone call
Sure
Mmm. She could have
used my cell phone
Hi, it's me
You're not gonna believe this...
I'm at the cafe
around the corner
Why do you have to introduce me
as Sally from Planned Parenthood?
What do you mean?
Well, it makes it sound like I'm
in New York handing out condoms
I'm stuck here
Will you wait for me?
Wait for me
...with the redhead.
Just can't take it
She has it the next
morning... all the time
Had to call Gloria, remind her...
to pick up the dry cleaning
when she gets Charlie
Never a dull moment
No. Charlie is so adorable
Thank you
I can't eat
I'll have a coffee
Well, I guess I'll have coffee, too
Excuse me again.
Ladies room
- God, she looks good
- Mm-hmm
Do you think she's had work?
Why would she have work?
She still looks gorgeous
That's when they're having it now
Early, before it all goes to shit
I have friends out there
You take me to the best places
Wait
Let me...
She's not like that.
She's really nice
Of course she is.
That makes it worse
She is nice, and she's sweet...
and her ass is in exactly
the same place it was
when she was in college
Are you taking tennis?
Oh, I wouldn't call
what I do taking tennis
- Ok
- There you are
I was beginning to worry
No, it's fine. I'm fine
We thought you were
abducted by that heartthrob
What heartthrob?
You didn't see him at the counter?
He was gorgeous
I miss everything
Your button's undone
Oh, thank you
That's him
I guess I could see the appeal
Well, if he looked at me twice,
I would be on my back in a second
Oh, you would not
Oh, I would so. Why not?
Well, a couple of reasons.
Adam for one, your kids for another
Well, you know, Tracy, they
wouldn't have to know about it
It could be just something
that I did for myself
You know, to... broaden my horizons
It'd be like taking a pottery class
Having an affair is nothing
like taking a pottery class
- Could be
- No. It would start out like that
And then, um, something would happen
Someone, uh, finds out,
or someone falls in love...
and it ends disastrously
They always end disastrously
Tracy!
No
When?
It was a long time ago
And it's the one thing in my
life I would undo if I could
Did you just fuck me
across the street?
Mm-hmm, I did
You know, we could end this
now, and no one would get hurt
Yeah?
I think if we ended
this now... I'd get hurt
So, no matter what,
someone get's hurt?
Maybe not
Maybe we'll get tired of each other
God, I hope I get tired of you
You're in my mind
You're the only thing in my
mind when I wake up every morning
You're in my brain
before I even open my eyes
What do you think of?
It depends
If it's a day when I don't know
if I'm going to get to see you
I'm anxious... thinking of excuses
to come into the city and see you
And the days you know we meet?
On those days...
I'm...
calm...
and... hating myself
Oh, God
This is what we have over here
And... I'll have it ready
for you this afternoon
That happens all the time...
Ed, what's up? It sounded important
I've heard you're talking
with Dunbar and Brinks...
a few other companies
Oh, yeah? Where'd you hear that?
Well, look, I mean, I
suppose they could be...
uh, wooing me,
if that's what you mean
Apparently a lot of people
are wooing you these days
Now, who's wooing who?
Whoa. Whoa. Wait.
What are you talking about?
So I talked
to some people. So what?
This is about loyalty, Bill
I'm letting you go
You'll have my
recommendation, if you need it
I have a family, Ed
You had a family here
Wait. Wait a minute. You're
telling me... about family?
Well, you don't know the
first goddamn thing about it!
Why don't you take a look at
your own fucking family, Ed?
Take a goddamn look at that
- Hi, Ed
- Frank
Thanks for coming
on such short notice
This is personal.
It's not business...
So you think about it
I don't know if you're gonna
want to get involved with this..
but I need someone I can trust
I want you to follow somebody
I...
I want you
to follow my wife
It's burning, Mom
What?
It's burning.
The chicken
Oh, shit!
Shit
It's boiling, Mom
It's boiling!
Thank you
Watch it. Watch it.
Watch it. Watch it
Chicken's a little dry. I'm sorry
It's fine
I have to go to Chicago tomorrow
For how long?
Not long. Probably
just a night
What time's your flight?
8:00
A. M.
Diane Dryer's son is
marrying Amy Lynne's daughter
I'm never getting married
Why not?
I hate giris
Well, you might change your mind
That happens sometimes
I won't
What?
I fired Bill Stone today
So that's what's
bothering you
Nothing's bothering me
Why did you fire him?
He's not accountable
What's accountable?
Is it, like, people who eat people?
No, no... that's a cannibal
Anyway, I can't
trust him anymore
So if you run into
Dolly, you'll know
Well, how are you gonna clean up the
area so pedestrians can get through?
What?!
I can't believe you!
What are you doing?
Shit!
Charlie...!
Come on!
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry
I', sorry
Honey, are you ok?
You must have been so worried, huh?
- Stop, Mom
- What?
- People can we see
- Ok
Hi, this is Paul Martel
Leave a message after
the beep. Thanks
Mom?
Honey...
You're supposed to be in bed
You're crying, Mom
Oh, honey...
mommy's just a little sad,
that's all
Come on, I'll take you to bed
Let's get you into bed
Don't be sad, Mom
Dad will be home tomorrow
His name is Paul Martel
He lives at 433 Mercer Street,
apartment 3
She sees him during the day
Usually goes around lunchtime
Stays about 2 hours,maybe 3
They go to the movies?
They did that day. Otherwise,
they're in his apartment
Pick up!
Hey. Hey, lady!
Forgot your keys
Wait!
Who is she?! Who is she?!
No!
Calm down!
Why are you doing this?
How many are there?
5? 10?
God, what am I?
The Monday one. What,
did I get my day wrong?
She's just a friend, ok?
Just a friend
You're a fuckin' liar
Me? I'm the liar?
I can't do this anymore
Fine. Go back to
your suburban carpool
Your tennis dress on your...
What are you doing?
Fuck you!
That'll make you happy
No
No, I can't
Paul, it's over
I can't!
I hate you. I hate you
I know
Stop it. I can't
You gonna fuck me?
- Huh?
- You want it?
Yeah, I want you to
Say it
- I want you to fuck me
- Say it
I want you to fuck me
Oh, thank you
Thank you very much
Thank you very much, indeed
Yes?
You're Paul Martel?
Yes
How old are you?
Who are you?
Edward Sumner
Connie's husband
May I...
may I come in?
Yeah. Sure
Would you like a drink?
Yeah. Why not?
I have scotch,
vodka... prune juice
Uh... vodka
Is it cold?
Yeah
I keep it in the freezer
So do I. At home
So tell me, how did you...
...meet my wife?
By accident
On the street
There was a wind storm,
she hooked her knee...
Oh... you're him
She told you about that?
Yes
How's it going?
Fine
Fine. I mean, ok
This is... this is where you meet?
Yes
She likes it?
Well, I guess.
She never complained
Do you stay in all the time,
or do you go out, too?
It depends. Sometimes,
yes, we go out
She likes that?
She...
...likes this neighborhood?
Oh, yeah
More exciting than
the suburbs, I guess
Do you know that we have
been married 11 years?
We have a son
Yeah, she told me
More?
Yes, please
He's the reason
that we left the city
Connie thought it
would be better for him
Oh. She told me it was your idea
You... talk about me?
Lot of books...
Yeah. Lot of buying and selling
Didn't know it did that
Where did you get this?
It was a gift
From her
Why would she do that?
I don't know...
Maybe... maybe she just
wanted to buy me something
She didn't buy this for you.
I gave it to her
I gave it to her...
What?
I gave it to her
I gave... I'm s...
I'm feeling sick. I can't...
You want some water?
I'm feeling sick.
I'm...
I don't...
I'm... I'm not well
I'm not feeling well
I'm not...
I'm not feeling...
God!
Hi, this is Paul Martel
Leave a message after
the beep. Thanks.
Hi, it's me
Listen...
I don't like saying this
to your machine, but...
...I have to end this
I just... I can't do it anymore
I can't live like this
I'm so tired of lying
and hurting my family
I'm sorry
Um, I hope... I
don't know what I hope
I'm... I'm sorry
Messages erased
Does that pinch?
No
Do you know your solo?
- Yep
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm
- Can I hear it?
You need a hand?
No
No, I'm fine
Thanks
...focus on the journey
for there will be those
who will love to see you fall
Catch a star from the sky
Let it sparkle in your eye
Set your sights above the crowd
Walk tall, dream loud
Take your mark and go
focus on the journey
Where were you?
You ok?
...who will love to see you fall
All along the way
hiding on the sidelines
they must be the ones
who have never dreamed at all
Catch a star from the sky
Let it sparkle in your eye
Set your sights above the crowd
Walk tall, dream loud
What's the sense in dreaming
if your dreams are small?
What's the sense in walking
if you don't walk tall?
Dream loud
You were spectacular.
You know that?
Mm-hmm
- Wasn't he great, Edward?
- Great
He was great, great
Really great
I have to help clean up
I'll come and kiss you good
night later when I get home, ok?
Sorry, Ed
It looks like I nailed you
It's all right, Jerry. It's ok
You'd better check to
see if this is gonna open
No, no, this is... this is fine
It's nothing.
It's nothing. It's fine
Did he dent you, Dad?
Yeah. Yes, he did. Yes, he did
Can we call
the cops, Dad?
You sure you don't
wanna check the trunk?
- We'll deal with it tomorrow
- It'll just take a second
No!
Oh, my God
Charlie...
look at your dad and
tell me what's wrong
What?
His shoes!
They're different colors
Honey, you look awful
What happened last night?
Did you sleep?
I got up and looked for you
Oh, I just, um...
got some air
Are you ok?
Yeah
Do you like it here, Connie?
What?
Of course I like it here
'Cause we don't have to stay here
We can... we can
move back to the city
Honey, what has gotten into you?
Are you ok?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine
I'm fine
Everybody's fine, and
we're not moving anywhere
The cops are here, Mom
What do they want?
I'm sure it's nothing
N.Y.P.D., Mom
Hello
- Mrs. Sumner
- Yes
Yeah, I'm detective Dean
This is detective Mirojnick...
...New York City
Police Department
Did something happen?
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, no. No. Uh...
do you know a Paul Martel?
Yes, um... not very well. Why?
Do you know where he is?
No. Um...
At home, I would imagine
Do you know
where he lives?
Soho, isn't it?
Your name and number
were found on his desk
Has he done
something wrong?
Well, we don't know. He's been
reported missing by his family
His wife doesn't know where he is
I didn't know
he was married
Separated
When did you see him last?
I don't know... It's hard to say
Um...
he's a book dealer. I...
I barely know him at all. I was
going to buy some books from him
And did you?
No, not yet
Has something happened to him?
I mean, do you think he's all right?
It's hard to say at this point
We're workin' on it
Anyway, thanks, uh...
thanks for your time
Thank you
I like these snow glass things
My boy has some of these
If you hear from Mr. Martel,
let us know
Certainly
Dad! The cops came
to our house today
Cops? What did they want?
Someone's missing... and they
have to check everyone, you know
Who was it?
Honey, sit up straight
I don't think
you know him
He's, uh... he sells books
I forget where I met him
Was it a bad guy, Mom?
So what did they, uh... why
did they wanna talk to you?
I guess... he had my name and number
Why... why would
he have your number?
I think I bought a book from him
Be careful. Be careful
Hey, Charlie
Hi, darlin'
Oh, I wish you lived closer
Lord, bless this food to our
use and us to thy service...
and help us to be ever
mindful of the needs of others
Amen
Edward!
All right!
I have a... I have a story
you don't know about Edward
He was at the club...
Hello, Mrs. Sumner
Sorry to bother you on the weekend
- I'm, uh... detective Dean
- Oh
This is detective Mirojnick, N.Y.P.D.
Ok
We were hoping to talk
to you for a few minutes
Uh, sure
Charlie, we're gonna go up
on the porch for a minute
Can I come?
No, sweetheart.
You stay out here
Play with Poppy.
We'll be right back
I don't know if
your wife mentioned
we was here about a
week and a half ago...
about Paul Martel
Yeah, that was the...
the man who was missing
Well, he's not missing anymore
His body was discovered last weekend
God, that's... that's terrible
Oh, my God
Do you recall where you met
Mr. Martel, Mrs. Sumner?
- I told you
- Uh, no, ma'am, you didn't
I'm sorry, um...
I can't remember
A fund-raiser, I think
Can you be more specific?
Juilliard
The music school
Yes, I know what Juilliard is
Oh, of course you do.
I'm sorry
Were you there, too, sir?
Yes, yes... I think I was
Well, maybe you met Mr. Martel
No, no, not that I remember
Maybe you'd recognize him
No, no. I never met him before
- Is that him?
- Yes, yes
You ever been
to his apartment?
No
No, I... I... I hardly knew him
I didn't even know why
he had my phone number
Maybe he liked you
Look, I think that's enough
So you've never been
to his apartment
Well, how 'bout, the neighborhood.
Did you hang out down there?
- No
- No, not often...
- ...or no, never
- Never
I can't remember the
last time I was in Soho
It was 4 weeks ago, actually
You got a parking ticket right
in front of Martel's apartment...
...4 weeks ago
Oh, that. Right
I... had coffee with
friends at a little place
I forgot
- It was Tracy and Sally
- Oh, yeah. Yes. Yeah
Look...
my wife has told you everything
she knows. So have I. So...
...if you don't mind, we'd
like to get back to our son
All right. Uh...
why don't I give you my card...
I have your card
Right
- Enjoy your weekend
- You, too
Sumner, please
Oh, my God
Hi, Connie
Hi, Tracy
I'm just picking up my
silk suit for tonight
I was thinking of wearing the black
I'm gonna give up the good row
Let someone else be
gorgeous for a change
So what should we bring aside
from our sparkling personalities?
How we doing?
Fine
You need help?
No
The white is not cold, so I'm
gonna put it in the freezer
Just remind me it's
in there, all right?
Most people drink red anyway
Oh, I love these things
Is there anyplace
you guys haven't been?
Mmm, the Rosenthals
got 795 for their place
In 2 days, they had 6 offers
Sealed bids. That's
what everyone's doing now
What do you think
this place is worth, Ed?
Oh, I don't know
You sell your house,
where do you go?
At those prices, Tahiti
Bangkok
Connie, where's
this one from?
Fiji
Oh, remember, Jeff, I asked
you to take me to Fiji?
Mmm
And then you took me to Hawaii?
We went fishing every single day...
What happened, Edward?
What did you do?
Did you hurt him?
Huh?
Edward?
Did you hurt him?
You did, didn't you?
Oh, Jesus, Edward
Talk to me
Tell me what you did
No, you tell me what you did
How you fucked him over
and over and over...
You lied to me...
over and over and over...
Edward, please...
No, you don't talk to me now
I gave everything...
...for this family
Everything...
Snd what did you do?
You threw it all away...
...like it was nothing
For what?
To a fucking kid!
You didn't think I'd know?
I wouldn't feel it?
I knew it from
the very first day
Because I know you, Connie
I know you, and I fuckin' hate you!
I didn't want to kill him.
I wanted to kill you!
Oh, my God
Edward... Oh, my God
Dear God
Mom, look what I did
Honey... that's ok
That's ok
I'm sorry, Mom
It's an accident
Everybody has accidents
Why aren't you
in bed, Mom?
I don't know
Charlie, look at me
I want you to know...
that I love you... more
than anything in the worid
And I want you to know
that your daddy and me both...
will always, always love you
No matter what, hmm?
- Ok?
- Ok
Come on, sweetie
Let's go fix up your bed
all nice and fresh, ok?
All right
>If you find this DO NOT OPEN
until our 25th anniversary
to my beautiful wife
the best part of every day
"You can come on up
and clean it off, no?"
"Come on! I'm not an
ax murderer. I promise"
"Thank you"
What are we gonna do?
I'm so scared
I'll turn myself in
No
No, we can get through this
We'll take it one day at a time
No one will know
We'll know
31, 3.500, 3.800, 4.000...
42, 45, 4.800...
We could disappear
We could raise some
money, sell everything...
and just leave the country
"Señorita"
Mexico
Why not?
We could get a little
house on the beach...
Take a different name...
People do it all the time
What do we tell Charlie?
Tell him it's an adventure
We could fish all day
We could learn to play the guitar...
And I would serenade
you to sleep every night
We'd just live the rest of
our lives on that beach...
...and then when we die, we
could just push out to sea
What do you think?
It sounds perfect
POLICE