"If anyone finds this...
it means that my plan didn't work...
and I'm already dead.
But, if I can somehow go back...
to the beginning of all of this,
I might be able...
to save her."
Evan!
We're gonna be late again.
Since when do you care
about getting to school on time?
They're putting up the pictures
for Parents' Night.
Don't worry.
We have plenty of time.
- Is dad gonna come?
- You know the answer to that.
Can't he just
come out for one day?
We've been over this a hundred times.
It's too dangerous for him.
But Lenny said his dad's coming.
And Tommy and Kayleigh's dad.
Okay, I get the point.
- But I'm not so bad, am I?
- No.
Okay. Have a great day.
I love you. I'll pick you up later.
I gotta go.
Bye!
- Mrs. Treborn, I need to talk to you.
- Can it be at night? I'm late for work.
I think you really
need to see this.
Tommy! Leave Lenny alone.
Don't make me send you to Mr. Voytek.
I was gonna show to the principal,
but I should talk to you first.
- What is it?
- Yesterday I had all the children...
make drawings about what they
wanted to be when they grew up.
Most of them made drawings of
what their parents did, but this...
I don't understand.
Evan did this?
- Can I keep this drawing?
- Of course.
There is one more thing, Mrs. Treborn.
I feel bad even mentioning.
- What?
- When I asked about the drawing...
well... he couldn't
remember doing it.
I don't wanna go!
I don't like this place, Mom.
It's creepy.
- I promise I won't make a bad picture.
- You're gonna be fine, okay?
He just wants to do a couple of tests,
that's all. You'll like him.
That's good.
You're doing great.
Just tell me he hasn't
inherited his father's illness.
Result will be negative.
But there's something else
you can do to monitor his memory.
- Anything.
- A journal.
- Have him write everything he does.
- What will that do?
It could help to jog his memory.
He can remember new things after.
The results will come back in a few
days, and we'll take it from there.
Okay.
Today Mommy is taking me
to play with Kayleigh and Tommy.
I'll meet their father and see
what a real dad is like.
Great.
See you soon.
Evan?
Evan.
What are you doing
with that knife?
What happened?
Honey...
what were you doing
with that knife?
I don't remember.
- Hey, Andrea.
- George.
Hello, little man.
Watch your step.
- Thanks, George.
- Not a problem.
Here's my number at the hospital,
in case there are any problems.
And, please,
keep an eye on him, 'cause...
Are you kidding? We're gonna have
a great time today, right, Sport?
Okay.
Be good, kiddo.
- I love you.
- Bye-bye.
Bye, George.
Go long, go on. Right in the
back yard. Here it comes!
Guess what? Dad got a new video
camera, we're all gonna be in a movie!
That's right, Evan.
And you'll get to be the star.
- I thought I was the star!
- Hey, what did I tell you?
Now, Evan, you have to promise...
your bestest super-duper promise
that this is gonna be our little secret.
Think you can do that?
- Where am I? Where did all go?
- Calm down, kid. Stand still.
I was just somewhere else!
How did I get here?
Quit act like a retard or I'll call
your mom to tell a shit you've been.
Kayleigh. Kayleigh.
What happened?
The good news is
the results are negative.
I found no evidence of lesions,
hemorrhaging, tumors.
- It must have something we can go on.
- Lf I was to guess...
...the blackouts are stress related.
- But he's 7 years old.
What kind of stress can he have?
Plenty. Maybe he has severe coping
problems about not having a father.
The last time the blackouts occurred
was visiting his friend's dad?
Well, he has been pushing me to meet
his father and I've putting it off.
It's worth a short, Andrea.
We can arrange a controlled meeting.
A careful dose of sedatives
for Jason, some security.
Evan comes in for a guick
visit and, with a little luck...
no more missing father complex.
April, 1 5th.
Today I get to meet my father.
His name is Jason...
and he's crazy.
I hope he lets me call him Dad.
- My dad lives here?
- Not in this wing, actually no.
If your dad seems a little sleepy,
that's because of the medicine, okay?
Okay.
It'll just be a moment, okay.
It's okay, I won't bite.
You've seen pictures of me, right?
Mom says I have your smile
and your hair and your...
He has to die!
It's the only way!
Jason, stop! No!
- It's gonna be okay. All right.
- Man, he's hurt bad.
Get a stretcher!
Come on, let's get him outta here.
In sure and certain hope of
the resurrection to eternal life...
we commend to the Almighty God
our brother Jason.
The Lord bless him and keep him.
The Lord make His face...
to shine upon him and
be gracious unto him...
and give him peace.
Amen.
Come on, where is it?
I know it's down here somewhere.
- Tommy, I'm bored. What's up?
- Yeah, what are you looking for?
Shut up lard ass. And you, hold your
fucking horses. It's here somewhere.
We should go soon.
If dad catches us smoking
down here, we're dead.
So, let's go.
I knew dad had a blockbuster here.
Lets blow the shit outta something!
Here you go, buddy.
- No way. I'm not touching this thing.
- The hell you aren't.
If we do it, you'll puss
out and narc for sure.
Ain't not gonna work this time.
Look how small this fuse is.
- I'll get killed.
- Not necessarily.
Here you go. It should
buy you 2 minutes at least.
Gee, thanks, friend.
For Christ sake, Lenny,
you moron. Just do it.
Thanks.
- You got balls, man.
- Sure took long enough.
What the hell!
Come on!
Evan, help me get him up!
- Get you ass back here and help me!
- What happened? Where are we?
- Oh my God, what did we do?
- Evan, come on, help me!
- Oh my God, how could we?
- Come on, let's go!
- Shit, what happened to you?
- He's fine, he's gonna be okay!
Everything is gonna be fine!
- What's wrong, why isn't he speaking?
- He's in shock, ma'am.
Lenny, how many
fingers am I holding up?
What is it?
What happened?
We were just in the woods building
a fort when Lenny freaked out.
One minute he was okay,
then he just froze up. Right, guys?
- What happened? I want the truth.
- I don't know. I don't remember.
Something must've happened!
Something set him off!
- I blacked out.
- Don't use the blackouts to get out.
You're not making it up?
Breathe in...
breathe out... and relax.
You are completely
asleep and relaxed.
I want you to take me to the time
you were in the woods with Lenny.
Think of it like a movie:
You can pause, rewind or
slow down any details you wish.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Where are you now?
I'm standing next to Kayleigh.
My hands are over her ears.
- Are you hurting her?
- No. I'm protecting her.
Okay. Now let's move forward
in time. What do you see?
I see a car.
Yes, Evan.
Tell me about the car.
Go on.
Nothing can hurt you.
Remember? It's only a movie.
You are completely safe.
I can't...
The car vanishes, all of a sudden,
I'm on the ground in the woods.
The car doesn't vanish, Evan.
The movie in your head is broken.
Now, tell me about the car.
I can't!
It's coming!
Fight it, Evan.
Hurry! It's coming!
- Oh, my God!
- On the count of 1 0 you'll wake up.
- Refreshed, remembering everything.
- What are you doing?
What is happening to him?
Make it stop!
1 , you are feeling awake.
2, your eyes are not that heavy.
5, 6...
- Come on, Evan, wake up! 9, 1 0!
- Wake him up!
Oh, God.
What happened?
Did it work?
Thanks, mom.
See you later.
Wipe that sad-ass look off your
face before you get us busted!
- See the way Evan's mom look at you?
- Sorry.
All right, someone can tell me what
the hell happened with the mailbox?
Don't ever bring this up again.
Not ever!
Let's go.
Are you okay?
Holy shit! Look that fat fuck! He's
got bigger titties than Lenny's mom!
Shut up, faggot.
No one is talking to you.
Sorry, Kayleigh.
This was a bad idea.
You really don't remember
anything that happened?
- You're so lucky.
- Look, everything is gonna be okay.
Lenny'll be fine.
You'll see.
- Sorry.
- It's not your fault.
Mrs. Kagan called dad and blamed
us for what happened to Lenny.
- Your dad did that?
- I deserve a lot worse.
What are you talking about? What you
deserve is better father and brother.
All they do is make
you feel like shit!
You really have no clue how
beautiful you are, do you?
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Buying popcorn. You?
- Whoops.
- I don't believe you did that!
- Why do you have to be such a dick?
- I don't know.
- You see how far he went.
- I don't believe.
Stop it!
Stop hitting him!
What's wrong with you?
- Somebody please help us!
- That's it, kid. You're outta here.
Get him away!
The peaceful town of Briarville
was rocked this afternoon...
in the wake of a horrible
act of vandalism.
While the police believe it was an
act of criminal mischief gone awry...
the tragedy has clearly
devastated the community.
Now this was the grisly aftermath
of as powerful explosion...
believed to have been caused by
an unknown guantity of dynamite.
Police has no leads,
no suspects and no motive for the...
Good night.
We're moving.
I can't believe Tommy's still pissed
at me. He knows I'm moving away?
He's been acting real strange lately.
He won't even look at me in the eyes.
Duck, here they come!
Did your mom say
if Lenny was okay?
He must be. I mean,
they're letting him out, right?
Welcome home. I thought you might
like some fresh air for a change.
- Is Tommy with you guys?
- No. It's cool.
So, what'd you do in there?
It was awful. You can't sleep 'cause
everybody is screaming all night.
I never want to go back.
- Do you see that?
- Yeah. What's up with the smoke?
Crockett!
What are you doing to my dog?
- Look what you make me do!
- What the hell's wrong with you?
Kayleigh! My God!
Come on! Please, wake up!
Why don't you fucking kiss her,
Prince Charming?
How long I was out?
Kayleigh, what's wrong?
I'm sorry.
- Aced it.
- And time! Put your pencils down.
And place your blue books on
my desk before you leave.
You too, Mr. Nelson.
We're all in the same time zone here.
- Fuck you!
- So, how'd you do, Evan?
I don't know. I might've
mixed up some of the stories.
Was it Pavlov that conditioned
his dog to lick his nuts?
Typical psych major:
A complete wise ass.
How's your project coming?
Still planning...
to change the way we humble
scientists view memory assimilation?
I don't really have a choice.
Oh, jeez. It smells like patchouli
and ass in here.
Cricket, this is my well-mannered
roommate, Evan.
Yeah.
You're the one that fucked up the
bell curve on my anthropology final.
- Bye.
- Fucking dick.
- Oh! Sweet girl, man.
- Found your shirt, bro.
You sick fuck.
All right man, get dressed.
You're taking me out.
- Why? Aced another midterm?
- No.
Better than that.
Seven years, no blackouts.
Fuck yeah, bro.
Let's do this! Come on!
Be gentle to me!
I'm post-coital!
Did she cradle the balls
and lick the shaft?
Nice.
Look at this fucking guy.
Get the fuck out of my bar.
Which one of you
has the pet worm?
- Worms. Plural.
- That's so gross.
Talk to him about it.
He's got the fetish.
Watch it. It's a psych project.
It's a study on memory loss.
Better explain before all this
excitement gives me a heart attack.
- Ten bucks he eats it off the floor.
- Well...
if I could figure out how the
memories of a simple worm function...
it should help me to
understand the complexities...
of the human brain.
Let me get this shot.
- What the fuck, weirdo?
- The fuck is this?
Well, I guess that's your game.
Smells like sex in here.
Yeah, Thumper had
a busy afternoon.
You're kidding.
He's so big.
Yeah? Well, I guess charisma
and eyeliner go a long way.
- You want a beer?
- Yeah.
You got any incense or
scented candles or something?
No. These are my...
Most guys tuck porn under their bed.
All you've got are comp books?
They're my journals.
I've been keeping them since I was 7.
Wow.
Read me something.
I ought to be getting something out
of this. That's all I got to say.
"It's like my mind refuses
to believe what I'm seeing.
Hearing Crockett make
those awful screams.
Just writing about it
gives me the shivers."
Come on. Go on.
"It was like Tommy was
possessed or something.
There was a hate
in his eyes that..."
Are you okay?
Where am I?
What the hell is going on?
- I can't get it open!
- Drop it...
or I'll slit your mother's
throat in her sleep.
I got him, Lenny!
Save Crockett!
Listen to me, Evan.
Listen to me good.
There's a million other sisters.
Why'd you have to fuck with mine?
It's okay.
It was just a dream.
- Didn't feel like a dream.
- Maybe because they never do.
So, Don Juan, you pass
out on all your dates?
Lenny? I've got a surprise for you.
You'll never gonna guess who's here.
It's me. Evan.
What are you working
on there? A model?
Look, I see that you're busy,
so I'll try to make this guick.
You remember that day at the
junkyard when we were kids?
I was just hoping you
could help me remember...
just any details about it, or...
- I couldn't cut the rope.
- Yeah.
That's good.
Anything else?
"Drop it or I'll slit your
mother's throat in her sleep!"
Jesus Christ.
It really happened.
Lenny, I...
"Make one peep and I swear
it'll be your last, motherfucker!"
"What I remember before the blackout
was hold my hands over her ears.
I think I was more focused on her
hands on mine than on the mailbox...
...across the street."
- Maybe it went out. Should we check?
- Yeah. You do that, Lenny.
Make one peep and I swear
it'll be your last, motherfucker.
How's my sweet girl?
How's my sweet girl? You need
a change, don't you honey?
You want to open it?
You open?
- My God!
- Holy shit! Run!
Fuck, Lenny! Come on!
- Lenny, come on!
- Come on, Lenny! Let's go!
Christ, man, fucking brutal.
- Hello.
- Hello? Who is this?
Mrs. Kagan, it's Evan Treborn.
I hope you know
how much you upset Lenny.
Yeah. I'm really
sorry about that.
It took me over an hour to
clean up the mess you made.
- Can I just talk to Lenny?
- Don't call here.
Mom!
I can't help it.
I'm so proud of you.
Did Da... Did Jason
get good grades?
He got "A"s without touching a book.
This area of his memory never failed.
Did he ever say that he, figured out
a way to recall his lost memories...
years after he blacked them
out in the first place?
- Why do you ask?
- I just figured he was a brain...
you'd think that he'd figure out a
way to remember stuff that he forgot.
When he was your age, almost exactly
your age come to think of it...
he said he figured out
a way to remember his past.
I couldn't tell if they were real
memories or just his imagination.
Then, just before
it got so bad...
he had to be institutionalized,
he said he could...
What?
- What did he do?
- Forget it. It's nothing.
He was far too sick by then.
"I never wanted to be
in the movie anyway.
And it was cold,
so I wanted to wear my clothes.
- Mr. Miller took my shirt off."
- What the fuck are you doing?
- I need guiet for this.
- Are you stupid or what, man?
Maybe there is a reason you repressed
some pervert in your tighty whities.
I'd think twice. You could wake
up more fucked up than now.
More fucked up than I am. You
think you know me? I don't know me.
No, it's my fault.
I'm fine.
Can we get through one damn day
without you breaking something?
Evan?
Oh, my God,
it's been a long time.
How've you been?
- Same old same old, you know.
- No, I don't know.
Fill me in.
Well, I'm going to State now.
It's going good. My mom's good.
- Want a smoke?
- No. Not since we were kids.
I've guit, like, a hundred times.
Are you walking home, or...?
- Can I walk you?
- Sure.
- My God.
- So...
how's Tommy?
They kept him in juvy for while. Now
he's working over at Dale's Auto Body.
That's good.
- Still living with your dad?
- No. I emancipated myself at 1 5.
- Must've taken a lot of courage.
- Not if you remember my dad.
Couldn't you have moved in
with your with your mom?
Nah, she had a new family.
Wasn't enough room. Whatever.
Well, look, the reason I came back
to town was to talk to you.
To me?
Why?
Well...
remember when we were kids and
I used to have those blackouts?
Yeah, of course.
Well, some of those memories
have been coming back to me.
And I wanted to talk to you
about one of them in particular.
Well, I'll try to remember.
When we were kids,
your dad was making a movie...
...about Robin Hood or something.
- What do you want to know, Evan?
Did he...?
- What happened in the basement?
- Look, it was a long time ago.
- I know.
- Is that why you came all the way?
To ask a lot of stupid
guestions about Robin Hood?
No.
I just think that something
really bad might've happened.
Is there a point to any of this?
Whatever happened,
it wasn't our fault.
We were kids. There was nothing
that we could do to deserve...
Just shut up, Evan!
You're wasting your breath.
You can't hate yourself because
your dad's a twisted freak.
Who are you trying
to convince, Evan?
You come all the way to stir up my
shit because you have a bad memory?
Should I cry on your shoulder and
tell you everything's all better now?
Fuck you, Evan. Nothing's all better,
okay? Nothing ever gets better.
You know, if I was so wonderful,
Evan, why didn't you call me?
Why did you leave
me here to rot?
When he was your age, almost exactly
your age come to think of it...
he said he figured out
a way to remember his past.
- Some dude left a message for you.
- You can smell from the bathroom.
This is Professor Carter. Why you
didn't hand in your essay today?
I was a bit concerned.
Call me to schedule a makeup.
What'd you say to my sister,
motherfucker?
Last night she cried on the
phone for over an hour to me.
She said you came and
saw her last night. She...
she fucking killed
herself tonight.
She's dead.
And so are you.
If the scar on my stomach didn't
just come out of nowhere...
maybe my father wasn't as
crazy as everyone thought.
If I can make scars,
do I have the power to heal them?
What about Kayleigh's scars?
"I never wanted to be
in the movie anyway.
It was cold so I wanted
to wear my clothes...
but Mr. Miller...
took my shirt off."
Let's go down to the basement. It'll
look more like a dungeon down there.
A little light here.
- What I say about keeping that shut?
- But I want to see!
You'll see the back of my fist in two
seconds if you don't do what I tell.
Now, in this part of the story...
Robin Hood has just
married Maid Marian...
and they have to kiss and
stuff like the grownups do.
So take off your
clothes, Kayleigh.
Come on. Just like
when we take a bath.
Don't make a big deal
out of it. You too, Evan.
Come on, let's go. Let's go,
we're making a movie here.
Put your hands on your ears.
What time is it?
It's time for you to do
what I tell you to do.
Wrong answer, fuckbag. This is
the very moment of your reckoning.
In the next 30 seconds, you're
going to open up one of two doors.
The first door will forever
traumatize your own flesh and blood.
What? What's happening?
How are you doing this?
It'll change your daughter
from a beautiful child...
into an empty shell
whose only concept of trust...
was betrayed by her
sick pedophile father.
Ultimately,
it'll lead to her suicide.
- Nice work, daddy.
- Who are you?
Let's just say you're being
closely watched, George.
Your other option is
to treat Kayleigh like...
see, like a loving father treats his
daughter. Sound okay to you, Papa?
Listen close then, fuckbag.
You screw this up again...
I swear I'll castrate you.
What you need to do is
discipline your son, Tommy...
because the kid
is one sadistic pup.
One last thing.
Don't ever touch me again!
I won't.
Faster!
Crockett!
Kayleigh, I can't
believe you came!
I think you got one.
Check out our new house.
Honey, are you all right?
- My God, Evan, you're bleeding!
- Kayleigh. It's you.
Incredible.
Well, thanks. Go get cleaned
up and come back to bed.
- Where are my clothes?
- Those are your clothes, silly.
The bathroom's...?
Hurry up.
I want a guickie before school.
What?
Un-fucking-believable.
I wish I could get as
excited over a nose bleed.
Sorry, I didn't see you.
You're the girl that was with those
assholes throwing popcorn at Thumper.
What?
And your name is Gwen.
I know you.
Seriously, Evan, lay off the blow.
Don't freak out when
I ask you this...
but do you remember when
your dad got that video camera?
What's up, man?
I think he had it the first day and
then he gave it away or something.
Why would that freak me out?
I don't know.
- Just being weird.
- You are such a goofus.
- So I'll see you tonight.
- Okay.
- Come on, mom.
- Andrea...
- Evan...
- And Chuck aren't home right now!
You know what to do.
Hey, Mom, it's me.
And hey, Chuck.
I'm just calling to say hi.
Just give me a call back.
Thumper, do you know
what time it is, man?
What's the matter? You lost
your Rolex? Fuck you, frat boy!
Remember, there's only
two more weeks...
until your psych projects are due.
About that essay I missed last week.
We're still okay with the extension?
- And you are...?
- Evan. Treborn.
The answer's no, Mr. Treborn. Please
sit down. The exam is about to begin.
All right, settle down, everyone.
The exam will begin in one minute.
Get off me, asshole.
You guys started that shit.
Evan, you're hysterical.
Did you study for this?
- We'll find out, huh?
- Me neither.
- Holy shit. Are these the answers?
- Damn, Evan keep it on the DL.
I want to do something special
for Kayleigh tomorrow night...
so if I said that I needed some
help from you and the brothers...
I'd say, "Blow me."
Get the pledges to do it.
- Right. The pledges?
- Yeah.
You may begin now!
That was so good.
Oh, my God.
Where'd you learn
those new tricks?
It wasn't weird, was it?
Yeah, if you call
multiple orgasms weird...
Fuck them.
What do you think it is about us...
that makes us so perfect?
I mean...
why did you sneak out to
visit me after I moved away?
Because I missed you.
You think my dad could've
stopped me from seeing you?
What's he gonna do?
Oh, my Gosh, my toes are numb.
Do you think that we'll
be together forever?
That is a plan, isn't it?
- Hell or high water?
- Yeah.
That's...
I was just making sure.
Yeah. That's the plan.
All right.
All you rushes, you know
what you have to do for me.
Pledges.
We're pledges, sir.
Brother Evan, sir.
Are you kidding me?
What?
What'd you say to me?
You know what, give me the
Greek alphabet. Give it to me.
- Alpha, beta...
- Gamma, delta, epsilon, zeta...
eta, theta, iota, kappa, lambda,
mu, nu, xi, omicron, pi...
rho, sigma, tau, upsilon, phi, chi, psi,
omega, sir! Maybe that's what it is!
Don't fucking look at me!
Look down.
All right.
So, you pledges, you guys know
what you need to do for me.
Take a shower and if anyone gives
any trouble, tell I said it was ok.
What?
Shower up, bitch.
- Where are you taking me?
- I'm not telling.
Oh my God!
Wow. It's beautiful.
Go on. Sit down.
Thank you.
Why are you doing this for me?
When I woke up
this morning...
I saw your smile.
That smile.
And I knew that I wanted to spend
the rest of my life with you.
I've been looking all over for you.
Someone trashed your car.
What the...?
Who did this?
Who did it?
It was probably those
Beta fuckers!
How did somebody get away with this
right in front of the frat house?
- Dude, what is that, a dog collar?
- Tommy.
Don't.
He might be watching.
It's my fault. I should've told you
that he was released few weeks ago.
Might've been nice.
Like this will do any good.
Maybe one of the frat guys got a gun.
Evan! Don't even joke!
He's not gonna hurt you, okay?
He's just trying to scare
you away from me.
- He killed my dog. Remember?
- Evan, it's not his fault.
You know how bad he
had it when we were kids.
Oh, no. Don't give me
this bad upbringing shit.
- You turned out just fine.
- My father never laid a hand on me!
It's like that prick
saved it all for Tommy!
All right.
We'll let campus
security deal with it.
I think I should sleep alone.
No. You're not staying alone.
I'm staying with you.
Evan, I just don't want Tommy
to see us together right now.
No. I lost you once and
I'm not losing you again.
What do you mean? Evan, you never
lost me. What are you talking about?
God, you've been acting
so weird lately!
Look, my car just got wrecked, okay.
I'm kind of freaked out.
I know, but your accent's changed,
you don't even walk the same.
- I walk differently?
- I mean, that dinner tonight...
It was so beautiful,
it was gorgeous...
...but it just wasn't you.
- I can't do something nice for you?
Wait.
Isn't that your jacket?
Tommy!
- Stay away from us, you sick fuck.
- Get this "us" shit.
Like I'd ever lay a hand
on my own sister.
You've done real nice for yourself.
You got a nice life...
you got nice friends. Not to
mention you're fucking my sister.
- Not a bad piece of ass if I say so.
- Shut up, Tommy!
Oh, come on.
That's a compliment.
- What are you doing, man?
- It's not good the world loves you...
you got to take the only thing that
doesn't think I'm a piece of shit?
- Tommy, you know I love you.
- No one thinks you're a shit.
Oh, yeah? What was it you said?
I believe it was, "sick fuck"!
No! Tommy!
Stop! Stop!
- Oh, my God!
- Tommy...
Stop!
Oh my God!
- Stop it! You're going to kill him!
- He's a fucking maniac!
Don't do this,
I'm begging you!
You ruined Lenny's life!
You killed Crockett!
You killed that
woman and her baby!
Now you're trying to kill me!
You're trying to
fucking kill me!
Oh my God!
What did you do?
Drop the bat!
You, faggy!
First time?
Yeah.
Better not bitch out, man. You'll
wind up someone's luggage that way.
Can you protect me?
Jesus himself couldn't make me
stand up against the Brotherhood.
Look man...
when they come...
you go someplace else in your head.
Be somewhere else.
- Back your ass off!
- Move your ass.
Hey, yo!
Give me that.
I spoke to your lawyer...
and he says he's sure he can
get you off on self-defense.
- So if you're just patient...
- Mom...
...how long am I gonna be in here?
- I don't know.
These things take time.
What about the journals? Did you
bring the ones that I asked to?
I found these two.
- The others are still in storage.
- Mom!
I need them all.
All of them.
I'm going to get them to you, but now
you need to concentrate on the case.
Please.
Fine.
You're right.
What about Kayleigh?
Is she all right?
Try to tell her I'm sorry.
- Time's up.
- I'm not gonna lose you, kiddo.
Promise me you'll hang on.
Shit on my dick or
blood on my knife.
They're mine.
Back the fuck off!
Show's over, ladies.
- Get this maggot back to his cell.
- Move!
We'll be seeing you later
on tonight, little sister.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, Reece!
You're religious, Carlos.
Do you believe in that whole bit
"the Lord works in mysterious ways"?
Straight up, man.
Because I think Jesus sent me
to your cell for a reason.
For you to help me.
Shit. I knew you
were crazy, man.
I ain't bullshitting you.
Jesus speaks to me in my dreams.
Oh, yeah?
That's cool. Great.
Pack of smokes says
I can prove it to you.
When I'm out, I need you to watch
my hands and face closely.
- You need to see the prison shrink.
- Tell me if you see anything weird.
- Weirder than this?
- It could be marks, scars, anything.
"On Wednesday I got in trouble
for a drawing I didn't do.
Mommy won't let me see it."
Hey! No monkey business, Evan.
Sit down and finish your drawing.
That's great. Just imagine what
you want to be. There's no limits.
Oh, Mrs. Boswell?
Sweet Jesus! It's a miracle!
Look, it's stigmata, man!
- What'd you see? What'd it look like?
- Signs of Lord come out of nowhere!
Man, I thought you
were fucking crazy.
- So now you believe me?
- Straight up, man.
Want to make a deal?
All right, look. I'm new here,
but I think I get how things work.
You either join a
gang or you're dead.
Well, I sure as fuck ain't joining
up with no spics or niggers.
And I don't want to die.
So...
what do I got to do? I'm the new guy.
I got to work my way up so...
should I suck your dick now...
or...?
Is your blood pure?
Well, I ain't no fucking kike
if that's what you're asking me.
Well, then, let's see
what you got, honey.
- Watch the teeth or leave without.
- Yes, sir.
Come to Daddy.
Carlos!
"We took the woods so we wouldn't
bump into Tommy. No smoke yet."
Hold them! Hold them!
"We took the woods so we wouldn't
bump into Tommy. No smoke yet."
Rot in hell you
fucking animals!
Wait, before we...
we need something
to cut open the sack.
I want you to take this, Lenny.
Today's your day of atonement.
I know guilty you feel about
that woman and her baby.
- Evan, stop it. It's not the time.
- Now's the only time!
Today's your chance to redeem
yourself, to start over clean slate!
- What are you talking about?
- Evan, you're acting crazy.
Please! If you ever trusted
me before, trust me on this one!
Cut the rope.
Come on!
- Listen to me good, Evan.
- I'll do what you want.
You don't want me to see Kayleigh
again, fine. Just let Crockett go.
Besides, if you kill him now,
they'll stick you in juvy for sure!
And I know you'd never leave
your sister alone with your father.
Lenny, no!
My God, Lenny.
I said cut the rope!
It's all backwards.
Evan?
Who did this?
What the fuck, weirdo?
Lenny, no!
Wanna a ride?
Lenny.
Somebody call 91 1 !
Evan! Evan!
Fuck, Evan!
Hey, doc. What's the damage?
How much time do I got?
Cute, Evan.
It's a little complicated. I haven't
seen results like these before.
Not even with my father?
Well, actually they didn't
have these tests 20 years ago.
- So, what did you find?
- Most of the hemorrhaging is coming...
from the outer layer
of the cerebral cortex.
- That's where memories are stored.
- Thank you, Evan.
I've never seen anything like it. We
compared these to last year's ones...
we found severe hemorrhaging
and massive neural reconstruction.
- What does that mean for Evan?
- He's saying...
I've jammed 40 years worth of
memories into my head in a year.
It's overload city. I've completely
reprogrammed my brain. Isn't it, doc?
Yeah.
I'm going to wait in the car. Light
in here is kind of bugging my eyes.
It was good seeing you, doc.
It was very informative.
But, you know, I got people
to see, things to read...
It's me, Evan.
Can I get you anything?
What about some of those
model airplanes you like, huh?
I bet I can get a shitload of
model airplanes up in here.
Lenny!
You knew the whole time,
didn't you?
When you put that
shard in my hand...
you knew something big was
gonna happen. Didn't you?
Yeah.
- I knew.
- Then you should be where I am.
You should be where I am.
"Today I get to meet my father.
His name is Jason...
and he's crazy.
I hope he lets me call him Dad."
You ok? Because you looked like you
went somewhere else for a second.
I need some fast answers from you if
I'm ever going to fix what I've done.
I prayed this curse
would end with me.
It didn't. So now I need information
to make things right again...
...you're the one that can give it.
- There is no "right"!
You can't change who people are
without destroying who they were.
Who says you can't
make things better?
You can't play God, son!
It must end with me. Just by being
here you may be killing your mother.
Bullshit. I'll send you a postcard
when I made all perfect again.
No, no!
Just get out, did you?
Nothing. My brother did a stint in
the pen and he used to eat like that.
- I come from a big family.
- Well, I meant no offense.
None taken.
Is Kayleigh Miller
still working here?
Sorry, I never heard of her.
God! Can't a man get a little
goddamned peace in his own house?
- You're not selling cookies.
- Good guess, fuckbag.
Remember me? We had
a nice chat once when I was 7.
I got one guestion for you.
Where can I find your daughter?
I thought you were
someone else.
Make it fast,
I'm expecting someone.
It's good to see you.
Can I come in?
If I knew you were coming
I would have cleaned the sheets.
What do you want?
- Just to see a friendly face.
- Time is money, Evan.
Money.
Guess I can spare 1 0 minutes
for an old friend, right?
So how's tricks?
Sorry. Occupational humor.
I got it.
You can stop know.
Sorry. Does my line of work make
you uncomfortable, precious?
No. Just that you felt like
you had to use it to hurt me.
I've been where you've been.
- Where is that?
- You wouldn't believe if I told you.
I know people always say that, in
this case it's not even worth trying.
I knew I needed to find you.
So I went over to your dad's and
made him tell me where you were.
- Then I came here, the rest you know.
- You're right. I don't believe you.
I never thought you would.
That's why I never told a soul
until now and I never will again.
I'm the only person you've told?
That's a great line.
Does that make other girls wet?
Do they actually eat up that bullshit?
You know, I could give a shit
whether you believe me or not.
Frankly, I'm too tired
to prove it to you.
Oh, there's proof now, huh?
How else would I know that you
have twin moles on your inner thigh?
Anyone with $ 50 bucks
could tell you that.
Okay.
Forget that.
How about the fact that you prefer
the smell of skunk to flowers?
Or that you hate cilantro?
For some reason unknown to you,
it reminds you of your stepsister.
Or that when you have
an orgasm your toes go numb?
I'm sure all your
clientele know that.
Look, I just thought
you should know.
Know what?
That you were happy once.
With me.
You know, there's one
major hole in your story.
There's no way on this planet
I'd ever be in a fucking sorority!
- You were happy then.
- You crying?
- Sure you don't want your wallet?
- I don't need it where I'm going.
Are you off to change
everyone else's life again?
Maybe next you'll
pop up in a mansion...
while I end up in Tijuana
doing a donkey act.
You know what?
I'm over it.
Every time I try to help someone,
everything just goes to shit.
Well, don't give up now, slick.
You've already done so much for me!
Why don't you go back in time
and save Mrs. Halpern and her baby?
And then maybe Lenny wouldn't
freak out and ruin my family!
No! Go back to when I was 7...
and fuck me in front of
my daddy's video camera.
Straighten me out a bit.
You're on my bed!
Get out!
Buddy, I thought it'd be okay,
with you being sick and all!
I am not gonna say it again.
"What I remember before the blackout
was my hands over Kayleigh's ears.
I think I was more focused
on her hands on mine...
than on the mailbox
across the street."
Stay back!
Don't go near the mailbox!
- Idiot!
- Get the hell back!
I'll save you, lady!
Goddamn it! I thought
I told you two to get out?
Sorry, man, did we wake you?
No. It's cool.
It's really cool.
What the fuck is this?
- Please save his arm.
- Can you open up my locker?
- Happy Birthday!
- You wanna go now?
- Can I come too?
- Want me to move your popcorn?
Evan?
Get a towel! Get a towel!
Evan! Evan!
- Where you going?
- You ever notice Kayleigh's smile?
- Lenny is the best.
- You guys make a great couple.
You ever think that
I'll find someone?
Evan!
- Where are we going?
- We're taking you to the hospital.
- No! Take me back.
- I'm sorry, your mom would kill me!
You take me back, Lenny!
You owe me that much.
What are you geeks looking at? Must
be nice to be so goddamn perfect?
Fucking losers!
Lenny, help me!
God. Here.
Get him over.
Hey, Brian, how's your head feeling?
I saw that girl you went home with.
- She borrow your razor this morning?
- So bad!
Hey, there's Tommy.
Hey, Tommy! Tommy!
What's up, guys?
Hey, man.
I did what you said. We're pooling
our funds with the Hillel House...
Maybe I can spin my chair to a "Hava
Nagila" techno remix till I puke.
- Maybe we should get to class.
- What's the point of psych class now?
Tomorrow I could wake up
a dirt farmer in Bangladesh.
Let's go for a stroll.
- Yippee.
- Bye, sis. What's up with him?
So Tommy's really into
this Jesus freak thing, huh?
You know how spiritual he's gotten
since saved Mrs. Halpern and Katie.
He saved Mrs. Halpern?
Please. The twisted fuck.
Here. Why don't we sit right here.
Want a granola bar?
Here.
Yeah, I got to fix these
things or something.
Kayleigh...
do you ever think about us?
I mean, do you ever wonder...
if things might've been
different between us?
Sure, Evan.
You were the first person
I really ever cared about.
- I was?
- Yeah.
Yeah. That's why when I was little,
I never went to live with my mother.
- I don't get it.
- When my folks split up...
they gave me and Tommy the
choice who we wanted to live with.
And I couldn't stand my dad,
but I knew that...
if I went to move with my mom
I'd never see you again.
I didn't know that.
So, you still think
about us together?
Well, it's crossed my
mind from time to time.
And...?
Well, a lot of things
have crossed my mind.
I mean, I could play out the entire
movie of our lives in one second.
Boom. We fall in love,
we get married, we have kids...
our kids grow old,
as do we...
matching burial plots,
the whole thing.
It took a lot longer to
spit out than to imagine!
Things like that usually do.
So... do you think that
it might've worth?
Yeah.
I mean, but that's not
how things wound up.
I'm with Lenny.
Lenny is your friend...
And that's where it ends.
Well...
would it make a
difference if I told you...
that no one could possibly ever
love anyone as much as I love you?
I'm not saying that.
- Yeah.
- I'm just saying it, like...
if you were a girl would that be
something that you'll wanna hear.
Hold on one second, Lenny's calling.
I'll be right back, Ev, okay?
He's a little down.
He'll be all right.
You forgot to put the
toaster on the ledge.
Lenny likes Pop-Tarts.
You guys are all better now.
Man, I know it's hard,
but you can't give up.
- I can't even fucking kill myself.
- Don't talk like that.
I got to get you out of here.
Visiting hours are almost over.
Mom get transferred again?
What are you talking about?
She's been here the entire time.
Looking good, kiddo.
"Lung cancer." You started chain
smoking when I blew myself up.
Sorry, Mrs. T, he's been
acting out of sorts lately.
Mom, you're gonna be okay.
I can change it.
I'm going go down to the chapel.
You're acting...
just... like your father.
- I'm going to get you out of here.
- No.
You're not gonna hurt anymore.
I'm going to fix it.
No.
- Are you sure you even packed it?
- My mom packed it.
I think she sent
everything I ever owned.
- Is this it?
- Yeah.
- What's it for? I don't get you lately.
- Duly noted.
- I have to ask you one last favor.
- What?
Be guiet. I have to concentrate
to destroy the blockbuster.
- What? The blockbuster?
- Lf I hadn't blown off my arms...
my mom would have never started
smoking. Never mind. Just open it.
Turn it.
There.
"Today Mommy is taking me
to play with Kayleigh and Tommy.
I will meet their father and
see what a real dad is like."
Now, how do I
destroy the blockbuster?
Evan?
What are you doing
with that knife?
That didn't work.
You want to...?
Turn it.
Turn it. There.
"I never wanted to be
in the movie anyway.
I wanted to wear my clothes.
Mr. Miller took my shirt off."
And in this part of the story, Robin
Hood has just married Maid Marian...
and they have to kiss and
stuff like grownups do.
Wait.
I need my belt.
Don't even bother about a belt.
Back off, fuckbag. Amazing that
word never fails to impress you.
Easy does it, Evan.
Don't be a bad boy or I'll tell your
ma what a naughty little shit you are.
I'll tell child protective service of
your little kiddie porn endeavors.
One step closer and
I'll shove this up your ass.
- You could blow off your hands.
- Been there, done that.
- Sparkler.
- Kayleigh, no!
No! Kayleigh, no!
Hey, man?
Good, kiddo.
I've got no choice but to...
Evan, you'll have to live
somewhere else for a while.
I'm so sick of it!
I want my medication.
How do they treat you?
- Where are my goddamn books?
- We're not supposed to meet for...
...another hour.
- Where are my goddamn books?
Books?
My journals.
I need them.
So if you could give them to me,
it'll help a lot.
It hurts me to go through this again.
There are no journals.
There never were.
It's part of the fantasy created to
cope with the guilt of kill Kayleigh.
Think, Evan. Think!
You've created a disease
that does not exist.
Alternate universes with colleges
and prisons and paraplegia.
I want my journals now!
I know you got them!
You're going to give them to me!
You're not going to hide
them from me! I want them!
You remind me of your father.
He was always screaming for a photo
album even though he never had one.
I'm so sorry.
Photo album?
- Photos.
- Evan?
The damage is irreparable.
Frankly, I'm surprised he still
has use of his motor functions.
Mom?
Did you remember to bring those
home movies that we used to make?
Yeah, they're right here.
Good. Because I really
like to watch them.
So that's good.
I think it's best we transfer him to
Bellevue first thing in the morning.
"If anyone finds this...
it means that my
plan didn't work...
and I'm already dead."
He's not in his room.
Search the grounds!
"But if I can somehow
go back...
to the beginning
of all of this...
I might be able...
to save her."
Evan!
- Over here!
- Evan!
Evan!
- What's your name?
- Kayleigh.
This is Evan.
Evan!
Let me in!
Say hi. Go on
I hate you.
If you come near me again...
I'll kill you
and your whole damn family!
What happened, sweetie?
What's wrong?
Goodbye.
Sparkler.
Kayleigh, Tommy!
I missed you. I'll never let you
out of my sight again.
Like the sacrifices our parents
have made for us to be here today.
Good, Tommy!
Are you all right?
- Where's Kayleigh?
- Who's Kayleigh?
"Who's Kayleigh?"
- Want me to take you to the doctor?
- No.
No. I think everything's gonna
be all right this time.
You sure about this?
I know who I am. I don't need
a bunch of stuff to remind me.
I'm just running a little late.
I had to finish up with a patient.
Well, get the soup
or something.
All right.
Love you, Mom.