There is one kidnapping every 60 minutes
in Latin America.
70% ofthe victims do not survive.
?Si? ?Bueno?
Family is everything, no?
Now, do you love your son?
Si.
Now, do you understand?
You have a $10 million insurance policy.
I know that.
Follow these instructions
or God be with your child.
You will remove your shirt
and hold it out the window to ID the car.
Be professional.
Come alone.
!Porfavor!!Ayùdenme!
!Ayùdenme, porfavor!
EL PASO, TEXAS
US / MEXICO BORDER
Georgina! Obey me.
I will love you. Come on.
- That's how it works, huh?
- That's right.
She got a sister?
How's business?
The Japanese are here in a big way.
Cheap labour, factory space, but they feel
a lot safer living over the border in EI Paso.
I ferry them back and forth.
They think I'm John Wayne.
- I live like a king down here.
- Yes, you do.
- You been workin'?
- Yeah. No.
No. I've been movin' around. You know.
Colombia, a couple of places I can't name.
Nothin' catches my fancy.
You think God'll forgive us
for what we've done?
- No.
- You don't?
Me either.
- How long you stayin'?
- I don't know, I just... you know.
I wanted to see you, Ray,
see how you're doin'.
I just came by on impulse.
I could do with some impulse.
What happened?
Family paid the ransom, then they
sent the kid home after a couple of days.
Minus an ear, of course.
Now every mother in Mexico City
with money wants bigger bodyguards.
- My own wife included.
- I hate to break it to you, but she's right.
She's right.
Look, Sammy, all my clients
have kidnap and ransom insurance.
I have a policy.
AIG. My dad gave it to me.
Yeah, I know. I got it for your dad.
But what'll you do in 60 days when you can't
renew it because you have no bodyguard?
I know. I had to let Emilio go.
Well, you gotta please Lisa.
I mean, ass like that's hard to find.
Look.
A bodyguard's like anything else.
You get what you pay for, OK?
You could do this.
Get one that's got a decent résumé.
We're not lookin' for goddamn Superman,
right? Get someone cheap.
So you renew the policy, and then
fire the prick for whatever - incompetence.
All kidding aside, the most important thing
is that your daughter goes back to school,
and that your wife gets to save face.
This way you won't be the only
unprotected family in the neighbourhood.
That's right, a bodyguard.
Your Spanish is good enough.
- You're crazy.
- You even look the part.
In my state, I couldn't guard a corpse.
It's rich guys flashing their cash.
It's all for show. Nothing's gonna happen.
Yeah? You think they'd
hire a drunk, a has-been?
You have to keep it under control.
What ifthere was, you know... just, say,
a kidnapping attempt? What do I do then?
You do your best. They're not gonna be
paying you enough to perform miracles.
It's not exactly a scam, Crease.
Even at half speed, you're pretty damn good.
Yeah. A bodyguard's gotta
be close to people, though.
They talk all the time.
You know I'm no good at that.
You'll be the silent type.
They're gonna appreciate that.
Bodyguard. So who's the guy?
Samuel Ramos. He's a young guy.
- He owns one ofthe plants in Juàrez.
- Yeah?
The Jap car industry is in the toilet.
He's trying to persuade Ford
to partner with him.
I think he's in trouble.
His family lives in Mexico City.
He asked me if I knew anybody he could trust.
- And you thought of me?
- Yeah.
Take ajob, Crease. Breathe some air.
Then decide ifyou want to stick around.
Besides, I'm glad to see you, you know?
I got nobody to talk to down here.
Listen, my wife wants
someone presentable and polite.
You'll be the fifth candidate
she sees this week.
Your résumé's quite impressive.
16 years of military experience,
extensive counter-terrorism work.
I'm surprised anybody could afford you.
What's the catch?
I drink.
How does that affect you?
Coordination, reaction time.
Iftop professionals try to kidnap
your daughter, I'll do the best I can,
but the service will be on a par with the pay.
What if amateurs try it?
I'd probably kill 'em. Is that likely?
No.
No one is to know about your drinking.
That includes my wife.
Lisa!
My wife Lisa.
And this is John Creasy.
- You're an American.
- So are you.
It's all in there.
- Would you like a drink?
- Yes. Jack and water would be good.
Have you done much of
this kind ofwork before?
No, ma'am.
But he has a lot of experience
in related fields.
- Do you have a family, Mr Creasy?
- No.
Pita? Pita.
- Yes, Mom?
- Honey, this is Mr Creasy.
Buenas tardes, señor Creasy.
Mucho gusto en conocerle.
It's English, honey. Do you wanna
show Mr Creasy to his room?
- This way, Mr Creasy.
- OK.
Thank you.
Just like that?
I think it's nice that he's an American.
I think it's terrific. Are you sure?
Thank you.
I feel better now.
- !Hola, Bruno!
- Buenas tardes.
That's Bruno, the gardener.
And that's Maria, the cook.
- !Hola, Maria!
- Hola, Pita.
We fixed the room up two weeks ago.
It's nicer than before.
You've got a TV and a CD player.
What kind of music do you like, Mr Creasy?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
I don't know.
That's Bird. Emilio forgot
to take him when he left.
Emilio was my last bodyguard.
Have you protected
a lot of children before, Mr Creasy?
Creasy. You can call me Creasy.
And no, you're the first.
Creasy.
Bye, Creasy.
Bye, Bird.
- School tomorrow, Peeps.
- Does that mean we can get a dog?
Dad promised me one
when I went back to school.
Yeah, we'll see.
Ifyou get a dog, will you give up your bear?
You're getting too old for him.
- How did you like Mr Creasy?
- Creasy. He said to call him just Creasy.
- That isn't disrespectful, is it?
- No, not if he asked you.
Here. There you go.
He's like a bear, too.
- Yeah?
- A big, sad bear.
- Is he sad?
- I think. Or something.
Good night, honey.
Can you get me some floss in the morning?
- Floss?
- Yeah, the strawberry kind.
Sure.
Good night, Bear.
Creasy Bear.
- What's that one for?
- La Virgen de Guadalupe.
Business. For Toyota, for Ford.
If one dies, maybe she can
resurrect the other one. I don't know.
She likes him.
- What are you talkin' about?
- Creasy.
Pita likes him.
Pita loves school. Pita would love Count
Dracula if he took her back there, honey.
OK?
Hey. Are you OK?
- I don't know.
- OK?
I don't know, Lisa. I'm trying.
Come on, Bird.
That's right, that's right. Come on.
All right.
Home to Emilio.
You're home free, baby.
- Where are you from, Creasy?
- The US.
- I know, but which state?
- No state in particular.
- You can drive and talk at the same time.
- No, I can't, Pita, so please let me do myjob.
Are you going to stay?
My last bodyguard left. Somebody
gave him more money than we could.
I guess that makes me a bargain, then, huh?
Being black. Is that a positive or a negative
for a bodyguard in Mexico?
Time will tell.
There were 24 kidnappings in Mexico City
in the last six days.
- Four a day.
- Yeah? 24?
- 24. What do you think about that?
- I think you know more than you should.
Well, thank you.
- See you later.
- You have to sign.
- What?
- You have to sign in. Show them your ID.
- Buenos dias.
Come on.
Right there.
- Hola, Manuel.
- Hola, Pita.
- !Hola, Pita!
- !Hola!
Pita! It's so good to have you back.
Sister Anna,
this is my new bodyguard, Creasy.
- Sister Anna, the headmistress.
- Señor Creasy.
- Hurry. Class is about to begin. Go, go.
- Bye, Creasy.
Madre.
You must look after our Pita.
It is not good that she is late today.
I'm very sorry. I have to get used to
the routes. It won't happen again.
No offence, but I regret that
your profession needs to exist.
So do l, Madre, so do l.
Do you ever see the hand of God
in what you do?
No, not for a long time.
The Bible says, "Be not overcome of evil..."
"But overcome evil with good."
That's Romans Chapter 12 Verse 21.
I am the sheep that got lost, Madre.
When you were a kid, Creasy,
did you like school?
- I don't remember.
- You don't remember?
No, I don't remember.
No, I didn't like it.
Why not?
Because it wasn't a school like yours, Pita.
There was no Sister Anna.
Were you unhappy?
Being unhappy, that's a state of mind.
I really don't remember.
What happened to your hand?
- It's a birth defect.
- No, it's not.
Look, no more questions, OK?
- It really wasn't a question.
- It sounded like a question to me.
No, gracias. Gracias, no, no.
Listen to me.
I'm being paid to protect you.
No, no, no.
I'm being paid to be your bodyguard.
Look at me.
I'm not being paid to be your friend, but
to protect you. So no more questions, period.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes.
- No crying.
- I'm not crying.
Well, don't start.
You gotta understand, this is ajob.
In order for me to do myjob...
Wait a minute.
Yeah, come in.
Mr Creasy.
I just wanted to make sure
you have everything you need.
I'm fine, thanks.
Is the food all right?
Because Maria told me you didn't eat.
Yeah, the food is great.
I just wasn't that hungry tonight.
So you read the Bible?
Yeah, sometimes.
Does it help?
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Sure.
How are you doing with Pita?
Fine.
As soon as she figures out that
I'm not her new toy, it'll be fine.
- She told me about that.
- OK.
- You don't have children, do you?
- I told you I didn't.
Well, they can be tenacious
when they want something.
And Pitajust wants to be friends.
OK.
But you're paying me to protect her,
not to be her friend, right?
So...
Look, maybe this isn't gonna work out.
Maybe your husband should find
somebody that's a little more sociable.
No, you're right.
You're being paid to protect her.
And I'm confident that you'll do that.
I'll be coming with you tomorrow.
I hope that's all right.
You think God'll forgive us
for what we've done?
I'm tired of killin', Ray.
You think God'll forgive us
for what we've done?
In my state, I couldn't...
I couldn't guard a corpse.
They talk all the time.
You know I'm no good at that.
You know how they say...
a bullet always tells the truth?
Yeah?
- Hey.
- Crease.
What's wrong?
Hey, listen, you ever have
a 9mm round that didn't go off?
Yeah. Failure to fire.
I know, failure to fire and...
You know, I pulled the trigger
and click - nothing.
- You're talkin' about a bad primer.
- Yeah, yeah, but l...
Yeah, right. Dimple on the primer.
That may be...
Well, like we used to say...
a bullet always tells the truth.
Crease? You all right?
Yeah.
What were you shootin' at?
Yeah, I'm sorry, Ray. I'm sorry I woke you.
No, it's OK, it's nothin'. I was watchin' TV.
OK.
Pita, you have a pencil?
Thank you.
- It's hard to get used to the traffic down here.
- Yeah. I'm very sorry.
- See you, baby.
- See you later.
- Hey, don't forget your towel.
- Thank you.
Bye.
- You're a strong swimmer.
- I never win.
Thanks.
So, what do I do?
You're the fastest in the water,
the slowest offthe blocks.
What do you think that means?
What you gotta do?
- Get faster offthe blocks?
- Get faster offthe blocks.
- Our big swim meet is in three weeks.
- Yeah?
- I was gonna enter the 150 freestyle.
- You'll be fine. You'll be OK.
- I'll still be slow.
- You're not slow.
- I never finish better than third.
- Then maybe you are slow.
With us this evening we have
Mariana Guerrero from Reforma newspaper
to speak with us about the kidnappings.
Who are the ones responsible
for the kidnappings in Mexico?
It is an activity of organised crime.
It's not a random kidnapping.
They are not political kidnappings
like in Colombia.
!Vamos, Bird!
!Vamos!
How do you think he got out?
I let him go.
- It's better to be free, right?
- It's better for him.
Actually, he was driving me crazy.
Good night.
- See you in a couple of days, OK? I love you.
- Love you.
Be good. Come on, Lise.
All right, sweetheart,
so we'll call you from Detroit, OK?
- I love you.
- Love you.
- OK, bye.
- Señora, su café.
Gracias.
- OK, bye, honey. I love you!
- Love you.
I hate leaving her.
Concentrating?
Eyes are closed?
- What happened?
- I flinched.
The gunshot holds no fear. Say it.
- The gunshot holds no fear.
- The gunshot holds no fear! Say it!
- Louder!
- The gunshot holds no fear!
- That's good. You welcome the sound.
In fact, it's the sound that sets you free.
You are a prisoner on this block until
that sound sets you free. Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Are you ready? Are you set?
Creasy?
What's a concubine?
- Why do you ask?
- It's in my history book.
- It's like a wife, right?
- Yeah, yeah, it's...
Can I see that? It's kind of a wife.
Right there.
But the Emperor of China had 1,000 ofthem.
OK, like nowadays, in the West,
they have one husband for one wife.
But in the olden-time cultures they had,
you know, different... different rules.
Why? You feel sorry for the husband?
Yeah. Can you imagine my mom
multiplied by a thousand?
Creasy.
- You're smiling.
- What?
- You were smiling.
- No, I'm not.
- You were.
- No, I was not.
- You're not now, but you were.
- Youwere smiling. I wasn't.
- You were.
- When?
- Five seconds ago.
- I'm not smiling.
- Well, a second ago you were.
- You said five seconds ago. Now that's six.
- Ten seconds ago.
- Ten seconds ago I was smiling.
OK, in the next ten seconds,
we'll see who smiles first.
- You smiled already. See? You did.
- You.
No, that wasn't a... That was a smirk.
That's not a smile. A smirk is different. They
both start with S, but they're not the same...
- Do your homework.
- You were.
Bang!
Stop, stop, stop.
Come back, come back.
Bang!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Come here. Hurry up, hurry up.
Set.
Bang! Bang!
You don't flinch when you hear
the gunshot, understand?
Listen for the sound. You don't anticipate.
Concentrate on the sound. Understand me?
They're gaining on you. Go, go, go, go!
Stop, stop! Come on, get out. Let's go again.
?Yqué? ?Todo bien?
Las maletas, porfavor.
- Daddy!
- Come here, girl.
- I missed you so much.
- I missed you.
I got a surprise for you. Are you ready?
You got me a dog! You got me a dog!
- You bought me a dog! Oh, my gosh!
- What do you think?
Oh, my gosh.
Just what I wanted. What's his name?
- Sam. Like Dad.
- Come on, Sam! Come on, Sam!
State...
Bhutan. It's a Himalayan kingdom.
They were having some problems
with the royal family not long ago.
OK.
Any more questions?
- Do you have a girlfriend, Creasy?
- What? No. What kind of question is that?
- You're supposed to be studying history.
- It's Creasy history.
- No, ancient history.
- Who was your very first girlfriend?
- Nonya.
- Nonya?
Nonya business, that's who. OK?
Hi.
Tomorrow after you drop off Pita,
could you take me to get my hair done?
Yes, ma'am.
All right. Well, I'll...
I'll leave you to your history.
- Good night.
- Good night, honey.
- OK, now ask me.
- Ask you what?
Go, Pita! Go, go, go, go, go!
!Ràpido!!Ràpido!
Go, go, go, go, go!
!Bravo, Pita!
- 10.99.
- Yes!
- I'm tough, Creasy.
- No such thing as tough.
There's trained and there's untrained.
Now, which are you?
- Trained.
- Trained. OK, we'll go again.
- Here.
- Stand here near the finish line.
OK. Hey.
I'm a prisoner in the block
until the gunshot sets me free.
That's right. Don't smile, don't fool around
ifyou wanna win. Trained or untrained?
- Trained.
- Go.
- Señor Creasy, nice to see you.
- Good to see you, Madre.
Pita's parents are away on business in Juàrez.
Today, you are her father.
!Yla ganadora es Pita Ramos!
I won, Creasy! I won!
- OK.
- I won!
- Once upon a time, when we were young...
- When lwas young.
Well, when we were young
and he was younger,
and all heads turned our way,
we made a deal to take the world together.
Yeah, then one day I got a call,
and you said...
"I'm in love, I'm in love!"
"And I'm movin' to Mexico!"
And I said, "Huh?"
I said, "What happened to the plan?
What happened to it?"
- I said, "The plan's right here!"
- Yeah, yeah. And what'd I do?
I hung up. And then I met Alicia.
And then I went, "Now I got ya. I got ya."
I got it. Can I kiss her?
Absolutely.
Hey, what are you doin'?
- You got me.
- OK, I think now's as good a time as any.
I bought it with my own money.
Thank you.
Open it.
It's Saint Jude, the patron saint of lost causes.
Well deserved.
Thank you, Pita. It's beautiful.
You're welcome.
- Dad?
- Yes, sweetie?
- Can I talk to you?
- Yes.
I don't wanna play piano, I wanna swim.
It's not open for discussion, honey, OK?
Mr Lozzi's a very, very famous teacher.
If he accepts you as a student,
you're gonna play the piano. Sorry.
- Whatever.
- Baby.
- I love you.
- Love you.
- I just want what's best for you, you know?
- OK.
OK, honey.
Ifyou broke all my fingers,
then taped them back together,
I wouldn't be able to play piano,
but I could still swim.
Sam, get back.
Don't be a crybaby.
You're tougher than that.
Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
Remember the day you wanted the pencil?
- Yeah.
- I know why.
Yeah?
You wanted the licence number off ofthat car.
I wrote it down in my notebook.
I got it all but the last number.
I'll get it from you later. Can you belch?
Like burp. Can you burp?
- That's good. That's very good.
- I just had a Coke.
Listen to me. This famous teacher...
He teaches a lot of rich kids and plays
for the symphonies and all that, right?
Belch every few minutes
while you're practising.
You apologise to him, but you keep belching.
You'll offend every sensibility he has.
Very good. You'll be back in the pool
in 24 hours, I guarantee you.
Right, Sam?
- Hola.
- Lupita Ramos.
For you, Creasy.
Thank you.
- How does this look?
- Good. Good.
- Hola, Pita.
- Hola.
Come on in.
Bye.
- How long?
- One hour.
Gracias.
Pita...
!Pita! Porfavor, concéntrate.
Pita!
No te vas a callar.
Run!
Creasy!
Creasy. Creasy!
I can't...
John W Creasy is under arrest for the murder
oftwo officers ofthe Judicial Police.
Creasy!
This man, John W Creasy,
an American citizen,
is under arrest for the murder
oftwo officers ofthe Judicial Police
and is suspected of possible involvement
in the kidnapping of Lupita Martin Ramos.
Chief Ramirez...
The two officers who were killed.
Records show they were off duty at the time.
So why were they in uniform
and in a patrol car?
All I know is that they died bravely.
Of course,
but what exactly were they doing
at the scene ofthe kidnapping?
Or were they known
for their exceptional good luck?
They were known for being corrupt
and now are celebrated for being dead.
Excuse me.
Relax, OK? Relax, Sammy.
I know she's your little girl. When I
tell you everything's gonna be all right,
everything's gonna be all right.
Señor Ramos.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Victor Fuentes, Anti-Kidnapping Division,
Policia Judicial.
Excuse me. I'm Jordan Kalfus.
I'm the family attorney.
Speak slower, please.
My Russian is better than my English.
Well, I'm conducting the negotiations, and we
neither need nor want any police assistance.
We're gonna handle this thing ourselves.
Señor Ramos, two police officers were killed
during your daughter's abduction.
I have a written order from...
the Public Minister...
authorising our participation...
..."unofficially".
Ifyou want to speak to
Attorney General Diaz, it's on me.
OK.
The kidnapper will tell you
to deliver the money alone.
Porfavor, don't do that.
Or you will find yourself in a real
Mexican hell. No mariachi, no tequila...
and no Pita.
Crease?
Crease.
When I heard it was this hospital,
I was so pleased.
There is a pastry shop nearby. Delgado's.
They have the best pastries in Mexico.
Miguel Manzano. Director ofthe AFl.
And a former director of lnterpol, in Rome.
- And you are?
- A friend of his. Rayburn.
Rayburn.
?Hola?
Do you love your daughter, señor Ramos?
Yes. Yes.
- Do you want to see her again?
- Yes, I do.
Señor...
Ifyour daughter's life is
as important to you as it is to me,
you will do as I say.
Yes?
OK, yes.
Crease. You hear me?
You got four of 'em, all dead.
- Pita?
- It's...
It's been two days.
They're negotiating a ransom.
These things take time, Mr Creasy.
Crease.
Don't fuck with me, all right?
You have the ten million?
Do you have the money?
- Yes, we have the money.
- Now, ifyou do as I say,
the girl will be returned
exactly as she was taken.
But ifyou deviate
from the process in any way...
By the Virgin of Guadeloupe,
I swear you will never see her again.
I understand. Listen, I too
worship la Virgen de Guadalupe...
I ask ifyou understand.
Hello, sir. This is Mr Ramos's attorney.
He's going through a very difficult time,
but he understands.
Do you understand?
Repeat the drop instructions.
OK, the money, ten million US, will be divided
into two 15-gallon black canvas bags,
each containing five million, which
will be checked at the bank by the KR agent,
then driven to the house in an armoured car,
where it will be transferred to the delivery car.
You got a flat tyre here.
This is for you.
Hello. Yeah.
Listen, I need a driver to drive Samuel.
No. Why?
He's got a bad ticker.
He's got a heart condition.
Look, he's a nervous kid.
He doesn't respond well to stress.
All right, but the car will not be powerful.
Remove the trunk lid.
Use the maid's Valiant Acapulco.
You will arrive at La Diana fountain at 1am.
You will drive around the circle two times.
Samuel will remove his shirt
and hold it out the window to ID the car.
to ID the car.
There is a payphone on the southeast corner.
The phone will ring.
You will answer and wait for instructions.
There is a map on the top
ofthe phone. Follow it.
Perfecto.
Tranquilo. Si.
- What are you doing? He said no phones.
- Relax, relax.
I'm just trying to protect your daughter, OK?
What's goin' on?
Hospitals can be very dangerous places,
especially when you have
killed two corrupt cops.
Leave the money in the trunk ofthe white car
and return to your car.
Do not look back.
What's going on, guys?
Ambush!
Remember... I'm a professional.
Ifyou keep your word, I will keep mine.
- Hello?
- Mr Ramos.
You betrayed me. You killed my nephew.
You took my money.
Señor Ramos...
God be with your child.
All right. Get outta here, all ofyou.
Get the fuck out of my house!
OK, this is Lisa...
Martin Ramos. I'm Pita's mother.
And I'm very sorry for whatever happened
to your nephew, but I beg you...
Please don't harm my daughter.
This conversation is not being recorded.
You're negotiating directly with me.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
I wish we had talked sooner, señora.
I'm really sorry.
Now it is too late.
Fuck off! Get the fuck out
of my fucking house! Now!
Get out! Get out!
Hey, Ray. How are you...?
- Where am l?
- Well, it looks like a dog hospital.
Manzano was afraid
the cops were gonna kill ya.
How you doin', doc?
What's the matter?
She's dead, Crease.
It's a mess. Somebody
hijacked the drop and...
The kidnapper's nephew was killed,
so he killed Pita.
He has gunshot wounds
to the chest and the abdomen.
He has a collapsed lung
which we've re-inflated.
He's lucky to be alive.
If he doesn't rest, he will die.
How long will he be hospitalised?
Approximately a month.
No.
Did you recognise any ofthese men?
No. Does that make me a suspect?
No.
It would be convenient, but no.
Maybe you should show me pictures of some
Mexican cops. Maybe we'll get somewhere.
Those were all policemen.
Bad Judicial cops,
protected, by a brotherhood.
A brotherhood?
A brotherhood, called...
You all set?
- Right arm.
- Yeah.
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
Let's go.
- Somebody's on us.
- Yeah.
Lois Lane.
Mariana something, works for Reforma.
Newspaperjournalist.
I guess she thinks you're a scoop.
I'll get you up to the border.
A friend will take you to San Diego,
drop you at the Naval Hospital.
I'm not goin', Ray.
What are you gonna do?
Let's take a ride by the crime scene.
She can follow us.
Buenos dias.
Mr Creasy?
A lot of people are looking for you.
I'm Mariana Garcia Guerrero.
Reporter, for Reforma.
Nice to meet you.
I found this across the street.
Open it.
It's Santa Muerte. Death worship.
- They've put a curse on you.
- A little late.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm gonna get in my truck and leave.
I can help you.
There's a brotherhood called La Hermandad.
It protects government officials,
corrupt police and organised crime
at a level that is too difficult for me to reach.
OK.
And I think that you and Lupita Ramos
are victims ofthis organisation.
I want to expose them. Talk to me, give me
your story, and then I can help you. Please.
Help me do what?
You're gonna help me do what?
- You're a stranger here, no?
- That's right.
You're going to need friends
that know their way around.
OK.
OK, friend that's gonna help me.
Pleasure to meet you.
Tell your driver to keep his distance
next time. All right, friend?
Si.
- You'll be Stateside by supper time.
- I'm gonna need some help first, though.
You don't stop bleeding,
you won't last a day in your shape.
- Is that a yes or is that a no?
- Yeah! But...
- I'm done killing. I told you that.
- OK.
Anything else is yours.
- You're talkin' about war, Crease.
- Exactly. Can you help me?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Creasy?
What are you doin' here?
I came to get my stuff.
Couldn't find my Bible.
I thought it might be in here.
- I borrowed it.
- OK.
It's crazy, huh?
One week we're figuring out which
nightclub to go to, and the next thing I'm...
readin' the Bible.
It's a good thing. You hold on to it.
I keep thinkin' if only we hadn't...
It's like...
My whole life all I've ever thought about
was what I could get for myself.
Not my own baby.
She needed me so much, and sometimes
I felt like I had nothin' to give her.
Just... I don't know what to do.
- What are you gonna do?
- What I do best.
I'm gonna kill 'em.
Anyone that was involved, who profited
from it, anybody who opens their eyes at me.
You kill 'em all.
Yla Browning.
Reforma Newspaper
Mariana Guerrero,
tiene llamada telefonica. Pase a la cabina.
?Puedo usarsu teléfono?
- ?Hola?
- Yeah, it's me.
- Mr Creasy.
- I need the licence... No, excuse me.
I need the name and address of someone
whose licence number is C5TK8.
That's C5TK8.
I got everything but the last digit,
so I need ten possible matches.
And when do I find out which ofthe ten it is?
- Eventually.
- But where do I reach you?
I'll call you.
AGENCY FOR FEDERAL INVESTIGATION
MEXICO CITY
Do you know who he is?
Do you know what he's been doing
the last 16 years?
Counter-insurgency work in Thailand,
Pakistan...
Jordan, Angola, Lebanon.
Yes, I know all ofthat.
He's an assassin...
and you want to help him identify
the owner of a car for him?
He can go places we can't.
Ifyou don't want to use him... I will.
- Mariana...
- ?Si?
When do I get to sleep with you again?
We never sleep. We fuck.
Give it to me.
Gracias.
Ciao.
Maneja.
Jorge Gonzàlez.
I'm a Judicial Policeman.
Drive.
OK. Maneja.
What are you gonna do?
What I do best.
Anyone that was involved, who profited
from it, anybody who opens their eyes at me.
I'm gonna kill 'em.
Can you hear me?
My head hurts.
I am going to ask questions.
Ifyou don't answer fully and truthfully,
you will suffer much more than you have to.
I'm going to cut your fingers off.
One by one, if I have to.
This is to stop the bleeding.
OK? Ahora.
Don't mess with me.
?Sabes quién soyyo?
You know who I am?
A member of La Hermandad.
- ?Correcto?
- Correct.
OK.
!No mames!
!No me quemes, pendejo de mierda!
!Suelta!
- Chinga a tu madre, pinche pendejo.
- Yeah. Ytù. Ytù.
What do you want to know?
The Ramos kidnapping...
What went wrong at the drop?
No sé nada.
We were just ordered to take her.
That's all we did.
Ordered by who?
I don't know.
You don't know?
!No sé!!No sé!
We work in separate groups.
A voice calls.
We grab the target
and deliver it to the guardians.
The bosses never see the target,
theyjust make the deal.
!Eso es todo!
Who ordered it?
We call him "The Voice".
"The Voice." OK.
"The Voice", si.
The Voice.
The Voice. How do I find him?
You don't know?
Are you sure?
OK.
I believe you.
Tell me about the guardians.
I'm a professional.
I'm a professional. I just do myjob.
Tell me about the guardians.
- Guardianes.
- Guardianes, OK. Guardianes.
You don't know?
I don't know.
!No me mates, cabron!
!Ya déjame en paz, cabron!
He works the door at a rave in Neza.
He has a mark
on the left side of his face.
They call him "The Butcher".
Is he La Hermandad?
Yes, La Hermandad.
OK.
Wait, wait, wait.
Give me one cigarette, please, eh?
Si.
OK.
?Bueno?
OK, my friend.
It's offto the next life for you.
I guarantee you won't be lonely.
Revenge is a meal best served cold.
The Rave - Neza
Tell me about the girl.
I don't know her.
- !La niña!
- No.
!Vamos!
?Qué hay?
OK, OK. Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Tell me about the girl.
Do you know her?
No?
Hey, man, I heard you speaking Spanish
over there. You're American, right?
- And so are you.
- Yeah.
- Get outta here. Where you from?
- New Jersey.
New Jersey? I'm from New Jersey.
All right, listen to me.
Tell me how it works. The whole thing.
Tell me how it works.
All right, everything is done by cellphone.
You just wait around for calls.
We don't even have a fuckin' number.
- Who pays you?
- We got an ATM card.
We take out 200 fuckin' measly dollars
every two weeks.
- 200 dollars?
- Yeah.
- OK. What's the PIN number?
- The what?
- The PIN number, code number.
- Yeah, it's 4747.
- Yeah.
- Good.
- You wouldn't lie to me?
- I'm not lyin'.
- You didn't kill her, did you?
- No.
Don't lie to me!
- Don't lie to me! Did you kill her?
- You're makin' me fuckin' nervous.
- Did you kill her?
- No! The fuckin' boss did, or his brother.
Who's the boss?
- We never see his face.
- You're lyin' to me.
I'm tellin' you the truth!
Who? You never seen whose face?
Well, we were in the other room.
And he was yellin' at the girl cos his nephew
got killed and the money got stolen.
- Wait. Somebody stole what money?
- The ransom money at the drop.
- Who stole it?
- He said some fuckin' crooked cop took it.
- Who?
- Fuentes.
- Fuentes?
- Yeah, that's him.
All right?
- Jersey boy?
- Yeah.
- This Fuentes guy...
- Yeah?
He's a lieutenant
for the Anti-Kidnapping Division.
- Fuentes is?
- Yeah.
- What'd you do?
- Oh, man.
Tell me about the girl. What did you do?
- I just do what they tell me.
- You do what they tell you to do?
Did you say goodbye to her?
Answer. Did you say goodbye to her?
- No!
- You didn't?
- Here's your chance. Say goodbye.
- Oh, shit.
Say goodbye to her. Say goodbye to her.
Motherfucker, let me go!
?Hijo?
They threw the little girl against the wall.
She wasn't moving.
They threw her body in the trunk ofthe car,
and then they drove away.
Who? Who? Who's they?
The boss's brother.
I recognised his voice.
OK. OK.
Now listen to me.
Ifyou tell me where to find the boss,
I'll let you live.
But I don't know.
I'll give you the girl.
What girl?
The girl...
Do you want the girl?
Yes, yes, but what girl?
What are you saying?
- The girl.
- Here?
Si.
You sure?
Show me.
- Si. Guerrero.
- Listen, it's me.
Do you know about a young girl being
kidnapped recently, about 12 years old?
- Yes, last night. Do you know something?
- What's her name?
Camila. Camila Valencias.
- ?Camila? ?Se llama Camila?
- Si.
- I got her.
- Where are you?
- Creasy, what happened?
- It's OK. Sit down, relax.
- Camila, ?estàs bien?
- She's OK, she's OK.
You got banking connections?
Yes, I have connections.
PIN number's 4747. I wanna find out
who's puttin' money in that account.
4747.
What do you know
about a cop named Fuentes?
He's with the Anti-Kidnapping Division.
He drove Samuel Ramos to the drop.
- Fuentes?
- Who is she?
You can ask her later.
She'll tell you anything.
What do you know about Fuentes?
Three years ago they caught him with $50,000
and a dead body in the trunk of his car.
Never charged. The arresting officer
couldn't testify cos he was dead.
Was he La Hermandad?
- You know where he lives?
- He lives in a Judicial compound.
He travels by motorcade.
He's better protected
than the president of Mexico.
He's gonna need it.
Can you take care of her?
- Yes, but how can I find you?
- I'll find you.
This is myjurisdiction.
I want this man as much as Creasy does.
He'll deliver more justice in a weekend
than ten years ofyour courts and tribunals.
Just stay out of his way.
I plan to.
I will even help him, if I can.
But... I'd like to understand him.
Give me that.
Pita Ramos...
is a number to you.
One more dead, but a number.
- What was she to Creasy, then?
- She showed him it was all right to live again.
And the kidnappers took that away, huh?
And they're gonna wish
they never touched a hair on her head.
A man can be an artist...
at anything - food, whatever.
It depends on how good he is at it.
Creasy's art is death.
He's about to paint his masterpiece.
I don't have anything else to say.
I need the accounts linked to this card.
PIN number is 4747.
On one condition.
I'm not here to hurt you.
In the church, they say to forgive.
Forgiveness is between them and God.
It's myjob to arrange the meeting.
Don't move. Put your hands down.
Señor John W Creasy is under arrest
for the murder oftwo officers
ofthe Judicial Police...
Creasy!
Can you hear me? Huh?
You know where we are?
We're under the bridge
where the deal went bad
and the ransom got stolen.
You wanna tell me what happened?
- You've heard of La Hermandad?
- Yes, I have.
- You know what it is?
- Yes.
I'm the president of La Hermandad.
- You're the president?
- Yes.
The president? Wow.
Look at me.
Oh, you can't. I'm sorry. How's that?
I'll show you what I got here.
See this? This is a charger.
It's used by convicts
to hide money and drugs.
They stick it in their body, they tuck it
up their rectum. You familiar with that?
This... Look at me. Pencil detonator.
Timer. Used as a receiver, a transmitter.
C4. Highly explosive.
You put 'em all together, you got a bomb.
Not very sophisticated, but very powerful.
That's what you have in your ass right now.
Don't move. Don't move.
Don't move.
Cheap watch, pager watch,
used to send a page to the receiver
that's up your behind right now.
So...
I'm gonna send you a page
which you will receive...
in five minutes.
Now...
You got less than five minutes
to tell me what went down
between your men and the kidnapper.
I have nothing to do with the kidnapper.
- Four minutes and 30 seconds.
- Nothing. I don't know him.
You don't know?
Four minutes and 25 seconds.
Four minutes and 20 seconds. Are you sure?
OK.
I got all the time in the world.
You don't, but I do.
- Relax, relax, buddy.
- I'm relaxed.
You got three minutes, 59 seconds.
- I saw the opportunity, and I got lucky.
- And?
And I had my men ready,
as we got instructions where to go.
You had your men ready to steal the drop,
ready to kill one ofthe kidnappers, yeah?
You've done this many times.
What's going on, guys?
- One ofthe nephews ofthe head kidnapper.
- Bingo, bingo, yeah.
You've done this many times.
Many times, yes.
Yeah. You've killed
many victims too, haven't you?
- We just make out as best we can.
- "As best we could"?
Two minutes, 47 seconds.
Wait a minute.
- Come on, I have a little gift for you.
- For me?
- Yeah, come on.
- What have you got?
There was no $10 million.
There was two and a half in the bags.
The ransom was $10 million.
They put it in two bags, 5 million in each bag.
Two bags, true, but one has half paper,
the other only paper.
Maybe your men stole it.
No, no. Whoever did it
took it before the exchange.
OK.
At the Ramos house, before the exchange,
who put the bags into the car?
- Guess what.
- What?
Ramos' lawyer. Jordan Kalfus.
I'm sorry, I'm really sorry for the girl.
It was just business, you know?
Everybody keeps saying that to me.
I'm getting sick and tired of hearing it.
Do you understand me?
What are you going to do now?
What am I gonna do? Leave. I gotta go.
Go? Hey, come on, come on.
What about me?
What about you? You got 40 seconds.
- Come on.
- 35!
Give me a last wish, please, please.
Last wish? I wish...
you had more time.
JORDAN KALFUS RESIDENCE
?Hola?
- Mariana, it's me.
- Creasy, where are you?
I got something like banking codes
from Bankcoast in the Cayman lslands.
- I need it translated as fast as you can.
- Whose account is it?
Jordan Kalfus.
It looks like US deposits and withdrawals.
Give me the same thing on Samuel Ramos.
- That's it?
- That's it.
OK.
Poraqui, porfavor.
Creasy.
- Samuel.
- Honey?
What's goin' on?
That's what I wanna know.
What is goin' on?
Sam?
I'm gonna ask your wife
a couple of questions, OK? You move...
You make one sound...
and I'll snatch the life right out ofyou,
you understand?
What happened, Lisa?
Were you in on this,
or was itjust your husband?
- Am I in on what?
- You know what.
Pita's kidnapping, her death.
Were you a part of it?
- Pita got killed because the ransom...
- Shut up!
Yeah, the money was stolen, you're right.
The money was stolen by Victor Fuentes.
How much was stolen? $2.5 million, right?
- What are you talkin' about?
- He knows what I'm talkin' about.
- That's what Victor got.
- What are you talkin' about?
2.5 million.
2.5 million to your lawyer, Jordan Kalfus.
He put it in an account in the Cayman lslands,
but he won't get a chance to spend it.
What happened to the other five, Sam?
That's 2.5, 2.5.
What is five from ten? Five.
What happened to the other five?
Tell your wife. This is your chance.
- You got a wife, Creasy?
- No, I don't.
You'll never know how hard it is
to tell your wife the truth.
No, you have a wife!
You tell me what happened!
- It was in this room that my father...
- I don't give a fuck about your father!
He prayed for his gambling debts
and his infidelities to be forgiven.
- Samuel!
- What?
- I love you! Tell me the truth!
- I didn't inherit a kingdom! That's the truth!
You wanna know the truth?
I inherited his debt and his mess!
- Tell me what happened to my baby!
- I inherited his lawyer!
Say it! Say it! Say it!
Say it! Be a fuckin' man!
Jordan told me she'd sit in a room
and watch cartoons all day.
And she'd eat ice cream.
And we'd have her back in two days.
He lied to me!
That's why he's fucking dead. I did it!
I did it, Lisa!
I agreed to the kidnapping.
I did it for us. For the three of us.
I'm so sorry, Lisa.
You kill him.
You kill him, or I will.
You know how they say a...
bullet always tells the truth.
It never lies.
It didn't work for me, Samuel,
but maybe...
maybe it'll work for you.
I'll pray for you.
This is definitely the address
from the ATM card.
The PIN number was a great locator.
But there's no one that sounds
anything like The Voice.
Who's that?
He's the man,
The Voice.
My guys got into the house...
on the pretext of giving cholera shots.
We had to inject the whole barrio.
We bugged the house
and stole the picture of him.
Now it's time to pursue him.
We have to put his photo in
tomorrow's newspaper.
Ifyou value your life,
you won't publish those photos.
- ?Hola?
- Hola.
- Mr Creasy?
- Yeah, it's me.
I traced the PIN for you and I have an address.
Yeah?
The cardholder is Reina Rosas Sanchez,
the wife of "The Voice".
She lives in Los Arcos,
apartment 26D, via Appia.
- Good.
- And another thing.
In today's paper is a picture of The Voice.
"FEAR HAS A VOICE."
Good. Thank you.
He's in.
What do we do?
Nothing... Nothing.
José, ?qué te pasa?
Alto, alto, alto...
Out of my house, you son of a bitch!
Stop there!
Get out. The kids out. Now!
!Salgan, ahora!
Sit down.
Sit down!
Reina Rosas, yes?
- Si.
- OK.
Who is this? Who is this?
?Quién es éste?
Daniel.
Daniel what?
Daniel Rosas Sanchez.
The Voice?
- Si.
- OK.
And this is his brother?
- ?Si?
- Si.
What is his name?
Aurelio.
Aurelio Rosas Sanchez, OK.
OK.
And you are Daniel's woman, right?
- Si.
- ?Si?
How do you contact him?
We page him,
and he calls back on his cellphone.
Call him.
There's no signal in here.
We have to go on the roof.
Let's go outside.
Outside.
Momento.
They're going to get a call.
Be ready to track him.
Ifwe're lucky he'll lead us to The Voice.
Hola, Daniel.
- Señor Creasy.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I got your family here.
Your brother doesn't look too good.
Yeah, Reina, she's what,
about eight months? Yeah?
You wanna negotiate?
The most important thing in life is family.
Do you agree?
I agree.
There you are, you have my family.
Well, most of my family.
My wife and I are separated.
You know how that is.
Now, tell me seriously,
how much do you want?
Your brother wants to speak to you.
Here, hold on.
What the hell do you want?
Listen to me! Listen!
I'll take your family apart
piece by piece. You understand me?
Piece by piece! Shut up!
I don't want your money.
You understand me? You understand me?
I want you!
I'm listening.
I'm listening, Daniel. I'm listening.
All right. I will give you a life for a life.
Whose life? What are you talkin' about?
Whose life, Daniel? I want you!
I will give you her life. For your life.
And in exchange, I will get my life back.
- What life? Whose life?
- The girl's. Pita's.
- Pita's dead!
- Creasy!
I'm a businessman.
A girl dead is worth nothing.
She's alive.
All right.
I want proof of life, you hear me?
I want proof of life. I want...
I want the name of her bear.
What does she call her bear?
You tell her to tell you to tell me
what she calls her bear.
Little one...
What do you call your teddy bear?
Yeah?
Creasy. She calls the bear Creasy Bear.
Remember...
I will give you her life
for your life
and the life of my brother.
OK.
I give you your brother, you give me the girl.
- All right.
- Where?
He left the roof. We lost the signal.
We got cut off.
We lost him. We lost him.
Damn.
- Hello?
- Lisa, listen to me. Don't hang up.
I think Pita's alive.
I can't take this any more.
Take the road to Puebla.
Get offjunction 34, south side.
I'll meet you there in two hours.
So where is she?
She's right over there.
You see those two cars out there?
Pita's kidnapper, Daniel...
Here's his brother.
Here.
I'm goin' up on the bridge to get Pita.
Anything goes wrong, you put it to his head,
you pull the trigger, all right?
You understand?
You don't let him loose
until she's with you, you got it?
And you don't wait for me, OK?
- Yeah.
- You'll be all right. You OK?
Yeah.
Creasy!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
They didn't hurt you?
Hi.
All right, your mother's waiting for you.
She's at the end the bridge.
- OK, you go home.
- OK.
- All right.
- Where are you going?
I'm goin' home too.
I'm goin' to Blue Bayou.
I got something for you.
I got the last number too.
I love you, Creasy.
And you love me, don't you?
Yes, I do.
Now, come on, Pita, go.
- Go. Run.
- Bye.
!Vamos!
Pita!
- Mom!
- Baby, come here! It's OK!
- Come on.
OK, I'll let you go now.
Mom!
JOHN W CREASY
JAN 4, 1956 - DEC 16, 2003
DEC 16, 2003
DANIEL SANCHEZ "THE VOICE" WAS
KILLED DURING THE COURSE OF ARREST
DEC 16, 2003
A SPECIAL THANKS TO MEXICO CITY,
A VERY SPECIAL PLACE