(Man) 'Whenever I get gloomy
with the state of the world,
'l think about the arrivals gate
at Heathrow airport.
'General opinion makes out
that we live in a world of hatred and greed
'but I don't see that.
'Seems to me that love is everywhere.
'Often it's not particularly dignified
or newsworthy but it's always there.
'Fathers and sons, mothers and daughters,
husbands and wives,
'boyfriends, girlfriends, old friends.
'When the planes hit the Twin Towers,
'none of the phone calls from people on
board were messages of hate or revenge,
'they were all messages of love.
'lf you look for it, I've got a sneaky feeling
you'll find that love actually is all around.'
~ I feel it in my fingers
~ I feel it in my toes
~ Feel it in my toes, yeah
~ Love is all around me
And so the... ~
- (Feedback)
- I'm afraid you did it again, Bill.
(Sighs) It's just I know the old version
so well, you know.
Well, we all do.
That's why we're making the new version.
Right, OK, let's go.
(~ lntro begins)
~ I feel it in my fingers
~ ln my fingers
~ I feel it in my toes
~ Feel it in my toes, yeah
~ Love is all ar... ~
Oh, fuck, wank, bugger,
shitting arsehead and hole.
Start again.
(~ lntro begins)
~ I feel it in my fingers
~ ln my fingers
~ I feel it in my toes
~ Feel it in my toes, yeah
~ Christmas is all around me
~ All around me
~ And so the feeling grows
~ So the feeling grows
~ It's written in the wind
~ ln the wind
~ It's everywhere I go
~ Everywhere I go
~ So if you really love Christmas
~ Love Christmas
~ Come on and let it snow
~ Come on and let it... ~
This is shit, isn't it?
Yep, solid gold shit, maestro.
- God, I'm so late.
- It's just round the corner, you'll make it.
You sure you don't mind
me going without you?
No, really. I'm just feeling so rotten.
- I love you.
- I know.
I love you even when you're sick
and look disgusting.
I know. Now, go or you will actually miss it.
Right.
- Did I mention that I love you?
- Yes, you did. Get out, loser.
Karen, it's me again.
I'm sorry, I literally don't have
anybody else to talk to.
Absolutely. Horrible moment, though.
Can I call you back?
Of course.
Doesn't mean I'm not terribly concerned
that your wife just died.
Understood.
Er, bugger off, call me later.
So what's this big news?
We've been given our parts
in the nativity play
and I'm the lobster.
- The lobster?
- Yeah.
- ln the nativity play?
- Yeah. First Lobster.
There was more than one lobster present
at the birth of Jesus?
Duh.
Best sandwiches in Britain.
Try my lovely nuts?
Beautiful muffin for a beautiful lady.
Morning, my future wife.
(Man) OK, you can stop there. Thanks.
(2nd man) I need a couple of orange gels.
By the way, he introduced me as John
but everyone calls me Jack.
Oh, fine. Nice to meet you, Jack.
He got me right, though. I'm just Judy.
Great, Just Judy!
- No surprises?
- No surprises.
- Not like the stag night?
- Unlike the stag night.
- You admit the prostitutes were a mistake?
- I do.
And it would've been much better
if they'd not turned out to be men?
That is true.
Good luck, kiddo.
(Cheering, applause)
(Press shouting) Prime Minister, over here!
(Cheering)
Thank you.
- Welcome, Prime Minister.
- Woh! I must work on my wave.
How are you?
- How are you feeling?
- Erm...
Cool. Powerful.
Would you like to meet
your household staff?
Yes, I would like that very much indeed.
Anything to put off
actually running the country.
- This is Terence. He's in charge.
- Morning, sir.
Good morning.
I had an uncle called Terence.
Hated him, I think he was a pervert.
But I very much like the look of you.
- This is Pat.
- Hello, Pat.
Good morning, sir. I'm the housekeeper.
Oh, right. I should be easier than the last lot.
No nappies, no teenagers, no scary wife.
And this is Natalie. She's new, like you.
- Hello, Natalie.
- Hello, David. I mean, sir.
Shit, I can't believe I've just said that.
And now I've gone and said ''shit''.
Twice. I'm so sorry, sir.
You could've said ''fuck''
and we'd have been in real trouble.
Thank you, sir. I had a premonition
I was gonna fuck up on my first day.
Oh, piss it!
Right, I'll get my things
and then let's fix the country, shall we?
Yeah, I can't see why not.
- It's all right.
- Did you see what I did?
- Yes, I did.
- I just went ''blurh''.
- Hello there.
- I'm right over here.
Yeah, I'm in here. OK. Good. Thank you.
Ah.
(Clears throat)
Oh, no.
That is so inconvenient.
ln the presence of God,
Peter and Juliet have given their consent
and made their marriage vows
to each other.
They've declared their marriage
by the giving of rings.
I therefore proclaim
that they are husband and wife.
(~ Organ plays Wedding March)
And you resisted
the temptation for surprises.
Yeah, I'm mature now.
(~ Wedding March becomes
La Marseillaise)
(Chorus) ~ Love, love, love
~ Love, love, love
- ~ Love, love, love... ~
- Did you do this?
Er, no.
~ Love, love, love, love
~ There's nothing you can do
that can't be done ~
Oh, it...
~ There's nothing you can sing
that can't be sung
~ There's nothing you can say
but you can learn how to play the game
~ It's easy
~ All you need is love
~ All you need is love, love
~ Love is all you need... ~
Look, it's Pikey.
Hello! What the hell are you doing here?
Oh, I just popped over
to borrow some old CDs.
- The lady of the house let you in, did she?
- Yeah.
- Lovely, obliging girl.
I thought I'd pop back and see
if she's better. This is good.
- Oh.
- Listen, erm, I've been thinking.
I think we ought to take Mum out for
her birthday on Friday. What do you think?
- I just feel we've been bad sons this year.
- Sounds fine. A bit boring but fine.
(Girlfriend) Hurry up, big boy!
I'm naked and I want you at least twice
before Jamie gets home.
(Music and chatter)
(Juliet) I am so happy to see you!
- Delicious delicacy?
- Er, no, thanks.
Taste explosion?
- Food?
- No, thanks.
Yeah, a bit dodgy, isn't it?
Looks like a dead baby's finger. Oooh.
Oh. Tastes like it, too.
I'm Colin, by the way.
- I'm Nancy.
- Wicked.
- What do you do, Nancy?
- I'm a cook.
- Ever do weddings?
- Yes, I do.
- They should've asked you to do this one.
- They did.
- God, I wish you hadn't have turned it down.
- I didn't.
(Embarrassed giggle) Right.
- I've worked out why I can't find true love.
- Why is that?
English girls. They're stuck up, you see.
And I am primarily attractive to girls
who are cooler, game for a laugh.
Like American girls.
So I should just go to America!
I'd get a girlfriend there instantly.
What do you think?
I think it's crap, Colin.
That's where you're wrong.
American girls would dig me
with my cute British accent.
- You don't have a cute British accent.
- Yes, I do! I'm going to America.
Colin, you're a lonely, ugly arsehole.
Accept it.
Never. I am Colin, God of Sex.
I'm just on the wrong continent, that's all.
Bit of quiet
while we finish the lighting, guys!
- The traffic today was just...
- Unbelievable.
Judy, could you take the top off this time?
Lighting need to know when we're gonna
see the, erm, nipples and when we're not.
Yes, OK. Right.
At least it's nice and warm in here.
Not always the case, is it?
I was standing in for Brad Pitt once
on Seven Years ln Tibet...
- Yes, yeah.
- Bloody freezing...
Guys, time's tight
and we have to get the actors in.
- Fine.
- I promise I won't look.
(Judy laughs)
(Director) Right, let's have
another look at that, please.
Can you just put your hands on her breasts?
- OK, yeah. ls that all right?
- Yes.
I'll warm them up!
- And massage them, please.
- Right.
It's junction 13 that's just murder, isn't it?
Total gridlock this morning.
Jo and I had a lot of time
to prepare for this moment.
Some of her requests,
for instance, that I should bring
Claudia Schiffer as my date to the funeral,
I was confident she expected me to ignore.
But others she was pretty damn clear about.
When she first mentioned
what's about to happen,
I said, ''Over my dead body.''
And she said, ''No, Daniel, over mine.''
And as usual, my darling girl...
and Sam's darling mum was right.
So she's going to say her final farewell
to you not through me but,
inevitably,
ever so coolly,
through the immortal genius
of the Bay City Rollers.
(On speakers)
~ Bye bye baby, baby goodbye
~ Goodbye baby, baby bye bye
~ Bye bye baby
~ Don't make me cry
~ Goodbye baby, baby bye bye
~ You're the one girl in town I'd marry
~ Girl I'd marry you now if I were free
~ I wish it could be
~ I could love you but why begin it?
~ Cos there ain't any future in it
~ She's got me but I'm not free so... ~
(From DJ booth)
~ Bye bye baby, baby goodbye
~ Goodbye baby, baby bye bye
~ Bye bye baby, don't make me cry
~ Wish I never had known you... ~
Do you love him?
Er, er, what?
No, l-l just thought I'd ask bluntly
in case it was the right question
and you needed someone to talk to about it
and no one had ever asked you.
No. No. No is the answer. Absolutely not.
~ ..on my finger... ~
So that's a no, then?
Yes. Erm...
~ Bye bye baby, baby goodbye
~ Goodbye baby, baby bye bye... ~
This DJ, what do you reckon?
- The worst in history?
- Probably.
I think it all hangs on the next song.
Now here's one for the lovers.
That's quite a few of you,
I shouldn't be surprised and a half.
(~ S Club Juniors: Puppy Love)
~ And they called it... ~
- He's done it, it's official.
- Worst DJ in the world.
~ Oh, I guess they'll never know... ~
(Knocks)
Sarah's waiting for you.
Oh, yes, of course, erm...
Great, er, good, good.
How are you doing, Mia?
Settling in fine? Learning who to avoid?
Absolutely.
- Harry?
- Sarah,
switch off your phone and tell me exactly
how long it is that you've been working here.
Two years, seven months,
three days and, I suppose, what, two hours?
And how long have you been in love
with Karl, our enigmatic chief designer?
Um...
Two years, seven months, three days
and, I suppose, an hour and 30 minutes.
Thought as much.
- Do you think everybody knows?
- Yes.
- Do you think Karl knows?
Oh, that is... that is bad news.
I just thought that maybe the time
had come to do something about it.
- Like what?
- lnvite him out for a drink
then casually mention you'd like to marry
him and have lots of sex and babies.
- You know that?
- Yes.
And so does Karl.
Think about it, for all our sakes.
It's Christmas.
Certainly. Excellent. Will do.
Thanks, boss.
- Hi, Sarah.
- Hi, Karl.
(~ On radio: Christmas ls All Around)
(Mobile)
Babe. Absolutely, fire away.
Mia, Mia, would you turn that down?
What is that?
That was the Christmas effort
from the once great Billy Mack.
Oh, dear me, how are the mighty fallen.
I can safely say that is the worst record
I've heard this century...
Oh, and coincidentally,
I believe Billy will be a guest
on my friend Mike's show
in a few minutes' time.
Welcome back, Bill.
Billy, welcome back to the airwaves.
New Christmas single,
cover of Love ls All Around.
Except we've changed
the word ''love'' to ''Christmas''.
Yes, is that an important message
to you, Bill?
(Snorts) Not really, Mike.
Christmas is a time for people
with someone they love in their lives.
- And that's not you?
- That's not me, Michael.
When I was young and successful,
I was greedy and foolish
and now I'm left with no one,
wrinkled and alone.
- Wow. Thanks for that, Bill.
- For what?
For actually giving
a real answer to a question.
lt doesn't often happen here
at Radio Watford, I can tell you.
- Ask me anything, I'll tell you the truth.
- Best shag you ever had?
- Britney Spears.
- Wow.
No, only kidding! (Snorts)
- She was rubbish.
- OK, here's one.
How do you think the new record
compares to your old, classic stuff?
Come on, Mikey, you know as well as I do
the record's crap.
(Bill laughing)
But wouldn't it be great
if number one this Christmas
wasn't some smug teenager
but an old ex-heroin addict
searching for a comeback at any price?
Those young popsters come Christmas
will be stretched out naked
with a cute bird balancing on their balls
and I'll be stuck in some dingy flat
with me manager Joe,
ugliest man in the world,
fucking miserable because
our fucking gamble didn't pay off.
So if you believe in Father Christmas,
children, like your Uncle Billy does,
buy my festering turd of a record.
And particularly enjoy
the incredible crassness
of the moment we try to squeeze
an extra syllable into the fourth line.
I think you're referring to
''lf you really love Christmas...''
''Come on and let it snow.'' Ouch.
So, here it is one more time,
the dark horse for this year's
Christmas number one,
Christmas ls All Around.
Thank you, Billy. After this, the news.
ls the new prime minister in trouble already?
~ I feel it in my fingers
I feel it in my toes ~
- OK. What's next?
- The President's visit.
Ah, yes, yes. I fear this is going to be
a difficult one to play. Alex.
There's a strong feeling in the party
we mustn't allow ourselves to be bullied
- like the last government.
- (All) Here, here.
This is our first really important test,
let's take a stand.
Right. Right. I understand that
but I have decided...
not to. Not this time.
Let's not forget that America
is the most powerful country in the world.
I'm not going to act like a petulant child.
Who do you have to screw round here
to get a cup of tea and a biscuit?
Right.
(Knocking)
Yeah, come in.
- These are from the Treasury...
- Uh-huh.
..and these are for you.
Excellent. Thanks a lot.
I was hoping you'd win, not that
I wouldn't have been nice to the other bloke,
just always given him the boring biscuits
with no chocolate.
Thanks very much. Thanks...
Natalie.
God, come on, get a grip.
You're the Prime Minister, for God's sake.
So what do you reckon
to our new prime minister?
Oh, I like him. I can't understand
why he's not married, though.
You know the type, he's married to his job.
Either that or gay as a picnic basket.
Excuse me, Judy, if you could
just lower the nipples
- and cheat them a bit to the left?
- OK.
I have to say, Judy, this is a real pleasure,
it's lovely to find someone
I can actually chat to.
- Thank you!
- Oh, well, you know.
- And ditto.
- Thank you.
The move again, please, Judy.
- Ooh, sorry.
- Oh, God, sorry. You all right?
- Exciting news!
- What?
I've bought a ticket to the States.
I'm off in three weeks.
- No.
- Yes!
- To a fantastic place called Wisconsin.
- No!
Yes! Wisconsin babes,
here comes Sir Colin!
No, Col! There are a few babes in America,
I grant you,
but they're going out
with rich, attractive guys.
Tone, you're just jealous.
You know perfectly well
that any bar anywhere in America
contains ten girls more beautiful
and more likely to have sex with me
- than the whole of the United Kingdom.
- That is total bollocks. You're mad.
No, I'm wise. Stateside I am Prince William
without the weird family.
- No, Colin, no!
- Yes!
- Nyet!
- Da!
- Nein!
- Ja, darling!
Right, the Christmas party,
not my favourite night of the year
and your unhappy job to organise.
- Tell me.
- It's basic, really.
Find a venue, over-order on the drinks,
bulk buy the guacamole
and advise the girls to avoid Kevin
if they want their breasts unfondled.
- Wives and family and stuff?
- Yeah. I mean, not children.
But their wives and girlfriends, et cetera.
Oh, Christ, you haven't got some horrible
six-foot, tight-T-shirt-wearing boyfriend?
No. I'll just be hanging around the mistletoe,
hoping to be kissed.
Really?
Right.
He now spends all the time in his room.
I mean, he'll be up there now.
- That's not unusual. My horrid son...
- Bernard?
Bernard. Stays in his room all the time.
Thank goodness.
Yeah, but Karen, this is all the time.
I'm afraid that there's something
really wrong, you know?
I mean, clearly it's about his mum
but Christ, he might be injecting heroin
into his eyeballs for all I know.
(Karen) At the age of 1 1?
(Daniel) Well, maybe not his eyeballs, then.
Maybe just his veins.
The problem is his mum
always used to talk to him, you know, and...
I don't know, this whole stepfather thing
seems suddenly to somehow matter
like it never did before.
Listen, it was always going to be
a totally shit time.
Just be patient.
And maybe check the room for needles.
And then when he sometimes does
come out, it's obvious he's been crying.
It's just such a ridiculous waste.
And now if it's going to ruin
Sam's life as well...
I just don't know.
Get a grip.
People hate sissies.
No one's ever gonna shag you
if you cry all the time.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Helpful.
So, what's the problem, Samuel?
ls it just Mum or is it something else, huh?
Maybe school?
Are you being bullied?
Or is it something worse?
Can you give me any clues at all?
- You really want to know?
- I really want to know.
Even though you won't be able to help?
Even if that's the case, yeah.
OK. Well...
truth is, actually...
I'm in love.
Sorry?
I know I should be thinking
about Mum and I am but I'm in love.
I was before she died
and there's nothing I can do about it.
- Aren't you a bit young to be in love?
- No.
Ah, well. OK, well...
I'm a little relieved.
- Why?
- Because l...
thought it'd be something worse.
Worse than the total agony of being in love?
Er...
No, you're right.
Total agony.
- Night, Sarah.
- Night, Karl.
(Mobile)
Yeah, absolutely.
Free as a bird. Fire away.
Alone again.
Naturally.
- I'll deal with it.
- Mm.
- Ah. Natalie.
- Sir.
Thanks.
Natalie.
Erm, I'm starting to feel...
uncomfortable about us
working so closely every day
and me knowing so little about you,
it seems elitist and wrong.
Well, there's not much to know.
Well, erm, where do you live, for instance?
Wandsworth. The dodgy end.
- Ah, my sister lives in Wandsworth.
- Oh.
So which exactly is the dodgy end?
At the end of the high street,
Harris Street, near the Queen's Head.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, that is dodgy.
- Hm.
Erm, and you live
with your husband? Boyfriend?
- Three illegitimate but charming children?
- No.
I've just split up with my boyfriend, so
I'm back with my mum and dad for a while.
- Ah. Sorry.
- No, it's fine.
I'm well shot of him.
- He said I was getting fat.
- I beg your pardon?
He said no one'd fancy a girl
with thighs the size of tree trunks.
Not a nice guy, actually, in the end.
No.
You know, erm...
being Prime Minister,
I could just have him murdered.
Thank you, sir. I'll think about it.
Do. The SAS are absolutely charming.
Ruthless, trained killers
are just a phone call away.
Oh, God.
Did you have this kind of problem?
Yeah, course you did, you saucy minx.
So, let's go. We can definitely crack this.
Remember, I was a kid once, too.
So, come on, it's someone at school. Right?
- Yeah.
- Uh-huh. Good, good.
And what does she, he, feel about you?
SHE doesn't even know my name.
And even if she did, she'd despise me.
She's the coolest girl in school.
And everyone worships her
because she's heaven.
Good. Good.
Well,
basically you're fucked, aren't you?
(~ All I Want For Christmas ls You)
Hi there and welcome back.
So, three weeks till Christmas, looks like
the real competition is gonna be Blue.
I saw them on the show last week.
They weren't very nice about my record.
No. Little scamps.
But very, very talented musicians.
Yeah. I understand you've got a prize
for our competition winners.
Yes, I have, Ant or Dec.
It's a personalised felt-tip pen.
Oh, great.
It's brilliant. It even writes on glass,
so if you've got a framed picture,
like, for instance, this one of Blue,
you can just write on it.
(Kids snickering)
(Dec) Er, a lot of kids watching, Billy.
(Billy) Oh, yeah.
Hiya, kids.
Here's an important message
from your Uncle Bill -
don't buy drugs.
Become a pop star
and they give you them for free.
And I do believe it's a commercial break.
We'll see you soon. Bye-bye.
~ All I want for Christmas is you ~
- Look at him! Eurh!
- Just a minute.
Actually, they're not funny. They're art.
(Laughing)
OK, let's say, er, Thursday, my place.
Great. I've got Juliet on the other line,
she wants to ask you a favour.
- (Sighing) OK, fine.
- Thanks and, er, be nice.
- I'm always nice.
- 'You know what I mean, Marky, be friendly.'
- I'm always...
- (Juliet) 'Mark?'
Hi. How was the honeymoon?
lt was great.
Thanks for the gorgeous sendoff.
- So, what can I do for you?
- 'It's only a tiny favour.'
I've just tried the wedding video
and it's a disaster.
- 'It's come out all blue and wibbly.'
- I'm sorry.
I remember you filming a lot
and I wondered if I could look at it.
To be honest, I didn't really...
Please. All I want is one shot of me
in a wedding dress that isn't turquoise.
I'll have a look but I'm pretty sure I wiped it,
so don't get any hopes up.
- 'Must go.'
- (Click)
Any progress with our matchmaking plans?
No. I've done fuck-all and never will
because he's too good for me.
How true.
- (Sarah) Stop.
- (Mobile)
And of course, your mobile goes.
Hello. Hi. How you doing?
- So, how's the Christmas party going?
- Good.
Think I've found a venue.
- What's it like?
- Good. Good.
It's an art gallery. Full of dark corners
for doing dark deeds.
Oh. Right.
Good. Well, I suppose I should
take a look at it or something.
You should.
(Typewriter clacking)
(Bell tinkles)
Ah, bonjour, Eleonore.
Bonjour, Monsieur Bennett. Welcome back.
And this year you bring a lady guest?
No. There's a change of situation. Just me.
- Oh. Am I sad or not sad?
- I think you're not surprised.
- And you stay here till Christmas?
- Yeah, yeah.
Good. Well, I find you
a perfect lady to clean the house.
This is Aurelia.
Ah.
- Er, bonjour, Aurelia.
- Bonjour.
(French) Er, je suis, er, tres heureux
de vous avoir ici.
Unfortunately, she cannot speak French,
just like you.
She's Portuguese.
(ltalian) Ah, ah, buongiorno.
Eusebio, er, er...
(Pidgin Spanish) Er, molto bueno...
I think she's ten years too young
to remember a footballer called Eusebio.
And ''molto bueno'' is Spanish.
Right.
Anyway, it's nice to meet you and...
Can you drive her home after her work?
Oh, absolutely, yes.
Con-Con grande, er, pl-plesura.
Which is what? Turkish?
(Pidgin Portuguese) Bello.
Er, bella.
Er, mon-montagno,
arvarez...
No, right. Silence is golden.
As the Tremeloes said.
Clever guys,
although I think the original version was
by Frankie Valli And The Four Seasons.
Gr-great band.
(~ High-pitched humming:
Silence ls Golden)
Oh, shut up.
(Cheering)
(Press) Mr President!
- Over here, sir!
- What will you be talking about?
Mr President, welcome.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Come through.
I'm sorry your wife couldn't make it.
So is she. Although she would have been
kind of lonely.
Yes. Pathetic, isn't it?
Just never been able to tie a girl down.
Not sure that politics and dating go together.
Really? I've never found that.
Yeah, you're still sickeningly handsome,
whereas I look like my Aunt Mildred.
- Very jealous of your plane, by the way.
- Thank you. We love that thing.
Ah, Natalie. Hi.
Morning, ma'am. How's your day so far?
- (Natalie giggles)
- Excellent.
(Sighs) My goodness,
that's a pretty little son of a bitch.
Did you see those pipes?
Yeah, she's terrific. At her job.
No, absolutely not. We cannot
and will not consult on that either.
That is unexpected.
Well, it shouldn't be.
The last administration
made it perfectly clear.
We're being consistent with their policies.
With all respect, they were bad policies.
Thanks, Alex. I don't think
we're making progress here.
Let's, erm... move on, shall we?
Well, now, that was an interesting day.
Sorry if our line was firm but there's
no point in tiptoeing around today,
then just disappointing you for four years.
I have plans and I plan to see them through.
Absolutely.
There is one final thing to look at.
It's very close to my heart.
Just give me a second.
I'll give you anything you ask for.
As long as it's not something
I don't wanna give.
Hi.
Pathetic.
It's great Scotch.
I'll, erm... I'll be going, then.
Er, Natalie,
I hope to see much more of you
as our countries work toward a better future.
Thank you, sir.
Er, yes, Peter.
Mr President, has it been a good visit?
Very satisfactory indeed.
We got what we came for
and our special relationship
is still very special.
Prime Minister?
I love that word ''relationship''.
Covers all manner of sins, doesn't it?
I fear that this has become
a bad relationship.
A relationship based on
the President taking what he wants
and casually ignoring all those things
that really matter to, erm...
Britain.
We may be a small country
but we're a great one, too.
The country of Shakespeare,
Churchill, the Beatles,
- Sean Connery, Harry Potter.
- (Laughter)
- David Beckham's right foot.
David Beckham's left foot, come to that.
And a friend who bullies us
is no longer a friend.
And since bullies only respond to strength,
from now onward,
I will be prepared to be much stronger.
And the President
should be prepared for that.
(Press clamouring)
Mr President!
Joe.
It's your sister on line four.
All right. Er, yes, I'm very busy
and important, how can I help you?
Have you gone completely insane?
- You can't always be sensible.
- 'You can if you're Prime Minister.'
- It's the Chancellor on the other line.
- It isn't!
- 'I'll call you back.'
- No, you won't!
The trouble with being the Prime Minister's
sister is it puts your life into perspective.
What did my brother do today?
He fought for his country.
What did I do?
I made a papier-mâché lobster head.
What is this we're listening to?
Joni Mitchell.
I can't believe you still listen to Joni Mitchell.
I love her and true love lasts a lifetime.
Joni Mitchell is the woman who taught
your cold English wife how to feel.
Did she? Oh, well, that's good,
I must write to her and say thanks.
Which doll for Daisy's friend Emily?
The one that looks like a transvestite
or the one that looks like a dominatrix?
(Female DJ) 'It's almost enough
to make you feel patriotic,
'so here's one
for our arse-kicking prime minister.
'A golden oldie for a golden oldie.'
(~ Pointer Sisters: Jump)
~ Hold me
~ I'll give you all that you need
~ Wrap your love around me
~ You're so excited
I can feel you getting hotter
~ Oh baby
~ I'll take you down, I'll take you down
~ Where no one's ever gone before
~ And if you want more
~ lf you want more, more, more
~ Jump for my love
~ Jump in
~ And feel my touch
~ Jump, if you wanna taste
my kisses in the night then
~ Jump for my love
~ I'll take you down, I'll take you down
~ Where no one's ever gone ~
- (Music stops)
- Yeah, erm,
Mary, can we move the Japanese
ambassador to four o'clock tomorrow?
- Certainly, sir.
- Terrific. Thanks so much.
Erm. Would you like the last, er...?
(Portuguese) Thank you very much but no.
lf you saw my sister, you'd understand why.
That's all right, more for me.
(Portuguese)
Just don't go eating it all yourself,
you're getting chubbier every day.
I'm very lucky I've got a constitution
where I never put on weight.
(Phone)
- Hello.
- (Ringing continues)
Oop. Sorry.
(Ringing continues)
Hello?
- Thank you.
- (Portuguese) Nao!
- Eu peço imensa desculpa.
- Oh, no. Hold on.
- God, it's half the book. Oh, no.
- Que desastre.
Just leave them, please!
They're not important.
They're not worth it!
Stop! Stop.
Aa-ahh.
It's all just rubbish.
Just leave it.
Oh, God, she's in.
And now she'll think I'm a total spaz
if I don't go in too.
(Portuguese) Fuck - it's cold!
Fuck - it's freezing! Fuck!
(Portuguese) This stuff better be good.
It's not worth it,
this isn't bloody Shakespeare.
(Portuguese) I don't want to drown
saving some shit my grandmother
could have written.
Just stop. Stop.
(Portuguese) What kind of idiot
doesn't make copies?
I really must do copies.
There'd better not be eels in here.
(Portuguese) Try not to disturb the eels.
Oh, what the hell is that?
Thank you. Thank you so much.
I know. I'll name
one of the characters after you.
(Portuguese) Maybe you could name
one of the characters after me.
(Portuguese) What kind of book is it?
- Romance?
- Yes.
It's, erm...
(lmitates horror film sound effects)
Ah, er...
(Portuguese) Thriller...crime...
(Portuguese) Sim.
(English) Crime. Crime, murder.
(Portuguese) Frightening? (Gasps)
Er, scary? Yes, sometimes scary.
And, er, sometimes not.
Mainly scary how bad the writing is.
Mm.
(Portuguese) I'd better get back to work.
- Ah.
- (Portuguese) Later you'll drive me home?
Sure.
It's my favourite time of day...
driving you.
(Portuguese) It's the saddest part
of my day, leaving you.
Sorry.
(TV) 'And coming up
later this morning, it's this guy...'
~ There's no beginning, there'll be no end
- ~ Cos on Christmas...
- '..the bad grandad of rock'n'roll,
'here at 10:30. Do not switch off.'
Banoffee pie?
No, thanks.
Thank God. You would've broken my heart
if you'd said yes.
Right, well, lucky you.
- Can I come in?
- Er, yeah, well, I'm a bit busy...
I was just passing and I thought
we might check that video thing out.
I thought I might be able
to swap it for some pie
or maybe Munchies?
Actually, I was serious - I don't know
where it is. I'll have a look tonight.
Mark, can I say something?
Yeah.
I know you're Peter's best friend
and I know you've never
particularly warmed to me.
Look, don't, don't argue.
We've never got friendly.
But I wanted to say, I hope that can change.
I'm nice. I really am.
Apart from my terrible taste in pie and...
lt would be great if we could be friends.
Absolutely. Absolutely.
Great.
Doesn't mean we'll be able
to find the video, though.
I had a real search when you first called
and couldn't find it so...
This one says
''Peter and Juliet's Wedding''.
Do you think we might be on the right track?
Er, yeah, well... Wow. That-that could be it.
- Do you mind if l...?
- I've probably taped over it.
Almost everything's episodes of West Wing.
Oh.
Oh, bingo.
That's lovely.
Well done, you.
Oh, that's gorgeous.
Thank you so much, Mark,
this is exactly what I was hoping for.
I look quite pretty.
You've stayed rather close.
They're all of me.
(Mark) Yeah. Yeah.
Yes.
But...
you never talk to me.
You always talk to Peter.
You don't like me.
I hope it's useful.
Don't show it around too much.
Needs a bit of editing.
Look, I've got to get to a...lunch.
Early lunch.
You can just show yourself out, can't you?
It's a...self-preservation thing, you see.
(~ Dido: Here With Me)
~ Oh I am what I am
~ I'll do what I want
~ But I can't hide
~ And I won't go
~ I won't sleep
~ And I can't breathe
~ Until you're resting here with me
~ And I won't leave
~ And I can't hide
~ I cannot be
~ Until you're resting here
~ And I won't go
~ And I won't sleep
~ And I can't breathe
~ Until you're resting here with me ~
- (Knocking)
- Yeah.
Annie, my darling, my dream, my boat.
Ah...
- Need you to do a favour for me.
- Of course.
Anything for the hero of the hour.
Don't ask me why,
and don't read stuff into this,
it's just a weird personality thing.
But, erm, you know Natalie who works here?
The chubby girl?
Ooh, would we call her chubby?
I think there's a pretty sizeable arse there,
yes, sir. Huge thighs.
Yeah. Well, whatever, erm...
I'm sure she's a lovely girl
but I wonder if you could, erm...
redistribute her?
It's done.
Hey, Sammo. Can't sleep?
I got some terrible news today.
Let's have it.
- Joanna's going back to America.
- Your girl's American?
Yes, she's American.
And she's not my girl.
And she's going back to America.
That's the end of my life as I know it.
That is bad news.
Well, we need Kate
and we need Leo, and we need them now.
Come on.
'Hold on. Hold on.
'Keep your eyes closed.
- 'Do you trust me?'
- 'l trust you.'
- Do you trust me?
- I trust you.
- Fool!
- Get off, you big bully.
'All right, open your eyes.'
You know, Sammy,
I'm sure she's unique and extraordinary
but general wisdom is that in the end,
there isn't just one person for each of us.
There was for Kate and Leo.
There was for you.
And there is for me.
She's the one.
Fair enough. And her name's Joanna?
Yeah, I know. Same as Mum.
- (Knocking)
- Yeah.
- Prime Minister.
- Thank you very much.
(Pidgin Portuguese)
Oh. Appolo... Erm, appologia.
Grande, er... grande familio,
grande tradizione de Christmas presents.
Stupido.
Well, goodbye.
(Portuguese) Thank you.
Erm, it was, erm...
(Portuguese) I will miss you.
And your very slow typing...
and your very bad driving.
(Car horn)
~ You know I love Christmas, I always will
~ My mind's made up, the way that I feel
~ There's no beginning, there'll be no end
~ Cos on Christmas you can depend ~
Daniel!
- I have a plan.
- Thank the Lord. Tell me.
- Well, girls love musicians, don't they?
- Uh-huh.
- Even the weird ones get girlfriends.
- That's right.
Meat Loaf definitely got laid at least once.
For God's sake,
Ringo Starr married a Bond girl.
Whatever. There's this big concert
at the end of term and Joanna's in it.
I thought if I was in the band
and played superbly,
she might fall in love with me.
What do you think?
I think it's brilliant, I think it's stellar.
Apart from the one obvious
tiny little baby little hiccup.
- I don't play a musical instrument?
- Yes, sir.
A tiny, insignificant detail.
(Loud, repetitive snare hits)
(~ Sugababes: Too Lost ln You)
~ You look into my eyes
~ I go out of my mind
~ I can't see anything
~ Cos this love's got me blind
~ I can't help myself
~ I can't break this spell
~ I can't even try
~ Baby, I'm too lost in you
~ Caught in you
~ Lost in everything about you
~ So deep I can't sleep, I can't... ~
I suppose I'd better do the duty round.
You're a saint.
(Laughs)
Any chance of a dance with the boss?
Yeah, sure, sure.
As long as your boyfriend doesn't mind.
Not my boyfriend.
~ And you're all I see
~ And you're all I need
~ Help me, baby
~ Oh baby, I'm too lost in you
~ Caught in you... ~
You're looking very pretty tonight.
It's for you.
Sorry?
It's all for you, sir.
~ You do
~ I'm too lost in you
~ Baby, baby
~ Baby, I'm too lost in you
~ Yeah, yeah
~ Caught in you
~ Lost in everything about you
~ So deep I can't sleep ~
'This must be very exciting for you,
fighting for the Christmas number one.
- 'How's it looking so far?'
- 'Very bad indeed.
'Blue are outselling me five to one
'but I'm hoping for a late surge.
'And, if I reach number one,
'l promise to sing a song stark naked
on TV on Christmas Eve.'
- 'Do you mean that?'
- 'Of course I do, Michael.
'Do you want a preview? You old flirt.'
(Parkinson laughing)
'That'll never make number one.'
(~ Justin Timberlake: Like I Love You)
~ And I burn every track
Clipse and J Timberlake... ~
I suppose it's his job
to dance with everyone, isn't it?
Some more than others.
Just one dance?
- Before we run out of chances.
- Who, me?
- Unless you just...
- No! No! Good.
Yes. Thanks.
~ You're a good girl
And that's what makes me trust you like I do
~ Late at night I talk to you
~ Hey
~ You will know the difference when... ~
(Music changes to slow tune)
(~ Norah Jones: Turn Me On)
~ Like a flower
~ Waiting to bloom
~ Like a light bulb
~ ln a dark room
~ I'm just sitting here
~ Waiting for you
~ To come on home
~ And turn me on
~ Like the desert
~ Waiting for the rain
~ Like a schoolkid
~ Waiting for the spring
~ I'm just sitting here
~ Waiting for you to come on home
~ And turn me on
~ Turn me on ~
Well, then. I'd better go.
OK.
- Good night.
Actually...
- I don't have to go.
- Right. Good.
- I mean...
- No, that's good.
Just, erm, would you excuse me
for one second?
- Sure.
- Just one second.
Erm, OK, that's done. Erm...
Why don't you come upstairs
in about ten seconds?
- Ten seconds.
(~ Eva Cassidy: Songbird)
~ For you
~ There'll be no crying
~ The sun will be shining
~ Cos I feel that when I'm with you
~ It's all right... ~
- Just tug it.
- OK.
~ I know it's right
~ And the songbirds
~ Keep singing like they know the score
~ And I love you, I love you, I love you... ~
You're beautiful.
~ Like never before... ~
(Mobile)
l-I'd better answer that.
Hello. Hi. Hello, darling.
No, no, I'm not busy. No, fire away.
Right.
Yes, l... I'm not quite sure
it's gonna be possible
to get the Pope on the phone tonight but...
Yes. Yes, I'm sure he's very good
at exorcism but...
Well, I'm sure...
Jon Bon Jovi is as well
and I'll definitely look into it.
OK? OK, I'll talk to you later.
All right, bye-bye.
- Sorry about that.
- No, it's fine.
It's my brother, he's not well, he calls a lot.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's fine. It's fine.
I mean, it's not really fine, it is what it is,
and there being no parents now
and us being over here,
it's my job to keep an eye on him.
Not my job, obviously, I'm glad to do it...
That's OK. Life is full
of interruptions and complications.
So...
(Mobile)
Will it make him better?
No.
Then maybe...
don't answer.
Hey. How you doing?
Right, right. Oh, no, please.
Oh, please, please don't, little darling.
Between the two of us we'll find the answer
and it won't hurt any more.
No, no.
I'm-I'm not busy. l...
Of course, if you want me
to come over I will. Mm-hm.
OK.
That was a good night.
- Except I felt fat.
- Don't be ridiculous.
It's true.
Nowadays the only clothes I can get into
were once owned by Pavarotti.
I always think Pavarotti dresses very well.
Mia's very pretty.
ls she?
You know she is, darling.
Be careful there.
Have you been watching stuff on TV?
Yeah.
- Every night.
- Good.
And every day.
- The nurses are trying to kill me.
- Nobody's trying to kill you, babe.
Thank you.
Don't do that, my darling.
Don't do that.
(Dog barking in distance)
Right. Back at three. Christmas shopping,
never easy or pleasant.
Are you gonna get me something?
Er...
I don't know, I hadn't thought.
Where's Sarah, by the way?
She couldn't make it in. Family thing.
There's a word for hangover
I've never heard before.
- See you later.
- Yes. Looking forward to it.
A lot.
Are you gonna give me something?
I thought I made it clear last night.
When it comes to me,
you can have everything.
So, erm, what do you need?
Something along the stationery line?
Are you short of staplers?
No. I don't want something I need.
I want something I want. Something pretty.
Right.
Sorry I'm late, I had to drop off
Bernie at rehearsal.
Right, listen, you keep yourself occupied
while I do the boring stuff for our mothers.
- Thank you.
Looking for anything in particular, sir?
Yes. That necklace there, how much is it?
It's £270.
- Erm, all right. Er, I'll have it.
- Lovely.
Would you like it...giftwrapped?
- Yes, all right.
- Lovely.
Let me just pop it in the box.
There.
- Look, could we be quite quick?
- Certainly, sir.
Ready in the flashiest of flashes.
- There.
- That's great.
Not quite finished.
- I don't need a bag, I'll put it in my pocket.
- Oh, this isn't a bag, sir.
- Really?
- This is so much more than a bag.
Ooh!
Could we be quite quick, please?
Prontissimo.
- What's that?
- A cinnamon stick, sir.
- Actually, I really can't wait.
- You won't regret it, sir.
Want to bet?
'Tis but the work of a moment.
There we go. Almost finished.
Are you gonna dip it in yogurt?
Cover it with chocolate buttons?
No, sir, we're going to pop it
in the Christmas box.
I don't want a Christmas box.
- But you wanted it giftwrapped.
- I did but...
- The final flourish.
- Can I pay?
- All we need now...
- Oh, God.
- ..is a sprig of holly.
- No, no, no, no.
- No bloody holly.
- But sir...
- Leave it.
- Ooh!
- Loitering around the jewellery section?
- No. I was just looking around.
Don't worry. My expectations
are not that high
after 13 years of
Mr Oh-But-You-Always-Love-Scarves.
Actually, I do love this one.
(~ Darlene Love: All Alone On Christmas)
~ I've gotta know
~ Where do the lonely hearts go... ~
- Hey!
- What are you doing here?
Had to rent out my flat to pay for my ticket.
You're not actually going ahead
with this stupid plan?
I bloody am.
You think this is full of clothes?
Like hell it is.
lt is chock-a-block full of condoms.
Excellent. Excellent.
Perfect, keep that going.
(Clears throat) Look, erm...
sorry to be a bit forward and all that but...
you don't fancy going for a Christmas drink,
do you? I mean, nothing implied.
Just maybe go and see something
Christmassy or something.
Obviously, if you don't want to,
you don't have to. l...
I'm rambling now, sorry.
No. That would be lovely.
Oh, great.
Yay!
You know, that is really great.
Normally, I'm really shy, takes me ages
to get the courage up, so thank you.
(Repetitive drumbeats)
- Explain again why you're so late.
- Can't a man have any secrets?
We've been waiting for hours,
it's the first ever preview.
~ ..is a thing of the past
~ Maybe you can bring us all hope this year
~ Visions of sugarplums
have disappeared... ~
(Karen) It was a starry night
in ancient Jerusalem
and the baby Jesus was in his manger.
Sherlock Holmes is not a real detective.
(Russian) ls this the way to the train station?
I would like half-pint of churly.
I would like a one-day Travelcard.
(Portuguese) Oh, my God,
I've got a terrible stomachache.
lt must have been the prawns.
Milton Keynes has many roundabouts.
(Portuguese) My goodness,
this is a very big fish!
lt tastes delicious!
~ All alone on Christmas
~ Nobody ought to be alone on Christmas
~ Tell me I've got to know
~ Don't leave me alone ~
- You'll come back a broken man.
- Yeah, back broken from too much sex.
You are on the road to disaster.
No, I am on shag highway, heading west.
Farewell, failure.
America, watch out!
Here comes Colin Frissell.
~ And he's got a big knob ~
(~ Santana Featuring Rob Thomas:
Smooth)
- Take me to a bar.
- What kind of bar?
Just any bar.
Just your average American bar.
(On jukebox) ~ Man, it's a hot one
~ Like seven inches
from the midday sun... ~
- Can I help you?
- Yes. I'd like a Budweiser, please.
- King of beers.
- Bud coming up.
Oh, my God.
Are you from England?
- Yes.
- Oh...
that is so cute.
Hi, I'm Stacey. (Giggles)
Jeannie?
Yeah?
- This is...
- Colin.
Frissell.
Cute name.
- Jeannie.
- He's from England.
Yep. Basildon.
- Oh.
Wait till Carol-Anne gets here.
She's crazy about English guys.
(Stacey) Uh-huh.
- Hey, girls.
- Carol-Anne, come meet Colin.
He's from England.
Well, step aside, ladies. This one's on me.
- Hey, gorgeous.
- (Gentle growl)
That is so funny!
- What do you call that?
- Er, bottle.
(With English accent) ''Bottle.''
- What about this?
- Er, straw.
(Girls) ''Straw.''
- What about this?
- Table.
- Table. The same.
- Oh, it's the same.
- Where are you staying?
- I don't actually know.
I'll just check into a motel like in the movies.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, that is so cute.
No, no, no, listen. This may be a bit pushy
cos we just met you but...
why don't you come back
and sleep at our place?
- Yeah.
Well, if it's not too much
of an inconvenience.
- Hell no!
- But there's one problem.
What?
Well, we're not the richest of girls,
you know.
So we just have a little bed and no couch.
So you'd have to share with all three of us.
And on this cold, cold night it's gonna be
crowded and sweaty and stuff.
And we can't even afford pyjamas.
No?
Which means...
we would be naked.
No, no, I think it'd be fine.
- (Girls) Great.
- Erm...
The thing that's gonna make it
more crowded...
Harriet. You haven't met Harriet.
- There's a fourth?
- Yeah.
Don't worry, you're totally gonna like her
cos she is ''the sexy one''.
- Really? Wow.
- Yeah.
- Praise the Lord!
- Oh, and he's a Christian.
(All) Cheers.
~ lf I could
~ Then I would
~ I'll go wherever you will go
~ Way up high
~ Or down low
~ I'll go wherever you will go
~ lf I could turn back... ~
One present only each tonight.
Who's got one for Dad?
- I have.
- Let Mummy go first.
- I'll get it.
- No, no, no. I want to choose mine.
I think I want...
- ..this one.
- I have bought the traditional scarf as well
but this is my other,
slightly special, personal one.
Thank you.
That's a real first.
- Rip it!
- What is it?
I'm going to... All right, I'll rip it.
God, that's a surprise.
(Daisy) What is it?
It's a CD. Joni Mitchell, wow.
To continue your emotional education.
Yes.
Goodness.
That's great.
- My brilliant wife.
- Ah, yes.
Actually, do you mind if I just absent myself
for a second?
All that ice cream. Er...
Darling, could you make sure
the kids are ready to go?
- Back in a minute.
- (Harry to kids) All right, take it easy.
(Bernie) Mine first. Mine.
(~ Joni Mitchell: Both Sides Now)
~ Moons and Junes
~ And Ferris wheels
~ The dizzy dancing way that you feel
~ As every fairy tale comes real
~ I've looked at love that way
~ But now it's just another show
~ And you leave 'em laughing when you go
~ And if you care
~ Don't let them know
~ Don't give yourself away
~ I've looked at love
~ From both sides now
~ From give and take
~ And still somehow
~ It's love's illusions that I recall
~ I really don't know love
~ I really don't know love at all
~ Tears and fears
~ And feeling proud
~ To say I love you right out loud
~ Dreams and schemes
~ And circus crowds
~ I've looked at life that way
~ Oh but now old friends... ~
Oh, my God.
It's a miracle. You're all dressed.
Come on, come on, come on,
we're horribly late.
Come on, then. ln the car. ln the car.
~ Well something's lost
~ But something's gained
~ ln living every day ~
- Has she noticed you yet?
- No.
But the thing about romance is people
only get together right at the very end.
Of course.
By the way, I feel bad. I never ask you
how your love life is going.
Er-huh!
No.
As you know,
that was a done deal long ago.
Unless Claudia Schiffer calls, in which case
I want you out of here straightaway,
- you wee motherless mongrel.
- Oh!
No, no. We'll want to have sex
in every room, including yours.
(Male DJ)
'It's a rainy Christmas Eve all over the UK
'and the question is who is number one
on the Radio One chart show tonight?
'ls it Blue or the unexpected
Christmas sensation from Billy Mack?
'You might have guessed it
although you may not believe it.
'It's Billy Mack.'
- You are the champion!
- (Crowd) Shh.
- 'Hi, Billy.'
- Hello.
'We're live across the nation
and you're number one.
- 'How will you be celebrating?'
- I don't know.
Er, either I could behave like
a real rock'n'roll loser
and get drunk with my fat manager...
or, when I hang up,
I'll be flooded by invitations
to a large number of glamorous parties.
'Let's hope it's the latter. Here it is.
Number one, from Billy Mack,
- 'it's Christmas ls All Around.'
- Oh, Jesus, not that crap again.
~ I feel it in my fingers... ~
Bill, it's for you, babe.
Hello. Elton.
O-Of course. Of course.
Send an embarrassingly big car
and I'll be there.
(Crowd laughing)
It's gonna be a very good Christmas.
(Cheering)
- Right.
- I'd better be getting inside, actually.
- My mum and...you know.
- Of course, yeah. It's getting a bit cold.
Erm...
- Well, good night.
- Night.
Er...
Er... OK.
All I want for Christmas...
- is you.
- (Laughs nervously)
Right.
Thank you. Good.
Good night.
Ha ha ha! Ho.
(~ Otis Redding: White Christmas)
~ I'm, I'm dreaming
~ Dreaming of a white... ~
Oh, look, everyone, it's Uncle Jamie.
Hi, Uncle Jamie!
Yes, oh, splendid. It's lovely to see you all.
And, er...
I'm off, actually.
But Jamie, darling.
Sorry.
Man's gotta do what a man's gotta do.
I hate Uncle Jamie!
(Girl) I hate Uncle Jamie.
(Boy) I hate Uncle Jamie.
~ And try to listen
~ To hear
~ Hear for the sleigh bells
~ That are ringing in the snow... ~
Gatwick airport, please. Fast as you can.
(~ Song continues on radio, quietly)
~ l-l-l
~ I'm dreaming
~ Of a white... ~
- Night, Sarah.
- Night, Karl.
l, er...
- Merry Christmas.
~ I want you to know, may your day
~ May your day
~ Be so merry, merry and bright... ~
Hi, babe, how's it going? Yeah.
ls it all party, party, party down there?
~ All of your Christmases
~ And may all
~ And may all of your Christmases
~ Baby may your days
~ May your days be merry
~ Merry, so merry... ~
- Sam, time for dinner.
- I'm not hungry.
Sam, I've done chicken kebabs.
(Sam) Look at the sign on the door.
(Drumming)
Right.
It's a little long.
~ Dreaming,
dreaming of a white, white Christmas... ~
(Doorbell)
I'll get it.
- Oh, hi.
- (Peter) Who is it?
It's carol singers.
Give them a quid and tell them to bugger off.
(Turns volume up)
~ Silent night
~ Holy night
~ All is calm
~ All is bright
~ Round yon virgin
~ Mother and child
~ Holy infant
~ So tender and mild
~ Sleep in heavenly peace
~ Silent night
~ Holy night
~ Shepherds quake
~ At the sight... ~
(Whispers) Merry Christmas.
~ Glories stream
~ From heaven afar
~ Heavenly hosts sing alleluia
~ Christ the saviour is born
~ Christ the saviour is born ~
Enough.
Enough now.
(Sound turned down)
(Doorbell)
What the hell are you doing here?
You're supposed to be at Elton John's.
Well, I was there for a minute or two
and then I had an epiphany.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Come on. Just come up.
So what was this epiphany?
Erm, it...it was about Christmas.
You realised it was all around.
No. I realised that Christmas is the time
to be with the people you love.
Right.
And I realised that, as dire chance
and fateful cockup would have it,
here I am,
mid-fifties,
and without knowing it,
I've spent most of my adult life
with a chubby employee. (Snorts)
And, much as it grieves me to say it,
it might be that the people I love is, in fact...
you.
Well, this is a surprise.
Yeah.
Ten minutes at Elton John's and you're gay?
No, look. I'm serious here.
I left Elton's and a hefty number
of half-naked chicks with their mouths open
in order to hang out with you at Christmas.
- Well, Bill...
- It's a terrible, terrible mistake, chubs...
but you turn out to be
the fucking love of my life.
And to be honest,
despite all my complaining...
we have had a wonderful life.
Well...
thank you.
I mean, come on, it's been an honour.
I feel very proud.
Oh, look, don't be a moron.
(Clears throat)
Come on, let's get pissed and watch porn.
(Natalie) 'Dear sir, Dear David,
'Merry Christmas and I hope you have
a very happy New Year.
'I'm very sorry
about the thing that happened.
'lt was a very odd moment
and I feel like a prize idiot.
'Particularly because -
'if you can't say it at Christmas,
when can you, eh? -
'I'm actually yours. With love, your Natalie.'
Jack, yeah, I need a car.
Right now. Thank you.
(~ Pointer Sisters: Jump)
Oh, don't wait up.
I'd like to go to Wandsworth, the dodgy end.
Very good, sir.
~ Tell me how you want me
~ I can feel it in your heart beat
~ I know you like what you see... ~
(Terry) Harris Street. What number, sir?
(David) Oh, God, it's the longest street
in the world and I have absolutely no idea.
~ Wrap your love around me
~ You're so excited
I can feel you getting hotter ~
(Doorbell)
Hello, does Natalie live here?
- No.
- Right, fine, thank you. Sorry to disturb.
Here, aren't...
Aren't you the Prime Minister?
- Er, yes. ln fact, I am. Merry Christmas.
- Oh.
Part of the service now. Trying to get round
everyone by New Year's Eve.
(Doorbell)
Ah. Hello. Does Natalie live here?
- No, she doesn't.
- Oh dear. OK.
- Are you singing carols?
- Er, no. No, I'm not.
- Please, sir, please.
- Please.
Well, I suppose I could.
Please.
- All right.
- (Girls cheer)
~ Good King Wenceslas looked out
~ On the feast of Stephen
(Joins in with rich, deep voice)
~ When the snow lay round about
~ Deep and crisp and even
~ Brightly shone the moon that night ~
- (Doorbell)
- Hello. Sorry to disturb.
- Does Natalie live here?
- No.
She lives next door.
Ah. Brilliant.
You're not who I think you are, are you?
Yes and I'm sorry about all the cockups.
My cabinet are absolute crap.
We hope to do better next year.
Merry Christmas to you.
(Doorbell)
- (Chatting stops suddenly)
- Ah. Hello.
ls, er, Natalie in?
Oh, where the fuck is my fucking coat?
- Oh. Hello.
- Hello.
Erm, this is my mum and my dad
and my Uncle Tony and my Auntie Glynne.
- Hello.
- Very nice to meet you.
And, erm...this is the Prime Minister.
Yes, we can see that, darling.
And erm, unfortunately, we're very late.
It's the school Christmas concert,
you see, David.
All the local schools have joined together,
even St Basil's...
- Too much detail, Mum.
- Anyway, how can we help, sir?
Well, l...just needed Natalie...
on some state business.
- Oh.
- Right, yes. Of course.
Right, er...
Well, perhaps you should
come on later, Plumpy.
Er, Natalie.
I don't want to make you late for the concert.
- No, it's nothing, really.
- Keith'll be very disappointed.
- No, really, it doesn't matter.
- The octopus costume's taken me months.
Eight is a lot of legs, David.
Mm. Erm...
Listen, why don't I give you a lift
and then we can talk about
this state business business in the car.
OK.
- Lovely, yes.
- Thank you.
Hold tight, everybody.
- How far is this place?
- Just round the corner.
Ah, right. Well, er...
I just wanted to say...
thank you for the Christmas card.
You're welcome.
Look, I'm so sorry about that day.
I came in and he slinked towards me
and there was a fire
and he's the President of the United States
and nothing happened, I promise.
I just felt like such a fool because...
I think about you all the time, actually.
- And I think you're the man that I really...
- We're here.
- ..love.
- Oh, wow.
That really was just round the corner. Er...
Erm...
Ow!
(Sighs)
Well, look, l...
I think I'd better not come in, you know?
Nobody wants some politician
stealing the kids' thunder.
No, please come. lt'll be great.
No, I'd...I'd better not.
But I will be very sorry
to drive away from you.
Just give me one second.
John's been very mysterious.
Where did you two meet?
- Erm...erm...
- Um...um...
No!
Come on in. We can watch from backstage.
OK. Terry, I won't be long.
Look, this has to be a very secret visit, OK?
Don't worry. This was my school.
I know my way around. Come on.
Look, the sheep are ready already
and you're not even...
- Oh, David.
- Ah!
Oh, how are you?
Hi, guys. Hey, hey, hey. You all right?
What the hell are you doing here?
- Well, you know...
- We always tell your secretary
that these things are going on but it never
occurred to me you'd actually turn up.
I thought it was time I did.
I didn't want anyone to see,
so I'm gonna hide somewhere.
Good luck, Daisy, good luck, Bernie.
I've never been gladder
to see my stupid big brother.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Oh, now. We haven't been introduced.
Right. Well, this is Gavin.
- Hello, Gavin.
- My copper.
And this is Natalie, who's my, erm...
- who's my, erm, catering manager.
- Oh.
- Hi.
- Catering manager.
Watch he keeps his hands off you.
20 years ago, you'd have been his type.
I'll be very careful. Don't try something, sir,
just because it's Christmas.
- No, seriously.
- (Bell)
Come on. Showtime. Quickly.
- Look, see you after, yeah?
- Probably.
- Thank you, Prime Minister.
- It's all right.
- Come on.
- Right.
~ Catch a falling star
and put it in your pocket
~ Save it for a rainy day
~ Catch a falling star
And put it in your pocket
~ Never let it fade away
~ Never let it fade away ~
(Cheering, applause)
Hillier School would now like to present
their Christmas number.
Lead vocals by ten-year-old
Joanna Anderson,
backing vocals coordinated by her mother,
the great Mrs Jean Anderson.
Erm, some of the staff
have decided to help out
and for this, we ask you to forgive us.
Thank you.
(Applause)
(A capella) ~ I don't want a lot for Christmas
~ There's just one thing I need
~ I don't care about the presents
~ Underneath the Christmas tree
~ I just want you for my own
~ More than you could ever know
~ Make my wish come true
~ All I want for Christmas
~ ls you
~ I don't want a lot for Christmas
~ There's just one thing I need
~ I don't care about the presents
~ Underneath the Christmas tree
~ I just want you for my own
~ More than you could ever know
~ Make my wish come true
~ All I want for Christmas is you
~ You baby
~ Oh, all the lights are shining
~ So brightly everywhere
~ And the sound of children's laughter
fills the air
~ Laughter fills the air
~ Everyone is singing
~ Oh yeah
~ I hear those sleigh bells ringing
~ Santa won't you bring me my honey
~ Won't you please bring my baby to me
~ I don't want a lot for Christmas
~ This is all I'm asking for
~ All I'm asking for
~ I just wanna see my baby
~ Standing right outside my door
~ Cos I just want you for my own
~ More than you could ever know
~ You will ever know
~ Make my wish come true
~ All I want for Christmas
~ ls you
~ And you and you
~ All I want for Christmas
~ All I want for Christmas ~
(Cheering, whistling)
Right.
So, not quite as secret as we'd hoped.
- What do we do now?
- Smile.
Little bow.
And a wave.
Absolutely no idea.
I mean, can you imagine?
I'll see you later, all right?
I'll speak to you. Bye.
Tell me, if you were in my position,
what would you do?
What position is that?
lmagine your husband
bought a gold necklace
and, come Christmas,
gave it to somebody else.
- Oh, Karen...
- Would you wait around to find out...
- Good night.
- Night, darling. Happy Christmas.
Would you wait around to find out
if it's just a necklace
or if it's sex and a necklace
or if, worst of all, it's a necklace and love?
Would you stay? Knowing life
would always be a little bit worse?
- Or would you cut and run?
- Oh, God.
I am so in the wrong.
A classic fool.
Yes, but you've also made a fool out of me.
You've made the life I lead foolish, too.
Darling. Ooh, darlings!
Oh, you were wonderful.
My little lobster, you were so...
What is that word?
Orange.
Come on, I've got treats at home.
Dad's coming.
Sammy! Fantastic show!
Classic drumming, son.
- Thanks. Plan didn't work, though.
- Tell her, then.
- Tell her what?
- That you love her.
No way. Anyway, they fly tonight.
Even better. Sam, you've got nothing to lose
and you'll always regret it if you don't.
I never told your mum enough.
I should have told her every day
because she was perfect every day.
You've seen the films, kiddo.
lt ain't over till it's over.
OK, Dad. Let's do it. Let's go get the shit
kicked out of us by love.
Yes.
- Just give me one sec.
- Yeah.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
That's OK.
- My fault.
- No, no, really, it wasn't.
You're Sam's dad, aren't you?
Yeah. Stepdad, actually.
- Daniel.
- I'm Carol.
Carol.
- OK, I'm back. Let's go.
- Yeah. Well...
I hope we'll meet again, Karen.
Carol. (Laughs)
- I'll make sure we do.
- Yeah? Good.
(Carol laughs)
- Tell her.
- What?
- You know...
- Don't be such an arse.
- Look, there she is.
- Where?
Over there.
Oh, no.
It's OK, we'll go to the airport.
I know a short cut.
(Portuguese) Good evening.
- Senhor Barros?
- Sim.
I am here to ask your daughter
for her hands in marriage.
You want to marry my daughter?
Yes.
Come here,
there is a man at the door.
He wants to marry you.
But I've never seen him before.
Who cares?
You're going to sell me
to a complete stranger?
Sell? Who said sell? I'll pay him.
Pardon me. I'm meaning
your other daughter - Aurelia.
She's not here - she's at work. I'll take you.
You! Stay here.
As if I would. Stupid!
Father is about to sell Aurelia
as a slave to this Englishman.
Wait. Wait.
Oh, no.
You better not say yes, Father.
Shut up, Miss Dunkin' Donut 2003.
- Look, we're not actually flying.
- You can't come through.
Not even to let the boy say goodbye
to the love of his life?
No.
- I'm sorry, Sam.
- Boarding pass, sir?
Just a moment, I know I've got it.
Would you hang on to that?
- Unless...
- What?
- Do you want to make a run for it?
- Hold on to that.
- You think I should?
- Yeah.
- OK.
- Yes!
I must have left them
where I was having a cup of coffee.
(Beeping)
(lnaudible through glass)
(Chattering excitedly)
Apparently he is going to kill Aurelia.
Cool!
Joanna.
Sam?
- I thought you didn't know my name.
- Course I do.
Oh, Jesus. Here, I've gotta run.
- (Portuguese) Where is Aurelia?
- Why should I tell you?
This man wants to marry her.
He can't do that - she's our best waitress.
Boa noite, Aurelia.
Boa noite, Jamie.
Beautiful Aurelia...
I've come here with a view to asking you...
to marriage me.
I know I seems an insane person
because I hardly knows you
but sometimes things are so transparency,
they don't need evidential proof.
And I will inhabit here,
or you can inhabit with me in England.
Definitely go for England, girl.
You'll meet Prince William -
then you can marry him instead.
Of course I don't expecting you
to be as foolish as me,
and of course I prediction you say no....
but it's Christmas
and I just wanted to...check.
Oh, God - say yes, you skinny moron.
(English) Thank you.
That will be nice.
Yes is being my answer.
Easy question.
(Portuguese) What did you say?
Yes, of course.
(Cheering)
Bravo!
(English) You learned English?
Just in cases.
(~ Beach Boys: God Only Knows)
~ I may not always love you
~ But long as there are stars above you... ~
Hello, Daisy.
- This one's Greta.
- Hello, Greta.
~ I'll make you so sure about it... ~
Here she is. This is Aurelia.
This is Juliet. This is Peter.
- Mark, didn't see you there.
- Just thought I'd tag along.
Jamie's friends are so good-looking.
He never tells me this.
I think maybe now
I have made the wrong choice,
picked wrong Englishman.
She can't speak English properly.
(Daisy) Dad! Dad!
Oh, God.
- Did you get us any presents?
- Matter of fact, I did.
(Bernie) Thanks, Dad.
- How are you?
- I'm fine. I'm fine.
Good to have you back.
Come on. Home.
There she is.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Aw, he should have kissed her.
- No, that's cool.
- All right?
- Hey. What are you two doing here?
- I might get a shag at last.
- Naughty.
- Got to go.
- Bye.
Yahoo!
Now, this is Harriet.
- Hi. Really pleased to meet you.
- Hello, Harriet.
I hope you don't mind,
I sort of brought my sister to stay.
This is Carla. She's real friendly.
Hello, you must be Tony.
I heard you were gorgeous.
~ God only knows
what I'd be without you... ~
(Press shouting)
~ God only knows what I'd be without you
~ God only knows
what I'd be without you... ~
- God, you weigh a lot.
- Oh, shut your face.
~ God only knows what I'd be without you
~ God only knows
~ God only knows what I'd be without you ~
(~ Kelly Clarkson: The Trouble With Love ls)
~ Love can be a many splendored thing
~ Can't deny the joy it brings
~ A dozen roses, diamond rings
~ Dreams for sale and fairy tales
~ lt'll make you hear a symphony
~ And you just want the world to see
~ But like a drug that makes you blind
~ lt'll fool ya every time
~ The trouble with love is
~ It can tear you up inside
~ Make your heart believe a lie
~ It's stronger than your pride
~ The trouble with love is
~ It doesn't care how fast you fall
~ And you can't refuse the call
~ See you got no say at all
~ Now I was once a fool, it's true
~ I played the game by all the rules
~ But now my world's a deeper blue
~ I'm sadder but I'm wiser too
~ I swore I'd never love again
~ I swore my heart would never mend
~ Said love wasn't worth the pain
~ But then I hear it call my name
~ The trouble with love is
~ It can tear you up inside
~ Make your heart believe a lie
~ It's stronger than your pride
~ The trouble with love is
~ It doesn't care how fast you fall
~ And you can't refuse the call
~ See you got no say at all
~ Every time I turn around
~ I think I've got it all figured out
~ My heart keeps calling
And I keep on falling
~ Over and over again
~ The sad story always ends the same
~ Me standing in the pouring rain
~ It seems no matter what I do
~ It tears my heart in two
~ The trouble with love is
~ The trouble with love
~ It can tear you up inside
~ Make your heart believe a lie
~ It's stronger than your pride
~ The trouble with love is
~ It's in your heart, it's in your soul
~ It doesn't care how fast you fall
~ You're losing that control
~ And you can't refuse the call
~ See you got no say at all
~ The trouble with love is
~ Ooh, yeah
~ It can tear you up inside
~ Ooh ~
(~ Girls Aloud: Jump)
~ Your eyes tell me how you want me
~ I can feel it in your heartbeat
~ You're so excited
I can feel you getting hotter
~ Oh baby
~ I'll take you down, I'll take you down
~ Where no one's ever gone before
~ And if you want more
~ lf you want more, more, more
~ Then jump for my love
~ Jump in
~ And feel my touch
~ Jump
~ lf you want to taste my kisses in the night
~ Then jump for my love
~ I know my heart
~ I know my heart can make you happy
~ Jump in
~ You know these arms can fill you up
~ Jump
~ lf you want to taste my kisses in the night
~ Then jump for my love ~