Don't sit so far away.
Anything that creates
a distance should be avoided.
OK.
And try not to frown.
- I'm sorry. Was I frowning?
- You have to relax.
How can I be expected to open up
if you're not relaxed?
- Right.
- Take a deep breath.
Start again.
As you can see, this piece of paper
has been divided into squares.
There are 287 of them.
Your sex history will fit on this
single page in a cryptic code.
Don't forget to mention
there's no written key to the code.
The subject will only be candid if he knows
he's speaking in the strictest confidence.
Right. OK.
So, when were you born?
June 23, 1894.
- Are you single or married?
- Married.
What is your race?
Don't waste time asking the obvious,
Martin. Fill it in yourself.
- What is your religion?
- Methodist.
- How often do you attend church?
- Not at all now.
But I did regularly until I was 19.
How did you get along with your father
and mother when you were growing up?
That's a multiple question. It allows me
to ignore any part I don't want to answer.
- How did you get along with your mother?
- Fine. We had a close relationship.
And your father?
How did you get along with your father?
And what are we to do?
We turn away from matters of the flesh,
and we turn to things... of the spirit.
Lust has a thousand avenues -
the dance hall, the ice-cream parlor,
the tenement saloon, the Turkish bath.
Like the Hydra...
it grows new heads. Everything.
Even the modern inventions of science
are used to cultivate immorality.
The gas engine...
has brought us the automobile joyride.
And an even more pernicious menace,
the roadside brothel.
Electricity... has made possible
the degrading picture show.
Because of the telephone,
a young woman
can hear the voice of her suitor
on the pillow, right next to her.
And let's not forget...
the most scandalous invention of all -
the taloned slide fastener,
otherwise known as the zipper,
which provides every man and boy
speedy access...
to moral oblivion!
- Are you currently in good health?
- I suppose so.
- What makes you doubtful?
- Every doctor I've seen.
Early disease left me
with a weakened heart.
- Any illnesses that kept you out of school?
- I had typhoid fever and rickets.
Also, rheumatic fever,
measles, chicken pox, pneumonia
and several bouts of influenza.
Pomeroy, what are you doing?
You're worse than Martin.
- Never make judgments about people.
- I wasn't.
Your body posture told me that my list
of ailments made you uncomfortable.
Maybe it did. Sorry.
Maintaining a nonjudgmental attitude
is harder than you think.
The best way is to smile, nod your head,
while looking me directly in the eye.
Where were we?
Your health as a boy.
lt improved greatly when
I finally discovered the outdoors.
I never got over the excitement
of setting off into the wild,
escaping bed, illness, family.
Alone?
No, no. Never alone.
I was surrounded by friends.
Being in the outdoors taught me
to rely on my own judgment.
I started to learn about things
by grasping them,
tasting them, looking at them.
- Biology.
- Yes, biology.
The science of life.
Fields and woods became
my new place of worship, my cathedral.
The only sadness they brought
was when I had to leave them.
How old were you when you
first tried to pleasure yourself?
No, no. No euphemisms.
lf you're talking to a college graduate,
use masturbation, testicles, penis,
vagina, vulva, urination, defecation.
With the lower-level male,
it's jacking off, balls, prick, cunt, piss, shit.
Gebhard, maybe your Harvard degree
is too ivory tower for our purposes.
I was brought up out west. I've mixed
with ranchers, miners, my whole life.
I thought you were gonna
shave that moustache.
- I like it.
- It's a disguise, a cover-up.
Look at any movie. The villain's
always the one with the moustache.
My wife likes it.
You have a chance to make an important
contribution to knowledge and science.
Are you telling me you'd give that up
for a little facial hair?
Yes, I suppose I am.
Well... keep it trimmed.
Let's get back to masturbation.
That's a mating call.
So how'd you wind up
at the Stevens lnstitute, Al?
I thought you wanted to be a biologist.
''There are enough scientists
in the world, son.''
''Engineers are what society needs now.''
l...
I had one of the old fits again.
I tried to stop it.
''Any habit which causes the sex fluid
to be discharged must be resisted.''
''Doctors link it to an assortment
of illnesses including insanity,
blindness, epilepsy, even death.''
What if it happens while you're asleep?
''lt is said the loss of one ounce of
seminal fluid equals 40 ounces of blood.''
I'm killing myself and I'm not even awake.
What are we supposed to do?
''Keep your bowels open.''
''Read the Sermon on the Mount.''
''Sit with your testicles submerged
in a bowl of cold water.''
''Think of your mother's pure love.''
Why don't we pray?
Keep firing questions.
Extreme rapidity makes it
difficult for a subject to lie.
How young were you when you first
had an orgasm while dreaming?
- How frequently did you have wet dreams?
- What did you dream about?
How young were you when you
first experienced hugging or kissing?
- Necking.
- Petting.
Oral sex.
How young were you when you no longer
thought of your parents' home as yours?
Al?
It's getting late.
Let's make our rounds.
- Al!
- Be right down.
Pack of Fatimas.
OK, son. That'll be 15 cents.
You're a criminal.
I shall report you to the local authorities.
Dear Jesus, a goddamn Protestant.
- Did you sell this vile weed to a minor?
- What business is that of yours?
lt is the Lord's work to protect
the young from temptation.
- Men like you, sir...
- Get the hell out of my store!
- ..are offensive to the great mass...
Shut up! You know what you are, Father?
- A prig.
- Al.
A skinflint, a petty tyrant,
and a hypocrite to boot.
You think you matter?
You don't matter.
There's something wrong with him.
Come on, Al.
No.
Maybe your workload is too heavy.
You could drop mechanical drawing.
I've withdrawn from Stevens.
That's impossible.
I'm a senior member of the faculty.
- Someone would've informed me.
- Why? Everyone there hates you.
I'm going to Bowdoin to study biology.
- How do you intend to pay for that?
- They've given me a partial scholarship.
And I've socked away
most of my Scouting money.
You've become a shady person, Al.
A person who keeps secrets.
I had no choice.
What a disappointment
you turned out to be.
How many years of schooling
did you complete?
20. After taking
my undergraduate degree at Bowdoin,
I received my doctorate from
the Bussey lnstitute at Harvard.
I took a position as assistant professor
of zoology here at Indiana University.
At first I studied the Rhaetulus didieri,
or stag beetle.
Then I discovered a far more
fascinating insect.
This is the American Cynipidae,
or gall wasp.
Here the wasp deposits an egg
into its host plant.
ln this case, an oak tree.
The adult wasp chews its way
through the tree,
and copulates.
At which point,
it has the good sense to die.
The animal kingdom includes
at least two million insect species.
So, what makes the gall wasp
so fascinating?
I've spent the last three years
crisscrossing the continent,
collecting gall wasps.
What have I learned from my friends
half the size of the household ant?
That you need a date.
After studying thousands of these
pesky creatures under the microscope,
I've yet to find a single gall wasp
that's the same as another.
ln fact, some are so different
that the offspring of one generation
bear no more resemblance to their parents
than a sheep bears to a goat!
There are those of us
who might take comfort in this fact.
Consider the implications.
lf every single living thing is different
from every other living thing,
then diversity becomes
life's one irreducible fact.
Only variations are real.
And to see them,
you simply have to open your eyes.
Good catch.
Hello. Mind if I sit here?
Why?
Because you're the only unattached male
and I'm the only unattached female.
That's very sensible.
A man who cooks - how refreshing.
I picked it up when I went west to
collect galls. I was gone for 11 months.
I don't think I saw more
than a dozen people.
Sounds lonely.
I enjoyed it.
I've been reading up on gall wasps.
I think I know why they appeal to you.
They have great big wings
but they can't fly.
They're incapable of getting from this hill
to that unless it's close enough to walk,
which means it's possible
to retrace each generation's steps,
hill by hill by hill by hill,
all the way back to the very beginning.
- The gall wasp Garden of Eden.
- That's interesting, Miss Millen.
You've bridged the gap between Darwin
and the Book of Genesis in a single phrase.
McMillen.
Clara McMillen.
- I'm Prok.
- Sorry?
It's a nickname my graduate students
have given me. Pro-fessor K-insey. Prok.
I worried it suggested
an inappropriate level of intimacy
between teacher and student
that could lead to a loss of respect.
I think itjust means they like you.
Yes. Eventually I realized that.
- Tomato bisque and sandwiches?
- Please.
- Such an impressive collection.
- Thanks.
They used to be categorized by period.
Then I arranged them by composer.
I find it's more efficient.
Did you ever think about playing
professionally? You're very good!
Thank you, but ''very good''
isn't good enough.
I got you a present.
Here.
How marvelous.
They're the right size.
At what age did you first
have premarital intercourse?
I didn't.
- At the time of marriage, you were a virgin.
- Yes.
- Was your spouse also a virgin?
When you got married,
did you want to get married?
Very much.
I see marriage as a lifetime
partnership between equals.
You're a brilliant scholar
with a keenly perceptive mind
and a profound respect for nature.
You're a capable hiker and camper,
and a champion swimmer.
You're the one girl who's
as interested in insects as I am.
To be honest, Prok... I'm just not sure.
OK.
- I consider myself a free thinker.
- Yes.
Frankly, I find you a little churchy.
- Churchy?
- And I've had another proposal.
I'm not saying no.
I just need time.
Prok...
I think you're mean.
Mean, heartless, and cold.
Astounding.
lf you'll have me.
Gall wasp in amber.
- How old is it?
- About 80 million years or so.
Does Mrs Kinsey like her wedding present?
It's perfect.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, l...
How beautiful.
May l?
I'm sorry.
I'm a little nervous.
- It's OK. We don't have to...
- No.
I'm ready.
Forgive me, Mac.
No, I'm sorry.
It's just, it hurts too much.
It's... it's a long drive to my parents'.
We should get some sleep.
Robert's had a 92 in mechanical drawing.
A 95 in mathematics, right?
And a clean 100 in shop practice.
That's splendid, Robert.
Congratulations.
I was worried his teachers were showing
him favor due to my senior position.
But they tell me he is the most
gifted student in his class.
Living with the best teacher
at Stevens doesn't hurt, Father.
Please.
No, at this rate he'll finish
his degree in... three years.
Al, tell us what you've been working on.
- Well...
- Don't bother, Al.
She won't be able to follow you.
She's only had a fourth-grade education.
I'm studying gall wasps, Mom.
I've gathered over 100,000 specimens,
which is really only a drop
in the bucket. But my aim is...
Ten years of higher education
and he's still collecting bugs.
Prok's also written a biology textbook.
Really?
It's read in colleges across the country.
It's actually a very good read.
So I assume you plan
to start a family soon?
Oh, no. Don't rush it.
Once you have children,
you're tied down forever.
Your life is over.
What?
I don't know what I expected,
but he's far worse than I ever imagined.
He is pretty awful, isn't he?
''l once read...
that the decline of the Roman Empire
was the result of too-frequent bathing!''
''Some speculate that rampant adultery
is a possible cause of earthquakes.''
I'm sorry you had to witness that.
I think I really fell in love with you tonight.
Seeing you here.
Do you think we can make this work, Mac?
I don't know.
I've heard some people
just don't fit together.
There's no one I'd rather be with.
Physically, I mean.
lf only there was a way to know.
That's it, Mac.
Every problem has a solution,
even this one.
We just need to talk to someone -
an expert who studied the matter.
What are you doing?
Why waste any more time?
Your hymen shows
an inordinate thickness.
Dr Kinsey... how large is your penis?
- Excuse me?
- When erect, how large is it?
How long from the scrotum? Here?
Here?
I'm surprised you didn't pass out.
- ls there anything we can do?
- It's a common problem.
Would you like to take care of it today?
Sure.
God, God, God.
The maximum frequency of intercourse
with your spouse in a seven-day period?
I'd say 20 or so.
At least three times a day the first week,
so 21 at a minimum.
ls there tongue kissing?
- Yes.
- Hand on breast?
- Mouth?
- Hand on female genitalia?
- Hand on penis?
- Yes.
- Mouth on female genitalia?
- Mouth on penis?
- Yes. Yes.
- Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
I became pregnant with Anne in 1923.
I decided to give up my graduate work.
By the time Anne was born
I had collected over 200,000 gall wasps.
Joan came along a year later.
After Joan's fifth birthday,
I reached my goal of half a million wasps.
And Bruce is our youngest.
Bruce found the gall
that hatched the millionth wasp.
- It was in mountains outside Mexico City.
- They grow up so fast.
We just didn't know who to talk to,
Professor Kinsey.
- What about your parents?
- I'd rather die.
We heard you had good advice
for the biology students.
Sexual difficulty among
newly married people is common.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
- How long have you been married?
- Two months now.
And Emily, you've had absolutely
no response during that time?
It's like I'm dead down there.
We went to the doctor,
and he said there's nothing wrong.
Does Ben ever use
his fingers to excite you?
Why bother?
Now that we can do the real thing.
What's your most common
sexual position?
There's more than one?
Mac and I are still discovering some.
Were you sexually experienced
before you got married?
No.
I still thought babies
came out of women's navels.
Did you ever masturbate?
It's all my fault.
I'm damaged in some way.
I'm frigid.
I don't think that's the problem at all.
Ben, do you ever perform oral sex on Emily?
- I don't know what that means, sir.
- Genital kissing.
My brother told me that
that causes problems.
Later on, with having babies.
I don't think that's true.
No, I heard that, too.
I assure you, there's no relation
between oral sex and pregnancy.
- But how do you know?
- How do I know the Earth is round?
ltjust is.
But has anyone actually proven
that there's no connection?
lf you're asking whether there's been
a study devoted to the subject
of oral copulation and fertility,
well, frankly, I don't know.
Well, then, how can you be sure?
I felt like a blundering amateur.
I couldn't imagine where this kid's crazy
idea came from until I discovered this.
ldeal Marriage:
lts Physiology and Technique,
Oh, dear.
''Oral contact, while acceptable
as a means of stimulation,
is pathological if carried through to orgasm,
and possibly injurious.''
- I must be in grave danger, then.
- And wait.
''The hands should never be used
for the purpose of sexual excitation.''
''There is but one finger of love
with which to approach the female genitals,
and that is the male organ.''
It's all just hooey.
Morality disguised as fact.
Just do your tie.
Professor Kinsey's methods
of collecting vast numbers of gall wasps
over a wide geographic range
have made him a starred scientist.
They have also earned him
his immortal nickname,
''Get-a-Million Kinsey.''
''Bore-a-Million Kinsey.''
His new book,
The Origin of Higher Categories in,,,
Cynips? Cy-nips?
Close enough.
..traces the origin of the gall wasp back
to its birthplace in the Upper Cretaceous.
So, now, I give you Dr Kinsey.
Thank you, President Wells, for that
incisive description of 20 years of work.
I thought you might've read my book
until I saw those crib notes in your palm.
Crib notes.
My other book on cynips hasn't been
checked out of the library in six years.
I'd be surprised if
a dozen people have read it.
But I guess I always knew
that gall wasps weren't going to...
make them beat a path to my door.
ln any case, thank you, Herman.
This is splendid.
A really fine event, indeed.
Thank you.
Cheers, Prok. Congratulations.
Here, here.
Some reform-minded undergraduates
paid me a visit the other day, Thurman.
- They're campaigning for a sex course.
- I covered sex in the hygiene class.
Which the student paper called
''the most useless course.''
Oh, Kinsey. I'm glad to see middle age
hasn't softened the edges. Mrs Kinsey.
Not only is your class irrelevant,
it's irresponsible. There's a VD epidemic.
That's my fault? I don't know
whether to be insulted or flattered.
Besides, there's a cure for syphilis.
- It's called ''abstinence.''
- Penicillin works just as well.
Herman. The trustees appointed you
to shake things up around here.
Why not address
the need for sex instruction
that deals with
students' real questions, concerns?
Open sex instruction
promotes daydreaming.
lt is better to address these matters
in a general medical course.
You mean an anti-sex course with
irrelevant gabble about dahlias and bees.
Gentlemen, please. I'm going to take
the students' proposal under advisement.
- Good.
- But since I just got this job,
and wouldn't mind hanging on to it
for a couple of weeks,
I think I'm gonna stick with
the hygiene course for now.
Medical authorities state that,
of the type of teenage girls
applying at public health stations for aid,
the percentage that is infected with
venereal disease is always very high.
ln all of these cases, where youthful energy
and inquisitiveness are unrestrained,
the sex urge is always present.
And promiscuity nearly always follows,
with its inevitable harvest of abortions,
illegitimate births and... disease.
- What's your trouble, Jerry?
- Well, I've got a bad sore down here.
Stretch out on that table.
We'll have a look.
This story vividly portrays
the misery caused to innocent victims
by the ignorance or selfishness
of individuals infected with syphilis.
You can't tell by the looks
of a woman whether she has syphilis.
That finishes me. I'll have to go someplace
where people don't know who I am.
The cure forjuvenile delinquency
is an education
in the dangers and consequences
of breaking the time-tested rules laid down
for the regulation of human conduct.
The idea that men need sex is a lie.
lf it were true, the boy who exercises
his sex organs regularly
would achieve the greatest
sexual experiences in later life.
Whereas, in fact, that boy
is likely to be sexually dead
by the time he reaches adulthood.
Abstinence poses no difficulty
for the college-age male.
Men don't reach their sexual peak
until the age of 40.
lt is the lower-class male, often Negro,
who finds it difficult to control his urges.
However, perfect inhibition,
although an ideal to be striven for,
is not always achievable.
Stress, and the worries of the day,
can lead to a weakening of resolve,
opening the door to temptation.
When tense at bedtime...
I find there are little tricks to relaxing.
lf I can't get to sleep,
I like to close my eyes...
and think of all the Johns I know.
Well, not only Johns.
Sometimes Peters.
How about Dicks?
I'm sorry?
lf you're here for Dr Kinsey's class, it's only
open to faculty members and their wives,
graduate students, seniors
and married undergraduates.
Come back and try in the spring.
- Are you a senior?
- We're engaged.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Why offer a marriage course?
Because society has interfered
with what should be a normal,
biological development,
causing a scandalous delay
of sexual activity.
Which leads to sexual difficulty
in early marriage.
ln an uninhibited society, a 12-year-old
would know most of the biology
which I will have to give you
in formal lectures.
So, let's start with the six stages
of the coital sequence.
Stimulation,
lubrication, erection,
increased sensitivity,
orgasm and nervous release.
Both sexes experience
all six stages equally.
Stim-u-lation.
Who can tell me which part
of the human body can enlarge 100 times?
Miss.
I'm sure I don't know.
You've no right to ask me
such a question in a mixed class.
I was referring to the pupil
of your eye, young lady.
And I think I should tell you,
you're in for a terrible disappointment.
lt is often with the eye
that stimulation begins.
The adjustments which are made
in the male and female genitalia
are shown on this slide.
The vagina must be spread open
as the erect male organ penetrates.
You will see that the clitoris is swollen,
providing the erotic stimulation
necessary for the completion of the act
on the part of the female.
You will also see
that this point on the penis,
which is one of the most sensitive points,
is similarly stimulated.
Where on earth did you get that cap?
Oh, Professor Kinsey. I'm sorry.
It's a whaler's hat. Not very pretty,
but extremely practical in a storm.
- Do I know you?
- I'm in your marriage course. Clyde Martin.
How are you finding it, Mr Martin?
It's the most enlightening class
I've ever taken.
I better get going. I've got ajob interview
at the zoology department.
Forget that. Come with me.
All right.
Dr Kinsey will be staying late.
He'll get to all of you.
Can too much sex cause cancer?
- Will wearing high heels make me sterile?
- I think my vagina's abnormally shaped.
- Can you get syphilis from a whistle?
- ls homosexuality a form of insanity?
I think about my cat... a lot.
Does suppressing sex
lead to stuttering?
''ls my penis smaller than most?''
''Does too much masturbation
cause premature ejaculation?''
''ls it unusual for my boyfriend
to touch my anus?''
All excellent questions.
And they all have the same answer:
I don't know.
From a sexual standpoint,
it's hard to say what's common or rare
because we know so little
about what people actually do.
This leaves most of us
feeling anxious or guilty.
''Am I interested in the right things?''
''Do I do things the normal way?''
One of the ways of finding out what people do
is to find out what they've done.
So, please, take the time to fill out
these sex questionnaires.
Try to be as accurate and honest
as you possibly can.
This will only work...
Pass that down.
This will only work if you tell the truth.
Dr Kinsey, this is really amazing.
These colors are incredible.
It's the most complete collection
east of the Mississippi.
We have over 250
separate varieties of irises.
Good work, Martin,
but you're using the wrong muscle group.
Come on. Here, bend the legs.
Use the thighs.
The arms should only be used to guide.
No, you do it.
Guide...
Lemonade.
Mac, these responses will floor you.
The gap between what we assume people do
and what they actually do is enormous.
What amazes me is there's no relation
between how sexy a girl looks
and her sex life.
The ugly ones seem to get all the action.
I always thought ''ugly'' was an ugly word.
Sorry.
Not only does every male have a history
of masturbation. Most of the women do.
That doesn't surprise me.
What about premarital sex?
About a third of the married men
claim at least one experience.
- Only one in ten for the women.
- lf they're telling the truth.
And there's extramarital sex, too.
Notjust heterosexual, but homosexual.
I just wish we could get more volunteers.
100 cases is hardly representative.
Maybe it's because it's a questionnaire.
Feels too much like a test.
I agree. Also, people don't
know if they can trust you.
They have to be sure their secrets are safe.
That's ridiculous. Everyone knows I keep
those questionnaires under lock and key.
Clyde has a point.
You're asking people to reveal information
that's very sensitive,
possibly even damaging.
What if you just talk to them?
Then all their secrets would be in your head.
Martin, you should have
spoken up months ago.
- I can't tell. Was that a compliment?
- Yes, I think it was.
People resist, but I'm trying
to choreograph the questions
so they'll be disarmed into answering.
- How many things did you put in there?
- It's the Kinsey stew.
- ''Clean out the refrigerator night.''
- Martin's been helpful.
He's an ideal practice subject since
he's had relations with both men and women.
- Where have you been?
- Swim practice.
- How'd it go?
- Pretty good.
- Coach might start me at the next meet.
- That's wonderful.
There won't be any swimming
unless your science grades improve.
- I hate biology.
- Because you never developed your intellect.
Physical activity is important, son,
but your interest in sports is excessive.
Yes. Maybe he should
take up engineering instead.
The one-on-one is turning
out to be so elastic.
Talking yields more information
than I imagined.
lt'll prove to be
a groundbreaking technique.
What if they make things up?
That's what I'd do.
I'm building in little tripwires
to catch lies and inconsistencies.
- Would you like to take my sex history?
- Do you have a sex history, sweetie?
- No.
- What about you, Anne?
- You've been dating Jim for a while now.
- We've done some petting.
I figured we wouldn't try
intercourse until college.
That's probably better.
lf Anne can have intercourse,
I should be able to.
Your sister's 18
and seriously involved with someone.
Does it hurt?
- What, dear?
- Breaking the hymen.
Just a little.
It's nothing too bad.
lt helps if you spread the vulva
to facilitate penetration.
Can we please talk about
something else for once?
Other families don't do this.
lt isn't normal.
When did you become such a prig?
My friends aren't allowed here.
Their parents think you're a menace.
You spend too much time in the water.
Chlorine's done something to your brain!
- Have you learned nothing?
- I don't know where he came from.
Nothing.
- Bruce? Bruce.
- I don't want to talk about it.
- I just want him to get off my back.
- Bruce...
I heard about this community
from a former student.
This is my third trip.
The results have been astounding.
By my calculation, there are over
300,000 cases here in Chicago.
No one's bothered
to talk to them before.
It's a gold mine of information, Martin.
We've got it all to ourselves.
- What'll it be, handsome?
- Two Scotches.
I find liquor is an essential tool
for social lubrication.
Although it does involve more drinking
than I thought I would ever do in a lifetime.
Let's get started.
Hello, I'm Professor Kinsey
from Indiana University.
And I'm making a study of sex behavior.
Can we sit and talk?
- I assume you're joking.
- No, I'm not.
I'd be grateful if you'd answer
some questions about your sexual history.
Mary here is a professor. She says
she wants to study my sex behavior.
Well, tell her to stick around and watch.
Come on. Andy's here.
You have to see what he's wearing.
I can't wait.
Andy.
Hello, I'm Professor Kinsey from...
Excuse me, I'm Professor Kinsey.
Excuse me.
Hello, I'm Professor Kinsey
from Indiana University.
I'm making a study of sex behavior.
Can I ask you a few questions?
I've heard about you.
You're the sex doctor, right?
I guess I am. lf you'd be
kind enough to talk to me,
it would be of great help to science.
Sure. What do you want to know?
..same boy, Tommy Potts.
We were messing around in a haystack.
You know, like kids will do.
Pop walked in.
Found us, locked us in the barn.
Called my brothers in.
They...
They branded us.
Took turns doing it.
Then they beat us raw.
Broke a couple of ribs.
Collarbone.
Tommy, he...
He didn't make out as well as I did.
- What age were you?
- 13.
- And you've been on your own since then?
- I get by.
It's not that I mind being queer.
'Cause I don't.
It's just...
I wish other folks weren't so put out by it.
Homosexuality happens to be
out of fashion in society now.
That doesn't mean
it won't change someday.
Right.
But why didn't I see it before?
Human beings are just bigger,
more complicated gall wasps.
All I have to do is collect
more than anyone else.
Homosexuals are the perfect place to start.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
I had an image of our friends
hearing you now.
As if the marriage course
isn't bad enough.
Now, Prok, promise me, you'll get
four hours' sleep before heading back.
- Of course.
- And let Clyde share in the driving.
Prok?
OK, Mac.
I'll sign off now.
I love you.
Love you, too.
You know what impressed me tonight?
ls the way that you talk to people.
You can getjust about
anybody to open up.
It's just a matter of putting
yourself on their level.
No, it's more than that.
You really seem to care.
This rating scale of yours?
Zero to six?
Zero being exclusively heterosexual
and... six being exclusively homosexual.
A great many people line up in the middle.
- What makes you think that's true?
- Common sense.
Remember, about a third
of our heterosexual histories
have homosexual acts, and vice-versa.
Right.
I guess I'm about a ''three.''
Based on your sexual history,
I'd say that's... right.
How about you?
I suppose I've been a ''one'' or ''two''...
most of my life,
even though it's taken
a long time to... recognize it.
And now?
Probably...
''three.''
Have you ever done anything about it?
Would you like to?
I've taken on so many
other people's secrets.
I don't want any of my own,
and certainly not with you.
You still haven't said anything.
It's not like I'm surprised, exactly.
I've observed...
certain things over the years.
- Such as?
- A look or a gesture.
The pet student who suddenly
becomes a member of the family,
then just as suddenly disappears
when you tire of him.
You must know me better
than I know myself.
I'm not sure I understand.
Haven't I always been open
to whatever you wanted?
It's not you, Mac.
You're the best partner any man could have.
I'm just not enough. ls that it?
Please, Mac. This is inside of me.
To what extent, I don't know.
But I'd be a hypocrite
if I pretended it wasn't there.
- You said you had feelings for other men...
- Don't use that against me.
I'm sorry, but what keeps you
from acting on your feelings?
- Convention.
- No. It's our marriage.
- It's our children.
- Exactly. Social restraints.
Did you ever think that perhaps
those restraints are there
to keep people from hurting each other?
I don't sleep with other men because
I love you, and I don't want to hurt you.
- But what if it didn't hurt me?
- Then I'd be hurt.
You're afraid I won't love you anymore,
which is impossible, Mac.
The human animal is capable
of all kinds of sexual expression.
Not all sex has to be sanctioned by love,
enriched by emotion...
Stop.
Stop lecturing, Prok.
Stop using science
to justify what you've done.
Oh, Mac.
Mac.
Listen to me.
You're my girl.
You always will be.
The bond we have, the life we share -
sex is nothing compared to that.
I can't talk about this any more.
Most people think that what
they do sexually is what everyone does.
Or should do.
But I might remark that nearly
all the so-called sexual perversions
fall within the range of biologic normality.
For example, masturbation,
mouth-genital contacts
and homosexual acts
are common among most mammals,
including humans.
Society might condemn
such practices on moral grounds.
However, it's ludicrous
to call them ''unnatural.''
But based on the first book of Genesis,
and according to public opinion,
there's only one correct sexual equation:
man plus woman equals baby.
Everything else is vice.
But the orgasm record of the males
in this classroom alone
proves the ineffectiveness
of social restrictions
and the imperativeness
of the biologic demand.
Why are some cows highly sexed,
while others just stand there?
Why do some men need 30 orgasms
a week, and others almost none?
Because everyone is different.
The problem is,
most people want to be the same.
They find it easier to simply ignore
this fundamental aspect
of the human condition.
They are so eager to be part of the group,
they'll betray their
own nature to get there.
lf something pleasurable
and strongly desired is prohibited,
it becomes an obsession.
Think about this.
You have better things to do than help
a middle-aged woman with her groceries.
Prok got worried when
he couldn't reach you.
Said he had to take histories
later this evening, so...
''He'd like an early dinner,
preferably five o'clock.''
Hardly gives me time to boil an egg.
- Can I help?
- No, I'll manage. I just...
- I'm sorry he made you play messenger.
- No, I volunteered.
Hear that?
- What?
- Sound of an empty nest.
Must be a big adjustment.
Have you heard from Bruce yet?
No. He's loving college.
Maybe it's just being away from here.
- Would you like a piece of pie?
- Rhubarb?
Have a seat.
You know, Clyde...
I didn't like you very much at first.
I don't blame you.
- Most women would've had me murdered.
- I considered it.
I hate to think of myself as conventional.
But, if this had to happen,
I'm glad it was you.
And, I have to admit,
there have been some benefits.
lt certainly sparked things up sexually.
I suppose we'd both grown bored
without even realizing it.
I think you've handled it remarkably well.
I learned something a long time ago:
once Prok has his mind set,
it's no use trying to stop him.
Yes.
He is...
relentless.
Clyde.
You know, this thing between Prok and me,
it was fine for a while, but...
I guess I just really miss
sleeping with women.
That's perfectly understandable.
It's clear from your history you have
a greater sexual in interest in women.
Good. Then you won't mind if
I ask Mac to have sex with me.
Only if it appeals to you, of course.
- Would it be separately or together?
- Definitely just you and l.
Well, I think I might like that.
What do you think, Prok?
Mac, the Rockefeller Foundation
is coming today.
You know I enjoy this... tremendously.
We still have to catalogue
those prints, Martin. Please.
Coming, Prok.
It's just, it's a very full day.
Coming.
One key to understanding
a foreign culture is its pornography.
Every culture produces its own peculiar
sexual imagery, as distinct as its cuisine.
As you can see, Brazil's imagery
tends towards zelophilia,
while ltaly favors nuns and priests.
ln England, one often sees depictions
of the stern headmistress.
Wankers and spankers.
While in the Far East,
it's soft flage and light bondage.
- You've amassed an impressive collection.
- Thank you.
Only what I've been able to afford
from my own savings.
lf the Rockefeller Foundation
agrees to our grant,
some of that money will help us build
a world-class library. Herman.
That's 200 years old.
Have you any idea
when you might decide?
Prok, please.
Dr Gregg just got here.
Sometimes I'm amazed
anything has survived.
The Library of Congress has a policy of
destroying whatever it considers too erotic.
The loss to science has been incalculable.
There's time to take your sex histories
before dinner. Who'd like to go first?
l... I don't...
Early in my bug-hunting days,
someone asked me what I was looking for.
I said I wouldn't know
until I saw it statistically.
A scientist can only generalize
with reliable certainty
if he has enough statistical information.
- ls this your first time in Bloomington?
- Yes. It's lovely. Hillier than I expected.
That's why I've broken
the American population down
into 200 major social subgroups.
We'll get 400 to 1000 histories
from each group
for a total of 100,000, give or take a few.
lt could take 20 years,
but we'll finally be able to answer
most of the basic questions
about human sexuality.
- Herman, is the pot roast dry?
- No, it's delicious.
The first publication will be a male volume,
followed a year later by the female study.
Then nine books dealing with sex offenders,
homosexuality, pregnancy and abortion.
And art, studied from a sexual standpoint.
With the children gone,
I don't get to cook big meals anymore.
Mac.
Let's get to the point.
This project is one of the greatest undertaken
in connection with the human animal.
But without support from the Rockefeller
Foundation, it will never get off the ground.
There are those who argue that...
sex is largely a matter of feelings
and psychological attitudes -
things beyond your training as a zoologist.
That's like saying a biochemist can't
analyze cooking because he's not a chef.
- It's inane.
- Prok, come on.
That is, it's really a very
stupid way of looking at things.
One of the aims of science is to simplify.
The only way to study sex
with any scientific accuracy
is to strip away everything
but its physiological functions.
And this team you're proposing...
I'll need two pairs of hands,
with advanced degrees in science.
And Clyde Martin, of course.
Since you're working
in such a delicate area,
they need to be as clean
as Fuller Brush men.
Door-to-door salesmen, Prok.
What Dr Gregg is saying is,
anyone involved
needs to have motives that are pure,
scientific, and above reproach morally.
I couldn't agree more.
Now, there's one more thing.
I hope you're not planning to dwell
on sexual oddities and perversions.
Science is always interested in the rare.
Yes, but it's advisable
to stick to what's normal.
You don't want to shake people up.
Of course not.
I'm just a taxonomist, a measurer.
I'm happy to leave
the social policies to others.
Well, that all sounds good.
Very good.
So, if you're ready, I'd like to begin
with a few background questions.
No, all wrong.
Start by putting the subject at ease.
- Would you care for a drink, Mac?
- A glass of water would be very nice.
- Do anything fun this weekend?
- My daughters were in town.
I never stopped.
We had a marvelous meal Saturday night.
- What did you cook?
- I started with...
See how much more relaxed
she's become?
Ease in with innocuous questions and
people forget they're giving sex histories.
- How did you find out about masturbation?
- I invented it, son.
Sometimes I tie a rope around my balls
when I jerk off.
What other masochistic acts do you enjoy?
Does that mean ''queer?''
How often do you have intercourse?
Two or three times.
- A month?
- No, a day.
- How often do you reach orgasm?
- Once.
- A day?
- No, only once.
About 20 years ago.
I was sitting on a piano stool,
listening to music.
That's good.
How old were you when you first
had sexual activity with a partner?
14.
- How?
- With horse.
How often were you having
intercourse with animals at 14?
It's true.
I fucked a pony.
You are genius.
How did you know?
You just said you had sex with a horse.
No. Whores, not horse. Whores.
Do you find my answers typical?
- Am I normal?
Am I normal?
I found a book in the dining room buffet,
under all the tablecloths.
And I used to put it under my shirt,
and go into the bathroom and sit and read.
But I was very frightened...
She told her mother she didn't like it.
Or maybe it was just
her mother who didn't like it.
Before you know it,
the police are banging on the front door...
I didn't even know it was illegal.
And now I'm in here for five years.
..l guess I was about nine, ten.
Then she said she was gonna show me
a new game called ''puddin'.''
And I guess I kind of liked it.
- Horses in the stable...
- Out in the field...
..nobody believed me.
Do men put their thing in women?
..you were a fallen woman.
Nobody would want you.
..masculine and feminine traits.
- They were both naked.
- It was part of...
My clothes...
You may kiss the bride.
Professor Kinsey found
a place for us to live.
Let me guess -
it's just a few blocks from here.
- How did you know?
- He likes to keep the troops in one place.
- At least you passed the test.
- What do you mean?
Well, he took your sex history, didn't he?
Well, he wouldn't have let
Clyde marry you unless you fit in.
Didn't Clyde mention the calendars?
Prok likes us to keep a record
of our sexual activity.
Buddy, tell them about that dream
you had the other night.
I was in the middle of the most
intense erotic encounter...
- He wouldn't say who with.
- All of a sudden, the doors flew open.
And there was Prok, with that stern look.
''Hurry up. You're wasting
countless hours of project time.''
- The mood was broken.
- He woke up. I had to take over.
lt was the quickest orgasm he ever had.
We're trying to get pregnant again, so there
was no raincoat to dull the sensation.
Do the Kinseys know
that you talk like this?
Could I get a picture?
Call me when you get back from
the honeymoon. We'll have a nice, long lunch.
Look at the birdie.
No, I've got them.
Thank you.
''Often among boys
who live in cities and towns, comma,
less often among farm boys, period.''
Perhaps you want to say,
''boys from small towns.''
Say... say ''farm boys.''
What's the difference?
He's gonna rewrite it anyway. Henry!
Everything looks in order.
You can have Thanksgiving or Christmas off.
Your choice entirely.
Do you need anything before I go?
We'll never get this book done
if people leave early.
I'll stay if you let me help you.
You don't have the time to answer each one.
lf people write, it's the least I can do.
Mrs Kinsey said to remind you
to come home to eat.
And your father phoned again.
Do you want me to talk to him?
No. I'll do it.
Thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory, forever and ever.
- Amen.
- Hello, Mildred.
- Mr Morrissey.
Come say hello to Father.
I'm very sad for you, Alfred.
Well...
It's not as though I'll be alone.
My daughter's too fat to get a husband.
My son's lost his business
and moved back home.
The only one I got rid of is the big scientist.
Now he's working on some...
secret project.
He was always the secretive type.
Would you really like to know
what I'm working on, Father?
Listen. He's gonna tell me his big secret.
It's really not a secret at all. I'm trying
to find out what people do sexually.
You heard right, Father.
It's a sex study.
- What do you expect me to do, applaud?
- No.
But I would like you
to contribute to the project.
And you first moved to Hoboken
at what age?
16.
Could have done this interview
without me, Al.
I haven't told you a thing
you didn't know.
Let's move on, then.
How young were you
when you first masturbated?
- What?
- Touched yourself.
I never did that.
The male without a history of masturbation
is almost nonexistent.
Well, he exists, Al.
And you're looking at him.
This isn't gonna work.
I don't know why I bothered.
Stay where you are.
I'll try again.
How often did your masturbation
occur in adolescence?
There was a problem.
''A chronic condition'',
the doctors called it.
How long did this continue?
I was outfitted...
with a tight strap
that I had to wear at all times.
lt kept me from coming into contact
with my genitals.
lt was a...
highly embarrassing remedy.
But it proved effective.
The condition was cured.
How old were you?
I was ten.
I'm so sorry, Dad.
I'm feeling a little tired now.
Sounds to me like you're
wasting your time, Al.
Nobody wants to know about these things.
When can we see Dr Kinsey?
That's him.
That's Kinsey.
My name is Dr Thurman Rice,
and I'd be happy to talk to you
about Professor Kinsey's repugnant book.
You're free to read and take notes
but the manuscript is not to leave the room.
I won't deny the going might get rough.
Dr Kinsey's findings are surprising,
sometimes even shocking.
For example, marital sex,
the only kind everyone agrees on,
is only one of nine means by which
the American male achieves orgasm.
Premarital sex, extramarital sex,
masturbation and homosexuality
are much more prevalent than
anyone has ever imagined before.
I can assure you...
that Dr Kinsey has done everything in
his power to present this book tastefully.
So, I thought this might be a good time
to ask for a formal show of support.
Those in favor...
I just hope it's not going
to bring too much publicity.
With any luck, Mrs Spaulding,
general public won't even notice.
That'll be six fifty, please.
But in a few of the cultures,
sex remains a dirty secret.
Mark my words.
As soon as the publicity dies down,
the American public will greet this book
with the thunder and silence it deserves.
What brings you to New York, Dr Kinsey?
We'll be taking the sex histories
of artists, writers and actors,
including the entire cast
of A Streetcar Named Desire,
We'll also be interviewing women
for our next book, a female study,
as well as meeting with
the Rockefeller Foundation.
- Are you surprised at the book's success?
- No. It shows the world has wanted this done.
Any plans on a Hollywood picture
based on the book?
- I can't think of anything more pointless.
- What about you, Mrs Kinsey?
- Has your life changed much?
- My husband's busier than ever.
- I hardly see him since he's taken up sex.
- What about the female study?
Gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Gentlemen, please.
lf you want to write about something useful,
look into the current sex-offender codes.
The majority of sex offenders in our prisons
have nothing in their histories
different from the rest of the population.
Their only crime is being too poor
to hire a lawyer. This is unfair.
Everybody's sin is nobody's sin.
And everybody's crime is no crime at all.
''Everybody's sin is nobody's sin.''
That wasn't my point at all.
Newspapers lift things out of context
to make sensational reading.
It's hardly your place
to offer moral prescription.
You're sounding more like
a preacher than a scientist.
My father always hoped
I'd become a preacher.
And why do you insist on flaunting
your association with the Foundation?
Haven't I just given you the best-selling
scientific volume ever published?
- Not only here, but across the globe?
- Yes.
And it's casting a bright light
on every aspect of the project.
Especially some of
your latest methodology.
- Who have you been talking to?
- I assume most of it is gossip.
Alan.
It's been said that
you've taken to observing women.
Go on.
ln a heightened state of arousal.
It's true?
Yes. And do you know why?
We went to the leading gynecologists
and asked for physical measurements.
They barely knew
what we were talking about.
When it comes to female sex organs,
we're all tragically ignorant.
- Who are these women?
- Volunteers. Friends of the project.
- Prostitutes?
- No.
Prostitutes are useless.
They fake their orgasms.
- Jesus.
- Alan.
The sex histories we have are invaluable.
True science lies in direct observation.
Nothing can replace what the eye
can see directly. Or the camera.
Camera?
Don't tell me, you're making movies?
Just some photographic studies
of mammalian behavior.
Nature films. Animals?
Yes, if you like.
Gentlemen, you're about to meet
a truly rare creature.
Even the most casual contact
arouses a sexual response in her.
ln intercourse, her first orgasm occurs
within two to five seconds after entry.
- All set there, Barbara?
- I think so.
Come on in.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
Did I mention that Barbara didn't have
her first orgasm until she was 40?
Notice how she gently strokes
the inner lips and the clitoris.
84 per cent of our samples
stimulate themselves this way.
What about the vagina?
For all but a small minority of women,
the vaginal tube is a dead cavity.
Practically devoid of nerve endings.
The introduction of the penis does nothing
to relocate the source of stimulation.
Even with as skilful a partner as Pomeroy.
- That is you, isn't it?
- Last time I looked.
For years, women have been told that
a clitoral orgasm is immature, neurotic.
So they've struggled, with great anxiety,
to relocate the orgasm in the vagina
when, for many,
it's a biologic impossibility.
According to the psychoanalysts,
this woman is frigid.
Good news, everyone.
The Rockefeller Foundation
announced its annual grants today.
We've received 40,000 dollars
for the next year -
the highest grant they've ever bestowed
on a scientific project.
And they've agreed
to underwrite a new corporation,
making us future employees
of the lnstitute for Sex Research.
- Dr Kinsey.
- Here, here.
- And Mrs Kinsey.
And to our husbands,
the Fuller Brush men of sex.
Come here, my little prick nibbler.
Come on, everyone.
Enjoy yourselves.
- You don't look happy.
- No, I am. Really.
It's just that Clyde is going
to be away for so long this time.
Well, don't worry.
I'll keep an eye on him.
A lot of good that will do.
What are you trying to say, Mrs Martin?
God, you're pretty.
Drink up your grape juice.
We've gathered only 9,300 histories.
We have the female volume to complete.
From tomorrow, we need to triple our efforts.
It's still tonight, and since my third leg
keeps hitting me in the face,
I think it's time for a tumble.
ln the bonobo chimpanzee,
our nearest primate relation,
sex is the glue
of social cohesion and peace.
Cleared of notions like romantic love,
religion or morality,
their society's behavior hangs together
as a coherent unit
of biology and conditioning.
Based on the experiences of females
who have contributed to our histories,
we have observed a wide range
of motivations for extramarital coitus.
At times, it is a conscious or unconscious
attempt to acquire social status.
ln other instances, it gives them a variety
of experiences with new sexual partners
who are sometimes superior
to their marriage partner.
There are occasions
when it is done in retaliation
for the partner's extramarital activity,
or for some sort of non-sexual mistreatment.
Some females discover new sources
of emotional satisfaction,
while others find it impossible
to share such an intimate relationship
with more than one partner.
We have also encountered
a considerable group of cases
in which husbands encourage their wives
to engage in extramarital activities
in an honest attempt
to give them the opportunity
for additional sexual satisfaction.
I've corresponded
with this man for over ten years,
but I never thought he'd agree to meet me.
He's amassed a lifetime of data.
Working for the forestry department
has involved a lot of traveling.
So I've met a wide array of people.
- By the way, my name is...
- Please. There's no need.
..Kenneth Braun.
Don't worry, Dr Kinsey.
I trust you.
- We're actually a lot alike, you know.
- How so?
I record everything, too.
The depth of every vagina I've encountered.
The length and circumference
of every penis.
The time to reach orgasm.
The distance of ejaculation.
I've written it all down.
This is a record of my life's real work.
Which is sex, by the way.
I find that recording is a...
is a way to experience things
a second time. Don't you?
I also have certain... rare abilities.
From a completely flaccid start,
I can become erect
and ejaculate in ten seconds flat.
I'd say that's pretty much
physiologically impossible.
Why, the rush of blood alone would...
Shall we get started?
My grandmother introduced me
to sexual intercourse when I was ten.
My first homosexual act
was with my father.
Of the 33 members of my extended family,
I've had sex with 17 of them.
That's five generations.
My penis is 8.24 inches long with
a diameter of 2.8 inches when fully erect.
ln my youth, I averaged eight cubic
centimeters of semen per ejaculation.
By the time I was 50, I was down to five...
I've had sex with 22 separate
species of animals...
I've had intercourse with 9,412 people.
I've had sexual relations with...
605 preadolescent males and...
231 preadolescent females.
Have you ever seen a boy orgasm?
No.
I guess that's why I'm such a catch.
Physiologically, it's almost
identical to an adult orgasm.
Screw this.
I'll see you down at the bar.
Thought you trained him to be impartial.
Sometimes it's difficult.
I suppose someone like me really
puts your beliefs to the test.
- How?
- You know.
- Everybody should do what they want.
- I've never said that.
No one should be forced to do
anything against their will.
No one should ever be hurt.
You know, you're a lot more square
than I thought you'd be.
Let's get on with it.
Sure.
Please, Governor.
You're so angry, I can't reason with you.
When you calm down, we'll discuss it.
Seems that the archbishop of Fort Wayne
tipped off the customs board.
What is it with these people? They're simply
depictions of man in his natural state.
I don't know much about natural states, Prok,
but here in the state of Indiana,
we have a problem.
We'll have to take
the customs office to court.
Who's gonna pay,
the Rockefeller Foundation?
- You're an inch away from losing your grant.
- That's not true.
What do you mean?
Hoover is annoyed you won't help him find
homosexuals in the State Department.
lt is rumored that he is
compiling dossiers on you.
The activities of your staff.
And, as you know, there have been
complaints about your statistical methods.
Trumped-up nonsense.
Nothing but disguised prudery.
Prok.
Maybe there were small mistakes
in the male study,
but we've corrected them
in the female volume.
This will be a very great book, Herman.
Much better than the first.
Let's hope so.
Kinsey is a deranged Nebuchadnezzar,
leading women out into the fields
to mingle with cattle.
''Self-appointed messiah
of the sexually despised.''
''Having had his way
with the male of the species,
Kinsey now insecticizes
American womanhood.''
Did you get any sleep last night?
How many years do I have
to study human behavior
- before I'm no longer an entomologist?
- Why do you read them?
I'm trying to find out
why people hate this book so.
You told them their grandmothers
and daughters are masturbating,
having premarital sex,
sex with each other.
- What did you expect?
- Some respect.
- Don't answer it.
- Hello.
Hey, Kinsey, what kind of sick man
are you? Why do you want to...
We're in trouble.
The cost of film stock is astronomical.
Shouldn't our nonprofit status
get us a discount?
You've got to let some of this go.
We need a full-time accountant.
What in heaven's...?
Stop this. Stop it at once.
ln my office.
Gebhard, get in here.
Everyone, back to work.
Do you have any idea
what a delicate time this is?
Our enemies are watching everything we do.
We can't afford a single slip-up.
- This has nothing to do with the project.
- Everything is about the project.
- It was just a misunderstanding.
- No, it's not.
You let things get out of hand with
Martin's wife. Now she wants to leave him.
lsn't that right, Martin?
What about you, Gebhard? Are you
planning to leave Agnes and the kids?
- No, of course not.
- Then end it.
- I've tried.
- It's not difficult.
Just tell her it's over.
No explanation necessary.
All right.
Clyde, I'm...
I'm very sorry about all of this.
I saw this coming.
Gebhard should've nipped it in the bud.
You are so full of shit.
What are we to you, Prok? We're just lab rats?
Just another part of the project?
To prove that sex...
No, I'm sorry.
Fucking... is nothing more than friction
and harmless fun?
Well, let me tell you.
That is a risky game, because fucking
isn'tjust something. It's the whole thing.
And if you're not careful,
it will cut you wide open.
Go home to your wife, Clyde.
She's going to need you.
I thought the rules were clear.
No intense romantic entanglements.
They only make people's lives unstable.
Well, I guess we all can't be
as disciplined as you, Prok.
The question of marital infidelity remains
one of the most complicated issues
facing our society today.
Reconciliation of the married individual's
desire for a variety of sexual partners
and the maintenance of a stable marriage
presents a problem,
which has not been satisfactorily
resolved in our culture.
The fact is, America is awash
in sexual activity,
only a small portion of which
is sanctioned by society.
Sexual morality needs to be reformed.
And science will show the way.
Sometimes...
I sometimes wonder what
this country would look like
if the Puritans had stayed at home.
What if all the rogues and libertines
had crossed the Atlantic instead?
But the enforcers of chastity
are massing once again,
to dissuade the scientist, intimidate him.
Convince him to cease research.
Yes, Mrs Kinsey.
Mac?
He's killing himself...
and you have to help me stop him.
OK.
Hi.
Doctors say my heart
sounds like a cement mixer.
At least they found one.
Seems I've developed
a dependency on barbiturates.
So, if I've been a bit harsh lately...
- How's Alice?
- She's fine.
We're fine.
You should get some sleep.
It's always been my biggest fear, Clyde.
Dying before I finish this work.
ln the course of these hearings
on tax-exempt foundations,
we intend to show how communists
are financed in the United States.
There is a diabolical conspiracy
back of all this,
and its aim is the furtherance
of socialism in America.
Do you agree that Kinsey's research
aids the communistic aim
of weakening and destroying
the youth of our country?
I do not agree, sir.
Well, tell me, Dr Gregg,
does the Rockefeller Foundation
really believe that it belongs
in the business of sex research?
I think it's probably
something the Foundation
shouldn't have anything to do with.
Dr Kinsey's project is now in a position
to obtain support from...
other sources.
With the loss of support
from the Rockefeller Foundation,
Dr Kinsey's project will need
other funding if it is to survive.
Prok?
Prok, you home?
We are running a budget surplus
due to increased enrolment,
which is a direct result
of Dr Kinsey's success and fame.
A small amount of this money would
be enough to keep the project afloat.
Prok?
Why don't we put it to a vote?
All those in favor of increasing
Dr Kinsey's grant...
That's it, then.
This woman was beaten by her father
when she first menstruated.
Now she's incapable of
physical intimacy of any kind.
And this man -
''Dear Dr Kinsey.''
''lt has taken me
a long time to write to you.''
''l suppose because
I was too ashamed and l...''
Where'd that blood come from?
I punctured my foreskin.
I wanted to understand different...
different kinds of sensations.
lt didn't give me any pleasure.
And there was only a little...
pain.
I couldn't help them, Mac.
I couldn't figure it out.
Just stop punishing yourself.
Now I've ruined it for everyone.
This is an exercise in futility.
Huntington Hartford
is the heir to the A&P fortune.
He can solve your
financial problems with a pen.
I won't beg, Mac.
I won't beg.
Ohio deplores fellatio
but tolerates cunnilingus.
ln my home state of Indiana,
all forms of oral sex are illegal,
even within marriage.
The current sex laws are completely
out of touch with the real world.
I've had four wives. Some people say
that makes me a sex offender.
Hunt, if you keep interrupting Dr Kinsey,
you're gonna have to find a fifth.
Please, go on.
Even now, 43 states will punish
a single act of adulterous intercourse.
I'm thinking of building a museum. What's
your opinion of modern art, Dr Kinsey?
It's not my area of expertise, Mr Hartford.
I really don't consider myself
qualified to discuss it.
Well, why not?
Just because I own some supermarkets
that doesn't mean I'm only capable
of talking about groceries.
Do you hate modern art as much as I do?
Squiggly lines, empty canvases...
So, the next book
will deal with sex offenders?
We need money, Mrs Hartford.
We need someone to give us money.
You have no idea what I've had to endure
just to obtain the same rights
other scientists take for granted.
My funding has been slashed and my name
has been dragged through the mud
in every newspaper and magazine
across this country.
Every dollar I've ever earned has...
Leave me alone.
Every dollar I've ever made
has gone back into the project.
But fighting this customs case has cost us
an appalling amount. We're broke.
- Dr Kinsey...
- Please.
I'm not even sure how much time
I have left. Help me.
I have to get it all in the record.
Well, I'm very sorry.
Any support I give might be misconstrued
as an endorsement of sex.
I can't afford that kind of exposure.
I see.
But I'm sure something will come through.
You're right.
Rich people have lazy minds.
Took them five minutes
to find a water glass.
I'm taking you to the hospital.
No. No more beds.
I spent my whole childhood lying in bed.
Let's go back to the hotel, Mac.
I want to pick up a few histories
in the morning.
We'd been married for 23 years,
with three marvelous children.
And, as soon as my youngest left
to go to college, I took ajob.
ln an arts foundation.
I met a woman there.
Secretary in the grants office.
We became fast friends, and...
before long, I fell in love with her.
This came as quite a shock,
as you might imagine.
The more I tried to ignore it,
the more powerful it became.
You have no idea what it's like
to have your own thoughts
turn against you like that.
I couldn't talk to anyone about my situation
so I found other ways to cope.
I took up drinking.
Eventually, my husband left me.
Even my children fell away.
I came very close to ending it all.
It's just another reminder of how
little things have changed in our society.
What are you talking about?
Things have gotten much better.
What happened?
Why, you did, of course.
After I read your book, I realized how many
other women were in the same situation.
I mustered the courage to talk to my friend.
And she told me, to my great surprise,
that the feelings were mutual.
We've been together
for three happy years now.
You saved my life, sir.
Just one more question.
You've just told me your entire history.
Childhood, family, career,
every person you've ever had sex with.
But there hasn't been
a single mention of love.
That's because it's impossible
to measure love.
And, as you know, without measurements,
there can be no science.
But, I've been thinking a lot
about the problem lately.
''Problem?''
When it comes to love,
we are all in the dark.
So, you do think it matters?
- What time's our flight, Mac?
- Not for a couple of hours.
Let's stop in the woods.
Mac?
I'm right here, Prok.
Just imagine,
these trees are over 1000 years old.
Hence the name, Sequoia sempervirens,
''Always green.'' Always alive.
Mac, did I ever tell you about the Mbeere?
No, not that I recall.
They're an ancient East African tribe.
They believe that trees are imperfect men,
eternally bemoaning their imprisonment.
The roots that keep them
stuck in one place.
But I've never seen a discontented tree.
Look at this one,
the way its roots are gripping the ground.
I believe it really loves it.
Come on, Mac.
What's the hurry?
There's a lot of work to do.