New Orleans, good morning.
It's Rod Ryan with you.
Coming up, tickets for the
Voodoo Fest coming to...
- to the banks of the Mississippi,
from Baton Rouge to Bayou Boutin...
... this is Hooks checking
news headlines.
- Good day to be in New Orleans...
How's the birthday boy?
- This is for Mommy.
- Thank you, sweetheart.
- Look at Grandpa. Say hi.
- Open my present.
Want to open a present?
- Good morning, Mr. Wood.
- Morning.
Paper.
Thank you.
How was your weekend?
- Great. How was yours?
- Very nice. How are the kids?
Great.
Magic trick. Henry!
- Jacob.
- Ted. Good Morning.
- It's happening.
- What's happening?
Does your car have a radio?
Greenspan's speech was delayed.
Rumor is he's sick. Looks like end
of the world is factored into prices.
Everyone in the conference room
in 10 minutes.
Deborah, I need you for five minutes.
Ted, it's Monday. There'll be a Tuesday.
You have a call about the antitrust
approvals with Harry at 11.
Close the door, please.
How'd Henry's party go?
- Terrific. He had a great time.
- Good.
I have a problem.
Okay. What is it?
He taught me a song for his birthday.
I have to sing it for him tonight
at bedtime, and I can't think what it is.
Sing a little more and we'll figure it out.
What the hell was that?
- Oh, my God!
- Call 911!
- 911.
- I want to report a shooting.
- Get behind the desk and stay there!
- Ma 'am?
The Laurel Morgan Building.
- Third floor.
- How many are injured?
I don't know. I don't know
how many... No, stay with me!
- God! They put me on hold. Hello?
- Oh, shit.
- Come on, somebody...
- Calm down.
- Can you see anything?
- It'll be fine. I promise.
Hello?
Come on.
Please send somebody.
Pick up. Please pick up.
- Good morning, Mr. Pulaski.
- Morning, Nick.
Need some help with that?
The bilge ring keeps crapping out,
blocking up the damn pump. I got it.
Last time you nearly took out
every sink in the Quarter.
That was those kids messing
with the water main.
- You should really quit those things.
- What for?
Christmas comes a little early this year.
There's our boy.
So, what do you say?
- Does he stop in for coffee and a cruller?
- Let's give him a cruller.
- Bingo! We have a winner.
- I can smell the fried dough over here.
And there he is.
Breakfast of champions, right there.
We're losing him. I'll take
just a couple more.
Say goodbye to Mr. Nicholas Easter.
Who's next on the hit parade?
Hi.
Can I look at that candle?
No, I'm sorry, the red one.
Just to the left of that scary pentacle
and the jar of bloodroot.
Right there.
Thank you. What'd you say?
She's cajun. I told her you wanted
the St. Nicholas candle.
- Is that what you wanted?
- That's the one.
What happened right there?
What did she say?
She said you're nice-Iooking,
but she doesn't trust you.
She didn't say that, did she?
You know what it is?
Jury duty.
I got a summons in the mail.
- I was trying to pray out of it.
- Where's your sense of civic duty?
I flunked civics.
- Do you have any other tips?
- I would go with a St. Catherine candle.
What does she do?
She's the patron saint
of unmarried women and jurors.
- Really?
- Really.
That's not what
that candle really is, is it?
- This your first time in New Orleans?
- No, no.
- I've been here a number of times.
- I had you pegged as a first-timer.
Is that right?
Yeah.
- How's your mother?
- Excuse me?
- She feeling better?
- How do you know about my mother?
She was in the hospital.
Now you care for her at home.
- She had a stroke.
- Your wife wants to put her in a home...
...but you're feeling guilty about that.
You've checked out a few of them...
...and it doesn't feel
like the Christian thing to do.
My advice, reconsider the home.
Better an unhappy mother
than an unfriendly wife.
I'm up here on the right.
- The same thing with guns
and Vicksburg Firearms.
The only thing
that's gonna win this case...
...is because for the first time,
we got a gun company ex-executive...
...who's gonna go up
against his former employer...
...and with good conscience,
he's gonna testify for us.
I promised Celeste that I would win it for
her and all the others that died that day.
You're gonna make history, celeste.
We're gonna do it together.
Thank you for your courage.
We got the Strickland SUV
case at noon.
And celeste, I'll see you
and your son at Arno's at 6.
- As long as we don't...
- Nothing about the case.
This is dinner with you and Henry.
Got time to see her to her car?
- Absolutely.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Rohr.
- Yeah.
Lawrence Green.
Lindus, Hostetler...
Hostetler. Yes, jury consultants,
New York City.
Philadelphia.
Thank you for meeting with me.
Guess how many phone calls
and letters I get...
...from expert jury consultants
such as yourself.
- I can imagine, sir.
- Go on, take a guess.
I appreciate you inviting me here.
- This is more important now. Which one?
- I'm sorry?
I'm off to court.
This is the striped.
- Non-striped? Striped? Non-striped?
- The striped matches your jacket.
Yours is striped because
you're from New York.
- Philadelphia.
- I'm gonna go with the non-striped.
As a clever jury consultant,
you should know...
...that jurors down here don't trust
a lawyer who's too nattily turned out.
- How familiar are you with my case?
- Very, sir.
- You think it's a strong case?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you think it's a winning case?
- People don't win gun cases, Mr. Rohr.
I think I can help you with that, sir.
There's gotta be another
commuter flight.
Can you try one in Richmond
or Atlanta?
I gotta call you back. He's here.
You represent the widow of a man
shot by a Vicksburg Firearms gun.
They're finding out things about jurors...
- ...their spouses don't know.
- Is that right?
And the word is the defense
has retained...
...Rankin Fitch as their
lead jury consultant.
Rankin Fitch?
- You don't...?
- I know who he is.
- Mr. Fitch, how was your flight?
- Fine. We up and running, Miss Monroe?
We are. Kaufman's inside with Birk,
and the kid from MIT, Lamb, is here.
What about Broussard,
forensic linguistics?
Out of Rochester.
He missed his flight. He'll be here by 3.
- Who's our backup?
- He'll be here by 3.
- Who is our backup?
- Levon Raines out of Dallas.
Call Mr. Broussard. Tell him
his service is no longer required.
- See what time Raines can be here.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. Fitch.
Tell me why I need a jury consultant.
Fitch will scientifically
pick jurors predisposed...
...in his favor by using surveillance,
wiretaps, psych profiles, graphology...
- Where's my car?
- Where you parked it.
- We're going together.
- Sir, I have a master's in psychology...
...from the University of Chicago. I know
handwriting. I know this stuff, I do.
Delores Kinnerly, registered Democrat,
46 years of age, unmarried...
...occupational therapist,
devout cat lover.
Look how she turns
from the man walking his dog.
- She's self-conscious about her weight.
- Maybe she just hates dogs.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Freeze that, Mr. Lamb.
We love fat women, people.
They're tight-fisted, unsympathetic.
I want her on my jury. Let's find 11
more jurors and three alternates like her.
- Who's next?
- Jerry Fernandez, 40, Puerto Rican...
...works for a moving company.
I got 35 years experience
in courtrooms...
...and my instincts for picking juries
have served me nicely so far.
- I wanna thank you for your time.
- I flew down here on my own dime.
- Why?
- Because I...
- Because I believe in this case.
- Why?
- I believe in a world without guns.
- That's very sweet, but naive.
- Thirty percent.
- I'm sorry. Excuse me?
Thirty percent of your usual fee.
You're hired, strictly probationary status.
- You don't wanna check out my résumé?
- Already did.
It's impressive.
- Here's your thing.
- What do you got?
- "The following are exempt:
- I read it.
- Not a resident of New Orleans..."
- That won't work. What am I gonna say?
I'm gonna tell them
I'll pack and leave?
Number two. Pack up and leave?
You ain't got nothing to pack.
No, it's true. They own you.
One thing you can do.
Leave the country.
- Why am I gonna leave?
- Church convention.
Sex change. You're leaving
because you're becoming a woman.
- You own a goat farm.
- This thing is a disaster.
I got my life and work.
- And I got my training. The Challenge.
- Oh, wait a sec.
- You could claim hardship.
- It's 8 weeks away. I can't do it.
- I can't do it.
- You got the challenge. You can't go.
Hold on, check this. "If you have
been convicted of a felony..."
Have you been convicted of a felony?
- No.
- You should commit a felony.
- Commit a crime.
- Are you serious?
It doesn't have to be a bad crime.
- I should commit a crime?
- You're asking to get out of it, right?
You registered to vote.
If you register to vote,
then they got you in the jury pool.
We need to de-register him.
One day, I'm gonna organize,
throw half this stuff away.
What's that, Walther PPK?
That's a nice piece.
That's the same gun James Bond uses.
You know that?
Really? You can 't be too safe
these days.
- Walking on the streets, all alone.
- Smooth, Maxine.
It's easier to find an honest firearm
these days than a good man.
- Know how to use it?
- My brother took me to the dump once.
Let me take you down
to the firing range.
- Thattaboy.
- I'll show you how to shoot.
- I got a few ideas.
- I bet.
Nice job, Maxine.
Frank Herrera, Cuban, 43 years old...
...retired Marine sergeant, served
in Panama and Grenada, twice divorced.
Now he cleans swimming pools.
Fair to say he misses
his former position of authority.
I think Herrera would make
a good foreman. Don't you, Mr. Cable?
I'm only lead counsel for defense. I don't
pretend to know about jury selection.
- Really?
- Really.
- Who's next?
- Nicholas Easter.
Thirty-four, co-manager of Game Trader
in the Esplanade Mall.
- He's gonna love this.
- Watch me hit this lady in the head.
- See how her head explodes?
- It explodes.
Don 't hit her. Hit the bad guy.
- I can try? Show me how to hold it.
- Give it a shot.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
I threw in this little sniper game.
- I thought you might like it.
- I wrote down my phone number.
Oh, okay. That's a local number.
You're here.
- We're close.
- Right on.
Perfect. I'm Maxine.
I'm Nick Easter.
He calls himself a part-time student.
- At Tulane? City College?
- Currently, nowhere.
So he's lying. Where's he from?
Moved here eight months ago.
Trail's cold.
He dropped out of the sky
like the Archangel Gabriel?
Put him on a jury with Herrera, he's
gonna be doing dog tricks in minutes.
Without reviewing his questionnaire,
a formal Q&A, I can't trust this.
You're only lead counsel
for the defense.
You shouldn't pretend to know much
about jury selection.
Nicholas Easter, he's an entertainer.
He wants to make everybody happy.
Not a bad way to go through life,
making everybody happy.
But in court, it's not that simple.
Somebody always loses.
Just not me. He's a risk.
Let's move on.
The case stems from the shooting death
of stockbroker Jacob Wood...
... two years ago.
Seating a panel won't be easy
in this highly-watched...
...politically-charged trial that begins
with jury selection.
On the defense, Vicksburg Firearms.
Attorneys will begin questioning
potential jurors today...
The gun industry hasn't lost in court,
but the man leading this fight...
...attorney Wendall Rohr,
says it'll be different.
He says this time the gun industry
will pay.
It's not sticking. I need the other tape.
- Know what you're doing?
- Good to go.
Could I get your glasses? Perfect.
Same prescription. The frames
will feel a little heavier.
Come on.
Right side of the table. Keep it square.
Keep it clear. Mr. Cable.
I'm gonna be putting
this behind your ear.
- What is that?
- It ain't Dramamine.
Right there. All set.
- You done?
- I am.
Mr. Rohr.
- Can you smell that?
- Two-hundred-year-old mahogany.
Furniture polish, cheap cologne
and body odor.
Wendall.
- How you doing? I'm Nick.
- Lydia.
So, what are we supposed to do,
sit here all day? Is that it?
- What do they want us to do?
- I'm sure we can think of something.
All rise.
Oyez, oyez, oyez, civil district court for
the parish of Orleans is now in session.
The Honorable Frederick Buford Harkins
presiding.
God save the state
and this honorable court.
Thank you, bailiff.
You may take your seats.
This suit is brought by plaintiffs...
Over your left shoulder.
Rankin Fitch, 2:00.
Dark suit. You've heard the myth,
now meet the man.
Quaking in my Florsheims.
Celeste Wood claims
that Vicksburg Firearms is liable...
...for her husband's death and seeks
damages for loss of future earnings...
...as well as general damages,
including pain and suffering.
Plaintiff has exercised
her right to a jury trial.
- We are now ready to begin the voir dire.
- Miss Coleman.
- Mrs.
- Mrs. Coleman, excuse me.
I see from your questionnaire that you
have no particular feeling about guns...
- Briefcase on the jury.
- Yes, sir, that's correct.
I don't feel one way
or another about guns...
...but I sure hate to see people get hurt.
- I understand.
- Do you or your husband own a gun?
- We do not.
Ever fired a gun for sport?
Or in self-defense?
Shoulder shrug.
She's evaluating the person
asking the question before she answers.
She's telling Rohr exactly
what he wants to hear.
- You think she's lying.
- Not necessarily.
- She knows how to.
- Rikki Coleman, 36 years of age.
Her husband's a Baptist minister.
She's a card-carrying member of the
Sierra Club and a registered Democrat.
I hate Baptists almost
as much as I hate Democrats.
- What else?
- She had an abortion two years ago.
- And? And?
- The guy holding her hand at the clinic...
...not the Baptist minister.
Tone of voice, body language,
she's got an open mind.
She's gonna be fair
and sympathetic to Mrs. Wood.
Mr. Rohr, do you wish
to exercise challenge for cause?
- No, Your Honor. We accept this juror.
- Mr. Cable?
- Take her. Take her.
- No objections here, Your Honor.
Enter Mrs. Coleman as a juror.
I'm co-manager of Circle Foods.
It's a local grocery chain.
I've been living here about 14 years.
Circle Foods. Take him, Mr. Cable.
- We accept this juror, Your Honor.
- Mr. Rohr?
- No objections, Your Honor.
- Thank you.
You may enter Mr. Shaver as a juror.
Next!
Prison for those people
who break the law.
Your Honor,
we accept this juror.
- She looks good.
- No objections.
- Enter Miss Hullic.
- They flooding the community...
- No objection.
- No. No. No.
- Peremptory challenge.
- What are your grounds?
- We accept.
- Mr. Rohr?
- No objections.
- We accept.
- You have a gun?
- I'm thinking about it.
- You may go.
- Mossburg pump.
I like him! Yes! Let's take him.
- We accept this juror.
- No objection.
- Herrera as a juror.
- I'm a mechanic.
- What about gun control?
- Same way I feel about birth control.
- Doesn't work.
- We accept.
- Enter Eddie Weese as a juror.
- Yes, definitely.
- No challenge.
- We accept this juror.
- Call me Millie. I'm a sculptress.
- Accepted.
- Take her.
- DeShazo as a juror.
- We accept Ms. Deets as a juror.
- We accept this juror.
- An AK-47 overstates the case.
- I want her.
- No objection.
- Lembeck as a juror. Mr. Cable.
- No challenge.
- Challenge.
- Peremptory challenge.
9 mm, more of a man's kind of gun.
- Jerry Fernandez as a juror.
- I like him a lot.
- We know about her.
- I don't carry a gun.
- We accept.
- Let's not go down this road.
Thank you, Mr. Rohr.
Well, thank you all for being here.
Thank you, Jim.
- Mr. Docken.
- Yes, sir.
- How do you do?
- Fine, thank you.
How do you feel about
being a juror in this trial?
- Do you feel you could be fair...
- Look at how he's hunched over...
...and his fingers are interlaced.
He's trying not to be too obvious.
He's definitely on our side
of the fence.
It's a veneer. He's campaigning.
He wants on. Bounce him.
- We're almost out of challenges.
- I don't care. Bounce him!
- Peremptory challenge.
- Hold on, hear me out.
Thank you, you're excused.
- I wanna be heard.
- You may be excused.
I wanna be heard!
This is the blood of innocent children
gunned down by greedy corporations.
You son of a bitch!
Help him.
Help this man. Help this man.
Get him out of here.
This is not a show in here.
Get him out.
The nation's trying to kill itself.
You wanna give it the weapons.
Son of a bitch! Let me go!
Let me go!
Let me go! Bastards!
Guess that's lunch.
Somebody add "class clown" to
Mr. Easter's ever-expanding résumé.
Court's adjourned. V oir dire will
resume tomorrow, 9 a.m.
Attorneys, both of you,
in my chambers, now.
Good call.
There are some things, however,
that seem to live eternal.
That's a tendency to always
come back asking for more.
A total of 12 million more.
Now, each of our gun companies has
already ponied up $4 million...
...into this Sportsman's Legacy Fund.
Now that may not seem like a hell of
a lot of money where you come from...
...but we think $20 million ought
to be enough to secure a jury...
...in the People's Republic of Berkeley,
let alone here.
How about 30,000?
Thirty thousand, what are
you talking about?
It's an interesting amount to reflect on.
The number of gun deaths every year.
The number of men, women
and children disabled...
...by your gentlemen's products,
last year alone:
"One hundred thousand."
Or we could focus...
...on the number one.
Because one is all they want.
One win. One precedent.
Once they get that...
...they're gonna be traveling around
filing civil actions...
...and siphoning away
at that $2 billion...
...that you gentlemen sell in firearms
and ammo every fiscal year.
Two billion dollars!
Where I come from,
that's a lot of money.
What I'm asking for is a pittance...
...compared to what
a negative verdict will cost.
Our share price is down 25 percent
just on word of this trial.
- I'm down almost 30.
- I'll kick in an extra 1.5, but no mas.
One-point-five each, that's 7.5 total.
- I'll take it.
- You have any additional plans...
...for this pittance?
- I do.
- Lonnie Shaver. Manager here?
- All day.
- Ernie Strode.
- I'm gonna put you...
...in the grocery business.
- Grocery business?
We're acquiring your store.
Meeting the managers to discuss
their future in the organization.
- He hasn 't been promoted in five years.
- Not all will be transitioned.
We've ID'd you as a candidate
for the Super House program.
- How soon can we fly you up?
- Mr. Shaver...
...in subtle and unspoken ways
can be made to appreciate...
...the terms of advancement
in the Hammond Foods empire.
- I don't like the looks of this one.
- Ex-Marine drill instructor.
These people are looking for a leader.
They'll follow Herrera.
- Lf they elect someone else?
- Whoever they vote for...
...will be following me.
Just like in Cincinnati...
...and Oakland and Pittsburgh.
Gentlemen, trials are too important
to be left up to juries.
God save this state
and this honorable court.
Good morning.
You may take your seats.
- Who's next?
- Herman Grimes.
- Is Herman Grimes in the court?
- Mr. Grimes isn 't on my list.
There's a swinging door ahead
of you, honey.
You got it?
Forty-five degrees to your left,
then 20 degrees to your right.
Hold on a minute there, Mr. Grimes.
There's no need
for you to have come.
You're excused for disability.
What if I do not wish to be excused, sir?
Well, I've never known a blind man
to serve on a jury.
And I must say, I can't recall any case
or law or statute that would permit...
...or prevent...
- State v. Jack.
The Supreme Court has held that it is a
violation of constitutional due process...
...to just automatically dismiss...
...the blind from jury service.
- He's right.
- Mr. Grimes, that's very impressive.
- Why are you smiling, sir?
Mr. Rohr, Mr. Cable,
any objections to Mr. Grimes serving?
The plaintiffs would welcome Mr. Grimes
to our jury, Your Honor.
- Our jury.
- Mr. Cable?
- As would we on the defense.
- Who 's next?
- Nicholas Easter.
- Mr. Easter.
- Mr. Rohr.
- Your Honor.
- Good morning, Mr. Easter.
- Good morning.
Says here you work
in an electronics store.
Yes, sir, that's correct.
How would you feel if a gun was
behind the counter in case of a robbery?
- We're in the mall, sir.
- But I think you'd agree...
...robberies take place in malls.
Do they not?
We're in the Esplanade Mall, which
is across from the sheriff's office.
Yes, I'm familiar where it is.
You'd have to be on crack to rob us.
I guess that's my point.
I see. Well, tell me...
That's the second time you've looked
at your watch. We keeping you?
No, Your Honor, I wouldn't
presume to waste your time.
If you knew my situation,
you might excuse me...
Your situation, Mr. Easter?
Yes, Your Honor.
- It's the Madden challenge.
- The Madden what?
You know Madden Football?
It's a video game.
You'd be surprised at how
many people play.
Every year they choose the best 15
players from across the country...
...to compete in a tournament against
NFL players and celebrities...
- I'm not following you.
- It's like this.
The prize is $ 100,000.
I can't afford to pass up the opportunity
to make that cash...
- I'd like you to learn civic responsibility.
- It's something I've been doing a long...
The jury system originated because for
thousands of years before that...
... a judge had the power to hang...
...for example, any young man
he simply did not like.
Yes, Your Honor.
- Any objections, Mr. Rohr?
- I have no objection, whatsoever.
- Mr. Cable?
- What do I do?
Any time, counselor.
Harkin sandbagged us.
Go ahead and take him. Take him.
- No objections, Your Honor.
- Enter Mr. Easter as a juror.
Freeze that, right there. Freeze it.
Thirty years in the trenches
have taught me this.
There's always a loose end.
Everybody has a secret...
...they don't want you to find.
Find it.
First group, Monroe: Rikki Coleman,
Sylvia DeShazo, Vanessa Lembeck.
Mr. Klein: Herman Grimes,
Millie Dupree, Eddie Weese.
Mr. Garson: Loreen Duke, Lonnie Shaver,
Frank Herrera.
Mr. Lamb, the three alternates:
Lydia Deets, yoga teacher. Phillip
Savelle, shrimp fisherman. Henry Wu.
Find out everything we don't know.
Doyle, you know this city
better than anyone.
You take Jerry Fernandez, Stella Hullic,
Nicholas Easter.
These are your babies, people.
This is what you live for.
Think you got the wrong apartment.
What are you gonna do, call the cops?
- You weren't there today.
- I couldn't, I was too nervous.
What are you gonna do,
hit me in the head...
...with my George Foster big stick?
What are you nervous about, huh?
You are not juror number nine
in the biggest case of the year.
You're kidding. You're kidding me.
You're kidding me.
No, I'm not kidding you.
How'd you do it?
- How'd you do it?
- The Madden Challenge.
It was a thing of beauty.
The judge even threatened to hang me.
- Juror number nine.
What do you have for me?
I love St. Catherine.
- How do I look?
- Handsome.
- Do I look honest and trustworthy?
- To an innocent eye.
- Enough to survive 10 to 15 in the pen?
- Don't say that. It's bad luck.
Luck.
Won't see each other for a while.
They'll be watching us.
- You have to come back to bed, now.
- We're gonna have to be more careful.
How much do you think it's worth?
Ten, fifteen million, maybe more.
- Look, that's enough. Come back to bed.
- We only need eight for a verdict.
Everybody's got a button.
We just gotta find out where and push.
You have them.
We don't have anything yet.
- Celeste Wood.
You'll recall, two years ago,
Wood's stockbroker husband, Jacob...
...was gunned down in a mass slaying
inside the firm where he worked.
- Two years ago by a failed day trader,
who later turned the gun on himself.
Never before has a jury found
the gun industry liable for murder.
You might remember,
the former mayor...
- after her husband was gunned down.
The man leading this,
famed attorney Wendall Rohr.
- Do you feel this lawsuit is frivolous?
- Well, it's capricious.
I find it's unfortunate that Mr. Rohr
chose to use Ms. Wood and the courts...
...as vehicles for civic reform.
- How do you expect to win this?
Reckless, profit-hungry gun companies
like Vicksburg...
...have been getting away with murder
for too long. And we have...
- Lonnie Shaver.
- Hi, I'm Sylvia DeShazo.
The room is 30 feet long
by 18 feet wide.
- I'm losing a lot of money on jury duty.
- Oh, really?
- Sixteen dollars a day.
- What?
- Sixteen.
- Sixteen?
- Yeah.
- No way. $ 16 a day? What's this, 1892?
You're not supposed to do it for the pay,
but for civic duty.
- Nice to meet you. Frank Herrera.
- Henry Wu. I became a citizen last year.
He deserves it,
he's the president of the free world.
Coffee and doughnuts over there.
Now, these muffins I made myself.
A treat for the first day.
These look like they are a treat.
Okay. Morning.
Well, everyone's here?
All accounted for?
Good. I think we should elect
a jury foreman...
...like Judge Harkin instructed us.
- Who would that be, Mr. Man?
Well, if no one else feels strongly,
I'd throw my hat in the ring.
Excuse me.
- Mr...?
- Herrera. Frank Herrera.
Mr. Herrera. Of all of us, what makes
you think you're the best person?
- Well, Miss...?
- Mrs. Loreen Duke.
Mrs. Duke. I was a master sergeant
in the Marine Corps.
I served my country in Panama,
Grenada, Beirut, you name it.
- I can run a six-minute mile.
- Young lady.
If nobody minds,
I'd also like to be considered.
I might not have served in Grenada,
but I'm the mother of two small children.
In that case, y'all ought to consider me.
Hell, I got three kids.
Ladies and gentlemen,
with all due respect...
...I think I know who would make
an excellent foreman.
- And who might that be, Mr...?
- Easter. Nicholas Easter, sir.
I was watching people very closely
during the jury selection...
...and only this man...
I don't know your name, sir.
- Herman Grimes.
- Only Mr. Grimes...
No, just Herman.
Only Herman had the guts to stand up
to the judge and seems to know...
...a little something about the law.
So in my book...
- ...it'd be good for him to represent us.
- But...
- But he's blind...
- So what? So is justice, right?
- That's right, brother.
- What do you think? Up to it?
Of course I am.
All in favor of Herman?
- Did I get any votes?
- Hey, it's unanimous. You're in.
All right, listen up.
Court's in session.
Lunch is set for 1:00.
We order up from v erti's Marte.
Please, fill out a menu.
- Thank you.
- Make sure you circle what you want.
Don't make it too expensive.
Thank you.
I had this last week.
It's really good. Thank you.
- They don't have sandwiches.
- Nothing on that menu.
All right, all right.
October, two years ago,
at 8:45 a.m. On a Monday morning...
...a man named Kevin Peltier casually
walks into the brokerage house...
...from which he was fired
the previous Friday morning.
He walks into the elevator,
he loads a 36-round magazine...
...into his Performa 990 semiautomatic,
and when he reaches the third floor...
...opens fire on his former coworkers,
killing 11 and critically wounding five...
...before turning the gun on himself.
They never had a chance.
This was less than two minutes.
They couldn't stop him.
Eleven lives ended.
That's all you jurors minus one.
And among them was Jacob Wood, the
husband of my client, Celeste Wood...
...and the father of their son Henry,
6 years old.
I don't know about you, but I'm angry
at the tragic and senseless loss of life.
Why does the Vicksburg Firearms
Company make it so easy...
...to buy these guns
on the underground market?
Because they care more about making
money than they do about your life...
...or my life or the life
of that woman's husband.
A very courageous former executive
of Vicksburg Firearms...
...is gonna testify
that this Performa 990 semiautomatic...
...was manufactured for,
principally, criminals...
...and all those others poised
for violence.
- One...
- Excuse me.
Would you give these to Mr. Rohr
and Mr. Cable?
- Into a very efficient mass murderer.
Yes, it was Mr. Peltier that squeezed
the trigger that awful morning.
But it was the Vicksburg
Firearms Company...
...through a deliberate,
negligent distribution policy...
...that put that assault-type weapon
into the hands of Mr. Peltier.
As such, they were complicit
in those murders.
This I'll prove to you during the course
of the trial. Thank you very much.
Your Honor.
Mr. Cable.
Thank you, Your Honor.
- I think that went very well.
- We'll be fine.
That was quite provocative.
I wanna tell you two things
about guns today.
I don't think either will be news.
First: Guns are dangerous.
They're guns.
This is their function.
I wanna tell you, no one
is more aware of that...
...or takes more responsibility for it...
- since before the Civil War.
The automobile industry works every day
to ensure their cars are safe.
Why? Because they drive them.
The people at Vicksburg
work every day...
...to keep the guns
out of the hands of criminals.
Why? Because they have families
with children...
- Did you see who handed this to you?
- It was a woman. She had blond hair.
She had pretty blond hair,
like that woman on television.
We didn't catch her
on any of the CCTVs.
Doesn't matter. I'm sure she was
wigged. I doubt you'll find any...
...but spray this for prints.
Anything turns up...
I'll process it through the database.
We are not here to legislate.
Mr. Cable is winding up.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
...amidst the finger-pointing,
Mr. Rohr did say one true thing.
This case is about money.
Hi, I'm calling from the courthouse.
It looks like Judge Harkin
won't be breaking till after 2.
Would you mind holding his jury's
lunch order till then?
Thank you.
I'm also a vegetarian.
What do you think about her?
I hear she teaches a class at Tulane.
- Yeah?
- Wouldn't mind taking that class.
- What subject?
- Well, she's a tall glass of iced tea.
A little too much lemon,
a little too much ice.
I'm sorry, but would you mind not doing
that in here? I'm predisposed to asthma.
I'll open a window.
It ain't gonna bother you.
Actually, I mind too.
Sorry, secondhand smoke.
I don't wanna smoke
your cigarettes either.
I can't smoke. I can't leave the room.
What is this, California?
- It is against the rules.
- Be quiet. You just an alternate.
What does that have to do
with anything?
Come on, come on. We're gonna
be here for a while together.
- So why are you bothering me?
- Let him smoke.
I think we're all just hungry.
And where's our lunch...
...they promised us?
It's 1:30.
That's why I wanna smoke, I'm starving.
Tamp down my appetite.
- Want me to see what's going on?
- Good idea, Nick.
- Iook over there and sees a cow.
He sees a golf ball in the cow's ass.
And he says, "Excuse me, ma'am,"
he raises that cow's tail and says:
"Does this look like yours?"
And she hit him with a four iron!
Excuse me, judge.
There's someone to see you.
All right.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
- You are...?
- Nick Easter, juror nine.
Yes. What are you doing
outside of the jury room, Mr. Easter?
And where is Lou Dell?
- She's chatting in the hallway, sir.
- Mr. Easter...
...I'd advise you to return
and finish your lunch.
That's the problem, sir. I think
somebody forgot to order our lunch.
- The jury has no lunch?
- That's why I'm here.
Everybody knows you like to keep
a tight schedule on your bench.
If we're gonna be back in less than 45
minutes, to be honest, we're hungry.
Well, what exactly
would you like me to do?
Lonnie, can you pass me
some garlic bread? Got any there?
Oh, absolutely, man.
This stuff is delicious.
I'm not sure, but I believe
I'm buying lunch for the jury.
Look, jury's right there.
In 35 years, that is the most
absurd thing I've ever seen.
- You have mustard on your tie.
- I did it on purpose.
First day of the trial, the judge is having
lunch with the jury. What's that about?
- Look at that.
- What?
Let's go.
Hey, hey, hey! To Nick!
- To Nick!
- Nick!
- This is horseshit.
- It wasn't me!
It was Judge Harkin.
Judge Harkin!
Okay. That's enough.
Thank you very much. All right.
- Here's the deposition you needed.
- Thank you.
Are we gonna talk about this?
I can't believe you had the nerve
to bring that here.
- I think we ought to discuss it.
- Why don't you just give it to the judge?
- They'd throw the case out.
- Let me explain something.
That's a defense tactic, okay?
All it's meant to do...
...is throw our focus off
so that we can move toward a mistrial.
I'd like it out of the office.
Give it to me.
Barry, after you shred it,
burn it, okay?
- You know how many of those I get?
- What if it's for real?
- No, it's not for real.
- What if it is?
Well, if it's for real,
then this isn't a trial, is it?
Then this is an auction,
and I might as well get on the phone...
...and call up all those anti-gun activist
friends and tell them:
"We're just gonna put on a telethon,
and we will buy this verdict."
Because they're not gonna think of that,
are they?
Somebody wanna get that?
Got any other suggestions?
Look at it. Syntax, handwriting, word
choice. Clearly, a woman did the note.
- Someone's working the inside. A juror.
- Miss Monroe.
I think seven hours spent on this
is sufficient. We agree?
Mr. Fitch, I got a call for you,
line seven.
- Yes?
- Hello, Rankin.
I'm the agent handling the property
you were notified about earlier today.
- I'd like to know who I'm speaking with.
- You can call me Marlee.
Pay phone, 15 miles away.
You can call me Marlee.
- Where are we going with this, Marlee?
- All the way to the verdict.
The fact is, the jury's mine.
I can push it either way...
...for a price.
- Sounds good.
So good, in fact,
I don't believe you can do it.
You're old enough to remember a time...
...when people delivered what they
promised. I'm one of those people.
I'm also old enough to remember
Watergate, Abscam, Linda Tripp...
- and other times people got entrapped
for engaging in conversations like this.
And you'd do very good
to remember that.
- There are consequences.
- Well, let me worry about those.
For now, I just hope
you're feeling patriotic.
- You hope I'm feeling...?
- Patriotic?
- Morning, Nick.
- Morning, Lou.
- Good morning, Vanessa.
- Morning.
- Nick.
- Hey, guys.
- How you doing, man?
- Okay. Thank you.
- Hey, Lonnie.
- Hey, man.
Morning, Frank.
Frank, you were in Panama
and Grenada, right?
- And Beirut.
- That really must have been something.
Yeah. Pulling the bodies of friends
out of rubble. It was really something.
No, you don't understand. I had a friend
in Desert Storm, in the Corps too.
- What division?
- The 1-4 out of Pendleton.
Yeah, well, that was mostly air power.
Not much real action.
Actually, there was, Frank.
You don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
My friend's name was Donny Rabbs, and
he was shot down in a Kuwaiti oil field.
- He was killed 12 years ago today.
- Sorry to hear that.
Sorry, it's a strange day. I figure if I
don't remember him today, nobody will.
That's the way people are.
Short memories.
That's terrible,
but we don't always know God's plan.
Listen, I don't know
if it would be inappropriate...
...but do you think we could
do something today to remember him?
- We could say the Lord's Prayer.
- I can't ask people to pray.
- "God Bless America"?
- I couldn't ask people to sing.
- I don't sing.
- I don't sing, okay?
You know what?
I have an idea.
Good morning.
You may take your seats, please.
I pledge allegiance to the flag...
...of the United States of America...
...and to the republic
for which it stands...
...one nation under God...
...indivisible, with liberty...
...and justice for all.
I don't know about you,
but I'm feeling pretty patriotic.
Thank you, please take your seats.
Jesus.
Pull!
You wanted to see me?
Mr. Cable called me last night
in a bit of a panic.
Now, he's concerned that someone's
trying to monkey with our jury.
As am I.
As are my associates.
- Who is it?
- It's a parlor game.
Just because somebody can influence
where a jury has lunch...
...doesn't mean they can hand us
the verdict.
Well, this is where I get
a little confused.
Because I was under the impression...
...that we already purchased
ourselves a verdict.
You know what I love best
about this gun?
It's over 70 years old,
just as reliable as the day it was made.
Mr. Fitch!
You find out who it is, will you?
Pull!
- One nation, under God...
At some point, everyone on the jury
acknowledges Herrera.
- It's like they're doing it for him.
- It's not him.
Right here at the end, Loreen Duke,
juror number 10...
Right there! Freeze there.
But tighten in on her left hand.
Right there.
Isn't that sweet?
Nicholas Easter, our song
and dance man, has an agenda.
Mr. Lamb, how did this confidence man
crash my jury pool?
- I don't know. I'd need some time, sir.
- Now. I'm asking for an educated guess.
Maybe he just did it. I mean,
who wants jury duty? Nobody, right?
It's like going to the dentist.
It's worse.
It's a municipal database
nobody would want to hack into.
Security is weak.
He could put his name on the list...
I got it, Mr. Lamb, thank you.
- Mr. Doyle.
- I'm on it.
Your Honor.
Good afternoon, Mr. Murphy.
You own and operate Excalibur Guns.
- Yes, sir, I do.
- Isn't Excalibur Guns an outlet store...
...for Vicksburg Firearms?
- Yes, sir.
Would you tell us about
your arrangement...
...with Michael Kincaid, who illegally sold
this Performa 990 semiautomatic...
...to Kevin Peltier smack-dab
out of the trunk of his car.
- My arrangement?
- Yes, sir.
Well, Mikey... Mr. Kincaid
bought guns from my store.
At a rate of more than 25 a month.
Didn't you ever wonder who your friend
Mikey was selling these guns to?
- That's none of my business.
- It's not your problem.
- Hold on, I didn't say that.
- Objection. Counsel is testifying.
Sustained. Mr. Rohr.
Thanks a lot.
- Afternoon.
- Your friend, Mikey Kincaid,
28 guns in December.
Ever wonder why one man would buy
112 guns in a period of four months?
- Collector.
- A collector, sir?
A hundred and twelve weapons, and all
of them semiautomatic assault weapons.
- I don't know.
- Come on, take a guess.
- Christmas presents?
- That's a guess.
- Objection. This is all speculation.
- Sustained.
Did they send a field rep...
...out to investigate?
- No, sir.
- Because they were pleased with you?
- Say again.
Is it not true that Vicksburg Firearms...
...instead of investigating the increasing
number of guns being sold to one man...
...instead sent you and your wife
on a trip to Jamaica?
- No.
- No?
My wife hates Jamaica.
We switched to Cancun.
- I have no further questions, Your Honor.
- Thank you.
We'll adjourn. Hold cross till tomorrow.
Release the jury 45 minutes early.
Oh, hi. Yeah, the landlord let me in.
He said some tenants have been
having trouble with the cable.
But I checked yours out, and...
Hey!
Looks fine.
I don 't think you have anything...
- What have we got, people?
- The drive's been erased twice...
...but not zeroed out. He may have been
sloppier than he thought.
- Give me a few moments.
- Mr. Fitch.
Lamb, trace it.
Fitch here.
You don't play nice.
- What are you talking about?
- You broke into Nick Easter's apartment.
You freely assume it was me?
Wouldn 't you be disappointed if I didn 't?
I'm bumping a juror. One of yours.
This time's just gonna be a pinprick.
Next time, it's really gonna hurt.
- Hey.
- Hello.
Looks like somebody had themselves
a good time last night.
I woke up on my stove.
Oh, man.
Stella, you don't got any aspirin, do you?
- I think I can do better than an aspirin.
- Yeah?
Little hair of the dog.
- Can you sweeten this up for me?
- Yeah, put it under the table.
You're an angel.
- Let me pour it. Let me do it!
- I'll pour it.
Jesus.
It's mine, sir.
I didn't take you for a day drinker,
Mr. Easter.
I'm usually not.
You still trying to get off my jury,
is that it?
Your Honor, I took an oath
to do my best, and I meant it.
Difficult as that is to believe...
...it's even more difficult
to believe this is your liquor.
I might be wrong, but I don't think
that's your shade of lipstick.
Miss Hullic?
Moving into Miss Hullic's spot
will be first alternate Lydia Deets.
Miss Deets, could you join
the jurors in the box, please?
Welcome to our jury. I trust you got
the same instructions as the rest.
Cell phone. Untraceable.
- Marlee?
- I'd like your offer, Mr. Fitch.
Not over the phone. This is not
gonna take place long-distance.
- Want to lose another juror?
- Anybody can get a juror booted.
That doesn't show
you can deliver a verdict.
I could get Easter canned if I wanted.
But you won't do that. You need him
to guarantee the jury swings your way.
So next time I call,
have your offer ready.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...this girl is an amateur,
do you understand? A dilettante.
And I want this nonsense ended today.
I want you to find her.
I want you to contain her.
Because you're losing me my jury!
Now find something
on every one of them.
Pull their files. Review every word,
every photo, every medical record.
Do it!
What do we have?!
Rikki coleman's boyfriend
is Neil Pollard.
Mrs. Coleman broke it off with him
two months after the abortion.
Mr. Coleman has racked up
three cases of domestic battery.
So she didn't cry to him about it.
Your husband looks a lot different than
your boyfriend with you at the clinic.
We'll be in touch.
Four months ago, Mr. Weese began
filling prescriptions for the following:
Crixivan, Epivir and AZT.
Unbeknownst to his mother,
his employer, his church and friends...
...Mr. Weese is HIV-positive.
Get off me.
That's what I'm talking about.
Got a little present for you.
- You an NBA scout?
- It'll change your life.
- Yeah?
- I'll be in touch.
Millie Dupree,
married 18 years to Hoppy Dupree...
Hey, Hoppy.
...one of the city's more
unprincipled real-estate agents.
Okay. Nice meeting you.
Mr. Ringwald has set the bait.
Mr. Ringwald, if anybody can help you
walk that land deal through, it'd be me.
Owens and Strode are about
to close the snare.
Is that convincing enough for you?
- Freeze! Nobody move!
- FBI.
- Sit down! Back in that chair!
- Hands on the table.
Hoppy Dupree, you're under arrest.
You're in violation of federal code,
attempting to bribe a government official.
Mr. Kincaid, you want to tell the court
just a little bit about your schooling?
Well, not a whole lot to tell.
I mean, most people
got a college degree.
And about the only thing I'd ever get
was the third degrees.
I appreciate your sense of humor,
but let's try to stay more on the topic.
Stay more on Kyle Murphy
and his shop, Excalibur Guns.
When you went there to get your
shipment, did Kyle Murphy ever say:
"We're out," or "Why do you need 25
assault-style pistols in a month?"
- Anything like that?
- No, he never said that.
- He always had plenty of guns around.
- Gotcha.
Thank you, Mr. Kincaid. Your witness.
Mr. Kincaid, you were the one
who sold the gun...
...used by Kevin Peltier in the
brokerage-house shootings, correct?
Correct. And I did a stretch for that too.
He'll help us get there.
To your knowledge,
was Vicksburg Firearms aware...
...that you were out there
reselling their product?
No. Not to my knowledge.
He flipped on us.
So Vicksburg Firearms
never sent you on any trips...
...or endorsed or fostered you selling
their guns in any way, is that correct?
Yeah, that's correct. But I wish they
had. I wish they had endorsed me...
...like they did Kyle.
Because I saw some pictures
from a trip he took to Cancun.
Man, Murph and Turf
were living it up down there.
I wish they'd sent me.
I'd have been on a beach with them,
looking at some thongs...
...and sipping on margaritas.
- A simple answer, please.
- My simple answer's no...
And I want it on the record now too.
I didn't have any idea what Peltier
was gonna do with that gun.
He was a wack job.
I wasn 't about getting anyone hurt.
I've retrieved some fragments.
I've got two things.
One: List of registered voters
for Cincinnati.
Why would Easter want a list
of registered voters?
Because voter-registration lists
lead to potential jury pools.
- What else?
- Well, this is from the drive's directory.
Time-stamped the day he got
his jury summons.
He synchronized the data on his drive
to another device.
That's what you should've snagged.
Doyle, you're going back in. This time
I want you to take Mr. Janovich.
- Why do I have to take him?
- Because Mr. Janovich can find anything.
I'm going for it.
Thank you. Thank you. Watch this.
- Nick.
- Got one for me?
Eddie, you seem kind of gloomy.
You all right?
Oh, no. No, I'm fine, man. You know,
I just got a lot on my mind, that's all.
- You okay? You want to talk about it?
- I'm cool.
- Really.
- Okay.
- Here's one more for you, miss.
- Thank you very much.
Sorry, man.
I left my key inside.
Congratulations.
We got it. Let's go.
Janovich, you don't have to do this.
I said, you don't have to do this.
Did you hear me?
Hey, guys. There's something
really wrong with Rikki.
I mean it. Come on.
See? Right there.
Come on, Rikki.
Give me a towel. Give me a paper towel.
Paper towel, now.
Oh, that's nasty.
She's had five shooters. It's no wonder.
- Call for help.
- What? She just...
- Call 911 now!
- Okay, okay.
Damn!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Rikki.
- Is she breathing, Nick?
- Yeah. She's gonna be okay, I think.
I can't believe this.
Damn lucky the place is still here
and no one was hurt.
People can't move back into this place.
They got to Rikki Coleman.
Woman's the president of the PTA.
She bakes cookies for her kids.
Whatever that son of a bitch had on her,
he brought out the heavy lumber.
She swallowed a fistful of sleeping pills.
Who's her replacement?
Who's her...? Did you hear what I said?
She almost killed herself tonight.
I'm sorry.
And they're putting heat on the others.
Eddie Weese and Millie Dupree.
They torched my place tonight.
At least we know
we have them motivated.
Here's the fun part.
They got the MP3 player.
The files are encrypted.
They're encrypted, but these guys
are good. They got teams of people.
You don't think they'll crack that?
We got three, four days tops...
...before the walls cave in.
- Lf we stay.
- Lf we stay?
What do you mean?
What are you saying to me, Nick?
- You saying you want to run away?
- Listen, Marlee.
- People are getting hurt.
- We're inside.
People could get killed.
- I'm inside. You're on the street.
- We're in this together.
It's our job to protect them.
There's only so much that I can do.
It's not just them that I worry about.
I can't protect you.
- Where are we with Rohr?
- He hasn't stepped up yet.
He will.
And Fitch wants to meet.
We knew I'd have to go
face-to-face with him.
It's okay.
I can play him. I can...
Set a date.
Okay.
We can't afford to lose any more jurors.
I know the math.
We put Fitch on his heels right now.
This video is from a security camera
inside juror nine's apartment.
Take a good look.
Oh, hi. Landlord let me in.
A lot of people have been
complaining about their cable.
But I checked yours out.
I don 't think you have...
Gentlemen, this malfeasance
will not stand.
I don't know which of you
this man was working for.
You're lucky I can't see his face.
I'd be inclined to turn this over
to the DA.
- Your Honor, I move for a mistrial.
- No, Mr. Cable.
There's not gonna be a mistrial.
Motion denied.
Not because of maneuvers like this!
For the remainder of this trial,
our jury is to be sequestered.
Bailiff, would you please inform...
The guy in the video set fire
to Nick Easter's place last night.
- What?
- Set fire to his place last night.
- How would you know that?
- Because I was there.
You were there? You went
to a juror's residence without asking me?
Wendall, listen to me.
- We're finished.
- That's what you pay me for.
You're a young punk.
You should've asked me.
- You're fired...
- Nick Easter is spinning this jury.
That's why Fitch ransacked his place.
There's a twisted power play
going on between these two.
You're afraid, you tell the judge,
they'll call a mistrial.
The defense would love nothing more.
Why hasn't the defense
told the judge about Nick Easter?
Because they're really
gonna buy this verdict.
- Bastards.
- Celeste, behind you.
All right. Hey, Celeste. Henry.
- Mr. Rohr.
- What's going on?
That reporter just told me...
She said something about a mistrial.
No, don't worry about that.
- She said the judge is...
- No. Now listen to me.
Everything's fine.
The judge has sequestered the jury.
- Not unusual for a heated trial...
- You said we had an excellent case.
- Yes.
- When I met with you a year ago...
...you said we could change the way
these people do business.
That my husband's life,
that all of those lives wouldn't be...
What?
- What's the matter, celeste?
- I just need to hear it.
- Tell me we can win this.
- We can.
We are gonna win it.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Come on, Henry.
- You going to the park?
- Yeah.
- We'll see you later.
I got Easter's list of potential jurors.
Boston, Pittsburgh and Cincinnati.
- What are the dates?
- Boston, 2000. Pittsburgh, Brooklyn, '99.
- And cincinnati, '98.
- They've been stalking gun cases.
Now they're in the house.
All right.
Amanda, I want the jury files
on all four cities. I want them tonight.
Line two. It's her.
Good afternoon, Marlee. I see you and
Mr. Easter are keeping busy, busy, busy.
The Palace Café on Canal Street.
Downstairs, dining room, 15 minutes.
Thank you.
- Mr. Fitch?
- Marlee? Good.
I just won a bet with myself.
I figured you for blond.
Oh, please, have a seat.
Nice massé, sequestering the jury.
Close ranks, makes them harder to...
- Mr. Fitch?
- Yes.
- This is for you.
- Thank you.
- What's your price?
- Ten million.
Non-negotiable.
This is made out to cash.
Five hundred thousand dollars...
...to walk away from my jury.
I wouldn't drop off
your dry cleaning for that.
You want to ask Nick about that?
Okay, okay. How do I know
that you can provide the verdict?
We got the jury sequestered, didn't we?
We know you're leaning
on a couple jurors. It's not enough.
You need nine warm bodies.
Nick Easter can deliver them.
He's very persuasive.
- You're such a good hustler.
- You're a good arsonist.
We both know what's at stake here.
You lose this, every civil lawyer in the
country's gonna be holding out his hand.
This is mine.
You won't get off until the next stop.
It's the zoo.
I'm gonna give you a second chance
to take this. I want you to consider it.
I think it's fair. I do.
I really do.
Listen, Fitch.
When you're ready to pony up the 10...
...e- mail me at this address.
It's a free account. Untraceable.
But then I'm sure you already knew that.
Here you are, sir.
Okay, I get this
"being sequestered" part.
But why put us all the way out here
by the east Texas border?
Hell, I can see Port Arthur
from the parking lot.
Does anyone know how Rikki's doing?
She was released
from the hospital an hour ago.
Lovely girl. Seemed fine to me.
But you never really know
what's going on with a person.
- Could be her marriage...
- No, no, no, it was nothing like that.
- Somebody got to that girl.
- No, that's hokum.
- Why would anyone want to get to her?
- Same reason they want to get us.
- To influence the outcome of the trial.
- Are we safe?
- Okay, here are your keys.
- We are now.
Hoppy was arrested.
And they said they would
put him in jail for life...
...if I didn't vote in favor
of the gun company.
It's okay, sweetheart.
- We'll talk about it in the morning.
- Thanks. Good night.
Didn't take you for a man
who goes for the big girls, Easter.
You're just full of surprises, ain't you?
I'm fine, Frank. How are you?
- Can I get by?
- I've been watching you, Easter.
- From day one.
- I just want to go to my room, Frank.
You're a real Boy Scout, aren't you?
Playing everybody.
Playing the judge. Playing Millie?
I've put up with guys like you
my whole life.
Now, I want you
to understand something.
Okay?
I don't like my hand being forced.
Do you understand?
Get some sleep, Frank.
Mr. Rohr?
May I sit down?
- I know you're playing both sides.
- We are.
May I sit down?
Yeah, go on. Sit down, sit down.
Now, you tell me...
You tell me why I shouldn't
go to the judge, get a mistrial...
...and have that provocative
little bottom of yours thrown into jail.
Do you know how serious we are
about jury tampering down here?
- You wouldn't.
- Don't be so sure.
You wouldn't put Mrs. Wood
through the pain of a mistrial.
You don't know anything
about Celeste Wood, what drives her.
Unlike you, she's not in it for the money.
And what are you in it for, Mr. Rohr?
Oh, you're something, aren't you?
- What do you think I'm in it for?
- You tell me.
- I'd like to get the law changed.
- That's why you're here.
But you need help.
It's up to you. You can be a good boy,
play by the rules...
...or you can win a huge victory
for gun control. The choice is yours.
This may surprise you.
I don't have to make that choice.
Your whistle blower is gonna testify...
...his company knows about the guns
that wind up on the black market...?
That's right, precisely.
What makes you think this witness
will make it to the stand?
- That whistle blower came to us.
- No. Fitch is gonna get to him.
He's your star witness.
If he hasn't already, you...
Sweetheart! Hey! Hey! Hey!
He came to us.
He's tucked away right now.
I'm not gonna tell you where.
The man, out of conscience, cannot wait
to get on that stand and testify.
Anyone can be gotten to.
What do you know?
How much we talking about here?
What do you want to bleed me for?
Five, six, seven million?
- Ten million.
- Oh, that's a big number.
That's a big number.
With Rankin Fitch in the game,
you can't win.
So if you just match his offer,
I'm gonna swing it your way.
Goodbye.
Who hurt you?
What made you this way?
You know what you're
messing with here?
You know how important this is?
We've been poring over those jury files.
We found this in the Cincinnati stack.
He used the name David Lancaster.
He was prospective juror number 54,
but he didn't make it on.
Call Doyle. Tell him to pack.
He'll be on the first flight to cincinnati.
Let's see if Mr. Lancaster's
left any loose ends behind.
Everybody's got a dirty little secret.
Let's find out what his is.
- Where the hell is he?
- He was in his room an hour ago.
I know. I thought you had
someone babysitting.
- I'll keep trying the hotel.
- Find him. Get him here.
Mr. Rohr, is everything all right
down there?
Everything's fine, Your Honor.
You called Mr. Kriegler 10 minutes ago.
Could we show him in, please?
Your Honor...
- Your Honor, may I approach?
- You may. Mr. Cable.
You let me know when he finds him.
Your Honor, I'd like to request
a brief adjournment at this time.
- Where's your witness, Mr. Rohr?
- We're looking... We're looking into that.
- Request for an adjournment is denied.
- Your Honor, this is my key witness.
You should've kept
a tighter leash on him.
I told you both,
I won't stand for any more foolishness.
- We will proceed on schedule.
- Your Honor...
Mr. Rohr, is there another request
you'd like to make at this time?
It would be highly prejudicial
if we are not permitted...
I'll take that as a motion
for reconsideration. Denied.
Call your next witness.
- Call your next witness, Mr. Rohr.
- I have no next witness.
If so, Mr. Rohr, then plaintiff rests.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Wendall Rohr.
An overdue pleasure.
Rankin Fitch.
Nice suit. V ery "of the people."
Yours is nicer. You call it,
"gun lobby protecting its own"?
Swank shoes.
- Big tobacco?
- Big alligator. Wrestled it myself.
Excuse me, we're cleaning up in here.
- Am I gonna get beat up?
- What'd you do to my witness?
Threaten his family, write a check?
Just curious what your technique is.
Maybe he decided against
biting the hand that fed him.
You know exactly why he came to us.
Oh, please, don't tell me you hung
your case on somebody's conscience.
I hung my case on my own conscience.
I get it now.
You are a moral man living in a world
of moral relativity. It's just so quaint.
- So precious.
- Don't do that!
This is about my witness
and you messing with my client...
...my case and the rules of law
that govern our country.
- Our country?
- Yes!
I didn't figure you for a patriot.
With your disregard for people's right
to bear arms. "Second Amendment"?
You're doing this to protect
the Constitution?
Of course not. I'm in it to win.
Just like you are.
That's what I was hired to do.
Everything else is colored bubbles.
Colored bubbles?! Colored bubbles?
A system that calls for 12 people to sit
and listen to testimony of witnesses.
And that includes my witness,
who you've disappeared.
If you're relying on testimony to win
this case, you've already lost it, fella.
You think this jury cares anything about
negligent distribution, product liability?
You bet they do!
They can't say the words,
let alone understand the meaning.
Think your average juror
is King Solomon? No.
He's a roofer with a mortgage.
He wants to go home,
sit in his Barcalounger...
...and let the cable TV wash over him.
This man doesn't give a single, solitary
droplet of shit about truth, justice...
...or your American way.
- They're people, Fitch.
- My point exactly.
You don't have an idea of what
I've been talking about, do you, sir?
What do you hope to achieve
if you win?
- What do you mean?
- Bring Jacob Wood back to life? No.
You just ensure that his wife
goes to the cemetery in a better car.
That the heel that she snaps
on the way to the graveside...
...belongs to a $ 1200 shoe.
And you get your name in the paper.
But Jacob Wood
and all the other gun-violence victims...
...remain rotting in their crypts.
You know what, Fitch?
- You're gonna lose.
- I doubt it.
Well, maybe not this case,
maybe not the next, but someday.
You know, someday.
I've seen it before with guys like you.
- You wanna know why?
- Why?
Because you cannot carry that much
contempt without it becoming malignant.
Until you'll be all alone
in a room full of shadows...
...and all you're gonna have...
...is the memories of all those lives
you have destroyed.
Well, that's a good story, Wendall.
But it's just further proof
of why you can't beat me.
Because you may be right...
...but the thing of it is,
I don't give a shit.
What's more...
...I never have.
That suit.
- Good evening, Wendall.
- George. Mason.
So...
...what's this about?
I'm going to need access
to the firm's emergency reserve.
- Emergency reserve?
- Yeah.
- In what amount?
- Ten million.
Gentlemen, I've lost my footing
in this trial.
- I'm looking for a David Lancaster.
- Are you a bill collector?
I work for Dodge,
tracking people down...
...who have rebates they
forgot to apply for.
I don't know where he went.
No forwarding address.
Wish I did, though.
Got this letter for him.
- Kept it right here.
- Wow, can I take a look at that?
"Jeff Kerr, care of David Lancaster."
- You know Jeff Kerr?
- No.
"Professor Frank Phelan
at Bloomington University."
I could maybe split the rebate
with you, if you wanted to...
Jeff Kerr.
David Lancaster.
Lots of aliases.
Jeffrey Kerr.
Hello there, Jeffrey.
So as CEO of Vicksburg Firearms...
...you were unaware that your product
was being sold illegally?
Yes, sir. Absolutely, sir.
Mr. Jankle, are you a family man?
Yes, sir, I am. I have a son.
I have an 8-year-old grandson.
Anything else you'd like to add?
The Second Amendment...
...permits every good citizen
of this country to keep and bear arms.
We at Vicksburg Firearms
didn't write it...
...but as long as it stands, we'll continue
to operate under its protections.
- Thank you, sir. Nothing further.
- Counselor.
Mr. Rohr, do you care to cross?
- Yes, Your Honor.
- Proceed.
- Now, Mr. Jankle.
- Yes, sir.
The ad copy used to sell the Performa
990, read it to the court, please.
It's right there, counselor.
The jury would like to hear it
from the head of the company.
If you could start with
"Also available in."
"Also available
in a print-resistant finish."
I see. Who in your mind...
...might be eager to purchase...
...a Performa 990 semiautomatic
assault-type weapon...
...in a fingerprint-resistant finish?
- Anybody.
- Anybody?
Fingerprints are 90°/. water.
Water corrodes metal. Metal rusts.
Wouldn't it be more appropriate then
to use "rustproof" ...
...than "fingerprint-resistant"
when you sell it to the general public?
Well, I didn't write the copy
for that advertisement, sir.
- Did you see it?
- Objection. Prejudicial.
Sustained. Mr. Rohr.
My apologies, Your Honor.
- Now, Mr. Jankle.
- Yes, sir.
How much of Vicksburg profits come
from assault-type weapons?
Oh, I have to apologize to you,
I'm not familiar with that percentage.
But you are familiar with who buys
a weapon of this sort?
- The gun's intended for recreational use.
- Farmers, weekend sportsmen?
- Home protection.
- Or disgruntled day traders...
- Objection, Your Honor.
- We sell these guns legally.
Come on, you know that this gun
is favored by criminals.
- Statistics show that.
- That is up to law enforcement.
So that's not your problem.
- Objection.
- It is the government's responsibility.
Tell the jury that it's not your problem.
Say it to Celeste Wood...
...who lost her husband,
that it's not your problem.
- Tell the people...
- You amaze me.
...that the print-resistant finish
is not your problem!
I stand on the Second Amendment,
goddamn it!
We've got damage-control strategies...
...and your testimony
before cross was strong.
Oh, you! I mean, you are the one that
told me denial was the route to take.
- I was improperly prepped.
- Look...
You, get out of here.
Mr. Fitch, I looked in the faces
of those jurors.
I didn't see friends.
Where are we with securing my verdict?
It's a cat-and-mouse game.
We're about to change...
You just be a little more cat,
little less mouse.
Yes, sir.
- Hello, Marlee.
- Hello, Rankin.
I'm ready to make a deal.
I'll meet your terms.
I'll pay you the money.
- I wanna meet Nick Easter.
- Won't happen.
Wendall doesn't need to meet him.
Besides, you know he's sequestered.
Well, fine. How about his pal,
Jeffrey Kerr?
Now, we meet or there's no deal.
Non-negotiable. What's it gonna be?
I hope you don't mind. I was waiting
so long, I made a sandwich.
It's a fine piece, Nick.
- Longines hunter case, circa 1908.
- 1910, actually.
- You filming this?
- No, no, no, I couldn't use it.
- Neither of us wants a mistrial.
- No.
Can we walk?
Our bus is leaving at 8 a.m.,
so that gives us a little time together.
Marlee, please come out of the kitchen.
I'm not here to hurt you.
Please, sweetheart, sit down. Relax.
So, what, I'm supposed to convince you
that I have them, right?
Oh, I think you've probably got them
or you will have.
- I just want to know why.
- Money.
Safer ways for a sharp kid like you
to make money. What's the real reason?
Business, politics, sports.
You tell me what isn't rigged.
Is there such a thing
as an objective jury?
Not if I can help it.
Then why should the lawyers
and guys like you make all the profit?
- You don't have much faith in the law.
- I'm agnostic.
I knew there was something
I liked about you.
And Marlee?
- She can tell you her reasons.
- Not what I'm talking about.
What are you talking about?
How well do you know her?
Did you really bring me out here
to talk about her?
- What's this about?
- Well...
...tomorrow's the big day,
and we need a little insurance.
So...
...let's talk.
Come on out here,
sit down and talk.
I'll make you a sandwich.
I'm ready to pay the money.
I can have 10 million wire-transferred
to the Caymans...
...subject to verification,
of course.
But tell me, who have you got?
Fernandez, DeShazo, Grimes
and Dupree are in the bag.
Deets and Duke pretty much
follow the others.
- Herrera and Shaver are wild cards.
- No, Shaver's taken care of. Weese too.
Herrera, I wouldn't worry about him.
Are you gonna swing this my way?
If you pay, yes, I will.
Good. Good.
Tell Marlee I'm ready
to conclude our business.
Done.
I must say, I'm impressed, Mr. Kerr.
- L...
- Easter.
Easter, correct.
I didn't see you coming.
Obviously, I underestimated you.
And as a rule, I don't do that.
Make damn sure
you don't underestimate me.
I'm sure one of us will be in touch.
I have a feeling after tonight,
we're gonna be fast friends.
Who is it?
Who is this?
Bet you didn 't expect to hear
from me so soon.
Is this a bad time?
- No, not at all.
- Oh, good.
Listen, I just wanted you to know
your associate with the accent...
...he's not coming home tonight.
At least he won't be walking home.
And the price just went up.
Fifteen million, non-negotiable.
Get some sleep, Rankin.
You're gonna need it.
Hey.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, I just...
I just wanted to hear your voice.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
- I want you to get some sleep.
- Yeah.
I miss you. Good night.
Lawyers Wendall Rohr and Derwood
Cable will have their last chances...
...to strike the winning blow in the case
of Celeste Wood v. Vicksburg Firearms.
Closing arguments will begin shortly.
The jury has now heard
all the evidence...
It's been a very highly-charged trial.
The jury has been sequestered.
They could begin deliberations today.
The high-stake decision will soon be
in the hands of the jury.
This decision could be quick,
with the jury delivering a verdict...
... perhaps by day's end.
All Jacob Wood
and those 10 people did...
... all they did wrong...
...on that Monday morning
was to go to work.
There's gonna be another shooting
and another shooting...
...and it's not gonna let up
until we demand a change.
You heard Mr. Garland Jankle...
...the chief CEO of Vicksburg Firearms...
...sit in that chair and say to you what
we do with his guns is not his problem.
And he's right. You can make it
his problem with your verdict.
You may, for the first time...
...make gun violence...
...the gun industry's problem.
If you do...
...you are going to see
fewer senseless deaths.
Like my client's husband, Jacob Wood.
Big wish! Big wish!
That's my boy.
Jeff had a real passion for the law.
He spent the summer
after his first year on a trial.
The reality of how a big firm
actually practices law...
...knocked some of the idealistic wind
right out of him.
Because the following spring, after
Gabby got her undergraduate degree...
...he dropped out, and they left.
- Did you say Gabby?
Gabrielle Brandt. She was Jeff's girl
from back home in Gardner.
Gardner, Indiana?
Only one I know of.
Jacob Wood, a man in his prime,
leaves behind a wife and little boy.
The sadness of that...
...the incomprehension,
that gives way to anger.
We must even the score. Not just those
that are directly affected, but all of us.
We all experience these emotions.
Which is precisely why the law exists,
to do what is just.
Now, these families grieve,
and we all grieve for them...
...but that is all the law
will allow us to do.
Doyle, where the hell are you?
Headed for exit 245.
Some backwater town in central Indiana,
but I think I got a good lead on the girl.
Well, move it along.
The judge is about to give this thing
to the jury. Shit.
Ladies and gentlemen, you've heard
the evidence and arguments of counsel.
I will give you some instructions,
after which we will hold a recess...
... and then you will begin deliberations.
- Wendall Rohr.
- Hello, Wendall.
Well, hello, Marlee.
Good to hear your voice.
Did you come up with the money?
You know, it's amazing how easy it is
to procure $ 10 million.
It's an interesting exercise.
Ten million dollars, like it was nothing.
But as bad as I want to win this case,
and I do...
... after 35 years of doing this,
you know...
...it's more important that I can
rest my head on the pillow at night.
- What are you saying?
- I will take my chances.
I'm not giving you a dime.
Not a dime.
Well, I am sorry about this.
- Because you're giving it to Fitch.
- I'm giving it to Fitch?
I'm gonna take my chances.
Hello. Hello, there.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I'm thinking of buying this house.
My wife and I have a 3-year-old
and another one on the way.
Is this a good neighborhood for kids?
Oh, this is a great neighborhood for kids.
I raised my girls here.
- Oh, really?
- I sure did.
His life was taken from him.
People were killed...
...and the gun company made it happen
by flouting the law.
Come on, Loreen, where does it end? All
these folks suing for profit. What next?
Have a heart attack, sue McDonald's?
Sue my grocery store because
you bought some pork chops...
...now you got clogged arteries.
- You been smoking.
It is still our right to keep and bear arms.
Remember that.
Well, Mr. Fitch, are we concluding
our business today or not?
- Could you hold for just one minute?
- One minute.
- Doyle, give me something.
- I can't really talk right now, sweetheart.
I met this nice lady, and she's telling me
all about the neighborhood.
The jury has the case.
- There could be a verdict any second.
- I hear you.
I'll call you back as soon
as I get on the road, okay?
- Doyle...
- I love you too.
All right. Bye.
Word just in.
Rohr's not paying.
It's yours.
Marlee, unhappy news, I hear.
Rohr has taken himself out of the game.
I thought you might be inclined to
make a reduction in your selling price.
Look, Rankin, in 30 seconds,
you're still gonna lose. Understand?
Now, do we have a deal or don't we?
We have a deal.
- I'm wiring the money.
- Congratulations.
You bought yourself a verdict.
It's not our job to change the law.
It is our duty to serve it. The law says
this guy Kevin Peltier was responsible...
...not the gun company.
Yes, we are meant to serve the law...
...but the law is also meant
to serve all of the people.
I'm with you, Frank.
Founding Fathers and all that.
Ladies and gentlemen, whoa!
I think a preliminary vote would help us,
if nobody has anything new to say.
- Let's vote.
- I'd like to say something.
- Couldn't be easy.
- Hey, Frank, let him speak.
Well, I hope you like lots of sugar
in your iced tea.
- Oh, yes, ma'am, I surely do.
- Well, that's good.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Are these your daughters?
Gabrielle and Margaret.
They were Irish twins.
You know, just one grade apart.
Forgive me.
It's still hard to talk about.
I'm sorry?
Well, it was bad enough
losing Margaret...
...but it's been so long
since I've spoken to Gabby...
- ...I just feel like I've lost them both.
- Well...
...what happened?
How did Margaret pass away?
You're not from around here.
You wouldn't know about the shooting.
I don't think this case is about guns.
It's about the law.
And like Frank says,
it's about serving the law.
Guns are involved,
and I don't know anybody in the world...
...who doesn't feel strongly about guns
one way or the other.
- What's wrong, Frank?
- I can guess which way you lean.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You've had an agenda
the whole time you've been here.
- You're the plaintiff's boy.
- Come on. What are you saying?
- It's the truth.
- What?
- Let him speak.
- What's the problem?
They made a good product.
It worked. Case closed.
It's more complicated than that.
A boy, James Pratt...
...showed up at the high school with
guns that he bought off the street...
...and he just started firing.
Yeah, I'm sorry the lady lost her
husband. I am, but that's life.
I know a lot of other people had bad
times, but they never sued anybody.
- Like who?
- Like my buddies, lost their arms or legs.
- Never got a dime.
- They deserved better. You're right!
You bet I'm right. We're done here,
Easter. Could we vote, please?
That's not good enough.
That's not good enough!
I wanna talk about the law.
I wanna talk about Celeste Wood.
The school said that something
had happened to Margaret.
That she had died.
- She doesn't deserve that money.
- She deserves a few hours of our time.
- Can we vote, please?
- Yes.
- Tell me why.
- I wanna vote. Anybody else?
- I wanna vote. Does anyone else?
- Let's vote.
- How's it work?
- Pipe down, Easter.
- Tell me why.
We all got problems here,
don't we? All of us.
- We don't get paid for it.
- She's suffered!
I suffered. I worked my ass off 12 years
at crummy jobs for shit pay.
- I have never asked for a handout.
- She's not asking for a handout.
That is bullshit.
She was with Jeff, Gabby's boyfriend.
He told me that my girl...
...she froze. She just stood there.
It took seconds.
Jeff just kept saying, "I couldn't
reach her. I couldn't pull her down."
He always thought there was something
that he could've done.
What are we gonna tell Celeste?
"Life isn't fair"? Write it on a postcard?
- Is that the best we've got?
- I tell you what else.
That lawyer can show me
all the home movies he wants...
...I deserve a lot more for what
I've been through than that woman!
- Forget her!
- What about the law?
Fuck the law!
I don't care if the gun company gave him
an M-16 with a morning doughnut...
...I'm not giving her a cent.
That's bullshit, Frank.
Bullshit.
Who's with Frank?
Yes, I'd like to report a robbery in
progress at Mardi Gras Costumes.
6510 Charter Street.
Maybe some of you are afraid
or intimidated.
Maybe some of you
are just out for yourselves.
Frank is right about me.
I'm the worst offender here.
I made up my mind about this case
before I stepped through that door.
But this trial's not about me.
And it's not about you. Now, we owe it
to Celeste Wood to sit in this room...
...and deliberate the facts of the case
for as long as it takes.
If you don't mind,
there's testimony I'd like to review.
Mr. Fitch.
- Yeah?
- Don't wire the money!
What? What's going on?
Where are you?
I'm in Gardner. Gardner, Indiana.
It's a setup.
Gardner.
- Take the front! Get it open!
- Oh, shit. We got company.
Take the network down now.
Okay, people, pack it up, tear it down.
Now! This is not a test. Clear your
drives. Wipe the screens. Let's go.
Box all photos and files.
No monitors. Leave the monitors.
Code four, people.
- Mr. Fitch.
- Thirty seconds!
We really need to go, sir.
Twenty seconds!
- Lamb, what happened in Gardner?
- 1989, Gardner v. Blackwell Arms.
Town sued the gun manufacturer.
Town lost. Town went bankrupt.
Fitch worked the case. You got it?
Fitch worked the case.
- Plan to hear the jury's decision.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
- We have, Your Honor.
- Hand it to the bailiff, please.
Thank you, bailiff.
In the matter of Celeste Wood
v. Vicksburg Firearms...
...the jury finds for the plaintiff,
Celeste Wood.
They award special damages
in the amount of $ 1 million...
...and general damages
in the amount of $ 110 million.
May I remind you
this court is still in session.
- The court is in session. Order. Order.
- That's bullshit!
That's enough. Court's adjourned.
When Judge Harkin read this verdict...
...a spontaneous round of applause
from the courtroom.
Support for the teary-eyed widow who
waged war on the entire gun industry.
No doubt a surprise...
No matter what the anti-gun lobbyists
say or the NRA says...
...on this day, in this courtroom,
the final word was given by the jury.
There have been other lawsuits filed
against gun manufacturers in the past...
... and juries have traditionally sided
with the gun industry, until today.
The $ 110 million award, which the jury
handed Celeste Wood today...
... could cripple the gun industry.
And to say it's been an uphill battle
for Mr. Rohr is an understatement.
In fact, you might say it's been
a David and Goliath battle.
But today in New Orleans,
one gun-industry giant has fallen.
The 12 people who sat on that jury...
Ten years, Fitch.
They're gonna appeal. The gun company.
You know that, right?
Of course.
But not with you.
You show up on another case, any case,
even a contested parking ticket...
...this goes to the IRS.
And the Justice Department,
Federal Board of Judicial Review.
You're out. Retired as of today.
Gardner, Indiana.
School shooting.
- He remembers.
- Blackwell Arms.
The town really thought
they had that one, didn't they?
We did have it.
Now what?
What on earth are you gonna do
with all that money?
- $ 15 million, that changes people.
- Yeah, well, that's what we're hoping.
See, back home, the victims' families
could really use that money.
Goodbye, Fitch.
Well, wait. How did you swing them?
How'd you swing them your way?
I hear you got 10 votes.
How'd you do that?
I didn't swing anybody. I just
stopped you from stealing the thing.
We let them vote their hearts.
That means you lose.
Enjoy your drink.
What are you...? You think you can
just walk away from this?
And I'm betting that the two of you,
you can't stop.
Because if you did,
what would you have?
Nothing!
- We're having lunch.
- Why?
We're celebrating, that's why.
Do you know why we're celebrating?
We are very happy today.
Go inside, get me an order of corn bread.
Get them that table.
- I'm just gonna be one minute.
- You got it.
I wanna go home.
Okay.
Let's go.