CARRUTHERS:
I'm telling you something...
You've got to be careful
when you're
doing your stakeouts.
I did one for... I was
on one for six months.
I gained, like, 20, 25 pounds.
You keep eating this crap...
MESSNER: Well, that's
my problem, though.
I don't gain weight. I tried.
That's 'cause
you're 12 years old.
Yeah, well, then,
who gives a shit?
Can I get you
something to drink?
You're disgusting.
Come on, don't keep it
by the water either.
Don't even let it
rub shoulders
with the other bottle.
Do you know what?
Urine is good for your skin.
My grandmother...
I swear to God,
my grandmother told me.
She said... She did, 'cause
when I used to get a zit
or something, she said...
She pissed on your face?
Get the fuck out of here.
Are you fucking nuts?
What?
It's my grandmother!
You just told me your grandma
said that piss
is good for your skin.
Have some respect. Come on.
STEVE ON RADIO. :
We have some activity here.
Why don't you speak
a little louder, Steve?
Just keep it fucking down.
CARRUTHERS: What, now?
The old man's in bed.
The nurse is in there,
and then Serna
is somewhere in the house.
Who's in the back?
Who's in the back? Joe.
Joe.
Joe, are you guys
seeing anything?
Because if you are,
it's certainly not
coming up here in the van
and we'd certainly like
to see what's going on.
We've been here for 16 hours.
It's pretty dead.
Thank you,
Captain Obvious.
All right well,
just stay awake, guys.
Stay on it. Stay alert.
AGENT 1.: Hey, yo, Mike,
where are you, man?
I can't see you now.
Are you nervous?
What?
What kind of deodorant
do you use?
I don't use deodorant.
Look at you.
What? I live in a van.
What does that mean?
It's bad for you.
It causes Alzheimer's.
What?
Alzheimer's. You get
Alzheimer's if you're
using antiperspirant
with aluminum.
I'm sorry. I forgot.
I don't remember
what you said. What?
Fucking asshole.
Watch it. Watch it.
Watch who your
superior is, pal.
STEVE. : Serna just picked up
the house phone.
AGENT 2.: He's on the phone
now. He is on the phone.
He's on the phone.
AGENT 1.: I got some movement
in there.
Ricky, pan to the right
and zoom in.
Okay, we got him.
We got him. We got him.
Here we go. Here we go.
Zoom back in
and stay there.
STEVE. : He is on the phone.
Do you guys have
any transmission?
He's on the phone.
Quiet, quiet. We got it.
He's talking
to someone right now.
Just keep zooming in.
SERNA. : Buzz.
Dialogue hot. Dialogue hot.
Everybody off the walkies now.
Everybody off air.
You got clicks?
PADICHE: Clicks? No.
Nothing on my end.
The line's clean.
STEVE. : Do you guys have
any signal out there?
Yeah, we got it.
Please stay off the walkies.
Buzzy, I'm upstairs.
I can't talk very loud.
Primo's downstairs.
I've been sitting
by this phone
for 20 fucking hours.
Now listen to me, Buzzy.
He's going to clip Israel.
Clip?
He's gonna kill him?
Buddy Israel?
Now, I was eavesdropping,
so let me lay
this thing out neat.
All right,
I'm listening.
Go ahead.
Now, what I heard
downstairs is they got
a guy. Some Swede.
Swede.
You know a Swede?
You know of a Swede?
Nothing.
Supposedly, a specialist.
And he ain't coming cheap.
So I'm thinking we jump,
get to Israel before
the Swede can,
we're in a power position.
We grab him...
It's a double-cross.
... ransom him back,
pick up that nut.
We're that much closer to
doing our own thing.
Kidnapping?
Can we bring this off?
Hey, we keep our mouth
shut, play the part,
nobody suspects a thing.
The old man's
on the fade, Buzzy.
Fuck them, you know.
These guys got balls.
Let me tell you.
These guys got some balls.
Do they ever.
Jesus Christ,
this is our time now.
You think they'll
really kick ransom
for Israel?
You ain't heard
the punch line.
But before I get to it,
one more thing. I should
probably bring it up.
Primo wants Israel's heart.
What'd he just say?
He's going to cut
his heart out.
His heart?
Jesus, what for?
He's been snitching
to the world.
I can't even blame Primo.
You know,
he's old-school Sicilian.
This is how they hate.
Now, big concern for me,
at least, we crew up.
Let's not fuck around.
Someone's cousin, some zip
off the boat from Naples.
Zip off the boat?
Let's get pros.
People who know
how to behave.
This thing's gonna
blow up huge.
You know, there's
a pair of broads I think
might be very good for this.
Which broads?
They're reliable?
They're good? What?
Two of the best.
They hit those Chinamen,
took out the big triad.
These girls are worth every
penny. I'll call Loretta.
She handles both of them.
All right.
Odds are they're gonna
get into some shit.
Might have to
put people down.
These guys
aren't fucking around.
PADICHE. : Well, just so
I get a quote in my head,
how much is the Swede getting?
That's the punch line.
You ready?
Here's the punch line.
One million flat.
Holy shit.
If word hits the street
that there's
a million-dollar bounty
for Buddy fucking Israel,
you're gonna have every
fucking hit man in the free
world looking for him.
We got to move quickly.
No more tomorrow.
I got to go, Buzzy.
He said one million.
One million.
One million,
plus the fucking heart.
Plus the heart.
And Buddy Israel.
Holy shit.
These guys want him bad.
Ladies and gentlemen,
there's a guy,
he is one of the biggest
stars in the world.
And we are thrilled
to have him stop by.
And he's won
all kinds of awards.
He has won
Entertainer of the Year
every year in Las Vegas
for the last five years.
Ladies and gentlemen,
would you give
a big round of applause,
a big Las Vegas welcome,
to a great Las Vegas star
and his name
is Mr. Buddy Israel!
Come on out here!
DUPREE. : Buddy "Aces" Israel.
Card sharp. Illusionist.
Asshole.
I say this
from the bottom
of my heart. Retire.
Douchebag.
Five-time Vegas
Showman of the Year.
The wiseguys,
for some fucking reason,
love him.
They think he's,
like, a mystic.
You know, something special.
Nice shot.
Now, Buddy starts
making friends.
The connected kind.
He's doing the Sinatra thing.
Becomes
the unofficial mob mascot.
Can I whack anybody?
Who am I gonna whack?
Stop it. Stop it.
Now he's got connections.
He's got pull.
So he starts to make plays.
Wants to live
the mob life for real.
Bankrolls a couple of B&Es.
Rich folks.
Fronts some smash-and-grabs,
pawn shops, jewelry stores,
that kind of thing.
Then he gets his dick wet.
Strong-arm robbery.
Get in the van, man!
Get in the van now!
Go! Go! Go!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Vegas lounge act
turns legitimate thug.
Truth is, Buddy
don't know the fucking ball
from the bounce.
What do you got?
He's a wannabe.
Like most wannabes,
he starts fucking up fast
and picking up speed.
Are you fucking kidding me?
That's good work.
Good fucking work.
I love it.
His little criminal foray
shines a floodlight on the
entire Carlotta organization.
Cops get curious,
they start camping out
and everything goes sideways
real fucking quick.
People get pinched,
snitches snitch.
The next thing you know,
Buddy Israel
has brought the heat to bear
on none other than
Mr. Primo Sparazza himself.
Enforcer,
extortionist, killer.
Sparazza has been rumored
to have performed
in excess of
100 contract murders,
including one of the Bureau's
most celebrated agents,
Freeman Heller.
I thought Heller
was a double-op?
He worked for the OSS
before joining
the Bureau in its heyday.
He was the first operative
assigned with
infiltrating the mob.
Fake identity,
falsified backgrounds,
everything that is now
standard operating procedure,
Heller implemented
way back when.
...your attention
to these overlays,
I'll show you exactly
what I meant when I said,
"Change my face."
And as a result,
his undercover work
was highly successful.
Using the latest techniques
in cosmetic surgery,
I will have my ears
pinned back.
Removing a slight piece
of bone in my chin,
I will alter my jaw line.
Eventually, he reached
the rank of capo inside
the Carlotta crime family,
but due to some
internal slipup,
his cover was compromised.
Primo Sparazza
was given the contract
to kill him.
Sparazza is
a bit of a specter.
Over the years, the serious
crimes with which he was
thought to be involved with,
including Heller's murder,
could never be
traced back to him.
A dedicated viciousness
and slavish devotion
to mob doctrine
had Sparazza's star
on the rise.
So they relocated him to
Nevada and made him the head
of the Las Vegas Cosa Nostra.
Water.
What's his connection
to Israel?
Sparazza introduced
Israel to the life.
Gave him his first big break
onstage, brought him up
through the ranks.
And Israel played
the situation very shrewdly.
Slowly amassing the loyalties
of Sparazza's top men,
with the idea
of toppling the throne.
You know, I've seen
some stupid moves, but...
Well, you spend your life
pulling rabbits out of hats
and sawing people in half,
anything seems possible.
Israel wanted to touch
something real,
something dangerous.
But what he wound up doing
was splitting the family
into dual factions.
Sparazza on one side,
Israel on the other.
The infighting that followed
drew the interest
of every investigative body
operating under the canopy
of the federal government.
This is it, right here.
Presently, we have...
Sixteen state
and federally-funded agencies
running concurrent
criminal probes
on select members
of La Cosa Nostra.
LOCKE. : With Israel
being the target of
virtually every one.
His testimony
has the potential
of blowing the lid
off of what's left
of La Cosa Nostra
in this country.
That alone warrants
total immunity
from prosecution
and a vanishing act with the
Witness Protection Program.
The wiretaps
on Serna and Padiche,
mention of Israel's heart?
Well, that corroborates
what we already know.
Sparazza's health
is in rapid decline
and before he dies,
he is demanding
the heart of his sworn enemy.
A recently opened
million-dollar escrow account
has been traced
back to Sparazza.
That, and the mention
of this mysterious Swede
makes the contract on Israel
all the more real.
SYKES: How real?
How about six figures
for that fool?
How's that love?
Bullshit.
No, baby.
They heard about
that triad hit,
the work y'all put in.
And they recognize
the skills.
Now, you all want this?
Hell, yeah.
Well, I'm gonna
get it for you.
What?
There it is! There it is!
You called the right bitches
for this one, man.
You see? Write that shit down.
Are you saying that just
because me and baby girl
here got a rep on the rise,
you know,
we chipped some nails
on some niggas,
they want us to
go in and drop
this mafioso motherfucker?
The way it works, girl.
Y'all peeled some
serious caps. Word travels.
So, we're supposed
to go in there,
bust on this punk
and remove his heart.
Is that for real?
You go in and pull him out.
That heart shit?
That's just for flavor.
Now, I'm still trying
to get the down-Iow
from this cat Padiche.
What we got right now
is a number and a name.
Buddy Israel.
What else did Padiche say?
He said the shit might get hot
and might get heavy.
I said, "Cool. 'Cause I got
two of the hottest,
"heaviest bitches alive."
Like who?
Like Pasquale Acosta.
Blood-money mercenary.
His countrymen have dubbed him
the more dubious "El Estrago."
"The Plague."
American educated. Fluent in
over a dozen languages.
Freelanced for the CIA.
Noted for his
legendary torture techniques.
(SCREAMING)
When he was caught by the SAS
in Northern Ireland,
in prison he chewed off
his fingertips to the bones,
so he couldn't be
printed or ID'd by Interpol.
Is it possible that
he could be involved in this?
A million-dollar hit fee
would draw some huge flies.
And Acosta's pure mercenary.
He has a history of
taking on tough kills,
and he's certainly not alone.
Who else?
How about the Tremor Brothers?
Three of them.
Same skank mom,
different deadbeat dads.
They're used for
that suicide-style,
kamikaze shit.
Heard about that
dinner club in Cleveland?
That got squat-fucked,
shot to shit,
slashed and burned?
What happened?
Well, the Tremor Brothers
go rip-shit riot
on the whole fucking place.
Seven dead, 28 wounded.
Just to get
this one fucking guy.
In the course of the melee,
one of them gets shot
in the neck. He passes out.
Another one catches blowback
from a jammed piece.
He's temporarily blinded.
Third one gets
a bullet lodged in his back,
he can't walk.
They're speed-freak,
neo-Nazi assholes
who read and recite
Mein Kampf like it was
Mother Goose.
They're meaner than shit,
they're dumber than hell
and these motherfuckers
will go megaton
at the drop of a hat.
S YKES. : I ain't never
heard of him.
WATTERS. : Me, neither.
Then listen up,
'cause he may wind up
being your main competition.
His name is Soot. Lazlo Soot.
A lot of folks want
this white boy clapped.
Word is Soot is working
for one of them.
Now, they don't know
where he's from, how long
he's been in the game,
or even what he looks like.
But when Soot decides to move
on somebody,
they're the last ones
to see it coming.
DUPREE. : So, there it is.
The bond on Buddy Israel
expires in 18 hours.
After that, it's a jump ball.
Who posted the bond?
Same guys who hired me,
his former law firm.
He walked out the door
after he made bail.
Hasn't been seen since.
If this Israel really is
the great white whale
of snitches,
then what are we doing
messing with the mob,
who are,
correct me if I'm wrong, but
I think they're going to pour
boxes of bullets into his ass?
Here we go.
What incentive
is there to track him
on something as small time
as a fucking skip trace?
I take it you're not going.
No, I'm gonna go
into Kentucky
and take Fort Knox
with a fucking slingshot,
and after that I'm gonna go
into hell after Hitler.
Would you please
find your fangs,
you fucking coward,
and get with this?
What is wrong with you?
Seriously.
Listen, I know
where Israel is, okay?
So we have maybe a day
before that location
that I know
gets grapevined and
the whole fucking world
gets hip to this.
He's in Lake Tahoe
on the Nevada side.
We got to lay
something out, though.
You go up in there
ad-libbing and shit,
it's your ass.
What are we talking
on the split?
Forty-five a piece
for you two.
Ten percent finder's fee
for me.
So, what's
the time frame?
Fast as we can
get you there.
We wait any longer,
someone gonna dead this fool.
MESSNER. : Then we
lose our witness.
And we lose our case.
Now, Israel's manager,
a man by the name
of Morris Mecklen,
has guaranteed us
that Israel will enter
into protective custody
once the government
has approved his deal.
Now, we've been monitoring
Mecklen's phone calls,
and we've learned that Israel
is at the penthouse level
of the Nomad Hotel and Casino
in Lake Tahoe, Nevada.
The high-roller suite?
No, that's the last place
they'd look.
Israel's lawyers were left
holding the bag
after he skipped bail.
And Rupert Reed, one of
the firm's partners, has
learned of his whereabouts.
And he's dispatched
a local bondsman
by the name of Jack Dupree
to pick him up and
return him to Las Vegas.
It's very simple, gentlemen.
We can't allow that to happen.
A Gulfstream is waiting
at the Reagan National Airport
to transport you
to Lake Tahoe.
And I'll be flying
to Los Angeles
to finalize Israel's deal.
No former witness against
the mob has been
as crucial or as important
as Buddy "Aces" Israel.
He's not only
essential to our case,
he is our case.
And understand that
if an attempt
is made on his life,
it'll be made by those
of the strictest
professional caliber.
They are amoral, ruthless
and without restraint.
They must not succeed.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
PADICHE. : Sid.
SERNA. : Yeah, Buzzy, I just
got a call from the mansion.
The Swede has arrived.
No shit.
The old man
sent for him.
So get yourself
on a plane and
get your ass to Lake Tahoe.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Fuck you.
Goodbye.
Good luck.
Godspeed.
Good day, sir.
Hey, baby.
Don't fuck... What the...
Where you going?
You call Mecklen?
(IN EASTERN EUROPEAN ACCENT)
I got the machine.
What did you say?
I leave message.
I know you left a message.
What did you say?
Hugo, you're staring at me
like I just asked you
for the fucking
square root of something.
What did you say to Mecklen
on the little
motherfucking machine?
That you were returning
his call and you were very,
very concerned.
Wow, that's
fantastic work, man.
You have the wisdom
of a 6,000
or 7,000-year-old man.
That's fantastic.
We don't have to
fill up the whole
blackboard after all.
Do me a favor, will you?
Will you tell me what that is?
About what?
Look at the collar on
that coat. What does that
look like? That stain?
I don't know.
Cinnamon roll?
(IMITATING ACCENT) Is it
cinnamon roll? The cinnamon.
The roll of the cinnamon?
That looks like jizz.
Yeah.
Eastern European jizz.
That looks like some fuckhead
shot his load on a $12,000
calfskin jacket!
The twist is it's my
$12,000 calfskin jacket!
So, you got the semen,
okay, you've got
the human ejaculate
that's been allowed
to soak in for, like,
7 hours! All right?
Work its way
into the fabric
fucking fibers...
If you like,
I send out.
To what? Incinerate?
Hugo!
There isn't a fucking
laundry detergent
or dry cleaning product
known to man
that will get that clean.
Some shit,
suffice it to say,
just don't wash out!
Do you want my apology?
Only if you really,
truly mean it.
I very sorry.
(PHONE RINGING)
Are you a colossal
fucking idiot?
I am, yes.
Get the phone. It's probably
Mecklen. Get Vitoli up here
and start cleaning.
All right?
And please, for me,
will you do one thing?
Get out of my fucking sight.
Yes, sir. Go ahead.
(TAPE REWINDING)
We're about three miles
from the Nomad now.
SERNA ON TAPE. : So do this in
the next day or so, get to
Israel before the Swede can,
we're in a power position.
All right,
we'll be awaiting word.
All right, we got time.
Want to go grab
something to eat?
Yeah. Any word on this Swede?
No, just the mention
in that phone call.
There's no Swedish hit man
on anyone's radar.
Maybe he's that good.
You know, never been caught.
No criminal record.
It's possible.
Maybe, but that's
very unlikely.
Jesus, I'll tell you,
engineering this kind
of play against Sparazza,
going to these lengths that
these two guys are going,
they're playing
some long odds.
Coffee? Anything?
I don't want
to order without...
No, no, we cool.
Coffee?
No, no, thanks, darling.
Lovely.
So, I spoke to Loretta
this morning.
And she told me you,
more or less,
have a plan of attack.
My associate, Mr. Serna,
I can get him on the phone
and if you could just
speak to him
and tell him your plan...
Your plans.
What you got in mind?
Pussy.
I'm sorry?
Pushy?
Pussy.
Yeah, Israel likes pussy.
And we like
that he likes...
Pussy.
Correct.
Well,
enough said.
REED: Hi, Jack. Great,
good, super. Come on in.
Good to see you.
How you doing? Pete.
Hello. Rip Reed.
Come in. Good. Good.
Great. Come on.
What's that in there...
Hello? Great. Come on in.
Sorry about that.
Hey, Hollis.
Rip Reed.
Hello, Hollis. Come on in.
So, Jack, he tells me
you guys a couple of ex-cops?
Yeah, we worked vice,
like, 6 years.
Is that right?
Four.
Four years.
About six years.
Vice.
Four, six, five. They didn't
teach you how to count,
I guess, huh?
But I bet you guys
got a bunch of stories,
right? I don't.
I grew up soft with the
private schools and little
blazers, you know, and...
Everyone talked things out,
you know?
No one ever threw any blows.
Still to this day,
never punched in the face.
Imagine that?
I'm pretty much a pantywaist.
I don't say this
to be self-deprecating.
I just, you know,
don't have much of an opinion
of myself. I'd much rather
be like you guys.
You know, bar fighters
and big, swinging dicks,
taking care of shit.
You know, sadly, this is it.
You know, it's disgusting.
Thanks, God!
Dog-pile of piss-poor physique
on top of a small cock
and hereditary alcoholism.
I appreciate it!
I'm babbling.
I do that drunk.
Please forgive.
Let's get to the
business at hand.
This wanted felon here,
Buddy Israel, little
Rick Springfield, I guess.
And his bail-bond
bobbing around up there
out at the lake.
Rip, hand to God,
you got nothing
to worry about with this.
Yeah?
Okay? I've assembled
a team now.
We're gonna go in,
we're gonna get this guy,
and everyone is gonna leave
the theater grinning.
No problem.
Will not be a problem.
Great, that's good.
You're feeling it,
you're feeling it. Come on.
Outstanding! Get it up there!
Come on. Come on, man.
And bones it.
Huh? Right there, and then
padlock it and then
you put the chain on it.
That's a new one
I'm working on.
Really getting the hairy
eyeball off that guy.
No, no. No, no.
He's all right?
He's all right. Tell him.
This is good, though, what
you're telling me. All right?
I need to hear this stuff.
Little boosts.
Helps allay my fears.
I pass that peace of mind
along to my partners.
All right. Look up. Hey, man.
That's not yours.
Put the fucking rabbit down.
Appreciate it.
Get your dick-beaters off it.
Couple of things.
The hangers-on,
his posse, you know,
they're all strapped
or packing heat,
whatever the phrase is.
Strapped.
I don't know
what you guys call it.
Strapped? Well, so,
they got guns.
What else? He drinks,
you know. Self-medicates.
Total cliché.
This guy. He's a strung-out,
washed-up, has-been,
jerk, snitch,
fucking drunk,
seven-layer loser.
Right. Now I'm praying
he puts up a fight!
Please! Please, please,
rape him if it's possible!
Punch him in the seat
or something, you know?
Hit him in the brown.
I don't know. Anyway,
I believe we had a retainer
for services rendered.
$50,000.
ISRAEL: $50,000
for this fucking suite?
Yo, calm down.
Don't tell me
to fucking calm down!
That's all
they're gonna give us.
Look at the attention
we gettin', man.
We campaigning
like niggas ain't hot.
We hot.
And they losing
a whole floor's
worth of business,
saying it's
under construction.
I am not shelling out
this kind of bread
for this shithole, all right?
This is a junior suite
in Vegas. So, fuck this
and the fucking
animal kingdom.
What?
Vitoli not answer the phone.
Go down there and get him.
Go down there!
Come on. Let's go.
Has Mecklen called?
No.
When do we get concerned?
We don't get concerned.
We'll see movement
on this soon.
All right? We just got
to knock off a few more hours.
These flowers have wilted.
Call the florist.
No, I need you to chill.
I need you
to call the florist.
When your guy gonna call?
That's what's happening.
Hey, yo, Beanie.
Hey, ladies. Get up.
Beans.
Bag them and get
some more on deck,
all right?
All right, y'all.
We did the damn thing.
Now proceed to the front
in an orderly fashion,
or how the fuck
y'all want to, but
get the fuck going.
Let's go, step lively.
Get your ass up.
Put your clothes on, girl.
You're acting like y'all
on sundial. Y'all need
to be on stopwatch.
Damn it. I didn't realize how
fucked up I was till I
just saw your ass, girl.
You went from Beyoncé
to Bigfoot in less than
six fucking hours.
Fuck you, pussy!
Hey, we did that dance,
bitch. Kick rocks.
Goddamn!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Hey, yo,
is this Madame Alex?
Hey, y'all got sick leave?
'Cause one of your hoes
just got fucked up!
Yeah, she might be
missing some work.
Oh, hell, no! This is nice.
This is real nice! Play it up!
What you doing, girl?
Come on, man. Come on.
Hoes gotta go.
Get them out of here.
Let's go!
Get them to the elevator.
GIRL: Fuck you!
Give me my purse!
Shut the fuck up!
Hey, bitch!
You forgot your hat!
Get your hands off me,
asshole!
Take your shit, bitch.
Thanks, Paul.
Israel's awake.
There was apparently a fight
with some prostitutes,
but he wasn't involved.
What, like an actual fight?
They...
Yeah, a fight.
Jesus Christ.
A scuffle, a donnybrook. Yeah.
He had one of his men
call a madam
for another group of girls.
We're getting robbed here,
man.
Seriously.
Three days staring
at Sparazza's house.
This guy's got hookers
up there fistfighting.
Look at all you're missing.
Have you checked
this stuff out yet?
This is unbelievable.
You know that Sparazza's
had major
elective plastic surgery.
Fifteen of them. Right?
Fifteen separate
procedures since 1952.
Look at the work
he's had done.
Nose, three times.
Eyes. Eyelids. Jaw.
You take every
has-been actor in Hollywood,
they haven't been
cut this much.
Easy.
Crazy, you know.
Wall-to-wall felony offenses.
Murder, of course. Extortion.
Arson. Grand larceny.
Blah, blah, blah.
And a paternity suit,
just to, you know,
round out the portfolio there.
And not one single
criminal charge
laid against him.
Well, you can't kill
over a hundred people
without knowing how to tiptoe.
Yeah, but the Bureau
knows he killed Heller.
Then why not go
after him for that?
Heller was buried
by the agency.
Any time an operative failed,
or was perceived to have
failed, he was blackballed.
Look at what happened to Ness.
Ness and the Untouchables
took down Capone.
Heller got shot and killed.
The bad guys beat him.
Worse, Sparazza walked.
How much longer you think?
Who knows? Locke has been
with the lawyers from Justice
since yesterday afternoon.
Israel's manager is acting
as his attorney. That's what's
holding things up.
So I want to be in that
penthouse a half a second
after this deal is done.
We gonna get any
guff from the hotel staff?
Israel's obviously
paid them off.
We're not gonna have
any trouble
with the hotel staff.
You show them your ID
with the letters
"FBl" in all caps,
it's instant compliance.
I've seen it happen
a hundred times.
Special Agent Gerald Diego,
Federal Bureau
of Investigation,
San Francisco Field Office.
We're conducting a series
of impromptu inspections
for the Nevada
Gaming Commission,
and I'd like to speak
with your head of security.
Okay, just one second.
Just hang on, sir.
Where'd you get these?
Same place that rents
to the guards.
All right, there's
a shift change at 9:00 a.m.
The graveyard gets off.
We're gonna slip in with the
daytime guys when they go on.
But what about
access cards, passkeys?
Yeah, well, we'll get
our hands on those
when we get inside.
Basically, there's two
security levels, okay?
You got your casino-floor,
count-room surveillance,
then you got
your general security.
But I guess your friend
don't want to hear this.
Hollis? Come on.
Get the fuck out of the car.
Come on. Come on.
How about
we put a gun to your head?
We've been
through that already.
Well, then quit acting like
someone took a shit in your
cereal bowl, all right?
Reed paid us 50 grand.
What am I doing?
Am I standing here?
Your attitude
is fucking horrible.
It's embarrassing.
All right. Cut it out.
Two security levels.
The one we're going in
under the guise of
is general hotel security.
They're basically in charge
of standing around the lobby
with their dicks
in their hands,
you know what I mean?
(SPEED METAL MUSIC BLARING)
There's a 35-person employee
contingent that goes
at 9:00 in the morning.
We're gonna break up,
split apart,
blend in with them
and reconnoiter at the hotel.
(URINE SPLASHING)
Come here! Get over here!
You stay down! You stay down!
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I forgive you, Darwin.
Shoot, I appreciate that, man.
If I needed your car
and me and my brothers
were wanted by the law,
I would've killed you
to get it, too.
You would've?
Hell, yeah.
We's just at
the wrong place
at the wrong time.
So don't feel so bad, chief.
Oh, damn.
All right, then.
You know, up here
in heaven, it's beautiful.
Really?
I'll see you up here someday.
You think so?
I know so.
Small world.
All right, enough
grab-assing, goddamn it!
Grab them suits and the car.
And pitch them
poor fellas in the lake.
And y'all follow me
over to the hotel.
(WOMEN CLAMORING)
Yeah, you want some of me?
Yeah, just wait
till we get outside!
Let go of me!
Let go of my arm!
Shut up! Fuck off!
That's gonna be real incognito
going in like that.
This is real brilliant.
You're brilliant.
Okay, why don't you just
chill for now?
Whatever.
Would you like two beds
in your room?
No, no,
we're not together. No.
Come on, baby. Don't be shy.
Just one bed, please.
Hey!
Come on, baby.
You know I'm playing
with your pretty ass.
Let me ask you a question.
Y'all really let
hoochies like that
stay up in here?
I mean, 'cause y'all
must be burning sheets
by the ton.
Well...
As a female,
that shit right there
don't get you?
Okay, it's bitches like that
the reason why niggas don't
pay our species any mind!
They don't respect us!
Yeah, we just meat
for male consumption.
Pieces of ass and pussy.
Something pretty in lipstick
and eyeliner that can
suck a fucking cock!
Shh! Shut up. What do you
have to shout for?
Shh, my ass!
She's asleep!
I'm trying to
wake this bitch up! Man!
Come here! Come here!
Bitches like that
make me weep
for what could be.
If we all sisters
everywhere, black,
white, brown and yellow,
put our shit down one time,
a unified front, you know,
the female race,
mobilized, baby,
moving as one! You feel me?
I'm gonna need
a minibar key, too.
MAN ON TAPE RECORDER. :
Say your name. Then say,
"How can I be of assistance?"
VITOLI. : I don't
understand.
I didn't ask for
your understanding.
I asked for your name,
followed by the phrase,
"How can I be
of assistance?"
My name is Vitoli.
How can I be
of assistance?
Bravo.
(GUN FIRING)
My name is Vitoli.
How can I be of assistance?
SOOT: My name is Vitoli.
My name is Vitoli.
How can I be of assistance?
(TAPE REWINDING)
My name is Vitoli.
How can I be of assistance?
(GARGLING)
(SPITTING)
My name is Vitoli.
How can I be of assistance?
Vitoli!
Let's go! What, your phone
broke or what?
Buddy wants you now up top.
Where are you,
you big nut?
Vitoli!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Come on, bitchy bitch.
You open the fucking door.
(DOOR OPENS)
Come on!
ISRAEL. : No, I tell you
something. You know what?
Listen to me. Listen.
The deal is off
in five minutes unless
they give us something.
MECKLEN. : I don't know what
to say to you.
It is what it is.
Bullshit! It isn't!
Listen...
I am not... I don't know
how to say it
any fucking louder, Morrie.
I am not giving up my boys.
And they are bricking us...
All right?
End of fucking song.
... on that particular issue,
pally.
I've been cohabitating
with these people
for the last 30 hours.
These are the premier
prick cocksuckers of all time.
And I feel beaten
by them. I feel bloodied.
You're just gonna
have to play ball.
No, I don't have to do shit,
which includes cooperating
with these fuckers,
until I get what I want!
Listen to me.
If we have to
give them someone,
give them Hugo, all right?
I can take that because he
needs that regimented prison
shit that they'll give him.
It's bigger than that.
They want everybody.
Ivy, Beanie, Hugo, the works.
This is not a fucking
swap meet, all right, Morrie?
I'm not giving up my boys
and you fucking know that.
I gave you Sparazza.
I'm gonna give them Sparazza
and the west-coast
syndicate gift-wrapped.
Get it fucking done!
Listen to me, kid.
Let's not antagonize
this any more, okay?
If we push this,
they are gonna revoke
your protective status
and that nullifies
any agreement we got.
And that is mate.
Checkmate, kiddo.
All right.
Israel rolled!
He's giving them
all up, isn't he?
His entire entourage.
He doesn't have a friend
in the world. We got to move.
Son of a bitch.
The Justice lawyers
sign off?
Yeah, that's happening.
Look, if he's gonna run,
he's gonna run now,
so we got to go!
I'm gonna call security and
make sure the whole place
is locked down.
We got to keep him
in that penthouse.
ACOSTA. : I'd like to take
a look at the penthouse.
No, I'm sorry,
the penthouse is currently
under construction.
MAN ON RADIO. : Do a sweep
on camera three. Maybe
we can pick him up.
Bill, can I
speak to you privately?
If you get a chance...
Gary? Let's get
our personnel up
on the catwalk over 12.
I don't like the rolls
that table's been getting.
It's tough, huh?
This is tough.
I don't know... This...
I don't know how you do this.
I mean, you have to
keep your eye on everything.
And everybody all the time.
Yeah, it can be a chore.
I'll bet.
So, Bill, if I'm
getting this right,
so you currently have
the penthouse level
under construction?
That's correct.
Okay.
But with these down,
doesn't that pose
a major security concern?
I mean, as you said,
you got to keep your eye
on everything at all times.
Well, we were worried
about the dust and
debris from the work
going on up there
ruining the cameras.
So you shut them off?
Yes.
Hey, Bill, you said there's
some situation on 12?
It's table 12?
Table 12. Okay?
I need somebody over
at table 12.
A little blue-haired lady
there who's rolled
about 14 times. Thank you.
Something happened
at table 14?
Table 12!
I got it.
You shut them off.
Yes. I mean, no, we...
There's personnel stationed
at both ends of that hallway
24 hours a day.
Okay.
What kind of personnel?
Right now?
A six-man security force
plus Vitoli, our executive
butler, so seven men, total.
You have an executive butler
on the floor?
Just in terms
of the men that are
up there now, my team,
serving lunch and dinner
and just generally
doing upkeep.
I'm not clear on the table.
Is it table... I'm at 12.
I don't know what
you're seeing right now, Bill.
It's a little blue-haired
lady. I'm looking at her
right now. Table 12!
She is killing it, all right?
I want you to keep
an eye on her! That's all!
It's got to be frustrating.
Copy that. We got her now.
No guests, though,
on the penthouse?
No.
We have noticed
a lot of action on that table.
Come on, Bill.
We just want to know
what's going on.
You got some sultan.
One of your whales.
No.
Big spender? Come on.
No, no.
Likes a lot of space?
Did you cook up this
little construction thing?
Is this a...
No, no.
We've been looking to renovate
that area of our hotel
for some time now.
The security in place
is solely to preserve
floor integrity.
And who else
has access to the floor, Bill?
(PHONE RINGS)
I'm sorry. We're covering
some very sensitive
material here,
and I've got to
safeguard myself,
so if you could just
show me your ID again,
get your clearance.
Of course, great.
If you could just tell me
who has access
to the floor,
I think we could...
I have the sole pass and
relieve all of the personnel
myself personally.
Now, if we can just
see your ID...
Absolutely.
Hello? Hello? Is anyone there?
I need to speak
to security right away.
This is Special Agent
Donald Carruthers of the FBI.
Hello? Is anyone there? Hello?
Is that
blood?
Yes, it is.
It's filling up
your lungs right now.
In less than a minute,
you're gonna asphyxiate
and pass out.
But you shouldn't be
feeling any pain
right now, okay?
Hey, hey.
Close your eyes.
Don't make this face
the last thing you ever see.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Am I really dying?
Bill.
Yeah, William.
We're all dying.
(GASPING)
MESSNER. : So it's
a confirmed double homicide.
CARRUTHERS. : Nobody
from security is
picking up the line.
Gunshot vics,
dumped in the lake,
maybe an hour cold.
You're on speakerphone.
AGENT. : Am I on
the speakerphone?
Yeah, go, go, go, go.
We got an ID pending
on a Jack Dupree.
He's a bail bondsman
out of Las Vegas, Nevada.
Did you recover
anything from his person?
We got a receipt
out of his pocket.
It was for a uniform rental.
What kind of uniform?
The receipt was
partially destroyed
by the lake water.
What kind of uniforms?
It was listed as
maroon in color.
CARRUTHERS. : Maroon?
AGENT. : Maroon.
With maroon,
that's Nomad security.
Were these uniforms recovered?
No, we're still looking.
Fuck!
Deputy? I need you...
I need you to lock down...
I need you
to limit physical activity...
Is that clear?
Nobody gets in the hotel.
Nobody gets near
the crime scene.
Make it happen, okay?
Dupree was
going in as security.
Yep.
I'm gonna go over
to the hotel.
You take the car.
You get over to the lake.
You find out
whatever you can.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna get to Israel
before they do.
I don't think
that's gonna work.
And why?
Because we don't need
to bring any more
shit down on our heads.
I'm saying we're gonna hit
whoever's between us and
Israel. That's how I'm on it.
I ain't trying to dead
the whole floor
and I don't want to be
killing no women.
No matter how
they make their living.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I'm getting some fucked-up
feedback off of that earpiece.
(FEEDBACK WHINING)
(RADIO CHATTERING)
That's better?
Yeah, much.
What you hearing right now?
There was something about
some faggot-ass fed
being up in the building.
A fed? Like FBI?
Yeah. That's all right though.
That's cool.
It's just some
little casino inspection.
Don't trip.
All right, then. When them
tricks hit the lobby,
I want you to holler at me.
I'm gonna meet them
on their way up,
blend in real nice.
Once I'm inside, I'm puttin'
chrome to Israel's head
and backing out hot.
Anybody get gully, you know.
I'm gonna grip and rip.
I got some handloads up here
ready to put some niggas out.
Trust me.
Just remember it's more
of a rescue than
a rampage, all right?
Hey, come on, man.
You know I had to bring
big mama through.
You got the .50 up?
Sure do.
What the fuck?
What the fuck
are you trying to shoot?
A jumbo jet out of the sky?
Blast down the moon?
Any of these niggas make
one false move, these
bitches taking dirt naps.
I ain't trying to be
up here all day.
And I tell you what.
That bitch-ass fed
get in the way,
RIP, nigga.
Fucking Kevlar, the way
I had to stitch it, this shit
is itchy as hell.
Let me ask you a question.
You heard from
that nigga, Keith?
Or he still fucking
with that little
light-skinned girl?
I ain't trying to
break a sweat off
of that motherfucker.
Yeah, fuck that nigga, man.
Anyway, we got each other.
That's all the love
we ever gonna need.
Feel me?
You feel me, girl?
Oh, wait a minute.
I think the ho train
just arrived.
Damn! Four skank-ass bitches.
That's your crew.
Hey, fuck you. All right.
Fuck you and this fucking wig
'cause this shit
is getting on my nerves.
I'm on my way out.
I'm going to just chill in
the hallway until they
come up in the elevator.
And you let me know,
all right?
You just get up in there
and do your thing, baby girl.
Mama's got your back.
Mama's got your back, baby.
(PHONE RINGS)
SERNA. : Buzzy? Buzz?
Yeah, it's me.
All right, you got clicks?
Anything?
No, nothing on my end.
So, how we looking?
Looks very good.
Fucking thrilled
to hear it.
So, this sit-down,
you must have felt it
from them then, huh?
Cold blood,
Sid. Dead eyes.
Okay, yeah, good.
So you're at the hotel.
Everything's all right?
It's quiet.
So, you're not
seeing anything?
No signs of trouble,
nobody lurking,
no threats? Nothing?
Absolutely no.
We got nothing
to worry about.
Israel's in
the penthouse now, right?
Yeah. I guess he's
been holed up there
for a week or so.
How are we on time?
The Swede's been dispatched.
He's flying himself.
All right, damn, all right.
So he's headed
to Tahoe then, huh?
Yeah. We're in
a bit of a footrace
right now, Buzzy.
It's a matter of who
outhustles who, you know?
We just got to get
to Israel first.
It's getting done, Sid.
We got to get him, Buzz.
Everything, and I mean
everything is riding on this.
We're gonna get Israel.
Trust me.
HUGO ON RECORDER. :
You open the fucking door.
AGENT. : I'm sorry, sir.
But this is eyes only.
They told me to hand deliver.
Where did this come from?
They dug it up
in archives as part of
the Sparazza investigation.
Has anyone else seen this?
Only the Director himself.
He asked that you
contact him immediately.
Should we inform
Messner and Carruthers?
No. Things have changed.
Get the Director
on the phone
and have our jet
at the tarmac at LAX
in half an hour.
Yes, sir.
Officer!
Hugo, what's happening, man?
Right.
Well, yeah, hey,
you're good to go in.
Hey, man.
Where the fuck Vitoli at?
The fuck do you mean? I ain't
trying to clean this
shit up myself, dawg.
Hey, don't even think
I'm touching my man's coat
that I know
you nutted all over,
you no-aiming ass.
Man, what the fuck
was you thinking,
barebacking them bitches, Hugo?
I bet you your dick
is disintegrating
as we speak, player!
Stupid-ass motherfucker.
Now, what the fuck
is wrong with you, man?
Hugo!
So, what did Mecklen
have to say?
They're getting close, man.
Got about a handful
of deal points and then
we're getting close.
What are you
shaking for, man?
But it's all good, right?
Yeah.
Look at me, man.
Look at me.
What's up? I'm working.
Yeah, okay.
What's up?
You believe in loyalty,
don't you?
Do I believe in loyalty?
Especially
the kind of loyalty
where an otherwise
sensible motherfucker
like myself
put his own
best interests aside...
That's why you're my man.
'Cause outside a goddamn dog,
that kind of loyalty,
my kind of shit,
don't get no more dedicated
or devout.
What are you trying to say?
What I've been saying.
I need to get your head
of security right now.
He's not picking up
the extension.
I know that.
What floor are they on?
I don't know right now.
What floor
are they on, Ricky?
Okay, you know,
that's one of our guys
right over there.
Excuse me?
Excuse me, sir.
Yes.
Special Agent
Donald Carruthers, FBI.
I need to get to
your penthouse level
immediately.
Well, I'm headed there
right now. Sure.
Is this an emergency?
Let's hope not.
I'm going down.
I'll bet you are.
Faggot-ass redneck.
What'd you say?
Not you.
Some assholes on the elevator.
Are these bitches
on a permanent
smoke break or what?
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
The ho train
has left the station.
Yeah, they're headed
straight to you.
Good.
Skank-ass bitches.
But that's the role
you wanted to play.
Yeah, that says
a whole lot about you.
A ho, ho lot.
What up, G?
Speak, come on. Speak up.
Bitch, I'm about to ball this.
Okay, then. Punk.
No, it was not
made clear to me.
This is the first
I'm hearing of it.
Have you contacted
Agent Carruthers?
Yeah, cell reception up here
is terrible, but until you
or I speak with him,
he's the SAC and he's
the guy I answer to...
REPORTER. : As to the identity
of the two bodies...
Look, in less than an hour,
you're gonna have
40 to 50-odd field agents
arriving in Lake Tahoe
without the slightest clue
as to why.
We are instructed
to take Israel
into protective custody.
That's a two-man operation.
What you're describing now
is a much larger movement.
Messner?
Listen. Hold it. I need
to speak with Locke.
Get him on the phone.
If the situation's changed,
I need to hear it from him.
You Messner?
Yeah. Who's this?
Take a look at that.
Hollis Elmore.
Vegas resident.
Used to be
with the PD down there.
Agent Messner,
we recovered the car.
What car?
Dupree's car. '89
Cadillac Sedan DeVille.
Where did you find it?
Parking structure
at the Nomad.
Are the overheads necessary?
Turn the overheads off! Now!
Not exactly low profile,
is this?
No, sir.
Hotel locked down at all?
I couldn't tell you that
right now, sir.
Hugo, what the fuck is wrong
with you, man?
What, you stuck on stupid
or something? I know. You rode
a little bus to school.
Hey, man, stop using
that fucking lotion, man.
You look like a damn Muppet.
And don't let your bitch
cut your hair no more, dawg.
It look like she put a bowl
on that shit, man. Damn.
Hey, but you need to bring
your ass down here and
help me out, Hugo, for real.
I ain't cleaning all this
shit up myself, man.
I'm tired.
I ain't no fucking
cleaning lady, dawg.
For real. Bring your ass
down here. Shit.
(SHOT FIRED)
(GASPING)
What the fuck?
Hell, no.
You didn't do that, dawg.
What'd you say to Mecklen?
What I've always been saying,
let's make the fucking deal.
You see,
this is one of them
rare moments where
your ass get a chance
to be completely honest.
If I'm asking you what
you said to Mecklen,
assume the shit is rhetorical.
Assume I already know.
What do you see right now?
You see exactly and only
what I choose to show you.
That is illusion, Ivy.
That is the lie that
I tell your eyes.
Making the magic happen
in the moment,
in that split second,
but seeing behind
this motherfucker and knowing
that it's all bullshit.
Yeah, you're on some bullshit.
But I can shape it, I can
shift it, I can make it
as real as this room.
That's why I'm valuable here,
Ivy. And that is why
you are not.
I ain't valuable?
I am sorry.
I love you. I never
wanted it to be like this.
You know that.
It don't matter
what you wanted.
It's what you did.
If you thought old man Primo
could twist your shit up,
wait till you see
what I'm about to do here.
I don't believe this.
Battery's completely dead.
Forget it. You won't get
a signal in here.
You'll have to wait.
What about that line?
Can't you contact
your people with that?
No, these phones
are hardwired directly
to maintenance,
but once we reach
the penthouse,
I can call down.
I'll have the elevators
taken offline, sir.
LOCKE. : Pasquale Acosta.
Blood-money mercenary.
El Estrago.
The Plague.
When he was caught
by the SAS in Belfast.
And in prison, he chewed off
his fingertips to the bone.
Why don't you
have maintenance do it?
Do what, sir?
Shut the elevator down.
An emergency shutdown
of our entire elevated
lift system, sir?
No. That has to be
handled by my staff, sir.
How long have you
been working here?
Bill?
MAN. : Oh, my God, I need
an ambulance for Bill!
I'm in the security room.
Are you anywhere
near the penthouse?
No, no.
But that definitely
sounds like gunshots,
and I don't know
where it's coming from.
It's your IFB, man.
Somebody got a earpiece.
You just picking up
their signal.
We need Nomad hotel security
to lock down the elevators
immediately.
Girl. Please don't tell me
this motherfucker
just went off.
Man, these fools.
What? What's wrong? What?
Man, fucking security's
shutting down the elevators
in your building.
AUTOMATED VOICE. :
Please remain calm.
Now that's the power, there.
Elevator service has been
temporarily suspended and
will resume momentarily.
Please remain calm.
Elevator service has been
temporarily suspended and
will resume momentarily.
Well, let's get on it, then.
I wanna pick them down there.
In the elevator.
More duct. Come on, more duct.
A little more duct.
That's how we do!
Now, okay, okay.
Now, I'm a registered nurse
and this was my bath
not a half hour ago.
Whoopsie.
We'll take care of that.
Hey, Boogie!
I need you to go in,
get my heating pad,
get my blanket.
Nana, not during training.
Okay, Grandma's
big helper boy?
Nana, Nana. Nana?
Grandma will get it. Go on.
Little angel butt.
I feel like
you're eyeballing me, dawg!
I don't like punk bitches
eyeballing me.
You got beef? You got beef?
You want some of this? Yeah.
What? What?
See? Skills. Skills.
Fucking stop it.
Yeah!
FEMALE REPORTER. :
... the two men were
slain here earlier today,
as authorities speculate as to
the apparent disappearance
of a third.
The name of one victim
is being withheld,
but the other victim
in being identified
as Jack Dupree...
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh, shit. Goddamn it!
Son of a fucking bitch! Fuck!
MALE REPORTER. :
The vehicle registered
in Mr. Dupree's name
has been recovered
in the parking lot
of the Nomad Hotel and Casino.
Don, if you can hear this,
I'm in the hotel, north side.
IVY. : I changed lives for you.
You ain't never had to wash
another man's blood off,
dig it out of
your fingernails.
You had us for that.
You ain't never made
no real beef on your own.
Shit, as light
in the ass as you are,
bet you ain't never
had to make nothing more
than a fucking fist
your whole life.
Ivy...
So if you think I'm gonna let
your little punk ass
with the dirt I done...
Listen to me.
...sell me off like
a fucking field nigga...
You know I wouldn't.
...hand me to the feds
like your last chip...
Whatever you think,
whatever...
You must be
out of your
fucking mind.
If you...
Motherfuck! Motherfucker!
You're out of your
fucking mind!
You fucked up...
You're fucked up, Ivy!
Hugo! You hit?
No! No, no, no!
Mr. Israel!
I'm in here!
Ivy's trying to kill me!
Motherfuck you!
Fuck you!
Get in here!
Come on.
Shit.
Drop that goddamn gun now
or you're a dead man!
Jesus Christ. Beanie's dead.
You murdered Beanie.
Put the guns down.
He's got nothing.
Get him out of here.
Jimmy, cuff him.
Put him in...
Take him to
the service exit. It's quick.
Get back here.
We'll handle the rest of it.
You all right, Hugo?
He's fine.
He's giving us up
to the feds, Hugo!
Yo, get out of here,
Hugo, man!
He working with them people,
Hugo!
It's all bullshit.
You know that, Hugo.
You all right?
You stay with me.
Stay with me.
Mecklen's gonna call
any second, all right?
All right? You with me?
You with me, baby? Huh?
We're almost home.
These two are down.
What the fuck is going on?
Come on, you fucker.
WATTERS. : Forget it. It's done.
Hey, quit saying that,
all right?
Girl, I just saw
muzzle flashes
coming from that suite.
That's probably
where you heard
the shots earlier.
Somebody just deaded
Israel's ass. It's a wrap.
I ain't come all this way
just to pack it up because
you thinking something up.
Whatever, man.
We can bounce out,
chill for a little bit.
Shoot a little craps.
Maybe spend the night.
Come on, baby, look.
We could break down now...
Shit, girl.
What?
These two dudes
just sitting in the elevator,
all shot up.
Whatever it was,
it got way past words.
What are they doing right now?
Dying.
So, them fellas,
the ones that was shot
and tossed into the lake?
Them police officers, too?
Mmm-hmm.
Them are left over
after my hysterectomy,
so they'd be a few years old.
I'm not gay because
I have a beard.
My fingers are cut off.
Poor me.
Warren, go and practice
your nunchakus now.
Leave us be alone, shug.
Go on, now, shug.
Anytime, anytime, fag.
I am sorry about that boy.
His mama abandoned him
going on a year now
and his daddy, my boy Dale,
he's over at the Reno-Washoe
Correctional Facility.
Got some clarity issues.
Did some home-invasion,
sodomy-torture type stuff.
Wrote a bunch of bad checks.
My husband, Bill, committed
suicide by hanging
about nine months back.
And ever since then,
little Boogie there
has been man of the house.
I don't think
that's been opened
since my husband died.
I might just borrow this
for a little while.
MESSNER. : Your IFB working?
No, that's why
we're on walkies.
Jurisdiction's
a nightmare right now.
Anything more
on Dupree's car?
Nothing.
You mean to tell me that
nobody noticed anyone
getting out of a Cadillac
that looked like
a wiffle ball?
I know.
Where's your guy?
Right here.
Ricky, this is Agent Messner.
Tell him exactly
what happened, nice and slow.
Yeah, so, earlier,
there was that guy,
Carruthers...
Yeah, Agent Carruthers.
Do you know where he is?
No. He wanted to know...
Yeah, he's here right now.
We're talking to the kid.
We need about two minutes.
...which floor security
was on.
And then later I saw him
get on the elevator
with the other agent.
Wait, hold on.
Wait a minute.
What other agent?
There were no other agents.
Our agents
are landing here now.
There was nobody here.
He said he was
from San Francisco.
Did he give you a name?
Spanish something.
It was Diego or Garcia.
Yeah, run both those names
through the DC database.
Something stinks here.
Call San Francisco.
See if they...
You know,
he was wearing
one of our jackets.
What?
Who was?
The other agent.
He said he was here
to do some inspections.
Then later, when I saw him
get on the elevator
with Carruthers...
This man identified himself
as a federal agent?
Yeah, I mean,
he had the badge
and everything.
And when you saw him later,
he was wearing one
of your security jackets.
Yeah.
And that didn't
seem odd to you?
I mean, I thought
they gave it to him
so he could...
Walk with me.
Okay, so obviously,
we got a man posing
as one of us.
Make your team aware,
but do it quietly. Okay?
Fuck it.
Okay, now let's get
a tactical team assembled.
We're going up.
Okay, we need to get
these elevators powered up.
All right, maintenance,
I need somebody to power up
these elevators immediately.
I need to get Deputy Director
Locke on a hard line
as soon as possible.
All right, done.
Come on, step back, step back.
Come on...
Are you kidding?
I thought you were gonna go...
Gonna go down and get Vitoli.
Get him back up here.
We gotta...
We gotta pack up.
We gotta pack it up now.
Bring him up here.
We gotta get packed up.
We're gonna pack it up.
All right? Where is he?
WATTERS. : He's dead.
No, I said dying, not dead.
Shit.
Shit, girl.
One of them is a fed.
Hello, did you hear me?
Did you hear what I said?
I said one of them
has got a FBI badge.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Hold up, hold up.
I'm getting all kinds of shit
over this scanner.
Just chill for a second.
AGENT. : Shots fired.
West tower. Nomad...
All right, hold on.
Just lay still for a minute.
Let me figure out...
What the fuck...
Get out of the way.
Fuck.
You ain't gonna
believe this shit.
Both these motherfuckers
is feds.
No. One of them is not.
One of them is bullshit.
It's all over the air here.
They got a impostor.
Some fool with a fake badge.
You think it might be
that motherfucker that Loretta
was telling us about? Soot?
Wait. Hold up, hold up.
What I got here
is a Gerald Diego.
A Donald Carruthers.
Which one of them is for real?
'Cause I'm gonna kill
the one that ain't.
Stop the elevator.
Come on.
(PHONE RINGING)
(MECKLEN CRYING)
They revoked the deal.
They pulled it.
Wait, wait. What do you mean?
What do you mean, man?
We got it, we got 'em,
we got 'em.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
It was the Deputy Director.
That prick, Locke.
He just smashed everything.
He wouldn't tell me why.
We're done.
They're yanking us, Buddy.
They killed us.
(PHONE RINGING)
Three minutes.
Prepare to move.
North elevator door's open.
Possible aggression inside.
Check your fire.
Clear on my mark.
Shar. Shar seven,
I'm pinched.
Bring some heavy shit.
Fire from the sky. My count.
Bet.
Oh, my God.
S YKES. : Bring it.
Get the fuck down!
Get down!
Put your fucking hands
in the air!
Throw your weapons down!
Step out of the elevator!
Are these feds fake or real?
I don't know!
Please, Sharice!
Oh, shit! I'm shot!
Georgia!
Georgia, where are you?
I can't fucking hear you.
How bad?
Mortal.
What?
No.
Fuck!
Secure these suspects!
I need medical assistance.
I got multiple officers down.
Watch him.
You're okay.
No, no. Stay awake.
Get me a medic!
Get me a fucking medic!
Where's that medic?
Fuck.
If you can hear me, girl,
I can't see shit
from where I am.
I'm moving down
for a better sight line.
I got officers down.
Repeat, on the seventh floor,
officers down.
Let me isolate the...
Never mind! Just get in there.
Get in there
and pin that girl!
Sharice?
Can you hear me? I'm hit.
Oh, shit.
I don't know
how bad this is. Shit.
That shit probably
got through that Kevlar.
It's on the way up
to the penthouse.
(CHAINSAW WHIRRING)
Lester!
Fuck.
Move! Move! Hurry!
Clear the valet area.
Fuck. Come on!
AGENT. : Left side of
the building's sealed off.
Goddamn. Can you hear me?
Get this shit off!
Move!
Girl, where are you?
God damn it, Georgia!
Just say something!
Mother...
Fuck!
I'm hit!
We need a medic!
Fuck!
Get me a medic!
I need a medic.
Somebody get him out of there!
I fucked up.
I fucked up!
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
I got three coming down now.
Go! Move. Move.
Forgive me.
Get your hands up!
Check the vitals on this guy.
Initiate all clear.
Clear.
Floor's secure, sir.
Okay, come in.
Hold him there
till we get somebody up.
Where is Carruthers
and Messner?
Carruthers is dead.
Messner's unaccounted for.
Account for him!
What's your name, baby girl?
Georgia.
You know you saved
this black man.
Now all you
got to be is grateful.
You hurting pretty bad, huh?
I got shot twice.
I think I accidentally shot
and killed my boy today.
If it gives you any comfort,
you know, I was going
in there to act a fool, baby.
Straight-rocking heat,
slaying niggas, man.
For real?
Your boy very well
might have been one of them.
I probably would've
busted on you, too.
What a shame
that would have been.
What was you
doing here, anyway?
We was after some fool
named Israel.
Damn, girl, you're gonna
make a nigga fall hard.
Put her down. Put her down
and get up
against the wall right now.
Show me your hands.
Show me your fucking hands!
Drop the gun down
or I'll fucking drain you.
Put the gun down!
I didn't do
your man downstairs.
I found him like that.
Whether you believe me
or not,
you know, that ain't
even the least bit
important right now.
We're going to
work this out and live,
or we gonna keep doing
the same shit
we've been doing.
I ain't got
no problem with you
or your Bureau,
so I think you're better off
just moving on
and letting us be.
Agent Messner
is on his way in.
(POLICE SIRENS BLARING)
Agent Messner.
What's going on?
Are you all right, son?
You need some
medical attention?
No, I don't need
medical attention.
Tell me what's going on.
Okay, come on, sit down.
Please, no, I don't
want to sit. Explain it.
It's very difficult
to explain everything
right now.
Much larger matters loom.
I'm sorry to hear
about Carruthers.
He's a good man.
Director Locke?
He's had a sustained
arrhythmic episode,
severe cardiac distress.
I can't help him here.
We have to take him to...
Okay, gentlemen,
let's get him up on the roof.
Get Mr. Israel up on the roof.
He's traveling back with us.
I can't explain
everything right now.
No, I...
I need you to go back
to Washington.
What the hell happened here?
I'm sorry, I cannot
disclose anything more
right now.
So many people are dead.
I need you to return
to Washington.
You'll be debriefed
in the days to come.
Explain it now.
Go back to Washington.
There he goes!
No, don't shoot me!
Don't shoot me, please!
He went this way! Please,
don't shoot me. Don't shoot!
Please! Don't shoot.
FBI. You gotta
get up there! Got to go!
Get these hotel guests out
in the hallway there.
Just clear them down the hall.
Make room. Make room, please.
We'll have to go all the way
around to the other side.
Clear the way here.
Clear the way.
(GUN SHOT FIRED)
Hey.
That your car?
No, I...
I'm confiscating it.
FBI.
Oh, you're FBI.
Yeah.
Yes, I am. I would advise you
to lower your weapon, sir.
You're investigating
those murders
out at the lake, huh?
Say what?
Three men were
ambushed and shot.
Two died and had
their bodies dumped
in the lake.
The other has
severe hypothermia,
possible dementia, and will
probably be a multiple
amputee by week's end.
Shit, okay. You're right.
I'm sorry.
You shot me.
And you murdered my friends.
Yeah, I know.
And you dumped us
in the lake.
Pretty much.
You were here hunting
the man named Israel,
weren't you?
Is that who
you was here for? Israel?
I guess we both got
beat out then, didn't we?
Yeah, goddamn.
Crazy motherfuckers
up there, huh? Gee whiz.
Just give us your keys
and get the fuck out of here.
Okay.
I'm really sorry
about all that.
Shit gets wild and crazy.
Fate just up and fucks you
for no good reason.
You know?
It's the way of the world!
The way it's always gonna be.
Okay, now.
Peace, bro.
Oh, fuck this.
LOCKE: Suicide of some sort.
You know, troubles
with the law. Drugs.
Deal with the patients.
All right, Doctor, thank you.
You know, just make it
sound good.
Okay.
Where's Israel?
What are you doing here?
My debriefing.
Your debriefing? Your
debriefing will be handled
in DC, like I told you.
No, we need to
handle it now.
You are instructed
to get out...
What are you doing,
Agent Messner?
Walk. Let's go.
You're going to tell me
why no call was made
to inform us
that the Israel situation
had been altered.
Why I and my friend
and partner,
whose body
is going into
a furnace tomorrow,
were never fucking contacted.
I cannot discuss it.
You can and you will.
You are finished.
Look at my fucking face.
You just figure that out?
Get that gun out of my spine
or engage the safety, please.
Thank you.
Make it make sense.
They are father and son.
Israel's mother was 19
at the time when she
and Sparazza
had a brief affair
of which Israel
was the byproduct.
That same year, she brought
a paternity suit against him.
Paternity suit?
Just for fun?
Our surveillance
of Padiche, Serna...
All bogus and bad information
that set off a series
of unfortunate events.
He's gonna clip Israel.
Buddy Israel.
They got a guy. Some Swede.
Swede?
Any word on this Swede?
...the mention of
this mysterious Swede.
There's no Swedish hit man
on anyone's radar.
Dr. Ingstrom, the Swede,
is not a hired killer.
Supposedly a specialist.
He's had a sustained
arrhythmic episode,
severe cardiac distress.
He's actually
the head of cardiology
at Stockholm University.
Primo wants Israel's heart.
Heart?
Mention of Israel's heart?
He's one of the
best heart surgeons
in the world.
The actual contract
went to Lazlo Soot,
the man who escaped
the penthouse yesterday...
Don't shoot me!
... in disguise.
He was hired by Sparazza
to neutralize
Israel's entourage.
Dr. Ingstrom was here
to perform the surgery.
And as father and son,
they are blood compatible.
You're talking
about a transplant,
aren't you?
You're talking about
a fucking heart transplant.
You're gonna kill Israel
to save Sparazza.
No.
Well, they dug it up
in archives as part of
the Sparazza investigation.
That Sparazza
had major elective
plastic surgery?
It wasn't elective.
It was undertaken
to save his life.
Look at the work
he's had done.
It wasn't cosmetic.
It was reconstructive.
Look at the date
of the first procedure.
Fifteen separate procedures
since 1952.
Same year that Sparazza
supposedly murdered
Freeman Heller.
I'd like to show you
exactly what I meant
when I said, "Change my face."
Using the latest techniques
in cosmetic surgery,
I will have my ears
pinned back.
Removing a slight piece
of bone in my chin
I will alter my jaw line.
A procedure known
as rhinoplasty will reduce
the size of my nose.
If you add facial hair
to the equation, gentlemen,
you have a face
that looks nothing like mine,
and more importantly,
nothing like
a federal agent's.
Oh, Christ.
I will maintain a slight limp.
My accent will be
a regional Calabrese.
My birthplace, Cosenza, Italy.
That's him.
And my name...
That's Heller.
...will be Primo Sparazza.
Now, gentlemen,
I understand that this is
a dramatic approach.
He went deep cover in 1940.
He could have ripped
the Mafia apart.
But I firmly believe...
Dismantled most of
the organized crime
...this is the only way
to truly infiltrate
organized crime.
His superiors were convinced
that he had gone rogue,
swapped allegiances,
so they gave the order
to terminate his cover.
All this time, we were told
that it was Sparazza
that killed Heller,
when it was us, the FBI.
And we didn't kill him.
He survived.
But the injuries he sustained
required constant surgery,
forever altering his features.
So he assumed
the identity of his alter ego.
The figment of Primo Sparazza
became flesh and blood,
and Freeman Heller
was no more.
Now, the brass wanted
Heller's op removed
from official records,
so they buried it completely
and they wrote Heller off.
All the agents from that era,
they're dead and gone,
so history defaulted to fable.
Until now.
Heller's op predated
the second World War.
About 60 years
of amassed intel.
Do you have any idea
of how valuable that is?
Yeah.
So you made another deal,
didn't you?
Israel's deal
with the government
was tossed out.
We are now trying to
rehabilitate him, so we
can attempt a transplant.
You realize that
you're doing this
to save Sparazza?
No, son. I'm doing all this
to save Heller.
So you send us in there,
bugles blaring,
and when it bottoms out,
we're the last to know!
We need cohesion
to move forward son, not...
Oh, shitcan
the cue-card rhetoric
and talk to me like a man.
You withheld information
while Carruthers lay dying
in vain and in the dark.
And your reasons
for doing that
are exactly what?
That?
Some mob fossil?
A monster that
the Bureau built?
You tell me something,
is he the Rosetta Stone
that's going to
blow the lid off
the last 60 years?
Possibly.
Is he gonna
show you where all
the bodies are buried?
Or is his ultimate worth
bullshit?
Utterly useless?
That's a risk we take.
Yeah, empty pockets.
Empty pockets paid for
by the lives of
our own people.
You're blowing this
way out of proportion.
Are you out of
your fucking mind?
My guy is dead.
You're starting
to piss me off.
The Bureau betrayed us.
Wake up.
You betrayed us...
Stop pointing...
...Deputy Director Locke.
Get that thing out of my face.
You betrayed us
the way you
betrayed them.
You fucking asshole!
Okay, if you like,
I'll take your verbal
resignation right here,
right now.
Do you want your career
to end here, now, like this?
Your call.
Now, I'm prepared to dismiss
your behavior. And in light
of what's happened,
I understand it.
I really do,
and I'm truly sorry.
But a decision
has been made.
And we're required to abide
by it, regardless of
our personal feelings.
Feelings that might
run contrary
to the collective good.
And that, I need you
to understand.
It's time for you
to get on a jet back to DC
and make no further
inquiry into this matter.
Is that understood,
Agent Messner?
Are we clear, Agent Messner?
We're clear.
(INSTRUMENTS BEEPING)