Legend tells of a
legendary warrior...
...whose kung fu skills
were the stuff of legend.
He traveled the land
in search of worthy foes.
I see you like to chew.
Maybe you should
chew on my fist.
The warrior said nothing,
for his mouth was full.
Then he swallowed.
And then he spoke.
Enough talk. Let's fight.
Shashabooey.
He was so deadly in fact,
that his enemies
would go blind from...
overexposure to
pure awesomeness.
- My eyes.
- He's too awesome.
- And attractive.
- How can we repay you?
There is no charge
for awesomeness.
Or attractiveness.
Kablooey.
It mattered not how
many foes he faced.
They were no match
for his bodacity.
Never before had a panda
been so feared. And so loved.
Even the most heroic
heroes in all of China,
the Furious Five,
bowed in respect
to this great master.
We should hang out.
Agreed.
But hanging out
would have to wait.
Because when you're facing...
the 10,000 demons
of Demon Mountain,
there's only one thing
that matters and that's...
Po. Get up.
You'll be later for work.
What?
Po. Get up.
Po. What are you
doing up there?
Nothing.
Monkey. Mantis. Crane.
Viper. Tigress.
Po. Let's go. You're
late for work.
Coming.
Sorry, Dad.
Sorry doesn't
make the noodles.
What were you doing up there?
All that noise.
Nothing. I just
had a crazy dream.
About what?
What were you dreaming about?
What was I?
I was dreaming about...
...noodles.
Noodles? You were really
dreaming about noodles?
Yeah. What else
would I be dreaming about?
Careful. That soup is sharp.
Oh, happy day.
My son, finally having
the noodle dream.
You don't know how
long I've been...
waiting for this moment.
This is a sign, Po.
A sign of what?
You are almost ready
to be entrusted...
with the secret ingredient...
of my Secret Ingredient Soup.
And then you will fulfill
your destiny...
and take over the restaurant.
As I took it over
from my father,
who took it over
from his father...
...who won it from a friend
in a game of mahjong.
Dad, Dad, Dad, it
was just a dream.
No, it was the dream.
We are noodle folk.
Broth runs through our veins.
But, Dad, didn't you.. you know...
ever want to do something else?
Something besides noodles?
Actually, when I
was young and crazy.
I thought about running away
and learning how to make tofu.
So why didn't you?
Because it was a stupid dream.
Can you imagine
me making tofu?
Tofu.
No. We all have our
place in this world.
Mine is here, and yours is...
I know, is here.
No, it's at tables
2, 5, 7, and 12
Service with a smile.
Well done, students...
if you were trying
to disappoint me.
Tigress, you need
more ferocity.
Monkey, greater speed.
Crane, height.
Viper, subtlety.
Mantis...
- Master Shifu.
- What?.
It's Master Oogway.
He wants to see you.
Master Oogway,
you summoned me?
Is something wrong?
Why must something be wrong...
for me to want to
see my old friend?
So, nothing's wrong?
Well, I didn't say that.
You were saying?
I have had a vision.
Tai Lung will return.
That is impossible.
He is in prison.
Nothing is impossible.
Zeng.
Fly to Chorh-Gom prison
and tell them...
to double the
guards, double...
their weapons,
double everything.
Tai Lung does not
leave that prison.
Yes, Master Shifu.
One often meets his destiny...
on the road he
takes to avoid it.
We have to do something.
We can't let him...
march on the valley,
and take his revenge.
He'll...
Your mind is like this water,
my friend.
When it is agitated,
it becomes difficult to see.
But if you allow
it to settle...
...the answer becomes clear.
The Dragon Scroll.
It is time.
But who? Who is worthy
to be trusted...
with the secret to
limitless power?
To become the Dragon Warrior?
I don't know.
Excuse me. Pardon me. Sorry.
Watch it, Po.
Sorry. Suck it up.
Sorry. A thousand pardons.
What's...?
Master Oogway's choosing
the Dragon Warrior. Today.
Everyone. Go. Get to the
Jade Palace. One of...
the Five is going get
the Dragon Scroll.
We have waited for
1,000 years for this.
Take the bowl.
This is the greatest day in kung fu history.
Don't worry about it, just go.
Po. Where are you going?
To the Jade Palace...
But you're forgetting
your noodle cart.
The whole valley
will be there,
and you'll sell
noodles to all of them.
Selling noodles?
But, Dad, you know I was
kind of thinking, maybe I...
- Yeah?
- I was kind of thinking maybe I...
...could also sell
the bean buns.
Well... they're about to go bad.
That's my boy.
I told you that
dream was a sign.
Yeah. Glad I had it.
- I'm a kung fu warrior.
- Me, too.
- There's spots at the top.
- Hurry, let's go!
Come on. Come on.
Almost there.
What?
No. Oh, no.
- Sorry, Po.
We'll bring you
back a souvenir.
No. I'll bring me back
a souvenir.
It is an historic day.
Isn't it, Master Oogway?
Yes, and one I feared
I would not live to see.
Are your students ready?
Yes, Master Oogway.
And know this, old friend.
Whomever I choose will
not only bring...
peace to the valley...
...but also to you.
Let the tournament begin.
Yeah.
No, no, wait.
I'm coming. Wait, wait.
Yes.
Hey. Open the door.
Let me in.
Citizens of the
Valley of Peace,
it is my great honor
to present to you... Tigress.
Viper. Crane. Monkey. Mantis.
The Furious Five.
Yeah, the Furious Five.
Warriors, prepare.
Wait. No. Oh, peeky-hole.
- Ready for battle.
- Yeah.
The Thousand Tongues of Fire.
Wow, look at that!
Hey. Get out of the way.
And finally Master Tigress.
And believe me, citizens,
you have not seen
anything yet.
I know.
Master Tigress. Face Iron Ox
and his Blades of Death.
I sense the Dragon
Warrior is among us.
Citizens of the
Valley of Peace.
Master Oogway will now choose
the Dragon Warrior.
Oh, no. No, no, wait.
Yeah.
Po.
What are you doing?.
What does it look like
I'm doing?. Stop.
I'm going to see
the Dragon Warrior.
But I don't understand.
You finally had
the noodle dream.
I lied. I don't dream
about noodles, Dad.
I love kung fu.
Oh come on, son. Let's
get back to work.
OK.
Come back.
What's going on?
Where?
What are you pointing?
OK. Sorry.
I just wanted to see
who the Dragon Warrior was.
How interesting.
Master, are you
pointing at me?
- Him.
- Who?
- You.
- Me?
The universe has brought us
the Dragon Warrior.
- What?
- What?.
Stop, wait. Who told you to?
Master Oogway, wait.
That flabby panda
can't possibly be...
the answer to our problem.
You were about to
point at Tigress...
and that thing fell
in front of her.
That was just an accident.
There are no accidents.
Forgive us, Master.
We have failed you.
No. If the panda
has not quit by morning...
then I will have failed you.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
I bring a message...
...from Master Shifu.
What?.
'Double the guard?.'
'Extra precautions?.'
'Your prison may
not be adequate?.'
You doubt my prison security?.
Absolutely not.
Shifu does. I'm
just the messenger.
I'll give you a message
for your Master Shifu.
Escape from Chorh-Gom prison
is impossible.
Impressive, isn't it?
It's very impressive.
One way in, one way out.
One thousand guards
and one prisoner.
Yes, except that prisoner...
...is Tai Lung.
Take us down.
What are you doing?
Oh, my.
Behold Tai Lung.
I'm eh... just gonna
wait right here.
It's nothing to worry about.
It's perfectly safe.
Crossbows. At the ready.
Crossbows?
Hey, tough guy, did you hear?
Oogway's finally going to
give someone the Dragon
Scroll, and it's
not gonna be you.
What are you doing?
To get him mad?
What's he gonna do about it?
I've got him completely
immobilized.
Did I step on the
wittle kitty's tail?
I'm good. I've seen enough.
I'll tell Shifu he
has nothing to worry about.
No, he doesn't.
I'll tell him that.
Can we please go now?
Dragon Warrior.
Wait a second.
I think there's been
a slight mistake.
Everyone seems to
think that I'm a...
The Sacred Hall of
Warriors. No way.
Look at this place.
Master Flying Rhino's armor,
with authentic battle damage.
The Sword of Heroes.
Said to be so sharp
you can cut yourself...
just by looking.
The Invisible
Trident of Destiny.
I've only seen paintings
of that painting.
No.
The legendary Urn
of Whispering Warriors.
Said to contain the souls
of the entire Tenshu Army.
Hello.
Have you finished
sight-seeing?
Sorry, I should have
come to see you first.
My patience is wearing thin.
Well, I mean, it's
not like you...
were going anywhere.
- Would you turn around?
- Sure.
How's it going?
How do you get 5,000...
Master Shifu.
Someone... broke that.
But I'm gonna fix it.
Do you have some...
...glue?
A splinter.
So you're the legendary
Dragon Warrior, hm?
- I guess so.
- Wrong.
You are not the Dragon
Warrior. You will...
never be the Dragon
Warrior until...
...you have learned the secret
of the Dragon Scroll.
So, how does this work?
Do you have a ladder,
or a trampoline, or?
You think it's that easy?
That I'll just hand
you the secret...
- to limitless power?
- No, I...
One must first master
the highest level of kung fu.
And that is clearly impossible...
if that one is
someone like you.
Someone like me?
Yes, look at you.
This fat butt. Flabby arms.
Those are sensitive
in the flabby parts.
And this ridiculous belly.
And utter disregard
for personal hygiene.
Now, wait a minute.
That's a little uncalled for.
Don't stand that close.
I can smell your breath.
Listen, Oogway said I was...
The Wuxi Finger Hold.
Not the Wuxi Finger Hold.
Oh, you know this hold?
Developed by Master Wuxi
in the Third Dynasty.
Then you know what happens
when I flex my pinky.
- No, no.
You know the hardest
part of this?
The hardest part
is cleaning up...
afterwards.
OK, OK, take it easy.
Now listen closely, panda.
Oogway may have picked you,
but when I'm through with you.
I promise you, you're
going to wish...
he hadn't. Are we clear?
Yeah, we're clear.
We're so clear.
Good.
I can't wait to get started.
- Let's begin.
- Wait, wait, wait.
What?
- Now?
- Yes, now.
Unless you think
the great Oogway was wrong...
and you are not
the Dragon Warrior.
Oh, OK, well...
I don't know...
if I can do all
of those moves.
Well, if we don't try,
we'll never know, will we?
Yeah, it's just,
maybe we can find...
something more
suited to my level.
And what level is that?
Well, I'm not a master, but...
...let's just start
at zero. Level zero.
No. There is no such thing
as level zero.
- Hey, maybe I can start with that.
- That?
We use that for training
children and...
for propping the door
open when it's hot.
But if you insist...
The Furious Five.
You're so much bigger than
your action figures.
Except for you, Mantis.
You're about the same.
Go ahead, panda.
Show us what you can do.
Are they gonna watch,
or should I wait...
till they get back to work
or something?
Hit it.
OK, yeah. I mean, I just ate.
So I'm still digesting.
So my kung fu might not be
as good as... later on.
Just hit it.
All right.
What you got? You got nothing,
'cause I got it right here.
You picking on my friends?
Get ready to feel the thunder.
I'm coming at you
with crazy feet.
Come on. I'm a blur.
You've never seen bear style.
You've only seen
praying mantis.
Or monkey style.
Or I could come at
you snickety-snake.
Would you hit it.
All right. All right.
Why don't you try again?
A little harder.
How's that?
That hurts.
This will be easier
than I thought.
I'm feeling a little nauseous.
Those are hard.
My tenders.
How did I do?
There is now a level zero.
- There's no words.
- No denying that.
I don't understand What
Master Oogway was thinking...
The poor guy's just gonna
get himself killed.
He is so mighty.
The Dragon Warrior
fell out of the sky...
on a ball of fire.
When he walks, the
very ground shakes.
One would think that
Master Oogway would...
choose someone who
actually knew kung fu.
Yeah, or could at
least touch his toes.
Or even see his toes.
OK.
Great.
Hi. You're up.
I am now.
I was just...
Some day, huh?
That kung fu stuff
is hard work, right?
Are your biceps sore?
I've had a long...
and rather
disappointing day, so...
Yeah, I should probably
get to sleep now.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Of course.
- OK, thanks.
It's just...
Man, I'm such a big fan.
You guys were totally amazing...
at the Battle of
Weeping River.
Outnumbered a thousand to one,
but you didn't
stop. You just...
Sorry about that.
Look, you don't belong here.
I know. I know. You're right.
I don't have... I just...
My whole life I dreamed of...
No, I meant you
don't belong here.
I mean, in this room.
This is my room.
Property of Crane.
OK. Right, right.
So, you want to get to sleep.
- Yeah.
- I'm keeping you up.
We got big things tomorrow.
All right. You're awesome.
Last thing I'm
gonna say. OK. Bye-bye.
What was that?
I didn't say anything.
OK. All right. Good night.
Sleep well.
That seemed a little awkward.
Master Tigress.
I didn't mean to wake you.
- You don't belong here.
- Yeah, of course.
This is your room.
I mean, you don't belong
in the Jade Palace.
You're a disgrace to kung fu,
and if you have...
any respect for who we are
and what we do,
you will be gone by morning.
Big fan.
I see you have
found the Sacred
Peach Tree of Heavenly Wisdom.
Is that what this is?
I'm so sorry. I thought...
it was just a
regular peach tree.
I understand.
You eat when you are upset.
Upset? I'm not upset.
What makes you
think I'm upset.
So why are you so upset?
I probably sucked
more today...
than anyone in the
history of kung fu.
In the history of China.
In the history of sucking.
Probably.
And the Five. Man,
you should've...
seen them. They
totally hate me.
Totally.
How is Shifu ever
going to turn me...
into the Dragon Warrior?
I mean, I'm not like the Five.
I've got no claws,
no wings, no venom.
Even Mantis has
those... thingies.
Maybe I should just quit
and go back to making noodles.
Quit, don't quit.
Noodles, don't noodles.
You are too concerned...
with what was
and what will be.
There's a saying:
Yesterday is history,
tomorrow is a mystery,
but today is a gift.
That is why it is
called the present.
- Oh, no.
- What's happening?.
To your battle
stations. Go. Go. Go.
Fire crossbows.
Fire.
Tai Lung is free.
I must warn Shifu.
You're not going anywhere.
Neither is he.
Let go of me.
Bring it up.
Wait. Bring it back.
- He's coming this way.
- He won't get far. Archers.
We're dead. So
very, very dead.
Not yet we're not. Now.
- Can we run now?
- Yes.
I'm glad Shifu sent you.
I was beginning to think
I'd been forgotten.
Fly back there
and tell them...
...the real Dragon Warrior
is coming home.
Good morning, Master.
Panda.
Wake up.
He's quit.
What do we do now,
with the panda gone?
Who will be the
Dragon Warrior?
All we can do is
resume our training...
and trust that in time,
the true Dragon Warrior
will be revealed.
What are you doing here?.
Hi. Good morning, Master.
I thought I'd
warm up a little.
You're stuck.
Stuck? Nah. What? Stuck?
Nah. This is one of my...
Yeah, I'm stuck.
- Help him.
- Oh, dear.
Maybe on three. One, two...
...three.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
- No, really, I appreciate...
- Ever.
You actually thought
you could learn...
to do a full split
in one night?
It takes years to develop
one's flexibility.
And years longer to
apply it in combat.
Put that down.
The only souvenirs we
collect here are...
bloody knuckles
and broken bones.
Yeah. Excellent.
Let's get started.
- Are you ready?
- I was born re...
I'm sorry, brother.
I thought you said
you were ready.
That was awesome.
Let's go again.
I've been taking it
easy on you, panda.
But no more.
Your next opponent will be me.
All right. Yeah, let's go.
Step forth.
The true path to
victory is to find...
your opponent's weakness...
...and make him suffer for it.
Oh, yeah.
To take his strength
and use it against him...
...until he finally falls...
...or quits.
But a real warrior never quits.
Don't worry, Master.
I will never quit.
If he's smart,
he won't come back
up those steps.
But he will.
He's not going to quit, is he?
He's going to
quit bouncing.
I'll tell you that.
I thought you said acupuncture
would make me feel better.
Trust me, it will.
It's just not easy
finding the right...
nerve points under all this...
- Fat?
- Fur. I was going to say fur.
Sure you were.
Who am I to judge a warrior
based on his size? I mean, look at me.
I'm over here.
Maybe you should
take a look at this again.
Oh, OK.
Stop it. Stop.
I know Master Shifu is trying
to inspire me and all...
...but if I didn't
know any better.
I'd say he was trying
to get rid of me.
I know he can seem
kind of heartless...
...but you know he wasn't
always like that.
According to legend,
there was once a time when
Master Shifu actually
used to smile.
- No.
- Yes.
But that was before.
Before what?
Before Tai Lung.
We're not really supposed
to talk about him.
Well, if he's
going to stay here,
he should know.
Guys, guys, I know
about Tai Lung.
He was a student.
The first ever to...
master the thousand
scrolls of kung fu.
And then he turned bad,
and now he's in jail.
He wasn't just a student.
Shifu found him as a cub...
...and he raised
him as his son.
And when the boy showed
talent in kung fu...
...Shifu trained him.
He believed in him.
He told him...
he was destined for greatness.
It was never enough
for Tai Lung.
He wanted the Dragon Scroll.
But Oogway saw darkness
in his heart and refused.
Outraged, Tai Lung
laid waste to the valley.
He tried to take
the scroll by force.
And Shifu had to destroy
what he had created.
But how could he?
Shifu loved Tai Lung...
like he had never
loved anyone before.
Or since.
And now he has a chance
to make things right.
To train the true
Dragon Warrior.
And he's stuck with you.
A big fat panda
who treats it like a joke.
That is it.
Wait. My fault.
I accidentally tweaked
his facial nerve.
And may have also
stopped his heart.
Inner peace.
Inner...
Would whoever is making...
that flapping
sound quiet down?.
Inner...
Oh, Zeng.
Excellent.
I could use some
good news right now.
Master. Master.
I have... It's...
It's very bad news.
Shifu.
There is just news.
There is no good or bad.
Master, your vision.
Your vision was right.
Tai Lung has broken
out of prison.
He's on his way.
That is bad news...
...if you do not believe...
that the Dragon
Warrior can stop him.
The panda? Master,
that panda is not
the Dragon Warrior.
He wasn't even meant to be here.
It was an accident.
There are no accidents.
Yes, I know. You've
said that already.
- Twice.
Well, that was no
accident, either.
Thrice.
My old friend,
the panda will never fulfill
his destiny, nor you yours,
until you let go
of the illusion of control.
Illusion?
Yes. Look at this tree, Shifu.
I cannot make it blossom
when it suits me,
nor make it bear fruit
before its time.
But there are things
we can control.
I can control when
the fruit will fall.
And I can control...
...where to plant the seed.
That is no illusion, Master.
Yes.
But no matter what you do...
that seed will grow
to be a peach tree.
You may wish for an
apple or an orange,
but you will get a peach.
But a peach cannot
defeat Tai Lung.
Maybe it can.
If you are willing
to guide it.
To nurture it.
To believe in it.
But how? How?
I need your help, Master.
No, you just need to believe.
Promise me, Shifu.
Promise me you will believe.
I will try.
Good.
My time has come.
You must continue
your journey without me.
What are you? Wait.
Master.
You can't leave me.
You must believe.
Master.
Yeah, so I'm like,
'Fine, you may be a wolf,
you may be the scariest bandit
in Haijin Province...
...but you're a lousy tipper.'
Really? So how did you
get out of there alive?
I mean, I didn't
actually say that...
...but I thought it...
...in my mind.
If he could read my mind,
it'd have been, like, 'What?'
Order up. Hope you like it.
- This is really good.
- Now, come on.
You should try my dad's Secret
Ingredient Soup.
He actually knows the
secret ingredient.
What're you talking about?
This is amazing.
- You're a really good cook.
- I wish my mouth was bigger.
Tigress, you've
got to try this.
It is said that the
Dragon Warrior...
can survive for months
at a time...
on nothing but the
dew of a single ginkgo leaf...
and the energy
of the universe.
I guess my body doesn't know
it's the Dragon Warrior yet.
I'm gonna need a lot more
than dew and universe juice.
- What?
- Nothing... Master Shifu.
You'll never be the Dragon
Warrior unless you...
lose 500 pounds and
brush your teeth.
What is that noise
you're making?
Laughter? I never heard of it.
Work hard, panda,
and maybe someday...
...you will have
ears like mine.
That's good.
Ears. It's not
working for you?
I thought they
were pretty good.
It's Shifu.
Of course it's Shifu.
What do you think I'm doing?
Master Shifu.
You think this is funny?
Tai Lung has escaped
from prison...
and you're acting
like children.
- What?
He is coming for
the Dragon Scroll,
and you are the only one
who can stop him.
And here I am saying
you got no sense of humor.
I'm gonna... stop Tai Lung.
What? You're serious?
And I have to?
Master Oogway will stop him,
he did it before, he'll do it again.
Oogway cannot.
Not anymore.
Our only hope is
the Dragon Warrior.
- The panda?
- Yes, the panda.
Master, please...
let us stop Tai Lung.
This is what you've
trained us for.
No. It is not your destiny
to defeat Tai Lung.
It is his.
Where'd he go?
You cannot leave.
A real warrior never quits.
Watch me.
Come on.
How am I supposed
to beat Tai Lung?
I can't even beat
you to the stairs.
You will beat him...
because you are
the Dragon Warrior.
You don't believe that.
You never believed that.
From the first moment I've got here,
you've been trying to get rid of me.
Yes. I was.
But now I ask you
to trust in your...
master as I have come
to trust in mine.
You're not my master.
And I'm not the
Dragon Warrior.
Then why didn't
you quit?. You knew
I was trying to get rid of you,
yet you stayed.
Yeah, I stayed.
I stayed because every time...
you threw a brick
at my head...
or said I smelled, it hurt,
but it could
never hurt more...
than it did every day
of my life just being me.
I stayed because I thought,
if anyone could change me...
...could make me... not me...
...it was you.
The greatest kung fu teacher
in all of China.
But I can change you.
I can turn you into
the Dragon Warrior.
And I will.
Come on. Tai Lung is
on his way here right now.
Even if it takes him
a hundred years...
to get here, how are you...
...gonna change this
into the Dragon Warrior?
How?
- How?.
- I don't know.
I don't know.
That's what I thought.
This is what you
trained me for.
Tigress.
Don't try and stop me.
We're not trying to stop you.
What?
We're coming with you.
What? I eat when
I'm upset, OK?
No need to explain.
I just thought you might be
Monkey. He hides...
his almond cookies
on the top shelf.
Don't tell Monkey.
- Look at you.
- Yeah, I know, I disgust you.
No, I mean, how did
you get up there?
I don't know. I guess that...
I don't know. I was
getting a cookie.
And yet you are ten feet
off the ground.
And have done
a perfect split.
No, this? This is just...
...an accident.
There are no accidents.
Come with me.
I know you're trying to be
all mystical and kung fuey...
...but could you at least
tell me where we're going?
You dragged me...
...all the way out here...
...for a bath?
Panda...
...we do not wash our pits
in the Pool of Sacred Tears.
The Pool of...
This is where Oogway
unraveled the mysteries...
...of harmony and focus.
This is the birthplace...
...of kung fu.
Do you want to learn kung fu?
Yeah.
Then I am your master.
OK.
Don't cry.
When you focus on kung fu,
when you concentrate...
...you stink.
But perhaps that is my fault.
I cannot train you the way
I have trained the Five.
I now see that the way
to get through to you...
...is with this.
Oh, great, 'cause I am hungry.
Good.
When you have been
trained, you may eat.
Let's begin.
After you, panda.
Just like that?
No sit-ups? No ten-mile hike?
I vowed to train
you, and you...
have been trained.
You are free to eat.
Enjoy.
Hey.
I said you are free to eat.
Have a dumpling.
Hey.
You are free to eat.
- Am I?.
- Are you?.
I'm not hungry.
Master.
Cut it.
Where's the Dragon Warrior?
How do you know
you're not looking at her?
You think I'm a fool?
I know you're not
the Dragon Warrior.
None of you.
I heard how he fell out
of the sky in a ball of fire.
That he's a warrior unlike...
anything the world
has ever seen.
- Po?
- So that is his name. Po.
Finally, a worthy opponent.
The battle will be legendary.
We've got this. Help her.
Monkey.
Go.
What was I thinking?.
Mantis.
Now.
Shifu taught you well.
But he didn't teach
you everything.
You have done well, panda.
Done well? Done well?
I've done awesome.
The mark of a true
hero is humility.
But, yes, you have done...
...awesome.
Guys? Guys?. They're dead.
No, they're breathing.
They're asleep?
But their eyes are open.
We were no match for
his nerve attack.
He has gotten stronger.
Who? Tai Lung? Stronger?
He's too fast.
Sorry, Po.
I thought we could stop him.
He could have killed you.
Why didn't he?
So you could come back
and strike fear...
into our hearts.
But it won't work.
It might. I mean, a little.
I'm pretty scared.
You can defeat him, panda.
Are you kidding?
If they can't?.
They're five masters.
I'm just one me.
But you will have...
the one thing that
no one else does.
You really believe I'm ready?
You are...
...Po.
Behold the Dragon Scroll.
It is yours.
Wait. What happens
when I read it?
No one knows but legend says
you will be able...
to hear a butterfly's
wing beat.
Really? That's cool.
Yes. And see light
in the deepest cave.
You will feel the universe
in motion around you.
Can I punch through walls?
- Do a quadruple back flip?
- Focus.
- Will I?
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
Read it, Po, and
fulfill your destiny.
Read it and become...
...the Dragon Warrior.
It's impossible to open.
OK. Come on,
baby. Come on now.
Thank you.
I probably loosened it up
for you though.
OK, here goes.
- It's blank.
- What?.
- Here, look.
No, I am forbidden
to look upon...
Blank. I don't...
I don't understand.
OK. So, like...
...Oogway was...
just a crazy old
turtle after all.
No. Oogway was
wiser than us all.
Oh, come on. Face it,
he picked me by accident.
Of course I'm not
the Dragon Warrior.
Who am I kidding?
But who will stop Tai Lung?
He'll destroy everything
and everyone.
No.
Evacuate the valley.
You must protect...
the villagers from
Tai Lung's rage.
- What about you, Master?
- I will fight him.
- What?
I can hold him
off long enough...
for everyone to escape.
But, Shifu, he'll kill you.
Then I will finally have paid
for my mistake.
Listen to me, all of you.
It is time for you to continue
your journey without me.
I am very proud
to have been your master.
We've got to get
them out safely.
Come, little one.
Let's find your mama.
Viper, gather the
southern farmers.
Mantis, the north.
Crane, light the way.
Look, it's the Dragon Warrior.
Hey, Dad.
Po.
Good to have you back, son.
Good to be back.
Let's go, Po.
So for our next shop,
it's time to face it...
...the future of noodles
is dice-cut vegetables...
...no longer slices.
Also, I was thinking,
maybe this time...
we'll have a kitchen
you can actually stand up in.
You like that?
Po, I'm sorry if things
didn't work out.
It just wasn't meant to be.
Po, forget everything else.
Your destiny still awaits.
We are noodle folk.
Broth runs deep
through our veins.
I don't know, Dad.
Honestly, sometimes
I can't believe I'm
actually your son.
Po...
...I think it's
time I told you...
something I should
have told you...
...a long time ago.
OK.
The secret ingredient
of my Secret Ingredient Soup...
Come hear me. The secret
ingredient is...
...nothing.
You heard me. Nothing.
There is no secret ingredient.
Wait, wait.
It's just plain
old noodle soup?
You don't add some
kind of special...
sauce or something?
I don't have to. To
make something special...
you just have to
believe it's special.
There is no secret ingredient.
I have come home, Master.
This is no longer your home.
And I am no longer
your master.
Oh, yes. You have
a new favorite.
So where is this Po?
Did I scare him off?
This battle is
between you and me.
So, that is how
it's going to be.
That is how it must be.
I rotted in jail for 20 years
because of your weakness.
Obeying your master
is not weakness.
You knew I was the
Dragon Warrior.
You always knew.
But when Oogway
said otherwise,
what did you do?
What did you do?.
Nothing.
You were not meant
to be the Dragon
Warrior. That
was not my fault.
Not your fault?.
Who filled my head
with dreams?.
Who drove me to train
until my bones cracked?.
Who denied me my destiny?.
It was never my
decision to make.
It is now.
Give me the scroll.
I would rather die.
All I ever did, I did
to make you proud.
Tell me how proud
you are, Shifu.
Tell me.
I have...
I have always been
proud of you.
From the first
moment, I've been...
...proud of you.
And it was my pride...
...that blinded me.
I loved you too much...
to see what you
were becoming...
...what I...
...was turning you into.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
I don't want your apology.
I want my scroll.
What?.
Where is it?.
The Dragon Warrior has
taken the scroll...
halfway across China by now.
You will never see
that scroll, Tai Lung.
Never.
Stairs.
Who are you?
Buddy, I am the
Dragon Warrior.
You?
Him? He's a panda.
You're a panda. What are...
you gonna do, big
guy? Sit on me?
Don't tempt me.
No. I'm gonna use this.
You want it? Come and get it.
Finally.
That scroll is mine.
Lightning.
The scroll has
given him power.
No.
Finally. Oh, yes.
The power of the
Dragon Scroll is mine.
It's nothing.
It's OK. I didn't get it
the first time, either.
What?
There is no secret ingredient.
It's just you.
Stop it.
I'm gonna pee.
Don't.
Don't. Don't.
You...
...can't defeat me.
...you're just a big...
...fat...
...panda.
I'm not a big fat panda.
I'm the big fat panda.
The Wuxi Finger Hold.
Oh, you know this hold?
You're bluffing.
Shifu didn't teach you that.
Nope.
I figured it out. Skadoosh.
Look.
The Dragon Warrior.
That's my boy. That big lovely
kung fu warrior is my son.
Yes.
Thanks, Dad.
Hey, guys.
Master.
Master?
Master Shifu.
Master.
Shifu, are you OK?.
Po.
You're alive.
Or we're both dead.
No, Master, I didn't die.
I defeated Tai Lung.
You did?
Wow. It is as Oogway foretold.
You are the Dragon Warrior.
You have brought peace...
...to this valley...
...and...
...and to me.
Thank you.
Thank you, Po.
Thank you. Thank you.
No. Master. No, no, no,
don't die, Shifu, please.
I'm not dying, you idiot.
Dragon Warrior...
...I am simply at
peace. Finally.
So, I should stop talking?
If you can.
Do you want to get
something to eat?
Yeah.
Everybody is kung fu fighting
Your mind becomes
fast as lightning
Although the future
is a little bit frightening
It's the book of your life
that you're writing
Everybody is kung fu fighting
Your mind becomes
fast as lightning
Although the future
is a little bit frightening
It's the book of your life
that you're writing
You are a natural
Why is that so hard to see?
Maybe it's just because
You keep on looking at me
The journey's a lonely one
So much more than we know
But sometimes you've got to go
And be your own hero
Everybody is kung fu fighting
Your mind becomes
fast as lightning
Although the future
is a little bit frightening
It's the book of your life
that you're writing
You're a diamond in the rough
A brilliant ball of clay
You could be a work of art
If you just go all the way
Now what would it
take to break?
I believe that you can bend
Not only do you have to fight
But you have got to win...
'Cause everybody is
kung fu fighting
Your mind becomes
fast as lightning
Although the future
is a little bit frightening
It's the book of your life
that you're writing
You're a diamond in the rough
A brilliant ball of clay
You could be a work of art
If you just go all the way
Now what would it
take to break?
I believe that you can bend
Not only do you have to fight
But you have got to win...
'Cause everybody is
kung fu fighting
Your mind becomes
fast as lightning
Although the future is a
little bit frightening
It's the book of your life
that you're writing