We're riding towards Absolution.
You know how far west we are?
Maybe he's a dummy.
Is there a reason you're not
answering my question?
Look here Pa.
He's got iron on his wrist.
He's been shot.
Could be he done broke out of hoosegow.
Might be worth bounty-money.
It could be ...
It's not your lucky day, stranger..
Turn around and start walking.
I said turn around
and start walking.
Translation by § §  kikka_fata
- www.italianshare.net -
Section: Movies ISubs
Get lost!
There 'no?
Balls to heaven, friend.
Calm ...
Alright, turn around,
nice and slow.
I've been shot.
Only two kinds of men get shot.
Criminals and victims.
Well, which one are ya?
I do not know.
You got a name, friend?
I don't know that either.
Well, just what do you know?
The English ...
Well, that... That's a right
odd-looking wound there.
Must 'cauterization.
Stink 'a little' ...
- That's it.
- It 'a city' mining?
You ', well, from what they say.
The people he's' gone, anyway ...
no gold.
Alright now, try and hold still.
There we go.
This is no gunshot.
Where did ya get this, son?
-I don't know.
Well I can't rightly absolve you of your sins,
If you don't recall now, can I?
That being said, I've seen
good men do bad things
bad men do good things.
Whether you're gonna end up
in heaven or hell...
it's not God's plan,
that's your own.
You just gotta remember
What it was.
Alright, put your finger
right here. Come On.
There you go.
- Done.
- Thanks.
Not bad for
a country priest.
It's that damn fool Dolarhyde kid
Hey, hey hey hey!
What are you doing?
Percy, there's people out there.
There's no-one out there, it's fine.
It's not fine. It's bad enough
he drinks for free...
..and now he's gonna shoot up the place?
Hey what was that, doc?
Nothing. He didn's say anything.
Everything's okay. -Go back inside.
Wait!
I wanna hear what you said.
It's bad enough... what?
Are you ungrateful for our business?
'Because if it wasn't
for my Pa's cattle,
There'll be no money going
through this town.
And there would be no
meat on your tables
And your doors would
be closed. Huh?
I don't mean no disrespect to your
father, Percy. You know that.
Of course not. But you ask me to pay
Come here to settle
the matter.
Come here.
Hey kid, I do not want any trouble.
I'm just trying to...
Better pick up your glasses, doc,
before someone steps on them.
Alright son, we're just trying
to make a living now.
You know what, preacher?
You just gave me an idea.
I know it ain't Sunday, folks, but...
What say we take up a collection
for the poor man, huh?
Now who's got money?
In the hat ...
Let's go, much obliged.
I'm sorry, doc's bad fortune has to
be taken out on you good people.
Very Christian of you.
Hey!
You too.
You wanna be careful where you
point that thing before you get hurt.
Listen ...
I'm gonna give you the benefit
of the doubt, because...
Maybe you don't know who I am.
Leave me alone!
Hey, you!
I warn you ...
Where the hell did he come from?
What the hell is going on here?
It 'was an accident ...
He came out of nowhere.
And he dry gulched me.
He tried to make me look like a fool.
It's not 'my fault, sheriff.
Damn it, Percy. You've crossed
the line this time.
I gotta lock ya up.
Taggart.
You know that is not 'a good idea.
Well I'm afraid I got no choice, Ned.
Ned? Ned, you son of a bitch,
where are you going?
Don't worry. I'll tell your father
about what happened today.
Don't ruin the coffee there, yankee.
Well, tell you what Ed.
The next time you can have coffee.
-Okay, alright. -Hey why don't you take
it easy on that tileslacking, Murphy
Mr. Dolarhyde don't like
drinking on the job..
Mr. Dolarhyde not like
that you drink at work?
I don't give a rat's ass what the high and mighty Colonel Dolarhyde don't like it or not.
I don't care how many Indians he put under neither.
You sure do slap your guns a lot
when the boss ain't around.
I'd say it to his face if he was here!
Colonel Dolarhyde ...
Let me tell you something, guys.
Money makes you soft.
Where the hell is that coach?
-Coach? What coach?
-You shot a deputy, Percy.
Federal Marshal's bringing
you to Santa Fe.
Federal Marshal?
Sherriff, have you lost your mind?
My pa is on his way down here.
you better let me out of here,
before things get out of hand.
Sheriff, and 'was an accident.
it's not like I'm Jesse James..!
Bastard ...
Hey, -your whisky
-can you put that on Percy's tab?
Fifty cents.
Just kidding with you there, pal.
Have they no respect in this town?
That's not true, okay?
-You wanna leave?
-No.
This is your dream.
I'd follow you anywhere.
I thought it was our dream.
Damn.
Charlie, why don't you play
something festive!
It's like a funeral in here.
Hey. You don't have to
prove anything, okay?
Ok? I love you.
Not now.
Whisky.
On the house.
For what you did.
I came here just to drink.
- I know you?
- No ...
My name is Ella ...
Where'd you get that bracelet?
Is there something you
know about me maybe?
You do not remember anything, do you?
What do you want?
I know you're looking for something.
So am I.
Well, good luck to you.
Go away.
Jake Lonergan.
Follow me to the office, so
we can have us a little chat
I think you've got the wrong man.
Well, I'm gonna need you to
come with us all the same.
Wouldn't do that if I was you.
I do not want trouble.
Hello there ', sunshine!
You're in trouble now..!
You're gonna burn.
here, my pa is coming for me.
He learned how to kill a man
good, and slow. In the war
I am gonna watch you suffer...
...for a long, long time.
You thought that cheap shot
in the pecker hurt, huh?
Please. I didn't steal your cow.
Colonel Dolarhyde, you've
gotta believe me.
You've only been riding for my
bran for what, two weeks?
You don't maybe know whom
you're dealing with, Roy.
Nobody calls me Colonel.
And them who that did are mostly dead.
Please.
So you had little Mickey's picking
up strays. How many did you get?
About forty-four of 'em, boss.
You've been drinking, ain't
ya? I can smell it on ya.
I haven't been drinking nothing.
You said it yourself, we shouldn't do drinking
What kind of a man goes 'round
blowing up other peoples cows,
then tells a bullshit story like this?
You could't do no better?
-You gotta believe me, there was a white light.
This bright light.
So there was this big light...
and you fell in the river, and
when you come back...
two of my best hands
has just disappeared.
There 'was no storm.
There weren't no lightning this evening.
You don't respect me, do you Roy?
Where 'Percy?
-Taggart locked him up, boss.
-Why?
-What did he do now?
-Shot a deputy.
Damn.
What the hell does Taggart
think he's doing?
He wouldn't even have a job...
Now I gotta go in there
and reason with him...
...because you failed to
look after my boy.
Thanks ... Thank you.
Alright. Everybody saddle up.
Boss, we oughta get more hands.
- Why '?
- You will not believe ...
I think Jake Lonergan
is in the city '.
I'm turning you over to the Federal Marshal.
You're gonna tell me
what I'm charged with?
Arson, assault, mayhem...
theft ....
It says you robbed the stage last month.
With Pat Dolan and Bull McCade.
Which makes you an accesory
to everyone they broke, too.
- Is that all?
- Murder.
Prostitute out in Cottonwood Grove
has con you over.
Her name was Alison Wills.
You say that I killed
this woman?
You tell me.
Oh, well.
Gimme your wrist.
Taggart, what are you doing?
Sheriff, this is going too far, I....
I was just fooling around.
Look, I didn't mean to hurt anybody.
- Go away.
- Look, I'm sorry.
But I had no choice.
I couldn't let you leave.
Well, I'm leaving now.
--I need you.
-If you have got something to say, say it.
I need to know,
where you come from.
So do I.
Lady ...
You gov'ners have a nice trip now.
Taggart. Taggart, let me out of here.
Sheriff!
What are you doing?
You get back home. Go to bed.
-Please, do not go.
-I have to, Emmett. It's my job.
I do not like it here.
Now your pa is getting things in order
and when he does, he'll send for you.
It's been a year.
Don't worry, he will
And your mom is buried here.
And you know I can't leave my little girl.
- Taggart.
- It ', I see them.
Go inside.
I want my boy, John.
- I knew you'd come, dad '.
- Shut up.
i'll deal with you later.
Yes, that's Lonergan, boss.
That's the son of a bitch who
stole my gold, off the coach.
I want that man.
You're gonna have to take it
up with the judge in Santa Fe.
I ain't going to Santa Fe.
You give him to me now.
Or I'm gonna take him.
-What about me, pa?
-I said shut up, boy.
What the hell is that?
What the hell ...?
-It's coming back!
-He's coming around.
Giu 'horses!
-Do not move.
-Wait for me.
-Give me your hand.
-What's going on?
-What the hell for?
I'll get us free.
Give me your hand.
Emmett. Come to me,
strong son.
Grandpa!
-Gimme your hand.
-No
Come on, kid. Give me your hand.
What is that?
Get up, boss.
-Come on, we gotta get out of here.
-Where's Percy?
-Come out of there.
-I can't, pa. -Can't?
Coward.
-What is that thing?
-Why are you asking me?
Since you shot us.
-Where did you get this thing?
-I do not know.
What do you mean you do not know?
What the hell '?
It took my wife.
Hey!
Is anyone in there?
-No. -Is my wife in there?
-No!
No!
And 'dead?
- It 'a demon?
- A demon?
Can't rightly say. Sure does
fit the description but uh...
Demons? What are you talking
about? Bible stuff -demons?
- It 's like in the Bible?
- Of the demons?
-I'm not talking about anything.
-What the hell are you talking about?
- Calm down, Doc
- Calm?
You're telling me that a bunch of demons took my wife?
-I didn't say any such thing.
-Took our people.....
Chief!
Boss, it went this way.
I do not know what it is, but it's bleeding.
It's in the same direction those
machines went with our kin.
We're not gonna be able
to track it in the dark.
Round up the horses,  get some supplies.
We set off first light.
And you ...
...You're going with us.
I need that weapon, it's
the only thing that counts.
I figure you owe me.
I don't see it that way.
What do you want?
Just tell me right now, or I'll kill you.
They took my people, too.
I've been looking for them a long time.
I know you can help me find them.
You stay away from me.
I can help you.
It's heading north.
It's tracks are still fresh.
-If it's all the same, I'd ride along too.
-Yes, ma'am.
We got a kid and a dog,
why not a woman.
You're back.
What is that?
-you have to take it back.
-Like hell I will.
-That's blood money.
-Well I didn't goddamn harm anyone.
-By robbing and killing.
That's gonna get us what we need.
Jake. -Stay there.
-Jake.
www.celebritysex.tk
Well, well, well.
See who's' back.
I'm seeing you, but I don't see my gold.
Well let's say we find
those people first huh?
And then you can take your
best shot at collecting.
Maybe that reward on your head would
be a more attractive proposition.
Or I could just shoot you in the chest
and cut that thing off your arm.
You know Doc, I don't even
know why we're doing this.
You know, they're all dead.
Well, if think if they wanted to
kill 'em I think they would have.
Well if.. if the boss is right,
they was roping 'em...
...then it's to eat 'em.
If it's me, I'd start with your wife.
Are you gonna be like this the whole trip?
we would
this conversation, right?
You know, you could say that
do you mind or ...
Cook some beans. Do something useful..
Want some friendly advice?
You get yourself a gun,
and learn how to use it.
Tracks are washed away.
I dont know much about boats...
...but I'd say that one is upside-down.
Five hundred miles from any river,
big enough to hold it.
Well let's get inside,
get out of the rain.
I'm not going anywhere near that thing.
Suit yourself.
Sleep in the rain.
You're fixin' to say something?
Maybe ... maybe we should
have call the army?
I ain't going to turn this
over to no WestPointers
gotta get on the telegraph, ask
Washington which hand to wipe with.
we waited around to ...
for them to tell me what to do.
For this reason,
I lost 328 people.
over a cornfield.
I remember those stories.
I don't recollect telling
you any stories.
I'd listened when you tell them to Percy.
You get this through
your thick Indian skull...
The stories weren't for you.
They were for my son.
Get out of here.
Go to take care of horses.
It 'your work.
Were you watching this knife, right?
Preview
Keep it to account.
Do not miss it.
Do not beat him!
It's not 'not your pack!
Remember that your life
depends on weapon.
What the hell am I doing?
It 'my fault, if those
flying machines have taken.
No, no, no.
It's not 'your fault.
The will report back.
Andra 'all right. You just have faith.
Faith?
Well, I do not think
that could serve ...
I will not disrespect,
father, and the Lord but I do not get along,
and I do not like me very much.
Surely you do not expect Doc
God does everything for you, right?
His presence,
you, you have to earn.
Then, you will recognize,
and then you
behave properly.
So, take aim
of that target ...
and shoots.
So 'it's better. Come on.
Again.
You are there 'long?
It '.
You need something?
Who are you '?
- It 'the only one who knows who they are.
- You know who you are.
- You just have to remember it.
- I can not ...
It ', as you can.
Does it hurt?
Is not 'nothing.
And 'here.
Calm dog.
Calm down.
What 'happened?
There 'no?
Stay away from the boy!
No!
- The boy! The boy ...
- He's fine ...
It's all right.
You must bring
those people back.
And I'll tell 'you something, son.
I know who you are ...
Dog?
Come on, come on!
So where are you?
Excellent track
north.
- Where are the men?
- They ran. Damned cowards.
I can not find the dog.
I do not expect.
O 'and ran or' dead. Come on.
Hey, hey, wait.
I would like to say a few words ...
The only one who could say
something 'buried.
It is not 'enough time
and we 'wanted to bury him?
No, not 'enough.
Say well ...
God ...
if there is one thing
called soul ...
this man had.
Please protect it.
It helped me feel better.
And now and 'in a better place.
Dust to dust.
Amen. How did he go?
Fine words.
Boy, 'cause you're coming with us?
I'm worried about my grandfather.
Well, when I was a little more '
greater than you,
this,
was Mexico.
We were aware that the Apache
would attack a colony called
... Jiruaca.
My father wanted
I was a man ...
then I bring 'with him
to make me go to bed with a woman.
I was terrified ...
When we arrived, it was too late.
They were all dead.
The flames had
destroyed everything.
Then we saw a man ...
crawling out of
from a burning building ...
It was burned ...
He knew he was dying.
He was severely burned ...
Yes and 'turned to me ...
and I looked in my eyes
and he said: "Kill me."
And what have you done?
I pulled out this knife
from his belt,
and I cut his throat.
Take it.
Be a man.
It 'been a little' hard, right?
You can say that again.
There we are.
The tracks are more 'frequent.
He slowed down, and and '
directed in the throat.
Hands up!
Also applies to you, young lady.
As they say: Hello!
Welcome to all.
Welcome.
Head?
Chief, are you?
Lonergan, what the hell
are you doing here?
Chief!
Who are your friends?
And 'your new gang?
I did not think I would
more 'revised, Jake.
You were always my favorite.
Silence.
Jake, I've broken a tooth?
Do you want to shut up!
I'm thinking!
How many were boys?
More 'or less the same.
- What would be ...?
- Thirty?
Exactly! Thirty.
Excellent.
Scortateci the field.
We need to fix things.
Let's go to camp!
- What have we?
- Gold nuggets.
With these there 'by
get rich.
- How much dynamite?
- Fifty ...
Dolan!
There's' wanted
to go back.
- What 'happened?
- He and 'here.
Nasty shit!
Do you have the courage ...
You'll come here, as if
nothing had happened.
Guys, take your guns.
Here we go.
No one will go 'anywhere
part with you, Jack.
We prepared
an assault on the coach ...
and e 'exactly
what 'we intend to do.
Are you the whore?
Who?
The tart that Jake
has left the gang.
- Be careful what you say.
- Or what?
Now I'm in command.
Point your guns
the bitch!
If only one of them moves,
let them blow your brains.
He said the tramp.
Call her again "whore"
and will be 'the last word you say.
You're in no position
make threats.
Hunte, take his gun.
Take his gun.
I'm sorry, Jake.
Where 'our gold, Jake?
I do not remember.
But I remember it well ...
you've decided to forget
us for someone else!
I guess I wanted svigartela
with all the gold in the last shot, right?
You'll ask '
once again.
Where 'the gold, Jake?
Demons ...
- What?
- The demons have taken your gold.
When you go
hell ...
you ask
return it.
Kill the bitch.
I warned you
not to call again so '.
All of them!
Drop your weapons!
I said, throw your arms!
Funny, huh?
And you is not know 'was very nice!
- Mounted on horseback.
- Go.
Jake, your gun.
You have always been
my favorite.
Let us follow him!
- I'm here.
- Hurry!
Most 'fast!
Ok, I've taken!
I have taken.
Can you swim?
- Oh, God
- Turn your head!
Are you okay?
Let's go back to the shore.
- We flew.
- Gia '...
- I do not want 'to do it again.
- Oh, no.
She ...
She remains with me.
Tell me.
Now remember, right?
- What?
- The woman ...
The loved?
- Can you tell me that.
- I can not remember.
Practically nothing.
Everything I know,
and 'that are in her debt.
And I must find.
Sorry ... I'm sorry.
I'll hold ... I'll hold you.
Not long.
You and I ...
we'll get along.
And 'Lonergan?
Chief!
- I'll take care.
- Put giu '.
- Drink.
- No, give it to her.
Doc?
How are you?
- It 'dead ...
- No ...
It is not 'dead.
It is not 'dead!
Jake.
He's' gone ...
- Doc ...
- Do not worry.
Doc!
E '"Black Knife".
And 'what the head of' that
and 'left of his people.
We must listen.
Lest we die!
The last Chiricahua!
He said that the white led
the destruction of his people.
Not 'true. We were
here before them.
They have come here.
He said that we were
us to bring the monsters.
We? They also kidnapped our
people. They took my wife!
- Tell him he kidnapped my wife!
- It's not 'a good reason.
I'm sorry, I could not tell you.
- Are you one of them?
- No.
I come from another world.
I have taken this form,
to stand among you.
You should have said.
You could not
take care of the old body ...
even if he was alive.
You may ask where it came from?
- What did he say?
- What is a world beyond the stars.
What do you mean from another world?
What do you mean by "other world"?
- What's up '?
- He says you should not talk.
What do you say that
should I speak? I have some questions to ask her!
- You are a guest!
- I'm not a guest!
I thought I was a prisoner.
You are both great men,
great warriors.
Therefore, we must listen to that
says the woman, whatever.
What are they doing here?
They wanted gold.
But it 'ridiculous.
What the hell are they doing? We buy anything?
For them and 'rare
as it is' for you.
- And my grandfather?
- And my wife.
And all the others.
Are they still alive?
If and 'so',
not be for long.
They are considering
your weaknesses.
These are only the scouts.
If we let them live,
will return with many others,
and no one will survive '.
And 'what' and that 'successful
to my people.
I came here,
to you 'that does not happen again.
But we must work together.
He said that his men
will join her.
In what sense do you join?
What will they do? Where will they go?
We can find them.
He knows where they are.
No, not 'true.
I can not remember anything.
Not even my name.
He said that
will occupy them.
I brought home the gold.
And then they kidnapped.
It's not 'your fault.
I know where they are.
Blessed Virgin Mary.
- How did they build such a thing?
- We have come with that ...
And 'their spaceship.
That and 'just the tip.
The rest 'underground. They are looking for gold.
And 'so', here is' gold.
We can see?
We do not see very well,
in the light of day.
By day they hide
in caves, where's 'more' dark.
That's it!
We're fried. We take
all, closer than before.
No, there 'another way.
Over there '. From where I ran.
We need to attract outside
creatures ...
so ', we
to approach.
And you shall go with that thing
you have the arm, freeing our people.
We have an advantage.
You underestimate.
They are like insects.
I'm not ready for defense
so they are vulnerable.
- Do not have enough men.
- I go for a walk.
He said he would like
use your telescope.
The Apaches are warriors
Mountain ...
He says it would be better
attack from a hill.
And tell him that 'a fool.
There 'hill that takes,
with those flying machines!
Jake is going on.
We are at the last stop ...
Bastard.
- How much gold do we have?
- Not much.
But I want my side now,
to leave the most 'far as possible.
- Red?!
- I gunpoint, boss.
Boy, have I at my
a deal that you can not refuse.
Going somewhere?
The most 'far as possible.
- Remember the beach in Puerto Vallarta?
- There are big fish.
Good tequila.
Want to come with us?
It makes no difference.
Not be able to
go very far.
What are those things, Jake?
No matter ...
we would find.
Would kill us all.
What the hell are you talking about?
The important thing 'that
you have a choice.
You could spend the last
hours that remain, drunk on the beach ...
which, however,
and 'a good idea ...
or you can follow me,
one last time.
We must make the best use
the latest resources.
We need a strategy.
Listen to me, dammit!
They do not understand anything.
You have to explain it to you.
Listen, we can not run around
here and the ', hurling spears
and firing arrows,
those damn creatures!
We need to flush them out from the 'inside!
On open ground.
So 'we will surround
and attack from all sides.
Destroy them!
Explain ...
He said that will allow '
to control its people.
What does it say?
He said they should open their
hearts to understand his point of view.
When his parents died
during the war in Mexico,
you have taken with you,
when he was just a kid.
You gave a purpose ...
have taught the
to take care of itself.
Even if it was your child.
Who despise the war ...
Whether you are a proud warrior ...
in any battle.
He wonders why 'if you're
a great warrior ...
have allowed a boy
and a woman will follow in the battle.
Dog!
What God is my lightning!
Are you ready to bounce back
your son?
Match ...
I know that I was wrong,
But do not let me back down '...
and climb again!
Go!
Hurry! Go!
I think we destroyed!?
They were under fire!
Take it and hide
somewhere.
- When you see our people, please advise!
- It ', sir.
We move from here!
Good job.
Our people and 'still
the 'inside. We need to get them out.
May God be with you.
Let's go!
That's where it goes' round
extract the gold.
- They can not be killed.
- It 'instead!
We must resist.
As long as' we do not save our people.
Doc!
Doc, come here, quick!
Oh, Jesus' ...
Doc!
We killed a ...
It ', we have taken.
You know, I always dreamed
to have a father like you ...
And I've always dreamed
a son like you ...
Go, Percy found ...
Reclaim your child ...
Do not look at the light ...
- I told you not to look at the light!
- You were right.
- How long does it take to recover?
- For each person, and 'different.
- Tiriamoli out ...
- We must hurry.
As others arrive!
Go!
They are all out.
Well ...
Hey, where are you going?
Let's go this way!
Dog, go!
Where the hell are you going?
We need to get out of here!
No!
- I came here to destroy that thing!
- But how?
- The bracelet ... Take it off.
- I can not remove it.
- It 'as you can, it controls you.
- How?
Like when you fire.
With the mind.
You have to stop thinking about it ...
It does not work.
And 'dropped ...
If I can achieve
the core, I'll be able 'to stop them.
Come on.
Take this.
The bracelet!
- Goodbye, Jake.
- What?
What? No!
I saw them.
They went out! That way!
There 'also Percy?
- It ', I see.
- And Jake and Ella?
No, no!
Everything ok?
- Where 'the girl?
- It 'in!
Grandpa!
It's me.
- Emmett.
You grew!
Percy.
Do not you remember me, boy?
I'm sorry,
I do not remember much ...
I am your father ...
Oh!
Do you remember me?
I thought you were dead ...
With gold, things
put it differently.
Soon will come '
the railway ...
Will change 'business
transport ...
The recorder
accounts in the bank?
And tell them, 'I want
the new checks.
Ok.
I would like it to be changed
the headline "Dolarhyde and Son."
- What do you think?
- It '...
It ', sir.
- John ...
- Woodrow ...
The city 'is becoming
more 'big ...
Do not you'd go
without saying goodbye, right?
I am a wanted criminal.
I could swear that Lonergan and Jake '
died in those caves. True, sheriff?
It 'a shame.
I could not wait to hang myself!
- There 'need brav'uomini here.
- Sure ...
Jake.
She and 'in a better place ...
See you, Colonel.