I'm going to bed.
- You drink one glass of wine and you fall asleep.
- It was two.
You'll get your masters,
Miss. 3-day student.
- Do you think it's an accident?
- Who would want to kill princess Dy?
She's so young and so beautifull!
I'm going to sleep.
Jony, don't forget to feed kitty.
Kitty, kitty, dinner time!
Turn the music down!
Kitty, kitty, dinner's ready.
Kitty!
Kitty, kitty, dinner is ready.
Kitty, dinner's ready.
Why didn't you feed the cat, already?
Hey, shut that damn cat off.
What is your name?
Chainy. Kates.
And the deceased was your sister?
Her name is Jony.
We are twins.
Were you able to see
who did this?
Just a glimps.
It was dark.
I'm not certain.
It is my opinion as a forensic psychiatrist
that John Forster is a serial psychopath.
If allowed to remain a free man in our society,
he will rape ang murder again.
Will the defendant, please, rise.
We, the jury, on this day, November 9th 1998,
find the defendant John Forster guilty
of murder in the first degree.
Oh, I've seen that outfit before.
I can't remember when.
Last night. Last night!
These things do return.
God, my head is still
pounding like a drum.
You party hard.
Yeah, well, you don't
look worse than I am.
I didn't drink as much as you.
History of my life, Sara.
Psychiatrist by day,
party animal by night.
I thought you've told
me you were a lawyer.
I'm not, yet.
Excuse me.
Yeah. Hey, Jack. It's Shelly.
I've been calling all morning.
You OK? I'm Ok. What's up?
I was worried.
You worry too much,
Shelly. What's going on?
Frank Parks is been calling. He
needs to speak with you immediately.
Pass him through.
I had fun last night, Miss. Pollard.
Me too.
Thanks for the wine tasting, Dr. Gramm.
Jack.
Hey, Jack, I've got
Frank Parks. Go ahead.
Hey, Frank. Jack.
We got another one.
Oh, no. The same?
Every detail.
Right down to the lateral laceration.
It's the Seattle slayer again.
Where are you now? Look, Jack.
There's a tape.
You're gonna wanna see it.
Jack, are you still there?
Yeah.
Meet me at my office, okay?
Sure, Jack.
Where to?
114 Western, please. Quickly.
Welcome back, Seattle.
We're continuing our
interview with John Forster...
Who was convicted for the death
of Janie Kay, nine years ago...
Based on the eyewitness testimony
of her twin sister, Janie Kay.
John Forster was dated to die at
midnight, at Walla Walla Penitentiary.
Do you mind changing it? John Forster.
What's your reaction to the State...
Thank you.
Congratulations!
For what?
I was referring to the hottie that
you left with the party last night.
She was a quite piece of ass.
Remember her name? Yes, I do.
Sara Pollard.
Is that a cut on your nose? You
didn't have that before I left.
I fell out of the bed. FBI hit here yet?
Yeah, 2 minutes in the
conference room. Okay.
Any calls?
New York Times,
Washington times, Newsweek.
They all wanna know if you have
a quote about Forster's execution.
What else is new? Kim
Cummings called twice.
She was worried about you
too. Kim knows this procedure.
Apparently not. She's in your office.
Jack Gramm Associates.
I put those case reports you
wanna me to look at on your desk.
I thought Lauren and Leeza
showed real insight and ability.
The others were pretty
much working the math.
Yeah.
Don't you have Federal
Agents waiting for you?
Yeah.
I' see you in class.
I'll take them trough
today's work if you run late.
Thanks.
Thank you, Kim. Bye.
Janie Keith came by
to give you a present.
Dr. Gramm.
I'm sorry. I don't know
if this is appropriate...
I just wanted to...
I just wanted to mark the day.
Thank you, Janie.
I'm glad that my sister Janie
hasn't been forgotten. Thank you.
For everything. You
went out of your way.
You are busy, so I'm just...
I'm gonna get out of here.
We did good, Janie. We did good.
All right.
Thanks.
Can I help you?
You are one of my students?
Hi.
Jack. Yeah.
I'd like to introduce you to Jeremy
Goober, with attorney general office.
Jeremy is in charge of the
Seattle slayer task force.
Dr. Gramm, it's so good to meet you.
This is a really big honor for me.
Sorry about the...
Oh, this is such a beautiful
conference room too.
And this special agent
MacTire from the FBI.
Dr. Gramm.
Pleasure. Have a seat.
Hey, big fellow?
Yes.
Jeremy.
Seattle slayer task force.
Well, okay. I'm sure you
have a lot of questions.
I'll do the best I can to
answer them, but first I...
No. First I think we
should all have a cookie.
These are from Janie Kay, whose sister,
Janie was murdered by John Forster.
Jeremy? Sure, thank you.
Frank? No, thanks, Jack.
No?
Mr. MacTire?
You are a good sport, Jeremy.
A little milk maybe, what do you think?
Shelley, we got milk, don't
we? Bring in three glasses.
Nothing for me, Jack.
All right, make that two.
No, make it three.
Maybe you have a change of heart.
So, let's see...
I can assume...
That last night crime scene...
Was very much like Forster's
previous crime scene, right?
They totally match, yeah.
What totally matches?
I have in here...
Halothane on the breath.
Subdued by Halothane.
Rape. Yeah.
The body was hung up side down.
Yes.
And...
Slashed throat.
And where this takes us?
Looks like a copy cat.
It could be. Maybe Could be? Maybe?
Maybe. It's a stage scene. Maybe what?
Maybe, and this might be far-Fetched...
But what if the perp
worked with Forster...
And these stage scenes were intended to
throw some doubts on his guilty verdict?
Go with it. Possibly providing him...
With a stay of execution
or even a new trial.
Goal star, Jeremy. Big goal star.
I mean, that's exactly what
I think is happening here.
No, I'm sticking with copy cat.
Of course there is another possibility.
Yeah? Forster is innocent.
Wrongly convicted. No!
The task force is aware...
That your expert opinion was
critical in convicting Forster.
But then why he walked his first trial?
Procedural error.
Why is he never been tried in any of
the other five pending murderers...
That you've attributed to him?
You realize that it is the dude of my
office to ensure that an innocent man...
Is not executed tonight.
You do understand that?
Look, Jack. If you have any
reconsideration of testimony...
Or anything new you
wanna lay on the table...
Now it would be the time.
Would you say it was
fair to characterize...
Your attitude towards John Forster...
As a personal vendetta? Lf
we're been fair, yeah, sure.
It's a personal vendetta. I have a
personal vendetta against Ted Bundy...
And Gacy and about 10 or
15 other serial murders...
That are on the streets
right now. Jack, please.
That's helpful.
There is one other issue
that we need to address.
Milk maid.
What's going on here?
Do you know a woman named Dale Morris?
Yes.
How?
She's a student of mine.
She's just a student of yours?
Dr. Gramm, we're federal agency
here. You don't wanna be lying here.
We had a relationship. You've
been very cryptic right now?
He had a professional relationship,
not a sexual relationship.
About a year ago her father
died. She was very troubled.
I treated her as psychiatrist.
I don't sleep with my
students, Mr. Goober.
Neither I sleep with my patients.
Now what does this have to
do with anything? Anyway.
Jack.
Dale Morris was murdered last night.
She's the third and latest victim.
When was the last time you saw Dale?
Well...
I saw...
I saw her last night.
To our impossibly difficult professor.
We say thank you...
For making our lives miserable.
The pleasure is all mine.
We're celebrating.
You're celebrating
Forster's pending execution?
No, we're celebrating his
conviction, not his execution.
It was an overturn so we're happy about that.
We worked hard on this case.
We have a tape that was
left on the crime scene.
We're gonna play it for you now.
This message is for Dr. Jack Gramm.
You got the wrong man.
Forster is innocent.
Please, don't hurt me anymore.
Don't hurt me anymore.
You gonna let me go, right?
You said you'd let me go. I've
read what you want me and...
Jack, it goes like that for
about an hour, before she dies.
Why do you think she was reading
you that message, Dr. Gramm?
Dr. Gramm?
In Dr. Gramm own words...
He analyzes a mental puzzle.
So they're no actual
tangible pieces per say.
He made a guess based
on what happened to Kate.
A guess based on his
intuition, a personal bias, ego.
And he sold that fiction lock,
stock and barrel to the jury.
What is it?
The girl that was killed last night...
Was Dale Morris. Dale?
Oh, my God.
Okay, let's see...
We have our investigators
coordinated with the FBI...
I wanna know everything Dale
Morris did on the last 24 hours.
I wanna know where she
went, who she talked to.
Can you please have Dr. Gramm's
car ready, please. Thank you.
Thank you, Shelley.
For what?
I don't know. For everything.
I hate when you do this, Jack.
Every time you o this, I
think you gonna end up dead.
Just don't ask me to marry you again.
Why not? We're perfect for each other.
Yeah, yeah. Except that I'm
gay and you're commitment phobe.
That's why we're perfect.
Thanks, baby.
Dr. Gramm is a world known
expert in forensic psychiatry.
What is forensic psychiatry?
I mean, is not the same profession
that destroyed MacMorton's life...
By conjuring up images
of child molestation?
None of the charges were ever proved.
And the accused, though innocent...
Was public crucified.
Jack, look. Look at the kite.
Jack, come here.
Yeah?
Hello?
You have 88 minutes to live.
What?
You know how long 88
minutes can be, don't you?
That's 11:45 am. Who is this?
Tic-Tac. Who the hell is this?
Tic-Tac.
What were you saying?
Jack Gramm Associates. Shelley?
I want you to set a trap
and and a trace on my cell.
What's going on?
I want you to contact
a wireless carrier...
And have them find out who
made that last phone call to me.
Jack, I could be more
helpful if... Just do it.
Just do it. I need it, all right?
And call me when you get it.
John Forster was an Eagle Scout, which
counts for his facility with ropes.
He also worked in a veterinary office...
Where he had experience using the
animal tranquilizer Halothane...
Witch he's used to subdue his victims.
Halothane. Sorry, I'm
late again. Thank you, Kim.
I see that the size of our
class is dwindling once again.
It could be because you
keep booting everyone.
My favorite student, Mike Stempt.
Okay. The legal distinction between
sanity and insanity rests upon what?
Free will. The concept of the free will.
And what is the most important thing...
One should remember when
entering a court-Room?
That insanity it's a legal concept.
It's not a medical or psychiatric term.
But despite the fact that
insanity is a legal concept...
It doesn't mean that
someone is not sick.
Yes, Lauren.
Of all the serial killers that
I've interviewed and studied...
Witch include our boy
Bundy, Dahmer, Gacy...
None of them was legally insane.
This is not saying
that they were normal.
I could argue that they
couldn't help themselves...
Precisely because of
their mental disorder.
Well, if you wanna argue, Mike...
School of law is across campus.
Come on, Dr. Gramm.
It's ingenuous to pretend that our
presentations are not arguments.
We create a narrative of
the crime and the criminal.
Narrative is based on
facts. Based on logic.
We don't walk into a court-Room
and advocate set scenes, do we?
We don't take sides. We
check our views at the door.
You mean you want us to pretend
we don't have an opinion?
We have opinions, Lauren, but
we just keep them to ourselves.
Share them with your
dog, if you have to.
Not with your parrot,
because it talks back.
It is that kind of logic that's gonna
get you in a law school across campus.
I've been there. I've done that.
Well, my condolences.
So, where is...
Dale Morris? She's
absent. I don't see her.
That's her first.
I didn't take her for a quitter.
Anyone who has her phone number,
please, contact me after class.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Shelley.
Tick-Tack, doc. You have 83
minutes to live, Dr. Gramm.
Tick-Tack, doc.
So where was I?
Bundy versus Forster.
What? Bundy versus Forster.
Thank you, Lauren.
You're welcome.
What we're gonna explore today is the
similarities and dissimilarities...
Say, from Ted Bundy's motives, let's
compared them to John Forster's.
Dr. Gramm, your phone is ringing.
Jack, are you there?
Shelley. What's going on?
The call was made from a cell phone.
One of those you buy
and pay minutes for it.
Registered to whom?
Look, I know you're in class,
but... Yes, who is registered to it?
A Kate Gramm.
Jack, it's a common name. It
doesn't have to be your sister.
It's just a coincidence.
It's not a coincidence.
Jack, I'm loosing you.
Shelley? Goddamn it!
Shelley?
Have you found out who my
phone is registered to by now?
Poor Kate. If it was Kate,
you'd like to call her?
I'm gonna find you, you here
that, you son-Of-A-Bitch?
You're barking up the
wrong tree on this one.
I'm gonna find you.
She suffered for such a long time.
You remember how long, don't you?
You still feel guilty about her?
You feel guilty about
falsifying the evidence?
For lying under oath?
Tic-Tac, doc. You have
79 minutes to live.
Do you find this funny, Albert?
Who were you calling on your phone?
Let me see your phone.
I was just...
Let me see that goddamn it phone.
I was just checking the Mariners score.
You were what? I was
checking the Mariners score.
Okay, what is the score?
The score.
What's the damn score?
It's 3 x 1 Mariners. B1.
Oh, my God, I can't believe it. What
does it mean? What's the problem?
Look.
What?
What's going on here?
It says that Dale Morris
was murdered last night.
Is that true, Dr. Gramm? Yeah.
You knew it? You knew it
and you didn't tell us?
You knew and asked for Dale's
number? Is it the slayer?
It could be. It could be?
Well, the police haven't
released any information yet.
Are we all in danger? I can't
believe you didn't tell us.
Dr. Gramm? Lynn Johnson.
Someone just called a bomb threat.
Everyone is to evacuate the
building immediately. Thank you.
Come on. Grab your stuff.
I'll get your papers
of presentation, Tom.
I got the slides, Kim.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat. Everyone must
evacuate the building.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat. Everyone must
evacuate the building.
Please, remain calm e do not run.
Proceed to the door to
the end of the campus.
I repeat. We must evacuate the building.
Jack? What are you doing? Get going.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
What was that on the screen?
Some student playing
a joke or something.
You of all people know that it breaks
school laws to proceed by a threat...
You need to report this to the
campus security immediately.
Carol. I get threat like this,
three or four times a year.
Your incredible arrogance will
slap the shit of you, Jack.
I wish you'd disclosure your
true feelings about me...
Before we became such good friends.
Maybe you should stop hiding behind
your assessments about other people...
And start assessing yourself...
Cause you need to get over your
past and go on with your life...
Cause what you're living isn't one.
It is not what you tell your patients?
Gum? Thank you.
I'll call campus security and
let them know you're on your way.
Where did you go last
night? When you left the bar.
Home.
Were you alone?
Screw you.
Roger. We're on it.
Yeah.
The press got a hold of Dale's
name. It's all over the news.
Yeah, I know that.
And Forster's attorney is going
to the court and try a stay.
A stay? On what grounds?
They're claiming that these...
Murders prove that the real killer
have never been brought to justice.
Nonsense. They're just trying
to buy time. They're desperate.
They're also claiming that you falsify
testimony and concealed evidences.
Well, it's all loose. Goddamn it.
Who is that guy?
What about Dale Morris?
Did we find anymore of her?
She was murdered in her apartment...
Between the hours of two and six am.
Any sign of force entry? No.
Does Forster still have that
group visiting him on prison?
He's like a goddamn rock
star. Website and all.
I want you to pull a background
check on all my students...
And get back to me.
Damn.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Kim? What are you doing here?
I'm getting my car, it's parked here...
Like it's every day
I come to the campus.
That was really horrible. Just
horrible what you did in class...
It's was little low for you. I
was looking for potential suspects.
That's what I was doing. What did you
do after you left the party last night?
I didn't end up drunk in
bed with an strange like you.
You left the party with Dale Morris,
the girl that was murdered, didn't you?
Yes, I did. So what did
you do? Where did you go?
You're not seriously considering...
Where did you go?
We went to the Hickory Stick.
We had a drink, two drinks.
And then? And then I went home alone.
You have anyone that can verify
that? No. No-One can verify it.
Come on. I've been your
teaching assistant for two years.
I'm your friend. I'm here
to help you, if you let me.
Follow me.
Who did that?
What does that mean?
According to a anonymous phone call...
That means I have 72
minutes left to live.
Can I borrow your cell phone?
I've broke mine.
These are my car keys.
Can you take that around front
and meet me there in ten minutes?
I have to go to the
campus security. Okay.
Call me on my Blackberry
if you run late.
Okay.
Shelley. You gonna have to
reach me on Kim's cell phone.
What happened to yours?
I broke it. What?
You have her number, don't you?
Yeah, I do.
Listen, just forward all the
calls, okay, to Kim's cell.
Please, thanks.
Dr. Gramm.
Hey, Mike.
Everyone is pretty upset about Dale.
Yeah, well, that's understandable.
Considering the circumstances.
I have a question about John Forster.
Yeah? What?
Well, I've been going through the
trial transcripts in Kate's history...
Why would you do that?
To understand your process better.
How you come to your conclusions.
And?
What?
Is it possible that Forster is innocent?
No.
You won't even consider the possibility?
You're completely convinced the scenario
you put together is the only one?
First of all, I didn't
put together a scenario.
I recreated the crime scene. Second...
I didn't convict Forster. A jury did.
But the evidence was circumstantial.
No DNA, no murder weapon.
Nothing directly linking Forster to
the crime, except your narrative...
And Janie Kay's testimony.
What's your point?
Just that your testimony
was very convincing.
That's my job.
To be convincing.
I thought it was to be right.
Help!
Somebody, please!
Lauren. Dr. Gramm.
What happened to you?
He's wearing a leather
jacket. He's out there.
I bit his hand, it's bleeding. If
his hand is bloody, you can get him.
You're okay? Go get him now! I'm fine!
Watch my car! It's a police action!
There's been an assault.
I wanna see your hands. Back off!
Roll the window down. No!
I'm a forensic psychiatric
with the FBI. Here.
Okay? Open the window now.
Yeah. See? Well, roll down the window...
And let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands.
If you have nothing to
hide, you can show me.
Look, I'm trying to go home. What?
Okay, sorry.
Excuse me.
There's been an assault.
I wanna see your hand.
Okay. Be cool now!
There's been an assault.
I gotta check your hands.
I'm a forensic psychiatric with the FBI.
Sorry.
I couldn't find him.
Here.
This is stupid.
I'm so stupid.
How I could be so weak? Such a
wimp. It's not your fault. Come on.
I can't believe I let him get away
like that. I should've fought back more.
Stop beating yourself
up? What exactly happened?
He came from behind. He put this
rag over my mouth and I bit his hand.
The rag had an odor? Something sweet...
It's Halothane, right?
Yeah. He's the one.
Probably.
I let Dale's murderer get away.
Stop beating yourself
up and tell me something.
Tell me something. Could you
identify him if you saw him again?
He came from behind, I didn't see him.
Let's go to the campus security,
you'll tell the everything.
Hello.
This woman has just been attacked.
Are you okay?
I think so.
What's your name?
Lauren Douglas.
And who are you?
Jack Gramm.
The famous Dr. Jack Gramm?
Then Johnson Fonsen
have you be coming in.
Is there someone to interview
Miss Douglas now, please?
Jimmy? Yeah.
You wanna check out
this girl? Wait a minute.
Right this way.
What's going on here?
The person who attacked her
may still be on the campus.
What the hell you guys doing?
We got all these guys
out on the bomb squad.
Excuse me for one moment. It's
a little crazy around here.
Jimmy, get off the phone and
interview Miss. Douglas, please.
I'll be right there.
Why won't you seat here?
Okay, you okay?
Jack Gramm Associates.
Shelley? Get Frank...
And pass him through
when you get him. Okay.
Okay, thank you.
I don't want you going back to your
apartment until the locks are changed.
I don't have anywhere else to go.
After you talk to the officer here...
Go back to my office. Shelley
will find a place to stay.
Okay.
Come on. It's gonna be all right.
Sorry for all the troubles I caused.
Miss. Douglas. Right this way.
Right in here. I'm sorry.
Yeah? I left a word for Frank.
Okay. There's been another incident.
The Forster's case
it's your thing, right?
Wrong, it's not my thing.
I saw your testimony on Court TV.
Yeah, right?
Fill those out.
Yeah, I follow the big crime cases.
They fascinate me.
When Dr. Jack Gramm takes the stand.
You come up with things
I didn't think off.
This here, this is just a job until...
Until you pass the police's exam.
See? How did you know that?
Just a guess.
That's the thing about you.
You know how to put two plus
two and you make it four.
Or five.
There are times that you know.
I'm not gonna be a campus cop
to a bunch of snob rich kids.
Especially these rich bitches...
My car is been analyzed.
The window was smashed.
There's a number on
the body. Look into it.
Dr. Gramm?
This is Johnny D'Franco,
from campus security.
Can you get me Lynn Johnson?
Jack Gramm Associates. Shelley?
Did you find Frank? No, not
yet. What the hell is going on?
Well, I received a threaten phone
call saying I have 88 minutes to live.
11:45h this morning, and my time is up.
Pull out my risk assessment file.
Anybody rating "e" and above...
I want you to cross
reference against Forster.
And when you find Frank...
Ask him if Sara Pollard or any of my
students ever visit Forster in prison.
Sara Pollard?
She's the girl I met
at the party last night.
Call Wong Lee...
And have him make a list
of all the phone numbers...
Forster called on the last 72 hours.
Where should fax the list?
My apartment.
And run a check on Kim.
Kim?
Yeah, just do it, okay? Hello.
Jack.
Damn it. The car is out front.
Drive Squaid. Good.
You're okay? You look
a little freaked out.
Yeah. You have...
A battery for your phone? Yeah, I do.
What the hell is this?
What are you doing?
Goddamn it, what is this?
What are you doing with
a gun in your purse?
Jesus, why don't you just
announce to the world?
I don't think they've heard
you in English Department.
Why the gun, Kim? For protection.
Where did you get it? I have
a permit. My dad is a cop.
Why you need a gun? I
don't. My dad thinks I do.
Why?
I have a crazy ex boyfriend, okay, Jack?
Oh. Jesus. God.
Yeah, I really know
how to pick one or what?
The judge said if he threats
anyone he goes back to jail.
Back to jail? What jail?
Prison, actually. Walla Walla.
That's where Forster is.
Come on, let's go.
Special Agent Parks.
Frank, it's Jack.
I'm at the university
campus. We got a problem here.
Someone attacked one of my students and
tried to knock her out with Halothane.
That's the Seattle
slayer. I know, hold on.
Give me a second.
Yeah. There's a security guard on
this campus, his name is D'Franco.
I don't like him. He's suspicious.
I want you to take him
in for questioning, okay?
Also get a warrant and search his place.
Jesus Christ, Jack.
You know I can't just get a
warrant without sufficient grounds.
Just get a warrant, Frank, come on.
Do you think he is the slayer?
To link Forster on the
outside? It's possible.
Listen, I checked the names
that Shelley, of the students.
And there's no record of Lauren
Douglas, Kim Cummings or Sara Pollard...
But you gonna love this.
Mike Stempt visit Forster four
times over the last six weeks.
Mike Stempt. What was his reason?
Research. He had written permission.
No, no, no. I didn't
give him any permission.
Written or otherwise.
Well, it's your signature,
Jack. I got a copy right here.
Hold on. That... Hold on a second.
That ex boyfriend of
yours. What is his name?
Guy LaForge.
Run a check on a parole
named Guy LaForge.
He served time at Walla
Walla with Forster.
And I'll call you back
when I get to my apartment.
All right.
Do you think that Frank
is working with Forster?
Someone is.
I got you Johnson. Yeah.
They've found a backpack
in your lecture hall.
What? With a bomb in it?
No. A photo, dynamite, and a
time with a note addressed to you.
What did it say?
Tic-Tac.
What does it mean, Jack?
I call you back.
You are okay? Yeah.
What the hell was that?
Probably somebody trying to scare us.
Who do you think would
do something like that?
Does your boyfriend drive a motorcycle?
Yeah.
Except he's not my boyfriend anymore.
How does it feel to know you
won't live through another night?
56 minutes.
Tic-Tac, doc.
Let's go.
Guy LaForge.
He isn't a boyfriend, is he?
The only thing that got me out
of Texas was my books marks.
And when I left for college,
I had that, but not much else.
So I tried to fit in. I drank too much.
Thought too little.
And I met Guy.
And he was this English...
Working class rock star wanna be.
And I fell for him.
And I married him...
When I graduated.
He didn't take to well to my
aspirations for higher education.
In fact he didn't really want me to
leave the house. And when I disobeyed...
He got filthy drunk and he beat me.
That's when he got
arrested and I divorced him.
I've been trying to make
up for lost time ever since.
You know, Forster is trying to
kill me. Forster is in prison.
Yeah, I know. He's got someone
on the outside trying to...
To do the job.
He's gonna kill me.
If I don't get him first.
Whoever is working with
Forster must be close to you.
A friend even. I don't
have many friends.
That's a plus.
It's a real pleasure to look at everyone
you know as your would be murderer.
Paranoia is a normal state of mind, huh?
Where is Errol?
I don't know. I'm a
temp. The agency sent me.
Dr. Gramm?
There's a package for you.
How did you know my name?
I don't. It was a question.
Yeah.
There's no returning
address on this? No.
Who delivered it?
A carrier. But there was another
person here at the same time...
Iooking for you. Who?
What was his name? No, I didn't get it.
When he walked in I was on
the phone with the plumber.
He said he would be right back. Okay.
You wanna me pull the
surveillance tapes?
That shouldn't take more than an hour
to get someone up here with the keys.
I don't have an hour. No?
Hey, you know, he was also wearing
leathers. He had a motorcycle helmet.
That's Guy. He was here.
If he comes back, don't
send him up to my apartment.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Gramm. Hi, Eva.
How did Guy know we're going to be here?
How does even know where you live?
Oh, Walther P99.
That would blow a hole through anything.
What? I grew up around guns.
Maybe he didn't know I was gonna be
here, maybe that's why he showed up.
I'll verify where he went
after the party last night.
There's a Lauren Douglas to
see you. Should I send her up?
Okay, send her up.
He got that right, didn't he?
Hey, what's that?
This?
It's a chemical detector.
It sniffs out vapors.
Custom agencies are using it.
And?
It's not a bomb.
That's good.
Yeah.
Hi. Hi.
Are you okay? Yeah.
I'm better, thank you.
What do you have? I went to
see Shelley like you said.
She tried to fax you over some
papers, but the machine was down.
So I said I'd bring the risk
assessment profiles over myself.
I didn't know you had company.
Dale told me how good you're
with her when her dad died.
She was so grateful.
Dr. Gramm?
Yeah?
If there's anything I can do to
help you find Dale's murderer...
Will you let me know? Of course, yes.
Thank you.
Can I call you a cab or something?
No, Mike is gonna give me a ride.
Okay. Thanks for these...
Bye.
All those people have threatened you?
Well, you know, it
comes with the territory.
How come you never
mention that in class?
How many students end up
going into this field anyway?
Not very many with you
booting all of them.
Yeah.
Can I ask you a personal question?
No.
How come you never got married?
I mean, you're a pretty good prospect.
You obviously make a shit load of money.
Why would I get married?
I'm a target for any nut with a grudge.
I can't afford emotional attachments.
Yeah, but don't you want kids?
Don't you want a family?
I'm too old for kids.
You're too young for me, Kim.
If you want me to leave, Jack, all
you've got to do is say it and I'm gone.
No, I don't want you to leave.
I need you, Kim.
You are smart and you
are important to me.
Really, you are.
Okay.
Yeah. Jack, it's Shelley.
What the hell happened to
you? Where have you been
Making calls for you, four lines
simultaneously. The fax is down.
I know, Lauren Douglas came over
and brought some papers with her.
Jack, you better turn on MS-NBC.
Why?
Forster got a judge to grant
his request for an interview.
He's on, live.
This is gonna heat things up
When looking for a home...
A real estate agent is really important
in you life. You need someone...
Shelley. Listen to me.
I want you to send some of the
boys to my apartment, all right?
There may be someone down at my lobby
in biker leathers when they get there.
Okay?
You got a name? Yes,
his name is Guy LaForge.
Put a photo on the FBI wire, okay?
If you are not granted another
stay of the execution...
Are you prepared to die?
You want me to call the police?
No, no, let Frank handle
it. He'll know what to do.
As prepared as any man can be to
pay for something he didn't do.
Listen.
You didn't message over a
package to my apartment, did you?
No.
There is a lot of people out there
that believe in your innocence.
And I'm grateful.
You know anyone that might have?
No. I'm grateful for their prayers.
Everything goes to your
office. And support.
What about Pollard.
Find anything on her?
You didn't actually
paid her, did you, Jack?
Pay her, what do you mean?
She works for a escort service.
Escort service?
You didn't know?
No, I didn't know.
What? She told me she was
a lawyer. A student lawyer.
What are your thoughts this time?
Well, Stephanie, that's one
thing I don't have a lot of...
You got a number for her?
Yeah, a phone number and the address.
I know the address.
Let me have the number.
If Dr. Gramm was with us right
now, what would you say to him?
555-1352.
He knows that I didn't do this.
There's only one... Thanks.
Other person in this world
who knows I've been framed.
That it was a set up.
That I'm totally innocent.
And that would be the forensic
psychiatric Dr. Jack Gramm.
I guess what I'd say to Jack
Gramm... I'd say, "Why me"?
I understand that you've suffered
a great loss with your sister.
I feel your pain, Dr. Gramm.
Pick it up, damn it. But
that doesn't exonerate you...
From false accusing me of things that
you know I did not, could not have done.
Pick up, Sara.
If I can be convicted of this
voodoo forensic science...
Think about it... Who is safe?
Shelley?
Shelley? I want you to get MS-NBC.
I want to talk to that
son-Of-Bitch. I would be the last.
Jack, I really don't
think that's a good idea.
It's a good idea. Just get them and
when you get them call me back, OK?
But I find hard to believe that
Dr. Jack Gramm can be out there...
Psycho battling innocent
people into the death chamber.
Who is the murder now, Jack?
Yeah?
Who is the murder now?
Jack?
We got D'Franco in custody.
I got the warrant.
The guys are on the
way over to his place.
Did he say anything about Forster?
A quite bit, but nothing useful.
What about Guy LaForge?
He hasn't checked in with his
parole office in six weeks.
Well, he was at my apartment
building less than an hour ago.
And he said he's coming back.
Listen, Frank.
I got a call a little while ago...
Saying I have 88 minutes to live.
Jesus, Jack. Why 88 minutes?
I don't know.
You have any idea who this caller is?
You better find Guy LaForge
before he gets here, okay?
Listen, let me call you back.
Jack?
Shit.
Mom.
Dad.
Jack.
There's someone in here.
And he wants to talk to you.
Where are you?
Please, come home quickly!
I'm here with a man.
It is not what you want me to say...
Jack, come here now! Help me. Help me.
Jack, what is that?
My sister.
Oh, my God!
That's horrible. Who
would send that to you?
There's only two copies
of this tape in the world.
One is...
Iocked up in custody of NYPD.
And the other...
Is in a restricted access room...
In my office file cabinet...
With the highest security measures.
So you're thinking it was stolen.
Of course it was stolen.
You think I stole it?
You left the bar
yesterday night with Dale.
One of the last people to
see her alive. Maybe the last.
Jack, you think I stole
the tape and killed Dale?
Have you lost your mind?
I don't have clearance to
your restricted access room.
Why Guy LaForge was
at the bar last night?
He was trying to protect me.
From what?
From you. From me? He knows about me?
Yes. What does he know about me?
He knows I have a silly
girlish crush on you.
Jack. Hold on a second.
I just got an email
from Mike Stempt, okay?
He saw Guy at Darby's Club last night.
When Mike left at 3 am, Guy
was still sitting there...
And they've bounced a beer until 6 am.
So there's no way that Guy
could have killed Dale Morris.
Yeah? Did you listen
to the tape, Dr. Gramm?
Why did you leave the
little Katie all alone?
Why, Dr. Gramm?
She'd still be alive today if you
hadn't left her all alone to die.
Now it's your turn. In a glaze of glory!
Tic-Tac, doc.
You have 37 minutes.
Yeah?
Hey, Jack, I got MS-NBC on the line.
I'll patch you through the prison.
You're sure you wanna do this? Shelley.
There's been a breach in my
place, in my most secure area.
Did you ever give anyone clearance
to go into my secure files?
Jack, what are you saying?
Did you ever let an
unauthorized person...
Into my secure files area?
No, never. To anyone.
Ever.
Okay.
Now put me through the MS-NBC.
Frank?
Yeah. Yeah, turn on the MSN-BC.
They've granted Forster
a live interview.
I can't, Jack, I'm in the car.
It's all right. They also will
cast. You just turn on 750 AM.
I'm phoning in.
Wait a second. You think is such a
good idea? With all the court actions?
I think he's behind everything. I think
he's behind the phone calls, threats...
I'm gonna try to get inside
his head. Make him crack.
Okay? You wanna stay
on the line, please?
Dr. Gramm? Yeah.
You're on the air.
I've been told that we have
Dr. Gramm joining us by phone.
Dr. Gramm, are you there? I'm here.
Have you been watching the interview?
Is that what you call it?
What would you call it?
I don't know, I don't call it an
interview. I call it an entertainment.
I call it a performance, maybe.
You must have got something to
say or you wouldn't have called in.
Oh, yeah, I think it's very interesting
that Forster talks about forgiveness.
I just want him to know that his
victims have not forgiven him.
Look, you've lied under oath,
Dr. Gramm, and you know it.
This is not about me. This
about the women you've raped...
And tortured and murdered.
Women like Janie Kay. I have
nothing to do with her death...
And you know it. Nothing
to do with her death?
There was an eyewitness, a
twin sister who identified you.
She was at the scene and identified you.
She was drugged and beaten so badly...
She said that she couldn't
be sure, but you...
You bereaved her until
she said it was me.
Interesting that you didn't
say that you're innocent.
I had nothing to do with the death...
No, I don't. I know you're convicted.
You're convicted by a jury.
You were trialed and
convicted, that's what I know.
Trial? That wasn't a trial,
that was an inquisition.
And the jury believed your lies.
You had to cause pain, suffer and
death, so you could feel alive.
Wait a second.
Pain and suffer is something that
you, forensics, know how to inflict.
Even your idol, Ted Bundy,
ultimately, identified his victims.
How about, man, identify your victims?
How about?
The bodies of Terry Hines, Alicia Smith,
Samantha Green. Where are they, man?
Come on, where are they?
Give these people's families
closure, man! Give them closure.
You're on national television now!
Millions of people are watching you.
Come on!
How about your colleague in
London, in the Clark case?
Putting in an innocent mother
for murdering her baby? Well done!
Well done, doctor. You must be so proud
of being part of an elite fortunate.
Fortunately for her, her
conviction was overturned...
When the doctor's testimony
turned out to be an absurd.
Quack, quack, Dr. Gramm?
You now what?
Why don't you take a
good look at your watch?
A good look.
Now imagine what it'd be like to
be minutes away from your own death.
To hear the ticking of a clock...
And know that your time on
earth is drying to a close.
Thank you.
There's another package for you,
Dr. Gramm. Should I send it up?
This has just got in.
A three judge panel of the Nine
Circuit has just granted John Forster...
A stay of the execution.
What?
Are you serious?
You hear that, Frank?
Yeah, I heard.
Forster got the stay.
I got him going, didn't I? No cigar.
Why did you send me on
a wild goose chase, Jack?
What do you mean, wild goose chase?
D'Franco is not a serial
killer, he's a serial groupie.
So he's a groupie so
what? What's the big deal?
I've just got a call from Jeremy
Guber from attorney general office.
You are wanted for questioning
on the murder of Dale Morris.
What? What are you talking about?
They've found physical evidence at her
apartment that implicates you, Jack.
What evidence?
Jack...
You know I can't say.
What you mean, you can't
say? What does that mean?
Frank? There's someone to see you...
Mister, you can't go up there.
You told the doorman
to don't let anyone up.
It's all right, don't worry.
Don't worry, no-One is getting in.
The state attorney general has
just announced that his appealing...
Is taken to the State
Supreme Court immediately.
Jack. There's smoke.
We'll keep you informed
with further developments.
There's smoke here too.
It's your boyfriend.
Let Kim go.
Let her go now and
no-One will get hurt.
Guy, I'm fine. There's no problem here.
The building is on
fire. That's a problem.
He's got a gun. Okay. Listen to me.
I know this man and I know
he's not gonna hurt me again.
You have to trust me,
Jack. Please, open the door.
Do it quickly. There's
smoke up here. Kim.
Guy, I'm coming out. We
can calm things down, okay?
Guy, look at me. I'm fine.
There's no problem here.
What are you doing with him?
I'm okay. There's no problem.
Guy has been shot. No!
On the roof there's a fire escape. Okay?
When I say "go", follow me. Okay.
Do you think he is dead?
He doesn't look good. We
should go back up there.
I gotta go back there and help him.
No. You can't go up there. Man.
Yeah? Jack, I need to talk to you.
I need two minutes to clarify something?
Shelley, I can't talk now.
I'll talk to you when I get
to Sara Pollard apartment.
Miss. Lewinsky. Are you okay?
I'm just a little bit dizzy. Come.
Because I didn't see
a device with a timer.
Get the bomb squad,
this is the second one.
Go.
Get her some oxygen. All
right. We got her, sir.
Let's go outside. You
gonna be all right.
Jack, I don't see the shooter, do you?
Jack.
He's got a gun. Where?
Where the hell is he?
Where? Jack!
Get down!
Kim! Keep moving!
Kim, where are you?
Go, go, go!
Move back!
Are you okay? Yeah, I'm gonna live.
Here, let's go.
Where are we going?
To Sara Pollard house.
She's the girl I was with last night.
That's funny. It worked in the garage.
Why did you do that?
I don't know. I had a feeling...
Are you okay?
What next?
I don't know.
Okay, let's get out of here. Okay.
Is that your cab? Yeah.
Okay. I give you a hundred bucks...
You let me drive it. I'm
just going across town.
A hundred bucks?
A hundred bucks plus tip. How is that?
All right.
I can not believe that.
Guy is dead.
He is. He is dead.
Shit.
You have not to say, huh?
It's just another day in
the life of Jack Gramm.
Was I actually fooling myself into thinking
I can have a relationship with you?
Now, I've enough common sense
to figure this out. I mean, what was I thinking?
Okay.
Can you wait outside
the cab for a minute?
You bet. Thanks.
You asked me about my kid sister.
Okay. It was a long time ago.
She was staying at my
apartment in New York City.
She was 12, I was 28.
And I was late for a meeting.
Very important meeting.
A meeting that was gonna change my life.
It was gonna make me
into somebody important.
Make all my dreams come true, so...
I went to this meeting
on my dissertation.
And I left her there by herself.
I could have taken her with me. I
could have left her with friends.
I could have postpone the meeting.
But I chose not to,
because I was in a hurry.
Anyway, I left her there alone.
At that time I was working in a case...
And this guy had strangled six women.
We were very close to nail him.
He was upset and he
wanted to get back at me.
So he came to my apartment,
only I wasn't there.
And that time I wasn't
concerned with security.
I was careless so...
He broke the door down...
And he went in.
And did...
Things...
To my baby sister.
Katheryn, was her name.
Katy.
He did things that you
wouldn't do to an animal...
That was bred for slaughter.
Anyway...
When they caught him...
He laughed...
And said...
It took him 88 minutes...
It took him 88 minutes
to have my sister dead.
Jack...
He is in prison now.
Coming up for his fifth parole hearing.
I left New York.
Left all that behind me
and came here, to Seattle.
You know, it seemed the perfect place.
It's on the far off corner...
Of the continent of USA.
To see if I had a second hanged in me.
Whoever stole that tape...
Knows the meaning of 88 minutes.
Is that enough?
Let's go.
If Sara is not home, we
don't have a search warrant.
Well, we don't need a search warrant.
We're not gonna arrest anybody.
We're just breaking in.
Not a good sign.
You can't say I've
never give you anything.
This looks familiar.
When did you take it?
I guess it doesn't matter, does it?
It just might.
Okay, check out that way. Okay.
Oh, Jesus.
What is it?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Calm, Kim.
Calm, Kim. Oh, my God. She is dead.
It's okay.
Who would do that? Why? Calm, Kim.
Who could torture someone
like that? Just, breathe.
Breathe, breathe. Okay.
Breathe. Oh, God.
Control. Take control. Okay.
I'm in control.
Are you in control? Yeah.
Okay, good. Let me show
you something. Okay.
That is my signature.
Forged. Credit card receipt.
This whole place is filled with my DNA.
The police is gonna come here.
They gonna know I was with Sara.
They gonna think that I killed her.
Your phone. Yeah.
Answer, Jack.
Yeah.
Jack? Carol?
Carol?
Did you here the tape with your
sister's 88 minutes of suffering?
I sent it to your apartment.
What are you saying,
Carol? What is this?
The Porsche was a close call.
I called Frank and told him you
murdered Sara after you killed Dale.
Think you are so smart...
Invincible and unbeatable.
John Forster is giving you a death
sentence and he is about to be free.
How ironic.
You've got 18 minutes left.
Meet me at your office alone.
Tic-Tac.
What is it?
It's Carol.
She wants to meet me at the
university, at my office.
Let's go.
Come on. Okay.
Shelley? What the hell
are you doing in here?
I need to talk to you.
That poor girl. That poor... poor girl.
It was me. Sit, sit.
It was me. Shelley, sit down.
I broke the security protocol.
Why?
Well, about six weeks ago...
I had a drink in your office
with a student of yours.
A couple of drinks, actually.
And she made an advance, and...
It was late, but the office was
jammed with people working still.
And when we woke up she left.
She didn't have a briefcase...
She didn't have anything she
could put the tape in, but...
But somebody else must have.
Somebody else did, while we're sleeping.
Who was this girl? What's her name?
It was Lauren.
Lauren Douglas.
And here is the...
It's a picture from
the security cameras.
This is the person that must
have rifle through my files...
And found the combination to
your vault and took the tape.
That's not a person, Shelly.
It's a hat and a coat.
And this the photo ID of everyone that
has visited Forster on the last month.
Oh...
Can you ever forgive me?
If I can't forgive you, Shelley...
I don't deserve you.
Understand?
I want you to call Carol
and patch her through to me.
Okay? Okay.
Kim?
Hi, can you transfer me to
Lynn Johnson office, please?
Kim?
Where are you going
in such a hurry, Jack?
Is there something upstairs
that you don't want me to see?
There's a woman named Sara
Pollard upstairs very dead.
You can see her, if you'd like.
Look, I'm a straight
shooter, right, Jack?
Yeah. And you'd never
screw me over, right?
Oh, come on.
Why are your finger prints
all over Dale Morris apartment?
They are? Yeah.
And you were right about the
Halothane on the blood stream.
What you failed to mention is the fact
that your semen is in her vagina cavity.
Is your semen in Sara Pollard?
Where the hell are you
going with this, Frank?
Can't you see this is a frame?
Forster is coordinating
this whole thing from prison.
Can't you see that? Yeah, right.
It is Forster's semen on
Sara Pollard it's yours, Jack?
Somebody hired Sara Pollard
to be with me last night...
Then killed her...
Took my semen and
deposit into Dale Morris.
Do you have any idea
how absurd that sounds?
No, it's not absurd.
I don't have time to explain, Frank.
Carol isn't answering.
What? What?
Get the names of all the women
lawyers who work for Forster.
I want their names and ages.
Look, I know how you operate,
Jack. What the hell are you doing?
I know how you use people.
It's no secret you're a
womanizer, you drink too much.
How do I know that you haven't
gone completely over the edge?
Oh, man, I can't believe
it! How do I know?
I don't know what you do
anymore. What did I do, Frank?
Did I send myself a tape?
Did I blow up my car? Did
I set my apartment on fire?
Did I fire bullets at myself?
For God sakes, Frank, wake up!
What the hell... What are you doing?
I have no idea who you're anymore.
You don't?
I got Gramm. I'm bringing him
in. No, you're not gonna do this.
Frank. Frank. Just give me some time.
Just give me some time.
I can untangle this. Okay?
Just give me... Here, give me some time.
Don't move or I'll blow your head off.
Don't point a gun at me, Frank.
Don't point a gun at me. Please.
I wanted to sync up
our watches, that's all.
All right, Jack.
What do you need?
I need time. I need ten minutes. Okay?
Here, let's sync up now.
At 11:40, meet me at my
office at the university.
Kim? What happened?
I know you're only trying to help me,
but don't go to my office on campus.
You understand? It's
dangerous. Don't be a hero.
When you get this message,
call me back A.S.A.P.
You understand? It's Jack.
Yeah.
There's still no answer
at Johnson's office.
Hold on. Yeah.
Jack? Kim...
Whatever you do, don't go to my office
on the campus. Do you understand?
You have 14 minutes.
What?
It was me, Jack. I set you up.
I had a computer dialing
service call you up...
Rearranging times, using
electronic altered voice.
Kim, this is no time to joke.
Meet me in your office
in ten minutes, Jack.
11:40. Don't be late.
Kim!
Oh, shit.
Man...
Yeah.
Hey, Jack, I got the names of
the women on Forster's legal team.
They were three.
Hannah Baker, 53. Rosane
Caputto, 47, and...
Lydia Doherty, 28.
And Lydia Doherty, 28. How did you know?
Cause her name is on the
signature sheet you gave me.
I want you to do a
search on Lydia Doherty.
I want you to get all
the information you can.
Fax it to my office on
campus. Okay? Do it now.
Hey, another hundred
bucks and I'll wait.
What the hell are you doing in here?
This is Lauren Douglas bag.
It was stolen today. I
found it in your desk.
Halothane.
What is it doing here?
What are you doing in here?
This is what you used
to kill Dale and Sara?
Or do you have no idea about this too?
Oh, sure I do.
I left all this stuff in my desk
so you'd come along and find it.
You convinced the jury
that Forster was guilty.
How do I know you didn't
kill these women too?
Who sent you here?
Yeah. I'd like to report a suspect...
In the Seattle Slayer
case. What the hell...
Dr. Jack Gramm. Put
down the goddamn phone!
What's the matter with
you? Who sent you here?
You think I'm too dumb to
figure it out from myself?
Yes, I do.
Because whoever sent you here is
deeply involved in the Slayer killings.
Lydia Doherty.
Lydia Doherty. What the hell is that?
Yeah?
Come to the Stern Building now.
Corner office, seventh floor.
Alone.
You have five minutes, Jack.
What are you doing? I'm not moving.
I don't have time to explain this.
Get away from the door.
Come on! You're gonna shoot me?
Yeah.
I'm a bad shot.
Frank, when you get this message
I'm gonna be at the Stern Building...
On the seventh floor. Get
there as soon as you can.
Oh, God.
Punctual, Dr. Gramm.
I'm gonna give you a B+ for effort.
Lynn Johnson is indisposed, but I'm
sure she'd say hello, if she could.
As for your old friend, Kim,
she didn't quite make the grade.
Lydia. You got the name right.
Lydia Doherty. Copy cat murderer.
God, I wish Forster could see your face.
You look so totally clueless.
I hope that's not a gun you're holding.
Is that a gun, Dr. Gramm?
What do you want?
Is that a gun?
I have a gun. Then do this.
Put it on the floor...
And slide it to me.
To me.
Okay.
You slide it.
One more time, slide it to me.
Slowly.
And move back.
Better.
I'd like to talk to
John Forster, please.
This is his appeal
attorney, Lydia Doherty.
They monitor his calls.
You gonna implicate him.
The brilliant Dr. Gramm...
And his psycho gamble, is that it?
Sorry for the trouble
I caused, Dr. Gram.
You know that I did,
Dr. Gramm, with honors.
Dale told me how good you're
with her when her dad died.
She was so grateful.
But despite the fact that
insanity is a legal concept...
It doesn't mean that
someone is not sick.
Have him call me on my cell.
He knows the number.
What do you want? What about
you start with a confession?
I confess. To what?
To what? To everything.
I confess.
I want you to speak clearly
and I want the truth.
Where do I start?
Janie Kay. Janie Kay?
I coached her.
Shut it off.
Shut it off. I am.
Go again.
I coached Janie Kay.
In what trial? I coached Janie Kay...
In John Forster's trial. I
coached her. She perjured herself.
I gave false testimony.
And John Forster was convicted.
Based on an unlawful testimony.
Feel good?
What are you doing?
Are you assessing me?
Are you looking for
a weakness, Dr. Gramm?
I'm just wondering what is next.
Aren't you gonna offer
to make me a deal?
Sacrifice yourself for Kim and Carol?
Be the hero.
Well, that wouldn't fly out, would
it? I'd offer, but it wouldn't fly.
Rejected.
Have any other moves?
Or you spent so quickly...
I could move my eyes, like
this, e look behind you.
To see if there is someone there
with a gun pointed to your head.
How much time I got left?
You have about a minute.
Jack.
Enough time for your last words.
I'm not gonna deny you those.
All this torture, all this torment...
For an infatuation?
It's not an infatuation,
don't demean me.
Well, if it's not an
infatuation what is it?
Stop, please!
I went through great
lengths to pull this off.
John really appreciates
the quality of my work.
Timing the phone calls...
Perfecting the ropes and plus
implicating everyone close to you.
Coaching Carol and Kim.
All the while staying invisible.
It was me, Jack. I set you up.
You know what I don't understand?
How, in God's name, does
anybody give up their free will?
How you do that?
45 seconds. I saw you.
You came to my class, I remember you.
You were intelligent. An individual.
You challenged things.
You challenged me. You challenged ideas.
You're your own person.
How could you ever allowed yourself
to be so manipulated by this guy?
30 seconds.
You're gonna take the fall for this guy?
If that's what he wants, so be it.
You see, Jacko...
I'm a true believer.
You better believe
that's an FBI agent...
With a gun pointed
right into your head...
At this moment.
Believe it.
No more kidding. Believe it.
Believe it. I believe your time is up...
Dr. Gramm.
God.
Jack!
No!
Again!
I got you. I got you.
It's okay.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Requesting immediately MT help.
At the UNW Campus, Stern Building.
I repeat.
Immediately emergency
medical technician.
Multiple stab wounds.
There you go.
That's okay. Don't move.
Yeah.
This is officer Finnegan from the
State Penitentiary Walla Walla.
I'm placing a call from John Forster
to his attorney Lydia Doherty.
Put him through.
Go ahead.
Lydia.
Did you finish with Gramm?
She's downstairs. Gramm?
Put my attorney on the phone, please.
She's indisposed.
Look, you're meddling her.
You shouldn't be meddling in.
You seized a naive junior
lawyer on your legal staff.
You realized that she's
damaged psychologically and...
Genius, isn't it?
Susceptible to your
craps. And what you do?
You get her to kill people for you.
So you can stay alive.
That's an innovative legal strategy,
if I have ever heard of any.
Dr. Gramm, I'm flattered
with your imagination.
But you're grasping in straw.
She becomes a student
of mine, no less...
You keep her on the appeal process,
but she's still your lawyer...
So she has unlimited access to you...
So you can plan your
copy cat murders together.
And then you can get a new trial.
And live happily ever
after. Isn't that the case?
Dr. Gramm, I want you
to listen very closely...
Because when I get out of here...
I'm gonna go out and have a nice meal...
Stop by your grave...
And piss all over it.
Now, please, put my angelical
attorney on the phone.
She's dead.
It's over, Forster.
Except for the clock,
that goes tic-Tac.
Tic-Tac. You got 12 hours to live.
I'm glad, that my sister Jony
hasn't been forgotten.
We did good, Jane,
we did good.