Want to take a walk with me?
...continue to protest the presence|of a convicted sex offender
in their neighborhood.|Michelle Betler reports.
Thanks, Rick. I'm standing here|on Woodward Court,
the quiet residential|street
that has become|the focus of controversy
ever since 48-year-old|Ronald James McGorvey returned here
after serving a two-year|prison sentence
for indecent exposure|to a minor.
ln the past few days|an organization
known as the Committee|of Concerned Parents
began distributing these notices|throughout the community
warning neighbors|of what they call a quote,
''Dangerous predator|in our midst.''
I don't really like having|him that close to my family.
I think it's outrageous.|This block has too many children
for a sex offender to, uh, be|moving in the neighborhood.
l-- I don't think|it's a good idea.
Makes me very nervous.|Makes me a little enraged.
Um, I'd have a problem|if I see him on the street.
It's like having an|alcoholic work in a bar.
They don't mix.|They shouldn't be together.
The conditions of his parole|expressly forbid McGorvey
to be within 100 yards|of any playground,
school or recreation area|where children normally gather.
These conditions seem|to be of little comfort
to the many parents whose|children play and go to school
in this formerly|tranquil community,
and who in the coming days and weeks|will be hoping for the best
but preparing for the worst.|Rick, back to you.
My husband and I had an|actual spiritual experience.
We did this intense|spa treatment--
- Oh, come on.|- No, listen to me.
lt was on our vacation in Cabo|and there were eight other couples
and this Mayan woman.
A goddess,|just a goddess.
- She had--|- She's due in September.
She thinks she's gonna|take three months off,
then it's Christmas, then she'll be back|to work the first of the year.
Please.
Six months from now she'll be right here|on this bench with us.
My friend Beth said|that the way she did it
was to just take him with her every time|she went to the bathroom.
- I find that strange.|- Yeah, that's what I said to Beth.
It's Oedipal.
What's the rush?
Although I will say, when I was trying|to potty-train Christian,
I opened the diaper|and it was huge!
Like a grown man.
Smiling politely to mask a|familiar feeling of desperation
Sarah reminded herself to think|like an anthropologist.
She was a researcher studying the|behavior of typical suburban women.
They weren't organic?
She was not a typical|suburban woman herself.
Troy, stop that!
Paul and I were having|sex the other night
and I drifted off|right in the middle of it.
lt happens.
Yeah, I guess.|But when I woke up and apologized
he said he hadn't|even noticed.
You know what|you should do?
Set aside a specific|block of time for it.
That's what Louis and I do--|every Tuesday night at 9:00.
''Whether you want to or not''|Sarah thought,
her eyes straying over|to the play area.
Even at such a tiny|playground as this
Lucy didn't interact much|with the other children.
Sarah didn't really know why|they even bothered coming here,
except that she'd|probably go crazy
trapped in the house|all day
with this unknowable|little person.
Morning snack time|was 10:30 on the dot...
Snack time!
...a regimen established|and maintained by Mary Ann,
who believed that rigid|adherence to a timetable
was not only the key|to a healthy marriage,
but to effective|parenting as well.
- I'll take this one!|- I want that one!
- Can I do it?|- Yeah. Ready?
Mommy...
where's my snack?
I'm sorry, honey,|Mommy can't find it.
- I forgot the rice cakes.|- Poor thing.
- I'm sure it's in here somewhere.|- Second time this week.
Well, who's going to keep|track of everything?
- Bad mommy. Bad mommy.|- Just calm down, please.
No calm down!|l want my snack!
All right, you know what?|It's--
it's just not here, okay?|See for yourself.
Wait!
Troy, honey,|give Lucy your goldfish.
No!
Troy Jonathan,|give me those goldfish!
But, Mama, they're mine.
No back talk.|You can share with your sister.
Troy has goldfish for you.|Go sit down.
That's much more than 10.
- That's great.|- Look how big I made my lawn.
Thank you, Mary Ann,|you're a life saver.
It's nothing.|l just hate to see her suffer like that.
Maybe you should make|a checklist and tape it to the door
so it's the last thing you|see before leaving the house.
That's what I do.
Yeah, thank you. That's-- that's|a really helpful suggestion.
You're welcome.
Drink your juice.
Are you the plane again?
Look.
Now you have to act like me.
The prom king.
Oh my God,|he's back.
Sarah followed|the other women's gazes
over to the entrance|of the playground,
eager to finally get a glimpse|of the prom king,
the handsome and mysterious|young father
who had been a regular|at the Walker Street playground
for several weeks|this past spring
before abruptly|dropping out of sight.
I don't need a rest.|l need an airplane ride.
His departure had left a gaping|hole in the emotional lives
of Cheryl, Theresa|and Mary Ann.
Barely a day went by without one|of them speculating wistfully
about the reason for his absence|and the likelihood of his return.
Here I come.|There's no room for two of us, diesel.
You've done it again.
I hate steam engines.
When I come back I will|pinch you with my pinchers.
Yeah?|Well, when I come back
I'm gonna ram you|with my rammer.
- Ready?|- No, you won't.
Every time you win,|diesel!
I know.
- Hello!|- Mommy's home.
The jester's cap was something|that truly disturbed Brad.
All day long the boy ate,|played and napped in it.
But the moment his mother stepped in|the house he had no more use for it.
As if the entire day|up to that point
had been a pointless|and somewhat useless charade.
You got some sun|today, didn't you?
Did Daddy forget|the sunscreen again?
What are you doing?
That's his full name.|What's your favorite thing about him?
Um...
I like to come over|to his house.
Hmm.
I think I'm gonna finally break down|and get a cell phone.
- Really?|- Mmm.
Why?
I have no way of reaching you|when I'm out with Aaron.
You're done,|right?
You've got one.
Don't you think it's|strange that I don't?
Yeah, I do.|You just never wanted one before.
Yeah, I know.
There's a family plan.|We can talk for free.
Okay.
Let's just see where we are|at the end of the month.
Yeah?
Are your hands okay?
As was her custom each week|night after dinner,
the boy's mother sent Brad|down to the municipal library
to study for the bar exam.
But he never quite made it through|the door of the building.
Brad had been watching|the skateboarders for weeks now,
sometimes for as long|as an hour at a stretch.
But he never received the slightest|acknowledgement from any of them.
He'd been the same age as these|boys when his mother died.
- You do that!|- No way!
- Nice.|- Hey, that was nice, dude!
''l must have been like this,''|Brad sometimes thought.
''l must have been|one of them.''
Awful.
He should be castrated.
Quick and clean,|just chop it off.
Then you wouldn't have to worry|about notifying the neighbors.
You know what else|you should do?
Nail his penis above the entrance|to the elementary school.
You know, as a warning|to other perverts.
You think|this is funny?
I just can't believe you want to|castrate a man for indecent exposure.
My brother used|to expose himself when--
when we were teenagers.|He'd do it in my bedroom,
he'd do it in the dining room,|he'd do it in the back seat of a car.
He'd always figure out a way to do it so|that nobody could see him except me.
Didn't you|tell anyone?
No, I didn't want|to get him in trouble.
Maybe he should|be castrated.
It's not the same thing.|He wasn't doing it to strangers.
Oh my God, there he is.
After all this time,|two days in a row.
Where's the fire?
Maybe he needed a vacation.
From what?
From being|the prom king.
It's a dirty job,|but someone's gotta do it.
- Close it?|- Close it.
Close the gate.|There you go.
- It's open.|- It's all right.
- Somebody else will close it.|- Are we practicing?
Are we playing|up on the swings?
Swing time!
What's he do for a living?
We've never actually|spoken to him.
Really?
We don't even|know his name.
I thought you guys said|he was a regular here.
- It was awkward.|- He made us nervous.
You had to think about what you|were gonna wear in the morning.
You know, put on makeup.|lt was exhausting.
Mommy, push me!
Okay.|I'll be right there.
Wait!
Five bucks if you get|his phone number.
How old is she?
Lucy,
tell the nice boy|how old you are.
I'm three.
My grandma|lives in New Jersey.
She doesn't have|a swim pool.
Do you like to swim?
I don't like sharks.|They eat you up.
Don't listen to him.
We go to the town pool|almost every day.
- I'm Brad, by the way.|- Sarah.
You guys come|here a lot?
No, just the last|few weeks.
I usually go to the one|over on Harris,
with the big wood things,|you know, and the slide across.
Yeah, we actually rent a house|right around the corner
from there on Ashforth.
That ice cream truck never leaves.|Such a nightmare.
Yeah, tell me about it.
You know, you're the first person|here who's ever talked to me.
You make 'em nervous.
Oh, right.
I guess they don't see too many fathers|here during the weekdays.
You don't have to be polite.|Go ahead and ask.
What?
You know, what the person who wears the|pants in the family does for a living.
Oh. All right,|what does your wife do?
- She makes documentaries.|- Oh, wow.
- Like Michael Moore?|- Uh, like PBS.
Oh.
Well, I think it's|admirable you're here.
There's no reason fathers|can't be primary caregivers.
I finished law school|two years ago,
but I can't seem to pass the bar exam.|Failed it twice now.
Maybe you just don't|want to be a lawyer.
I'll take the test|one more time.
lf I mess up now
I'll just have to find something else|to do with my life.
- Right, buddy?|- Right.
Sarah was shocked by how Brad|delivered this confession,
with no apparent sense of being in the|least bit embarrassed by his failure.
Most men weren't like this.
Her husband Richard|certainly wasn't.
She wondered if Brad was|always this forthcoming.
lf anything,|he seemed a little lonely,
all too ready to open his heart at|the slightest sign of interest,
like a lot of young|mothers she knew.
I couldn't help noticing|your stroller.
Do you have|another child?
No, just Aaron.|Got that at a yard sale.
Extra seat comes in handy|for the bear, though.
Lucy refuses to go|in a stroller or a car seat.
We have to walk everywhere. It takes us|half an hour to go three blocks,
unless I carry her.
- Daddy, I'm finished.|- Are you sure? We just got here.
I'm finished right now.
Okay. All right,|here we go.
Ready?|One, two, three.
- Oops.|- Oh, hold on for a second.
- There, thank you.|- Are you okay?
No problem.
lt was then while watching Brad|kneel down at his son's feet
that Sarah found herself gripped by|an unexpected pang of sadness.
''Don't go,'' she thought.
''Don't leave me here|with the others.''
- It was nice talking to you.|- Same here.
Wait! Um...
Come here. Just...
come here.
You see those women|over there?
Just, yeah, don't--|don't look.
You know what|they call you?
What?
The prom king.
Oh God, really?
Yeah, they mean it|as a compliment.
You're a big character|in their fantasy lives.
Wow.
Um, so one of them bet me $5|l couldn't get your phone number.
Five bucks, huh?
Yeah.
Could we split|it 50-50?
lt could be|arranged.
lt doesn't have to be|your real number.
Oh, well, you know, in that case, sure.|You got a pen?
Great. Oh shit, no l--|um, no I don't.
- Uh...|- Well...
No wait, just--|wait.
You know what'd|really be funny?
lf you gave me a hug.
- You think?|- Yeah.
- Yeah.|- All right, come here.
Oh my God.
Do you want to really|freak them out?
Yeah.
Who's gonna talk in there?
- Oh my God!|- Troy!
- Lucy!|- lsabelle!
lsabelle! Come here, lsabelle.|Okay, we have to go.
- lsabelle!|- Troy!
- I think that worked.|- Yeah, I think so.
- Um, well, it was nice meeting you.|- Yeah.
It's okay, yeah.|We're gonna go.
- It's all right.|- Lucy?
We're gonna go home.
Okay, here we go,|good girl.
Good girl.
I'm sure your daughter|found that very educational.
His name is Brad.|He's a lawyer
and he's really very nice.
For the past few days|Sarah hadn't been able
to concentrate on anything|but the prom king
and the curious thing|that had happened
between them|on the playground.
She didn't feel|shame or guilt,
only a sense of profound|disorientation,
as if she had been|kidnapped by aliens
then released unharmed|a few hours later.
As he had so often|in recent days,
Brad mentally reenacted|the kiss by the swing set.
He still couldn't believe|it had really happened.
And with all those women|and children watching.
Troy! Troy!
Aaron had been particularly|curious about what he'd seen.
Why you hugging|that lady?
Well, that's what|I'm trying to show you with Bozo.
Sometimes it's a game that adults play|to show that they're friends.
You say, ''Hi,|I'm your friend.''
Aaron was skeptical.
They returned to the playground|the following morning,
but no one was there.
Sarah hadn't shown up|at the town pool either,
though Brad remembered telling|her that he and Aaron
could be found there|most afternoons.
lt didn't seem to matter|that Sarah wasn't his type,
wasn't even that pretty--|at least not compared to Kathy,
who had long legs|and lustrous hair
and perfect breasts.
Sarah was short, boyish,
and had eyebrows that were thicker|than Brad thought necessary.
But even so, she'd walked|into his arms that day
as if she were fulfilling|a secret wish
he hadn't remembered|making.
Hey, pervert!
Yeah, you,|you pervert!
You like little|boys, do you?
- Larry?|- Yes, it's fucking Larry!
Jesus, man, don't|even joke about that.
What are you doing?|Are you busy?
Uh, actually I'm|supposed to be studying.
Taking the bar exam|next month.
I thought you|did that last year.
Yeah.|See how well I did?
I got a better idea.|Get in.
Come on. Come on,|come on, come on, come on, come on.
Do you mind holding these?|Try to keep them nice.
Oh, uh...
are you, uh, part|of the committee?
I am the committee.
Wow.
That's-- that's|quite a commitment.
Yeah.
Aren't you full time|on the force already?
Yeah, I'm-- I'm taking|a little time off.
You know what|they should do to this bastard?
Just castrate him.|You know, pfft!
Get it over with,|right?
Yeah.
You look good.
You've been, uh,|working out?
Uh, just push-ups,|crunches...
a little light running.
The guys are|gonna love this.
What guys?
Wow, this is something.
Yeah, it's pretty,|but doesn't have a lot of give.
It's like|playing on cement.
Hey, hold on|a second.
Duane, I've really gotta talk|to you about the committee.
I mean, it would mean a lot to have|your support on this thing.
I told you already, Larry, none of us|are gonna get involved in that shit.
We're here to play ball. lf that's your|thing, fine, but leave us out of it.
Okay okay, fine.|l get it, I get it, I get it. Guys!
Bring it in!
Come on, come on,|hustle up!
I want you all to meet|our new quarterback.
- Quarterback?|- Guy better not be a pussy.
He played in college.
Uh, I'm a little|behind the curve.
Who are you guys?
- We're the Guardians!|- We're cops.
Welcome to the Tri-County|touch football night league.
Let's just work on some|simple pass patterns.
Brad waited for his|good sense to kick in.
There were lots of excuses|available to him.
But it felt so good to be standing here|beneath the bright lights.
And he was filled|with a feeling similar to the one
he'd had right|before kissing Sarah,
like his world had|cracked open
to reveal a thrilling|new possibility.
Okay, just let me|warm up a little.
All right! Let's go!
Set, hut!
What the fuck?
That's a late hit!
This ain't|Pop Warner, ace.
You fucking faggot.|You call yourself a quarterback?
Oh, this isn't me.
What are you doing?
What is that?|What's that for?
I want the scumbag|to know I'm keeping an eye on him.
Oh, shit.|Oh, uh...
I don't think we want|to be here, Larry.
It's not a question|of want.
Joanie thinks I'm|obsessed with this creep.
She thinks if I had a job, I wouldn't|be driving past his house
five, six times a day.|But you know what?
I kinda think|this is my job.
There's a roll of duct tape|in the glove compartment.
Would you grab it for me?
Honey?
Hi!
Where were you?
Oh my God.|What happened?
l-- l-- I joined|this group.
The Committee|for Concerned Parents.
We're distributing flyers about|that creep on Woodward Court.
These guys play a little|touch football after.
This late?
Uh, it's a night league.
So it's gonna be|a regular thing?
No no no no,|just once a week,
after I'm done|studying at the library.
ls that okay?
Uh, who are the guys?
You remember|Larry Hedges?
The guy from the Sprinkler|Park with the twins?
It's his organization.
I thought you|didn't like him.
He's okay.
This committee makes a|lot of sense. I mean it's--
it's pretty scary having|a weirdo like that
living right|by the playground.
Mmm.|l know.
I hate to even|think about it.
Guess you'd better|take a shower.
Brad showered quickly,|sensing a rare opportunity
to have sex with his wife.
''This is just what I need,''|he thought.
''Something to take|my mind off that kiss.''
Please don't.
Come on, Kathy, we've|been through this before.
He needs to start|sleeping by himself.
I know.|He looks so comfy.
Well, he'll be just|as comfy in his own bed.
I just miss|him so much.
I'm getting a little tired waking up|with his foot in my face.
It's a perfect foot.
Look at him.|Just look at him.
He's a handsome devil.
Mmm, he's perfect.
Good night.
Number 2 Hillcrest
was an impressive|piece of real estate.
Even so,|Sarah was ambivalent
about the house|she occupied.
She wasn't involved|with its purchase or design.
The place was a hand-me-down of sorts|from Richard's mother.
And the furnishings|were leftovers from his first marriage.
By the time|Sarah arrived here
Richard wasn't all that|interested in redecorating.
And so she decided|to leave it as it was,
with the exception of a single room|that she staked out for her own
and gradually began|to populate it
with the remnants|of her former self.
From the moment|Lucy was born
Sarah had refused to hire|someone for child care.
Read me a story?
ln a minute,|okay?
- Can I sit on your lap?|- I said in a minute!
Go finish your|program, go.
She wasn't exactly sure|why she had taken this stance.
The truth was she spent|most afternoons marking time,
waiting desperately for the moment|when her husband returned from work
and she could finally|have a moment to herself.
But even this was not|something she could rely on.
You're ready to roll?
Could you wait|a few minutes?
I'm sorry, Richard's barricaded|in the upstairs office
- finishing some stuff for work.|- No problem.
I've got a little surprise|for someone anyway.
She's a terror at night.|l couldn't get her to nap again.
- Oh, the poor thing.|- Poor mom is more like it.
Hello.
ls there a cute little|girl in the house?
Oh, my goodness!
What--
what have I found?
- A beanie.|- Oh, a beanie.
Jean, you didn't|need to to that.
Oh, this little dog needed|a girl to take care of him.
And I know a little girl|who needed a dog.
Let me see.
Sarah was beginning|to get angry.
Her evening fitness walk|was the one thing
she looked forward to all day,|and Richard knew this.
But if there was one thing|life had taught Richard,
it was that it was|ridiculous
to be at war|with your own desires.
He could easily imagine what people|would say if they could see him now--
Exactly the same thing they'd|say if someone had told them
that Ray from next door|was a transvestite,
or that Ted from work
had anonymous gay sex|at highway rest stops.
''But we want what we want,''|Richard thought,
''and there's not much|we can do about it.''
He had stumbled|on the site 11 months ago
while doing research|for a consulting firm.
His office door|was wide open.
But he clicked|on the link anyway.
He was deeply engrossed|in his discovery
when Ted knocked|on his door.
I'm taking lunch orders.|You want something?
Casually, but with great haste
Richard banished Slutty Kay|from his screen...
Uh, yeah, I'll have|a chicken Caesar.
...and reentered the flow|of an ordinary day.
lt wasn't until|several months later
that Richard gave the slightest thought|to the site he had stumbled upon.
Do you need me|for anything else?
Uh, no no, you|can head home.
I'm just gonna catch up|on some e-mail.
Well, don't stay to late.|Your dinner will get cold.
Lately Slutty Kay|had become a problem.
He thought about her|far to often,
and spent hours studying
the thousands of photographs|available to him.
Some of Kay's practices|struck him as bizarre,
even off-putting.
She had a thing|about kitchen utensils,
spatulas, and dressing up|like a little girl
and playing with balloons.
But who was|Richard to judge?
Oh, that's it.
Though as close as Richard|sometimes felt to Slutty Kay,
as much as he believed|that he knew her,
he could never get past|the uncomfortable fact
that she existed for him|solely as a digital image.
The panties were an attempt|to solve this problem.
Maybe a sniff or two|would hurry things along,
so he could get back|downstairs to his real life,
where his wife|was waiting for him
her impatience increasing|by the minute.
What are you doing?
Are you almost finished there? 'Cause|I'd really like to go for my walk?
- You could have knocked.|- I did!
We need to talk.
You're awfully quiet|this evening.
- Everything okay?|- What?
Yeah.
You'll have to walk|without me tomorrow night.
I've got a book|group meeting.
Okay.
You're sure everything's|all right?
Yeah, sorry.
I guess I'm just|a little tired.
So what are|you reading?
''Crime and|Punishment.''
Wow. That's pretty|highbrow for a book group.
Well, we have some|very stimulating discussions.
You should come next month.|We're doing ''Madame Bovary.''
You could be|my little sister.
Little sister?
We're trying to get younger|women involved.
We call them|our little sisters.
I don't know, Jean.
I read ''Madame Bovary''|in grad school.
It's a pretty|misogynist text.
Well, that's an|interesting perspective.
- You should come.|- Let me think about it.
Oh, would you|excuse me, Jean?
Someone's at my door.|I'll call you, okay?
Hi!
Wow, God,
this is a surprise.
I haven't seen|you since--
l-- I hope you don't mind. Your husband|said you'd be back any minute.
Oh, no,|not at all.
It's good|to see you.
God, um, can I get you|some tea or something?
I can only stay a minute.|l just came to warn you.
- You know that guy, the pervert?|- Uh-huh.
He's been riding his|bike near the playground
- checking out the kids.|- Oh, God.
Oh, God,|do the police know?
Nothing they can do.|He's not breaking any laws.
I guess they're just waiting|for him to kill someone.
I just thought|you should know.
Thanks, that's|nice of you.
Let me get|you some tea.
I'm sorry.|l-- I don't think it's a good idea.
I didn't mean|to kiss him.
I don't even know|how it happened.
I'd better go.|Mike's gonna worry.
You wanna talk?
I'm tired.
Hello.
Hey.
No, he's still|sleeping.
Yeah, I'm, uh, I'm going|through it right now.
No, I guess l|don't need them.
Okay.
All right, bye.
H-hi.
H-hello?
Yes, I'd like|to place an order.
Pierce, Sarah,|Mrs.
Um...
it's the red bathing suit|on page 29.
The hide-your-tummy|halter neck.
Uh, I'm size...
10, eight?|l mean, I think.
E-eight.
You want to go|in the pool?
You do?
One, two.
Daddy, can I go|in the pool now?
ln a minute, okay?
Okay.
There you go.
Mommy, I have|to go pee-pee.
Just go in the pool.
Huh-uh, I want|to go to the bathroom.
Really?
Okay, come on.
Okay, ready?
There.
Swing down.
Hey, I'm drumming it.
Oh.
Wow.
- It's you.|- Yeah, hey.
- Hi!|- Okay.
I hope you don't mind.|Lucy has sensitive skin.
She's better off|in the shade.
Oh no,|not at all.
It's nice|to see you again.
Yeah, you too.
I'm sorry,|would you get my back?
Um...|okay, sure.
Thanks.
Right.
## Who is knocking|on the door? ##
- Thanks a lot.|- ## Knocking on the door ##
## Knocking on the door ##
- ## Who is knocking on the door? ##|- It's okay, just...
## A way, hey hey. ##
Lucy, say hi to the little boy|from the playground.
Hi.
You remember him?
The pool became a ritual.
I was trying to think.|l just didn't know the way.
- Oh oh, okay.|- I'm here, I'm here.
We have the creature|and we have flower.
Right.
Day after day they sat|together in the shade
getting to know|each other.
This needs mustard.
- Mustard?|- Yeah.
Having little choice|in the matter,
Aaron and Lucy formed|a fragile friendship.
Aw, that's perfect.
Sometimes Brad and Sarah|traded offspring.
Mama said, ''What Papa|told you was right.
It's not a good idea|to talk to strangers.''
lt was the most fun|Sarah had had in years.
But there was always|that longing to touch,
to be touched by Brad.
And, as badly as|she wanted this,
she wanted just as badly|to hold on to the innocent public life
they'd made for themselves|out in the open.
So she accepted|the trade--
the melancholy|handshake at 4:00
in exchange for this|little patch of grass,
some sunscreen|and companionship.
One more happy day|at the pool.
Okay, no pasta|for dinner, okay?
We eat way too much|pasta around here.
I thought you|liked my pasta.
No, I do.|That's the problem.
Pretty soon I can sell advertising|space on my ass.
No, that's okay.|I've got to go.
I've got|a 9:00 at Taps.
I thought you were|already editing.
Yeah, so did l.|lt was just--
there's something in this|family's story that really got to me.
The father was...
K-l-L-L-E-D
in a, um,|mortar attack,
and, um, left behind|a little boy.
I was talking to the mother the other|day on the phone,
and she was saying she didn't know what|she was going to do next Christmas.
Jeez, I bet.
No, it wasn't like that.|lt was more...
she was wondering, should she keep|this tradition with her son
that began with|the boy's father.
And she was saying|he had this knack
for requesting|odd Christmas gifts--
scuba gear one year
and rappelling gear|the next.
She said he wasn't|afraid to try anything.
Trying new things|made him feel...
more alive.
I've got to go.|See you later.
Patch one of your best|and then we'll patch both of them.
Okay?
Hey, I got something.
Hot enough for you?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's so humid.
I've got football|practice tonight.
Be like playing|in a sauna.
Watch out for|that ltalian guy.
What's his name?
Corrente?
Yeah.
Remember what|happened to your knee last week?
You should be|careful, Brad.
I'll be careful.
Promise?
Yeah.|Yeah, I promise.
Weatherman said|scattered showers.
I don't see|scattered showers.
Mom, could I please|have some money for a snack?
No, sweetheart.|You guys just had a snack. No.
Oh, okay.
All they want is sugar.
Constantly.
Oh, no.
It's him.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh my God,|it's him.
He's in the pool.
Oh my God!
Jacob, get out|of the pool now!
Oh my God.|That's him.
- Get away from that man.|- Why is everybody running to the pool?
Brooke?|Jake?
Dale, you'd better|get over here.
Get out of the pool!
Where's your sister?
Why'd we have to get out, Mom?
I'm scared.
- What did he do?|- What's going on?
Um, why the|police is here?
Um, there's a man over there who|doesn't have a ticket to get in,
so they're asking|him to go home.
Mr. McGorvey.|Mr. McGorvey.
lt'd be wise for you to get|out of the pool at this time.
Did that man|go near you?
You're sure he|didn't touch you?
Step out of|the pool, sir.
I was only trying|to cool off.
All right,|let's go.
You can go back in the pool.
Bear with us, please. You|know what that sounds means.
Let's go. Out of the pool.|We're closing her up. Let's go.
Exit the pool and vacate|the grounds immediately.
Okay, I'll see|you tomorrow.
You're going to carry her?|Come on, put her in the stroller.
No, she won't do the stroller.
- Really?|- No, she will not do this.
Lucy, would you like to go|in the stroller?
Can I interest you in a stroller?|lt appears she'd like a stroller.
It's out of|your way.
No, it's fine.|You don't mind, do you, Aaron?
Run!
You'd better come inside.|You can't walk home in this.
Oh!
- You can put him down in Lucy's room.|- Okay.
This is amazing.
She never naps.
Well, he'll be|out for the next two hours.
We'll have to get him out|of that nightgown, though,
before he wakes up|or he'll never forgive me.
Nice place.
- You think so?|- Yeah.
Well, Richard does|all right for himself.
What's he do, again?
Lies. Um, please have a seat.|Make yourself comfortable.
Better not,|l might ruin your furniture.
I'll put these things in the dryer|and get us some towels.
Okay.
Oh, God!
Do you feel bad|about this?
No, I don't.
I do.
I feel really bad.
Okay.
Son?
Be well.
May knew it wasn't natural
for a grown man|to be living with his mother.
No hobbies,|no diversions.
lt was like he was|still in prison.
What he needed|was a girlfriend,
and May intended to|help him find one.
There are four whole columns|of lonely women here,
and only a handful of men.|The odds are on our side.
Why wouldn't one of|these women want
to meet a nice|person like you?
I'm not|a nice person.
You did a bad thing.
But that doesn't mean|you're a bad person.
I have a psychosexual|disorder.
You're better now.
They wouldn't have let|you out if you weren't.
They let me out|because they had to.
Well, maybe|if you found
a girlfriend closer|to your own age
you wouldn't have|the bad urges so often.
I don't want a girlfriend|my own age, Mommy.
I wish I did.
What are you going|to do when I'm gone?
Who's going to|take care of you?
What's the matter,|Mommy?
Are you sick|or something?
I'm an old woman.|I'm not going to live forever,
Who's going to cook|for you?
Who's going|to wash the dishes?
I can wash|the dishes,
You've never washed|a dish in your life.
I could do it if I had to.|I'm not a retard.
No, you're not.
You're a miracle,|Ronnie.
We're all miracles.
You know why?
Because as humans,
everyday we go|about our business,
and all that time
we know, we all know
that the things|we love,
the people we love...
at any time, it can|all be taken away.
We live knowing that
and we keep|going anyway.
Animals don't do that.
Now I'm not asking you|to get married, Ronnie.
I'm just saying put an ad in the paper,|see what happens.
Fine. I'll do it if|it will make you happy.
But just one date.|All right?
You have a nice smile,|why don't we start with that?
What else?
You always eat what I put in front|of you. You never complain.
You're trying to|get back in shape.
You exercise.
Wait right there,|young man.
lf you're going out|for some exercise,
you can post this now.
Hmm.
Mmm.
Come on.
Let's do it again.
All right.
God, it's hot|as hell up here.
What's wrong with|the laundry room?
No mattress.
Come on.|Lie down.
You're nervous,|aren't you?
What?|What do you mean?
The game.
Don't worry.|You'll be great tonight.
I don't know.|l haven't played in 10 years.
lt used to be|my whole life.
Then when I stopped,|l just...
stopped. I didn't|even miss it.
Now that I'm playing|again, l....
feel l--
I don't know.
You feel alive.
Yeah.
That's good.
That's how you're|supposed to feel.
You're right.
I guess it's just|been awhile.
Yeah.
Shake.
- Call it.|- Heads.
Heads it is.
Ready?
- Hello?|- Hi, Mom. Did I wake you?
Oh, no honey.|ls everything okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You don't|sound fine.
No, there's nothing wrong.|l just wanted to say hi.
Well, hi.
Hi.
So how's my|little guy?
He's great.|He's sleeping right here next to me.
He's such|a cutie.
So where's Brad?
Brad's out.
Oh, I'm surprised|the library stays open this late.
Well, he's not|at the library.
He's playing football|with some buddies.
Oh, honey. Do you remember when|your father took up golf?
He's not|like dad.
Honey, they're|all the same.
Well, he's not.
You work so hard.
Now listen...
I could keep an eye|on the boys when you're at work;
make sure they're|staying out of trouble.
- Do you want me to come up for a visit?|- No no, Mom, don't come.
Well, honey, I worry|about you kids.
Now what are you going to do if he|fails the test again?
He's not going|to fail the test.
Oh, honey,|that's what you said last time.
Now how are you|doing for money?
We're fine.
I'm going to send you a little|extra this month.
- Mom...|- Honey, it's no burden.
- Mom... Mom, please.|- I'm happy to help.
Aw, shit.
Although the Guardians|lost by 26 points,
Brad felt oddly exhilarated in the bar|after the game.
He could feel a new respect|in the way the cops looked at him.
- What you drinking, buddy?|- He wasn't on probation anymore.
He was a member|of the team.
lce and Advil.
lf all else fails, you can always see|the team physician,
Dr. Daniels.|All his friends call him Jack.
- To the good doctor.|- Hear, hear.
- Larry? Here, you go Larry.|- Oh, thanks.
Let me just|grab a chair.
Oh, we just gave you a shot.|We just gave you a shot.
I had no business being|on that field tonight.
I let you down.
I let the whole|team down.
I'm slow and|I'm fat.
I let that guy|piss all over me.
Come on. That guy was offsides|the whole night.
Joanie left me.
Took the kids and went|to her mother's.
Jesus, Larry,|that's a tough break.
Oh, I deserved it.
Me and my big mouth.
I called her|a fucking whore,
right in front|of the kids.
Why did you do that?
Huh,|l don't know.
I was in a bad mood|or something.
Now I'm fucked.
Hey, did you hear|about the pervert?
He went swimming|at the town pool.
- What?|- Yeah.
- Who told you that?|- Nobody. I saw it myself.
- The town pool?|- Yeah, during the heatwave.
- The town pool?|- Yep.
Th-that place is|crawling with kids.
I mean, my boys|go there.
Yeah, well, you know what,|it was just that one time.
Um, he-- he won't be back.|The cops came.
Cops? What cops?|Anyone from the team?
Uh, no.
You sure?
- Anyone from the team show up there?|- No no.
- Yes or no!|- I'm saying no.
- No, nobody...|- Jesus Christ,
that little fucking weasel.
Larry, slow down.
Slow down, Larry!
- What now?|- Good evening, Mrs. McGorvey.
We were wondering|if Ronnie was home.
You leave him alone.
We just want a little|moment of his time. Just a little chat.
This is my house.|l pay the mortgage,
and I say who is|and isn't--
Yoo-hoo, Ronnie!
- Get your perverted ass down here now.|- I'm calling the police.
I hear they're well-disposed|to child molesters.
It's okay, Mommy.|Can I help you, gentlemen?
Ronnie, you go|on upstairs.
Larry, let him go. I think he gets|the point. We can go home now.
You listen to me, you|little piece of shit.
You stay the fuck away|from the town pool.
- You hear me?|- You're a bully!
My Ronnie would|never do what he did.
That poor child|at the mall--
what you did to him.
Larry?
Why did she|say that?
Oh, don't pretend you|don't know about me.
Everybody knows.|Everybody!
Look, h-honestly,|l-- I don't know anything.
I remember hearing|something...
a few years ago|when we first moved here, but--
something about|a-- a shooting
at the mall.
That's-- that's it.|That's all.
I didn't even|know you then.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Dispatch said there|was a shooter loose at the mall.
lt was 10 minutes|from the end of my shift.
10 minutes and there would have|been someone else.
I can still see that|boy's face staring up at me.
Yeah, but--|but it was an accident.
You were trying|to stop a guy,
and the-- the boy|g-got caught
in the crossfire,|right?
No, I panicked.
There was no shooter.
Just the boy.
Antoine Harris|was his name.
He was big for his age,|only 1 3 years old.
He was a good kid.|Thought it was a joke,
waving around an air gun|at his friend
in the Big 5.
They were acting out some scene|from some movie they liked.
Shop girl saw it|from across the way,
called 911.
Jesus, that's terrible.
That...
well, you didn't know.
lt could have|been real.
But it wasn't.
His parents...
uh, his parents--
I had to...
I was diagnosed with post-traumatic|stress syndrome
by three different|psychiatrists.
That's why I retired.
I couldn't do|the job anymore.
- So why don't you do something else?|- Like what?
Drive a forklift|at Costco?
Maybe you could|go back to school.
I loved my job.
I don't wanna do|anything else.
You ever think about the term|''homeland security''?
I mean,|really think about it?
The day that|you found out
that your father had|been killed in lraq,
do you remember|that day?
Can you talk|about that?
You feel comfortable|talking about that?
After the men came
to tell my mom,
I cried,
but she didn't.
She just went up|to her room
and grabbed the pillows|off the bed,
cut the tops off of them|with a pair scissors.
There were feathers|all over the place.
That must have really|frightened you.
No, she was trying|to find the crown.
The crown?
The crown you leave|in your pillow
when you've slept on it|for a long time.
My--
my father had|two crowns.
Stop there.
- You hungry?|- No.
Mind if I get|some lunch?
No, go ahead.
Brad?
Honey, you there?
Pick up.|l know you're there.
It's Aaron's nap time.
Okay, I guess you guys|are out somewhere.
Um...
I love you both.
Bye.
I certainly did.
Here we go.
I don't know, Jean.|l don't think I'm up for this.
Well, now don't|be silly.
- lt'll be fun.|- Really?
You're not the only|little sister here tonight.
- Oh, that's good.|- Oh!
Hi, would you|like a glass?
Did anybody like this book?|Because I really just hated it.
It's so depressing.
She cheats on her husband|with two different guys,
wastes all his money,|then kills herself with rat poison?
Do I really need|to read this?
Well, there is a lot|of good descriptive writing.
It's supposed|to be depressing.
It's a tragedy.
Madame Bovary was undone|by a tragic flaw.
What's her flaw?
Blindness.|She didn't see
that the men were|just using her.
She just wants|a little romance in her life.
- You can't blame her for that.|- It's about women's choices.
Back then, a woman|didn't have a lot of choices.
You could be a nun|or a wife.
- That's all there was.|- Or a prostitute.
She had a choice.
She had a choice not|to cheat on her husband.
I found it refreshing|to read about a woman
reclaiming her sexuality.
ls that a nice way|of saying she's a slut?
Madame Bovary's|not a slut.
She's one of the great|characters in Western literature.
I was a little puzzled|by some of the sexual references.
Look,|like this one.
Um...
''He abandoned|every last shred
of restraint|and consideration.
He turned her|into something compliant,
something corrupt.''
Does anyone know|what that means?
lt means|she's a slut.
ls he tying her up
or something?
Anal sex.
Mm-hmm.|Mm-hmm.
Did everyone get that|but me?
Let's set that aside|for now.
I'm really eager|to hear what
our other little sister|has to say.
I'm not sure if you know this,|but Sarah has a PhD
in English lit.
Just a masters.
I never wrote|my dissertation.
Well, you still have|a lot more expertise
than the rest of us.
I think I understand|your feelings about this book.
I used to have some|problems with it myself.
When I read it|in grad school,
Madame Bovary just|seemed like a fool.
She marries|the wrong man,
makes one foolish mistake|after another.
But when I read it this time,|l just fell in love with her.
She's trapped.
She has a choice. She can either|accept a life of misery
or she can struggle|against it.
And she chooses|to struggle.
Some struggle--|hop into bed
with every guy|who says hello.
Well, she fails in the end, but there's|something beautiful
and even heroic|in her rebellion.
My professors would|kill me for even thinking this,
but...
in her own|strange way,
Emma Bovary|is a feminist.
Oh, that's nice.
So now cheating on your husband|makes you a feminist?
No no no.
It's not the cheating.|It's the hunger.
The hunger|for an alternative,
and the refusal to accept|a life of unhappiness.
Maybe I didn't|understand the book.
She just looks|so pathetic.
ls she pretty?
Who?
Your wife.
Degrading yourself|for nothing.
It's a simple question.
She's pretty, okay?|Do we have to talk about this now?
I mean, did she really think a man like|that was gonna run away with her?
Possibly.
How pretty is she?
A knockout.
Beauty's overrated,|Sarah.
Brad had meant this|to be comforting.
But at 3:00 in the morning, it had|precisely the opposite effect.
He had a beautiful wife,
a knockout, and she was sleeping|beside him right now.
Only someone who took|his own beauty for granted
would have been able|to say something so stupid
and with a straight face.
Weekends were difficult|for Sarah.
48-hour prison stretches
separating one happy blur|of weekdays
from the rest.
I'm going to the ocean.
- You are?|- I'm going to the ocean.
ls he doing|his ocean dance?
Sarah sometimes let herself|be carried away by fantasies
of a future very different from the life|she was living now,
in which she and Brad were|free to love each other
in broad daylight;
where they had no one|to answer to
but each other.
lt could happen,|she thought. It had to,
because she wasn't sure she|could keep living like this
for very much longer.
Open your mouth again.
No, I don't want to.
May your mouth|be open.
May your mouth.
This is coming|into your mouth.
Open your mouth,|little fishy.
Hungry, hungry.
Little fishy|is not hungry?
You okay?
Yeah, fine.
- How about you?|- Great.
So how was|your weekend?
You really wanna know?|lt sucked.
How was yours?
Terrible.
- Really?|- Yeah.
Yeah, we went to the beach|and all Kathy and I did
was argue|the whole time.
Oh, you did?
Yeah, it was our|annual argument
over taking|the bar exam,
like our whole life|depends on it.
Get it over with.|You'll feel better.
It's this whole thing.
Gotta take a train|on Wednesday.
It's a two-day ordeal.
I'm not even|gonna pass.
- You'll be fine.|- No.
No, I won't.
I haven't cracked|a book all summer.
I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Don't-- don't do it.
- What?|- The test.
- Oh.|- Blow it off.
We should go somewhere,
just for a night,|you know?
Richard's out|of town till Friday,
and I'm sure I can get|a sitter for Lucy.
No, I can't do that.
I gotta take the test.
That's good.
- Looks good?|- Yeah.
Well, I have a good|feeling about this whole thing.
ln fact, I think I'm gonna go buy|a bottle of champagne
and put it in the fridge,|and we can open it to celebrate
when we get|the good news.
Don't get your hopes up.
We've been|through this before.
Huh-uh. This time's|gonna be different.
I can feel it.
Can you believe it?|This is our first date.
Like a date, you know,|without the kids, I mean.
How was Lucy?|Did she cry or anything?
No, are you kidding?
With Jean there, she|just about shoved me out the door.
I thought we could make something|really beautiful.
I have so|many things here.
We could make...
a picture frame.
Or a jewelry box.
Or a hat.
Something for my mommy.
Okay.
- Stop it, stop it.|- No, Ronnie.
Ron-- Ron-- Ronnie,|just hold on.
Now there.
You look handsome.|She won't be disappointed.
Wait'll she hears|about my criminal record.
I don't think you need|to get into that just yet.
Why don't you stick|to small talk?
What if someone|recognizes me?
That's highly unlikely.|l made the dinner reservation
at a restaurant over|in Haverhill.
Sheila.
- Sheila.|- Yeah.
Something wrong|with the food?
No, it's fine.
Back at the house you|mentioned you were on medication.
- What kind?|- All kinds.
Mostly psychotropic.
So you had some kind|of a breakdown?
Mm-hmm, my junior year|in college.
You were that young?
What happened?
I don't really know.
Well, nervous breakdowns|don't just come out of nowhere.
Something must have|caused it.
I guess.
But I was fine before|l left for college.
I don't know.|Maybe it was the stress
of being on my own.
Maybe it's a chemical|imbalance in my brain.
Every psychiatrist I go to|has a different opinion.
This one guy, Dr. Faris,
he said I must have been|sexually abused as a child.
When I told him|l wasn't,
he said I must be|repressing the memory.
Right, um, so what|happened after that?
Did you drop out|of school?
Not right away.
My mother wanted me|to go
to the campus|counseling center.
And they wanted|the problem fixed, like I could just
snap my fingers and everything|would be okay again.
Yeah, I know|all about that.
You do?
Yes, I do.
So they said|l could leave school
and get married and have lots of kids|like my sisters,
and I can't take care|of kids.
I can't even take care|of myself
most of the time.|Besides, who's gonna marry me?
You're not so bad.
What?
You're--|you're not so bad.
I haven't had|a real boyfriend in six years,
not since my second|breakdown.
I had this thing happen|on a Greyhound bus.
- I was--|- Do you want me to wrap that up?
Oh, no, thank you.
No, wrap it up, please.|I'll take it home.
Folks gonna want dessert?
What do you say, Sheila?|You wanna share something sweet?
Let's make a little stop.
Take the next left.
Turn off the lights.
I had|a nice time tonight.
The last guy|l went out with,
you know what he did?
He ditched me.
He got up to go|to the men's room,
never came back.
Stuck me with the check.
Never said goodbye.
Never called|to apologize.
He wasn't my type anyway.|He was a big-shot CPA.
Super normal guy.|Didn't want to be dating some psycho.
But you seem like|a nice person.
Better not tell on me.
You hear me?
You better not tell,|or I'll fucking get you.
Hold on, Mom.|Hold on, Dad.
You should park the car|on the escalator, and back...
- So?|- What?
- Up, down and then up.|- Test, dummy. How'd it go?
lt was all right.
You didn't call home|last night.
I was worried.
Go on the escalator.
Guess I could really use|that cell phone.
- Well, look who's back.|- Oh, hi.
Hi, Jean.
Thanks.
You're a lifesaver.
So how was|your old roommate?
Oh, great.
Yeah, thanks for doing this|on such short notice.
Let me give you something|for your time.
That's not necessary.
No, really.|l insist.
Please don't.
Okay.
Uh, any calls?
Nope,|it was very quiet.
She's asleep on your bed.|lt was a very busy day.
That's great.
Um, Jean,|is everything okay?
Yeah, she's|a wonderful child.
Mommy.
Mommy!
Yeah.
Are you coming?
- I have something.|- What?
I have something|for you.
Just give me|a second here, okay?
Brad.
Hmm.
Aaron's been telling me|about his new friend Lucy.
She sounds like|a sweet little girl.
What's her mother like?
Nice enough, I guess.
I can't even|remember her name.
lsn't it Sarah?
Sarah?
Yeah, Sarah,
from the pool.
Her daughter's name|is Lucy.
Oh, Lucy's mom.|Yeah, I forgot. That's right.
Her name is Sarah.
Hmm.
Yeah, it might be|really nice for Aaron
if they came over|for dinner.
Okay.
So you're|in advertising?
No, that's-- that's|a common misconception.
I'm not in advertising.|I'm in branding.
And that's very different.
Richard's pretty high up|in the company.
Yeah yeah,|l have these clients
and they'll come to me|when they have,
you know, a new product|they wanna sell.
Like, um, these guys,|they were in a couple weeks ago.
They're trying to open this chain|of Chinese restaurants, right?
They're talking to me|and l-- I look down at the table
and I realize that none|of these guys were Chinese.
Where were they from?
They're a bunch of fat cats|from Tennessee.
They think they can start a chain|of Chinese restaurants good enough
to fool the average|American boob.
Oh, God.
Mmm!
- This is delicious.|- lsn't it?
Brad's a fantastic cook.
So you guys see these|fliers with the guy's face
plastered all over|our village?
Lots of Sturm und Drang|in our quiet little town, huh?
Yeah, it's crazy.
What I want to know is why they let|a creep like that out of prison.
Some of the people|going after him are just as crazy.
- What do you mean?|- Well, just today I heard that
some nut's been spray-painting|the poor guy's house,
lighting fires on his porch.|God knows what else.
- Do they know who's doing it?|- Huh-uh.
They think|it's some ex-cop.
You know, that guy|who killed that kid at the mall.
Yeah, I don't think|it's him.
You're biased.|You're friends with the guy.
Brad's on that Committee|of Concerned Parents
with him.
I didn't know|you were on that.
I play on his|football team.
He asked me to distribute|some fliers.
He's on your team.
You never told me that.
Yeah.
You know what's weird?|I've never even seen this McGorvey guy.
- We did.|- No, we didn't.
Not you.|Me and Brad.
That day at the pool,|remember?
Yeah, l-l|totally forgot.
- Well, what happened?|- Sexual tension is an elusive thing,
but Kathy had|pretty good radar for it.
lt was like someone had|turned a knob a hair to the right,
and the radio station|clicked in so loud and clear
it almost|knocked her over.
Once she became aware|of the connection between them,
it seemed impossible that|she'd missed it before.
On a hunch,|Kathy dropped her fork
in the hopes that|while retrieving it
she would catch Sarah|and Brad playing footsie,
- but she was mistaken.|- Asked him to leave, and he left.
But you know what?|He didn't look scary, right? I mean--
No, it-- it wasn't that big|of a deal, you know.
- No, he's like a regular guy, you know?|- Yeah, I mean--
Kathy, are you okay?
Uh, yeah.
Just a sec.
Brad had convinced|himself
the dinner party|had gone well.
That he and Sarah had managed|to put Kathy's suspicions to rest,
at least temporarily.
She certainly hadn't|accused him of anything,
or behaved in a way|that made him think
she'd noticed|anything untoward.
I'm really glad|they came over.
- Good night.|- Good night.
Two days later, however,
his mother-in-law showed up|for a surprise visit...
- Thank you, John.|- ...of ominously indeterminate length.
And from that moment on,|she accompanied Brad
and Aaron everywhere:
To the playground;
- We need some butter.|- To the supermarket;
And to the town pool.
Hi, Aaron.
Hi, Lucy.
The worst of it|was the pool.
Nevertheless,|after threatening all week
to go the football game,|Brad's mother-in-law decided against it
at the last minute.
- So are you coming?|- Well, I'd like to,
but I'm a little tired.
You sure?|You're welcome to.
No, go ahead.|You and Aaron
sure kept me hopping|this afternoon.
Looks like|you're on your own.
Oh, that's my ride.
- What time are you gonna be home?|- I don't know.
Pretty late, though.
Be careful and stay|out of trouble.
Winds whisper|of high hopes,
victory is in the skies.
One joins with many|on the summer's green field.
At 0 and 5, the Guardians|were the basement dwellers
of the Tri-County|Touch Football Night League.
The Controllers, a team of young|hotshots from the financial district
were 4 and 1|with an explosive offense
that regularly racked up|40 to 50 points a game.
But from|the opening kickoff,
this ragtag group|of law enforcement officers
decided to crunch|their own numbers.
But the Controllers|scored first
after recovering|a Bart Williams fumble
deep in Guardians' territory near|the end of the second quarter.
The Guardians evened things up early|in the second half...
moving methodically|downfield
on an 80-yard|touchdown drive.
The Controllers regained the lead|with a fourth quarter field goal.
With less than a minute|to go, trailing by three,
the Guardians faced|the extinction of their hopes.
- Down!|- It was their last chance--
4th and 5|on their own 35.
Set!
Hut, hut!
Yeah yeah yeah!
Yeah yeah!
Yeah!
Oh my God!
Brad, Brad!
What do you want?
Everyone is waiting for us at the bar.|Are-- are-- are you coming?
Why don't you go on ahead?|I'll catch up later.
You're gonna come, right?|l mean, we gotta celebrate.
Yeah yeah yeah,|I'll be there.
- You promise?|- Jesus, Larry, I just told you.
- Well, you got a ride?|- Yeah.
Okay.
I'll have a cold one|waiting for you.
Larry, you have|to go home now.
Just give me five more minutes.|He promised he was coming.
I don't care what he promised,|l want to lock up.
Now get your butt|out of here!
Now!
When I looked up there|and saw you it was just...
wow... wow.
Thank God you came.
I don't want|to go home.
I want to stay|right here forever.
No, I do.|For the first time in my life
I feel like anything is possible.|Like I can do anything, you know?
What are we doing?
What do you mean?
It's not real, Brad.
What?
This. It's wrong|and it's weird.
How long are we|gonna sneak around together?
How long can that last?|l can't do this anymore.
No, no don't|say that.
As long as I know that|we're gonna have this--
Have what?
What is this?
Look...
if that dinner at your house|was any indication,
you seem pretty happy|with your wife.
You know, you have|a perfect life
- and I don't wanna to be the--|- Okay, stop stop stop.
Run away with me.
What?
You don't mean that.
You believe in me.
Come on.
We'll go away,|figure this thing out.
It's not weird.
The kids are comfortable|with each other.
I know there's more|to it than that, but...
let's do this.
Please.|Please, Sarah.
Oh my God.
You really mean|it, don't you?
Yes.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.|Yes!
Yes!|Okay, yes.
Fucking Brad, I'm so|sick of hearing about Brad.
I'm fucking over it.
I don't even like him.|He's a loser.
''Brad made|the fucking touchdown.''
Yeah, you know why|he hasn't the balls to show up here?
'Cause I fucking made the block.|It's bullshit.
That's why he's not even here,|he's fucking embarrassed to see me.
I don't even like anybody|in this fucking town.
Wake up, wake up!
Wake up, Woodward Court!
Okay, I'm awake.
Open your eyes! Get your goddamn heads|out of the sand!
My heads?|My goddamn heads?
Don't you people|love your children?
Don't you want|to protect them from evil?
Woodward Court,|there's a pervert in your midst!
There's a goddamn|pervert in your midst!
Open your eyes!|Protect the children!
Save the children!
Wake up|and see the grass!
- Just stay inside, Ronnie.|- Save the children!
Open your goddamn eyes!
Wake up and save|your children!
You dirty son of a bitch!|Get off my lawn!
Who the hell do you think you are,|Mr. High and Mighty?
No perverts|in Woodward Court!
You think you're God?|Far from it!
I don't think I'm God!|l never said I was!
You murderer, you|killed the boy.
I didn't murder anyone. Now why don't|you go back inside, put some clothes on?
You shot him through the neck.|l read it in the paper.
- No perverts in--|- You son of a bitch. Give me that.
Hey hey!
Give me that!|You're--
- You need to go home.|- The police are coming.
I mean, you're|scaring my kids.
Your kids need|to be frightened!
They live across|the street from a pervert!
Ow! Oh!
Oh my God, Mrs. McGorvey.|Are you okay?
May. May!
May-- I think we should|call an ambulance.
Karen, call an|ambulance, right now!
- I'm doing it!|- Oh, fuck.
- May!|- This is all I need.
Excuse me, Mr. McGorvey,|we need to ask you some questions.
$14.35.
The Fed continuing its|campaign against inflation
by raising short-term interest rates|for the 10th time yesterday.
Usually there is a correlation between|inflation and gold prices.
Let's take you over|to our stocks desk...
Cafe con leche?
Thank you.
Kim Bryson, please call|the operator.
Madre.
Me too.|She's resting.
Get down, knock it off!
Quiet.
Bring him around.
It's all yours.
Mr. McGorvey.
I'm afraid we|have some bad news.
Do you have a mortuary|to make arrangements for you?
It's not a problem. The hospital has|a list that I can provide you with.
Here's what's|going to happen:
Your mother's body|will remain in her bed
for up to three hours.
Three hours is typical.
But if there's a request for more time,|depending on our occupancy,
that's usually|not a problem.
lf there's anyone|you need to call--
family, friends--
they're welcome to full|bedside visitation privileges
before the body is taken|downstairs
to be prepped|for transport.
Do you have any questions|that come to mind?
Anything I can|help you with?
- No.|- Okay.
I'd like to remind you to take your|mother's personal belongings with you
before you leave|the hospital today.
And all I need from you now
is to sign this release-|of-remains form.
Aaron.
Hey hey, buddy.
Can you wake up?
Could you take your|hat off for me?
Just for a second.
Are you mad|at me, Daddy?
No.|No no no, not at all.
I just want you to know
that I love you very much,
and I would never do|anything to hurt you, okay?
Okay.
Now you can go|back to sleep.
Lucy, come on.
Let's go.
I will not go|in the car seat!
- You have to go in the car--|- I will not go in the car seat!
Yes, you will!
- You will go in the car seat.|- No, I won't!
Yes, you will.|Go in the car seat.
I will not go|in the car seat!
Okay, just...
you don't have to|go in the car seat.
You can just go here.|No, actually...
go on the floor.|Okay.
Okay, go down on the floor.|You have to stay down, okay?
Mommy is gonna get arrested.|Just stay down, okay?
Okay.
Mommy, I want to go home.
Yeah, in a minute,
as soon as Brad gets here.
Hello?
Ronnie?
Oh my God.
- Are you all right?|- Yeah! Let's do it. Let's go!
Hey, dude!
What's the hurry?
Yeah! Oh!
- This is so sick.|- Damn.
- Nice.|- Oh, man.
Yeah, man.
- How about you take a run?|- What?
Yeah, give it a shot.|See what happens.
You guys are crazy,|l can't do that.
It's not about that,|it's about skating.
Whoo!
Come on.|Come on.
Do you need help?
She's g-- gone.
She's gone.
Who?|Who's gone?
Mommy.|Mommy's gone.
l...
I'm sorry.
She loved me.
She's the only one.
Mommy died.
Lucy?
Lucy! Lucy!
Lucy!
Get in the car seat!|Get in the car seat!
It's okay, Mommy.
Lucy.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Would you like|to go home?
Yeah?
Brad.
Brad, can you hear me?
D-- don't move.|The ambulance is on its way.
Jesus.
What happened to me?
These kids say you've been|out cold for the last five minutes.
- You almost had it.|- Dude, you were awesome.
- That shit was gnarly, son.|- Back up, back up! Give him some space.
You just hold still, all right?|Hold still.
Hey, bro!
Here, this fell|out of your pocket.
I don't need it anymore.
- Hey, Duane.|- Hm?
Could you call my wife?
You got it, buddy.
Here we go.
I'm so sorry, Ronnie.
I really am.
I never wanted anything|like this to happen.
Are-- are you--|are you okay?
- Oh, no!|- Gonna be good now.
Oh my God!
Hold on, Ronnie.
You hold on.
I'm not gonna let|anything happen to you.
You hold on there,|okay, buddy?
ln his wildest dreams
Larry would never have imagined|he'd once again be in this position,
where precious|minutes count.
Tonight he could|save a life.
He knew Ronnie had done|some bad things in the past,
but so had Larry.
You couldn't|change the past.
But the future could|be a different story.
And it had|to start somewhere.