I can't think straight
Please, be very careful.
Hello?
We could just elope, you know.
But then you wouldn't get to see me
dressed like an extra of "Dynasty"
So much to do...
Your hair looks perfect madam.
When I want your opinion
I'll give it to you.
Madam?
That one.
Thank you, madam.
I need a cigarette.
Are you busy?
Almost...
I'm working.
20 minutes before our engagement
party starts?
Where is my husband?
In the garden, madam.
And where is my coffee?
Coming, madam.
Did the dress fit Tala?
She didn't stop eating at lunch.
Like a glove, madam.
I love you...
Bye Tala.
Bye.
And, Lamia? Did you take in her clothes?
By two centimeters, madam.
Excelent.
Let's hope this is the final engagement party
your father has to go through for your sister
For a man of his statute to endure the shame...
How do I look?
You could cover your shoulders
a little more.
It's not cold.
It's not proper.
Did Zina like the green dress I picked for her?
She loved it, madam.
"Wear this, no black for your
sister's party. Mama"
The cake, how does the cake look?
Careful!
It looks perfect, madam.
Just perfect.
Amman, Jordan
She'll do it before dinner.
No way, Tala loves her food too much.
The last time she broke the engagement before dinner.
And the first time
she waited till Reema had a mouthfull of coffee.
I just hope she keeps the jewelry this time
8 karats, D flawless.
Who wouldn't?
Tala never keeps the jewelry.
She's always had a screw loose.
And how is my favourite niece?
Dear Ramzi.
Hello.
You managed to get on a plane?
Plane?
You know i'll never get on a plane
not after that dream I...
The crash... the devastation...
The dream was in 1967...
Right after the 6 day war.
Israel has a lot to answer for.
Anyway, i wouldn't have missed it.
I wanted to meet the man who made
it this far, again.
Ammo, I love him.
Of course you love him,
he's christian and he's rich.
Not to mention kind, thoughtful
and foreward-thinking...
and handsome.
Handsome is good.
But ask your aunty why she married me.
Looks and character come and go...
only large sums of money last forever.
So it would seem.
You look amazing, sweetheart.
Wish I could say the same.
That's because i've been alone with
mum and Lamia for four whole days.
You know,
I think I found those weapons
of mass destruction Bush was looking for
How clever of him to disguise them
as to arab housewives.
Zina, that dress looks beautiful on you.
Mama said you should be entertaining your guests.
Yeah, Tala.
Surely you should be familiar with
engagement parties etiquette by now...
She looks so happy, doesn't she, Reema?
Of course.
And beautiful.
Just like her mother.
No, no, no. No I don't think so.
I understand what you're saying but I think that
10 procent
is the maxim you can expect of that...
Don't worry, we'll talk tomorrow. Goodbye.
I thought you'd gone for the day.
The printer's not working at home.
What are you printing?
Umm, just some bits and pieces.
Come on. Come on.
Sit down.
You have a minute don't you?
All this is going to be yours one day, you know?
All of it?
And your sister's.
But sales are everything.
They're the life blood of this place.
You know I'm not good at selling, dad.
You don't sell life insurance...
I know, I know...It sells itself.
Life insurance is a sure bet.
I just ask my client:
"Do you know you're going to die?"
There is only one answer.
Then I ask him:
"Are you 150% absolutely positively happy
that your wife and your kids are
properly taken care of?"
You've got him.
Come on, try it.
Dad...
Oh, come on. I'm your client.
Try it.
I'm sorry, dad.
I'm good with the admin,
and Yasmin's better with people...
She's a waitress.
She's learning so she can start her own food company.
Three years at university so she can wash dishes.
She doesn't need her own company
she has her own company.
I have a date with Ali tonight.
I like him. He's a good boy.
Are you going to the mosque first?
We're heading into town to see a friend of his,
then we're having dinner.
It's Friday.
I believe in our religion, I do, I just...
I don't like to get on when everyone else does.
If you don't go when everyone else does,
how will they know you're a good muslim?
Go on then, but don't be out too late.
I'm not 16, dad.
I know...
So she's palestinian, your friend?
Yes, she lives in London but her
wedding will be back in Jordan
where I was for her engagement party.
You remember?
What does Tala do?
Think she has some of her grandfather's spirit in her.
You know she's recently bought a company over here
For an arab woman from her background
that's pretty unusual.
What's the matter? Are you nervous?
A bit.
I'm always like that with new people
Don't be. Tala's great.
Trust me you'll love her.
Evening.
How long have you and Ali been dating?
About two months.
And? Does he want to marry you?
I think he's just waiting for me to ask him.
Tala, my eldest daughter is
getting married in six weeks.
And what does your father do?
Stop interrogating the
poor girl, mama. - Hey...
She's going out with Ali.
Not me.
Tala, meet Leyla.
Hello
Sorry to break your british reserve,
but we always kiss in Jordan.
Usually just before we slit your throat.
When are you going to stop criticizing our homeland, Tala?
When everyone else stops being afraid to.
How do you and Ali know each other?
He went to school with my third fiancé.
They were at Cornell together.
She's had four, you know.
Fiancés I mean.
Four?
She's still picky.
I always liked Namir.
Mama...
He was a drug addict.
He's from a very respectable family.
Yeah, and during our engagement party
I caught him with white powder on his nose.
You always jump to conclusions.
Maybe he was trying to hide a skin blemish.
He had some  pock-marks on one side of his face.
Tala, I've just had your wedding dress taken in.
COngratulations on your wedding.
Will it be in a mosque?
A church.
A church...
Not all arabs are muslims.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have assumed...
Are you a muslim?
Yes.
Why?
Tala, what kind of question is that?
Because she was born a muslim.
No, she wasn't.
Weren't you?
She was born a female and a member
of a certain race and...
if she'd been adopted by a jewish
family she'd've been jewish.
Thank God she wasn't adopted.
What the Middle East doesn't need is more jews.
Mama, please don't start with the anti-Semitism.
Anti-Sematic? Who's Anti-sematic?
I am semity, that's the point.
And yet the israelies grid Palestine from us.
And arab countries throw out
over a million a year of jews.
But the israeli should be fair to the  palestinians.
They know what it's like to lose their land.
Now someone's speaking sense.
True. But we need to draw a line
under the past and look forward
Your headache medicine, madam.
I don't have a headache.
But it's seven o'clock, madam.
Well, then I haven't adjusted to London time, yet.
Nice to have met you.
I apologise for my daughter.
Good night.
See you.
You didn't answer my question.
I'm not jewish.
Why not?
Why aren't you?
I don't subscribe to any religion.
So you live without any faith?
Ah, I didn't say that.
Why should my believes offend you?
They don't.
I just want to know why they don't offend you.
Tala, ease up.
Don't they do small talk in the Middle East?
This is small talk in the Middle East.
For serious debate we move on to politics.
And before that happens
I'm gonna take Leyla to dinner.
D'you wanna bluff your parents and join us?
They're going back to Jordan tomorrow...
But thank you... both...
Perhaps another time.
I'd like that.
We can be all british and talk about the weather.
You are naughty.
Leyla! The guests are due.
Come on!
I don't understand why Ali can't eat with us first?
He's hooked a tennis court, mum.
At one o'clock?
That's lunch time.
Only in the suburban house mum though,
I believe London's...
what 2 hours ahead of us?
Or would that be two years?
You and your cosmopolitan attitude.
What kind of salad are you making anyway?
It's a greek salad.
Oh, and an indian salad isn't good enough for you.
Mum, what is an indian salad?
Lettuce leaves and chilies?
You two are so worried about other cultures.
London... Greece...
What about your own heritage.
Did you ever think about that?
India has one of the richest cultures in the world.
Well, I'm glad you said that, mum.
Coz I'm thinking of spending 6 months out there.
Backpacking.
You are not going backpacking and in
India of all places...
What about the culture, the heritage?
What about being rapped and murdered?
And clean underwear?
I don't think you should take underwear, Yasmin.
What if you meet people we know?
They'll think we can't afford
to send you on a real holliday.
Mum, there like a billion people in India.
What are the chances that I'm gonna bump
into someone from your Surrey Bridge Club.
Ali!
Are you going to the door dressed like that?
We're going to play tennis, mum.
What's that smell?
Fetta cheese.
Hi.
How are you?
Ali!
Hi, Auntie. Hello. How are you?
First class.
Hi, uncle.
Hello, Ali.
Mmm, somthing smells good in here.
Thank you. That's my greek salad.
Hey, Yasmin, I didn't know you could cook.
Of course she can.
And so can Leyla,
who makes the best cakes
and never puts on weight.
Yeah, that's our Leyla.
She's gonna
make a wonderful housewife someday.
And apparently she knows how to sell
life insurance with the best of them.
How many times do i have to tell you?
It sells itself.
We should be going.
Bye, uncle.
Oh, next time come for lunch.
Oh, I'd love to, next time.
Come on.
OK, OK...
Let's hope she has the sense to hold onto him.
Like a life raft.
Mum!..
Oh, by the way. We're meeting
some friends at the club.
Hope that's OK.
Scared I'll beat you one on one?
Terrified...
Who're you playing with?
You remember Tala?
Oh, and another friend of mine, Jeff.
Actually, I owe Jeff a game so you
can play Tala.
Is that OK?
Fine.
Hey, how are you guys doing?
Hope you've been practicing.
Yeah, right.
Hey, how are you? Good
Hello.
Come, we'll play.
How are you?
They have a really great coach
here...
if you want a lesson...
That was amazing.
You're pretty good.
You're not so bad yourself.
This way.
I'll show you the changing-rooms.
That was quite a comeback.
I prayed for divine intervention.
I didn't say that there wasn't a God.
It's just religion that bothers me.
Sorry if I offended you.
On the contrary,
you made me think.
Yeah? Of what?
About... Thank you.
how we follow certain paths.
Is it just expectation or conditioning?
Let me take a look at that.
It's alright.
I'm always clumsy.
You know you should...
you should really relax more...
Just be at ease with yourself.
Maybe a shower will help.
They're over there.
Alright.
So, are you coming for the polo match tomorrow?
Honey, as much as I'd like to see
you fooling your ass,
no can do tomorrow.Rugby's on.
It's just a practice game.
It's usually fun.
I'm supposed to have lunch with my family tomorrow.
Hey, I'm sure they won't mind.
Think of all the fun you'll have turning divets.
Just watch where you tread.
You missed lunch yesterday and now
you want to miss it today?!
It's Sunday.
Why don't you ask Ali to come for lunch?
He could meet Nanima.
He's taking me to a polo match, mum.
Polo? You mean the game.
No, mum, she means the mints.
All those horses and sweating south-americans.
Will prince Charles be there?
Well, at least you're making an effort for a change.
What's that?
Excuse me.
Sure.
Hello.
Leyla?
Hi, dad...
Listen, we're gonna be later than I thought.
Ali's really into the Polo.
He just called.
Who just called?
Ali.
He asked if you wanted to go over
to his place to watch rugby
after you got back.
I didn't tell your mother, Betta.
Thanks, dad.
Thanks Antoinette. See you later.
Hello.
Impressed...
I didn't even break out in a sweat..
I kept thinking you were gonna fall.
leaning, of course, on a horse like that.
I like to take chances.
Is that why you left your family's business?
I wanted to see if I could create my own brand.
I'm impressed...
No, don't be.
Not yet at least.
I've yet to get a decent order.
But something should come up soon.
How about you?
Me? Nothing to tell.
My dad encouraged me to join his company
and I've never left.
And? You like it there?
It's not exactly inspiring.
So what inspires you, Leyla?
Writing... Fiction...
Can I read some of your stuff?
How else am I gonna find out what
goes on beneath that quiet exterior?
Let's...
Hello.
Really?
You have an amazing talent.
I'm... just learning.
Make sure you do something with it.
Have you really been engaged four times?
I mean, you seem like such a decisive person.
Yeah, well, I'm not proud of it.
You know about the last guy.
He had a problem with drugs.
The second guy.
Well he ticked all the boxes.
He's christian-arab, good family,
handsome, intelligent
It just didn't click.
I can understand that.
And the first?
Well, that was a big mistake I
let my mother pressurize me into.
He produces tons of dates...
my mother loves dates.
You can never have too many dates.
Oh, trust me, I found out you can.
How about you? What about you and Ali?
How is that going?
I like him a lot.
Does it click?
Not the way I imagined it should.
Well... maybe we expect too much.
It's starting to rain.
Oxford! Oxford's where you go to get
the degree not to get away.
It's ony an hour by train.
Why do you have to go for two days?
So if it takes me three hours I can stay the night?
Oh, my God.
What is that?
It's ethiopian bread.
We have indian bread right here.
Anyway, I thought they were starving in Ethyopia.
Yeah, well, if they had bread, then
this is what it would look like.
Who are you going with?
A friend.
Oh, Ali.
No, not Ali.
Does everything have
to revolve around him?
She has a friend and they're going
away for a couple of days.
Why do you make everything a problem?
Don't let her get to you Ley.
She's not... she's not getting to me.
What's wrong?
Are you two-timing Ali?
Of course not. You know me,
I can bearly go out with one guy properly.
Yeah, why is that?
Is there anything you want to talk to me about?
No.
I mean... anything.
You lied to mum and dad last week.
About the polo with Ali.
I know. I can't believe I did that.
No, it was about time if you ask me.
But why?
Who are you going to Oxford with?
Nobody.
Just Tala.
I see...
What? What do you see?
Well, nothing.
It's just that you've been spending
a lot of time with this Tala,
haven't you?
She's nice.
Nice?
Nice as in mum's bridge club
ladies nice or nice as in...
hot?
What's wrong with you?
Her family's sponsoring a charity event
and her sister's going to be there, OK?
OK...
Do you two think that lunch will make itslef.
No, but that lettuce leaf's walked
out of fridge on its own.
Come and take this horrible bread
and send it to Africa where it belongs.
Have you ever been to Oxford before?
Oh, I love it.
There's something magical about it,
especially the buildings.
"That sweet city with her dreaming spires".
Matthew Arnold?
Mhmm...
Shall we go see the library?
I'd love to.
What's Lamia doing?
Buying a picnic hamper.
Is she upset with us?
Just with me.
She wants me to show up for the wedding.
In Oxford?
Well, I've refused to meet her in Paris.
Here, Leyla. Try it.
Mmm, that is amazing.
Lamia, would you like to try some?
I don't do carbs.
Since when?
Lamia, you used to study here, right?
What subject?
Flower arranging.
So... I hear you didn't get the order.
Well maybe now you can come back and help Baba
and stop all this independent stuff.
You know, Leyla's the most brilliant writer.
You have to read her stuff.
No, no, no. I'm just learning. But I
do love it.
One day soon you will read her stuff in bookstores.
Could you publish an edition with pictures in it?
Shall we walk some more?
No.
Yes.
Whatever you prefer.
I need to get back to the room.
Karrem always checks where I am.
Tell him that you're busy.
Are you coming with me?
No. Come on.
It's exactly that kind of relationship
I wanted to avoid...
at all costs.
So your fiancé is not like that?
Hani? No.
He's an arab and was born
and brought up in Jordan.
But he's different from the rest.
Kind, open-minded.
And he makes a great Martini.
He sounds wonderful.
Yeah, he is.
He is...
At least I can't find
anything wrong with him.
Why are you trying?
Thank you.
For what?
For all this.
It's overwhelming.
You know it's been a while since I've
seen it all through new eyes.
Thank you.
I've absolutely no sense of rhythm.
Come here.
What are you thinking about?
Why I didn't meet you years ago.
We'd have been underaged.
Hello. Hi Hani. I'm fine.
Can I call you later.
No, nothing's wrong.
I just woke up.
I'll call you in a while, OK?
Bye.
Yeah, I love you too.
Have you ever done this before?
Slept with a woman when my fiance
makes wedding preparations?
No.
Never done that before.
That's not what I meant.
When I was 18, I fell madly in love
with a girl
in my first year in college.
We spent a few wonderful months together.
I never knew I could feel so
complete...
so alive...
Till now, obviously.
Till now...
So, what happened?
I broke it off. I was in pieces.
I told myself that it was for the best.
That I was away from home and
I was lonely and...
And now?
This is not a way to live, Leyla.
It's not easy.
It's not acceptable.
We didn't break any rules last night, Tala.
Yeah, but we did where I come from. Ok?
Nobody lives like this.
At least not openly.
And you live in the West now.
Yeah, but I don't think it's acceptable
to cheat on you fiancé
anywhere in the world.
What do you like most about this place?
The worlds that once existed.
Just, the scent of antiquity.
Ah, smells like mould in here.
I don't care what anyone says, Lamia.
You have a romantic soul.
Hello, mama. Can you hear me?
Stop the drier.
Hello, Lamia.
Mama.
Your tea, madam.
This place is a complete dump.
Give it to Philippe.
Only museums and no shops.
They don't even have a Gucci.
Did you get her something colourful?
Tala thinks grey is a colour.
And they got bored of shopping.
They?
Her friend is here with her.
Leyla?
The indian jewess?
The indian.
I didn't know that she was jewish.
They're spending all their time together...
I guess it's nice for Tala to
have such a close friend.
Good thing she's coming back next week.
That's the other thing.
I think she wants to stay in London a while longer.
She did this with the second engagement.
Or was it the first?
And she never came back for the wedding.
I'm sure it's not exactly like that.
Mama?
Home, sweet home.
Hello. Mama!
Hello, my love.
Hani.
Did you enjoy your trip?
Yes.
I'd give anything to be with you now.
Sit down. Sit down.
I have a surprise for Tala.
I'd like you to see it.
How was your trip?
Fine, I just walked in.
I know.
How do you know?
I can see you.
What do you mean?
Where are you?
Right here. Sweetheart...
They're so in love...
it brings tears to my eyes.
And you must be Leyla.
It's such a pleasure to meet you.
Tala's talked about you a lot.
You too.
How was Oxford?
Lovely, much more than I'd expected.
You know, no one ever says how
romantic Oxford is,
the river, its buildings, the history...
Well, let's have dinner.
You girls must be hungry.
I have to go but thank you.
Oh no, I won't hear of it.
A quick bite.
Hani works in the Jordanian gorvernment, you know?
The foreign office.
Does that cover relations with Israel?
Yes.
How can you stand it?
We have to stand it.
And sometimes even learn something from the israelies.
What do you want to learn?
How to shoot children?
Obviously, not that.
But Israel is the closest thing to
a democracy
that we have in the Middle East.
Oh, thank god I didn't send your
sisters to that american school.
They turned you into an arab-hater.
Auntie...
your daughter is one of the proudest
palestinians I know.
Why don't you show Leyla and Tala the invitations?
What invitations?
To our wedding.
Well?
It's beautiful.
Really perfect.
Are you alright?
Just a headache.
Here.
I just need to use the bathroom.
Upstairs. Ninth door on the left.
Thank you.
Do you want me to go with you?
No, I'm fine.
What are you doing?
Holding your hand.
So what happens?
We get five minutes of hand-holding.
I get a night in Oxford and he
gets a night in London.
That's not fair.
What is fair Tala?
We can't live like this.
Our families won't understand.
I can't lead you into a life that's...
difficult.
I don't need your protection.
Thanks to you I know what I want and
I can't go back.
I want to feel the way I felt last night every day.
I want to be with someone that
ten years from now makes my heart jump
when I hear her key in the door.
And that someone is you.
I...
I can't hurt Hani.
Are you in love with him?
There are things I love about him.
I can't ruin lives.
You will.
Especially yours.
Tala, are you OK?
Tell me you can do this.
Tala...
Ramzi, welcome!
Hello.
Christ... I'm still here.
No two women should look this
beautiful at six in the morning.
Is the king coming for breakfast?
No, I'm going to the airport.
Sami's flying in from New York for the wedding.
I haven't seen your brother in years.
Does he still like musicals?
I don't know.
But I'm sure he's looking very
much forward to seeing you.
Why?
We'll be back in time for breakfast
with your parents.
Wasn't he supposed to get a place
for Lamia, like four years ago?
Would you leave a suite at the best hotel
in town
if you were getting it for free?
I'd leave paradise itself if mama was there.
Well, Kareem would brave hell itself
to secure his enheritance.
He's not their son.
But in the absence of a son he
is the perfect son-in-law.
Which David could never be.
Anyway, he broke up with me.
He did? I'm sorry, sweetheart.
He wants to bring up his kids as jews.
Hanukkah... Pass-over...
Imagine mama's face...
I'd really rather not...
though it might be worth it.
We thought we could start our own mini peace process.
He never made a secret of being
attached to his culture.
Then why did he even get involved with you?
I mean, what kind of a person
allows you to
get emotionally entangled
when they know there's no way forward?
I need a coffee.
No. No...
You need to stop selling
yourself short.
Sometimes... sometimes..
you can't stop and rationalize
everything so perfectly.
Don't you ever just do something...
Even when you know deep down
it's going to be a disaster?
You will like Zina, if you give her a chance.
She's a nice girl.
And she wears a lot of black also.
I think the two of you will match perfectly.
I'm really not interested in women.
Too busy working at the investment bank,
I imagine.
I mean, you have to start thinking
about your future, Sami.
What? Like you?
Yes.
Like me.
Welcome, Sami.
Thank you.
It's not very often that I have
all my daughters at home at the same time.
I'd like to propose a toast.
To Tala and Hani.
And may you have many daughters.
Oh, papa!
No thanks, I'm vegetarian.
Really?
Me too.
Have you ever been to Dan's Bakery
in New York?
In the village...
I love that place.
They make the best arabic bread.
And they have the best looking beagles.
That's not important.
Well, it is to me.
Did anyone see?
There was another suicide bomb last night.
It's barbaric the way they brainwash these people.
This idea of a paradise waiting for you
if you kill innocent people.
They're not killing innocent people.
They're killing israelies.
Have you forgotten what they did to us at Sabra
and Shatilla and Deir Yassin?
So we sink to their level and kill children?
Children who grow up to be israeli soldiers.
Kareem, please...
With all due respect Hani,
but you and I have never suffered
like our palestinian countrymen.
If I remember right you were busy the last time
we went to a refugee camp
to interview people for jobs.
I was holding the fort at the office
for your father that day.
And Lamia and I went to the refugee charity
dinner just last month.
Where the refugees wash the dishes.
Will you all excuse me please, I've a...
I've got a lot I have to do.
The seamstress will be here at 10.
Make sure you hold your stomach in this time.
Are you trying to kill me,
creeping into the house like a rober?
Sorry.
You missed "Bollywood Sisters".
Nina's just found out her 16 years daughter
is pregnant and a drug addict.
I made you some pasta.
I need to talk to you.
What's the matter?
Are you sick?
No, I'm fine.
Actually very good.
Happy.
Where's dad?
In town with a client. He'll be back
home soon.
Ali called.
Oh, shit, I forgot about him.
Well, he's a wonderful boy.
Mum, I'm not happy with him.
Then auntie Gulshan's son is looking
for somebody.
He's very succesful.
He's a bookie.
And handsome.
He's 6 foot 7 all I can see is his navel.
Well, then you'll have tall children.
Mum, I can't be happy with him.
The way I'm not happy with Ali...
and I've always known why but...
I was hoping that the reason
I thought was the reason...
might not really be the reason...
and that things would change,
but they never have, not really and now...
I know for sure that what I've
been feeling all these years...
Is actually the right thing.
and there's nothing wrong with it...
-Do you want cheese with it?
Mum, what I'm trying to say is...
I haven't got cheddar for pasta, parmesan though...
I've got olive oil...
-Just listen to me, I'M GAY.
I'm home.
What did I miss?
I'm gay...
But I've only been gone two hours...
You always said you just wanted us to be happy.
I lied.
Who did this to you?
I haven't caught a disease, mum,
I'm just gay, like I have brown hair.
First you stop coming to mosque,
now, you're up to your neck in sin.
It's not a sin!
Mum, I haven't killed or stolen and I'm
trying not to lie to you.
It's a huge sin!
According to who?
According to God!
What kind of a God is that?
I don't accept it!
Then you will burn in hell!
That's enough!
It's OK.
I think maybe it's time we discuss getting
you that flat you've been asking for.
If I could help it I would, but I can't...
I know, Beta.
I know.
How many pre-wedding dinners is
it possible to have?
And another thing, if the rule's
"no black", then fine...
but how come you get a dress that's elegant
and I get one that's liberaci?
Because I did Tala's shopping for her in Paris.
"Zina, don't wear black, it's not a funeral. Mama"
It's a funeral for the 20 lambs that got
slaughtered for this dinner.
They made tofu kebabs for you, sweetheart.
Come on Zina. Sami's down stairs.
He asked where you were.
Send him this dress, he'd probably love it.
What kind of a stupid comment is that?
He likes you a lot, you know.
Yeah, well, I like him too.
You should go out with him.
He's the right age to marry.
You seem to have a lot in common.
You both like New York,
you both like black clothes...
We both like men...
Stop saying things like that.
Yeah, if you don't say it Z, maybe it
won't be true.
Kareem thinks it's a phase.
If he meets the right girl
he'll get over it.
That strategy sure didn't work for uncle Ramzi.
Uncle Ramzi is not gay.
Yeah, and the pope ain't catholic.
What do you think, Lamia?
Do you think that...
Do you think that being gay is a "phase"?
Do you thinks it's alright to sacrifice
your own sister to...
to a life of misery-marriage into
someone who's gay?
No matter how well their clothes match?
Well, I guess you would know more about
that than anyone else.
What's her problem?
I have a strange sense of "deja-vu".
I'm sorry, papa.
Have you told Hani?
I don't know what to tell him.
Except that I know it won't be fair to him
to go through with the wedding.
You know what fathers want for their daughters?
For them to be happy.
Son's move on, they have choices.
Especially here, in the Middle East.
But a daughter...
a daughter needs a hand now and then.
What are you gonna do about this?
Oh, I don't know...
Maybe we can just have the party.
Your uncle Ramzi can tell his plane crash stories.
And everyone in town can toast to
new scandal with champagne.
See Hani.
Go and get dressed. It'll be OK.
Ravi.
Sir?
Pack all the wedding food and send
it to the camps.
They should have cancelation insurance
for weddings...
That stuff would sell itself.
Can I have the keys, dad?
"I can't think straight"
She won't get it.
Get what?
Nothing.
Where are you going?
I'm having Leyla look for flats.
She doesn't have to go.
She needs to.
What exactly happened?
I broke Hani's heart.
Hey, Tala. You have to give yourself a break.
If you knew he wasn't the right one
then you did exactly the right thing.
Yeah, except I should've told him sooner.
Look, honey, we all wish we had far-sight..
So what about you, huh?
Me? YFS...
Young, free and single...
You're not seeing Leyla?
Neah, she dumped me.
What happened?
Well, on the plus side it wasn't really my fault
She told me she's gay.
I know, I was shocked too.
You know, she even told her parents.
You're kidding.
-No.
Got to admire her guts.
She's always had a fierce treat that one.
You know, there aren't many people in
our community that'd be willing to do that.
Always liked that about her.
Come on, you.
Hello?
Hello. This is Tala speaking.
Can I speak to Leyla?
Ah, yeah. One minute.
For you.
Who is it?
Tala.
I'm not talking to her...
Yasmine...
Yasmine... I'm not talking to her.
Take the phone.
She can't come to the phone right now.
No, I'll...
I'll call back tomorrow...
Perhaps one of the most stunning
archeological finds of that century...
indeed, any century,
was the founding in the south of
Jordan of the  Lost City of Petra.
Dramatically carved out of froze
coloured stone by the nabatheans,
the massive columns of the temple
rise up to surprise visitors
as they walk through a high cannion
to reach the entrance.
A breathtaking sight,
now, a thriving turist destination,
Petra has enthralled generations of
archeologists and visitors alike,
thanks to the stories and beauty of
its lost city.
Like the rest of Jordan, it is well
worth a visit.
She's good.
Hello.
-Naturally, it's much...
Oh, it was so great to go...
Apparently, you can only get into Petra
on a horse or a hump.
That would be a great laugh.
It'd be fun.
What are you doing here?
My family sponsored the lecture.
I'm interested in Jordan.
It has a population of 5 million
and no natural resources to speak about.
Petra's lovely but there isn't much
to say about Jordan...
because it's me you're interested in.
How's your wedding?
Leyla, let's go.
This is my friend Jennifer.
Your friend?
Her girlfriend.
Girlfriend...
Who's that?
That's my friend Tala, her family...
D'you want that?
D'you wanna join us for a drink tonight?
I can't, I have to work.
Yeah, how's that going?
I got the order.
That's fantastic, Tala.
Great! D'you know how difficult it is
to get into those big chains.
Thought that's exactly what you wanted?
Yeah, it was.
Well, we should celebrate.
It'll be fun.
Leyla said she might join us tonight.
No, I'm... I'm really busy.
Is everything OK?
I don't get it.
Which part?
Why d'you wanna get Leyla and Tala together?
I mean, the other day Tala didn't
seem interested at all.
Listen. Did you ever watch the TV show
"The L Word"?
No... But did you ever consider not
talking in riddles?
They're in love with each other.
Who?
Sonny and Cher...
Leyla and Tala.
Leyla and Tala?
Good evening, madam.
Good evening.
I'm meeting Ali.
The other party hasn't arrived yet.
Would you like to take a seat at the bar
or would you like me to show you
to your table?
The table.
-Sure.
Oh, good evening.
Reservation for Ali, 7:30.
Oh, yes, follow me.
There you go, madam.
Thank you.
The gentleman sends his regrets, ladies.
He's unable to make it.
But he does wish you a pleasant
evening at his invitation.
Thank you.
We've been set up.
So it seems.
You look wonderful.
So do you.
I know.
I'm just joking.
How's your husband?
I don't have one.
I broke off the wedding...
the morning of the wedding...
That must've been very difficult.
It was the second hardest thing
I've ever had to do.
What was the first?
Leaving you to go back to Jordan.
Well now, I'm glad to see you
were discreet.
Well? How did it go?
Their eyes met.
A brief smile played across Tala's mouth,
unconsciously Leyla licked her lips.
It's all over.
OK. I'm still getting used to the idea.
You sound just like my dad when
you say things like that.
You know what?
I've always liked your dad.
What about you? How are you?
Fine.
Really good.
My book got published.
Really?
I mean... it will.
Next week, actually.
That is so wonderful, Leyla.
No one deserves it more than you.
How's your girlfriend?
Jennifer?
Has it been more than one?
No.
She's fine. Thank's for asking.
Do you love her?
There are things I love about her.
And is that good enough for you?
No, not really.
Did you tell your parents why you
broke off your wedding?
I told them it wouldn't be fair to Hani.
Did you tell them why?
Look, Leyla, you...
you don't understand.
Jordan.. it's an unforgiving place.
My parents have a strong place in
that society and...
it's a culture that doesn't change.
And I guess as long as people don't
dare to be truthful about who they are..
it never will change.
Leyla, I love you.
It's that simple.
Why should it be anyone else's business,
even my family's?
We make it their business every time
we have to lie about
who we're with and why we're with them.
You know, you once told me
to be more at ease with myself.
Thanks to you, I am.
I'm telling you the same thing.
"Every night I empty my heart,
but by morning it's full again.
Slow droplets of you sip in through
the night, soft caress...
At dawn I overflow with thoughts of us
and aching pleasure that gives me no respite
Love cannot be contained,
the neat packaging of desire splits us under
spilling crimson through my days.
Long, languishing days set are now
bruised tender with yearning
spent searching for a fingerprint,
a scent, a breath you left behind..."
Rani, where's my parents?
They've just finished lunch, miss.
I gave madam some mint tea.
Go in.
Maybe I should try something american made.
As long as it's a third world country,
I don't mind where it is.
They work hard. They don't even think about...
Mama, papa, I have something I need to tell you.
What are you talking about?
You're a disgrace.
Haven't you shamed us enough already?
Please, Reema...
Tala...
Tala, wait.
"The sun hit her hand with a red hot force
that burned straight through the
clear-veined skin of her wrist.
And when she shut her eyes tightly
and briefly against it...
the heat still glowed under eyelids like coals"
Thank you, Leyla, for a very
illuminating talk and reading.
If anyone would like a signed copy...
Lyela has kindly agreed to do a signing.
I really loved it.
Especially the ending.
That's nice to hear.
Most people just love it when it ends.
Thank you.
Hi, Amina please.
Amina... quite an unique name.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Who should I make it out to?
To Tala...
who finally had the courage
to come out to her parents.
Thank you...
What did you tell them?
I told them I was in love...
with a beautiful...
intelligent...
talented...
clumsy...
woman.
Sorry we had to go to a hotel last night.
We won't from next week.
I'm getting my own place.
Congratulations. Is it a flat?
One bedroom.
What is it?
I was just thinking.
You're gonna need a bigger place.
Why?
Because...
I told my parents we're
gonna have children...
One day... Soon...
Children?
Soon.
She's what?
But some of my best friends are lebanese?..