Fatima...you came.
You waited.
Your CDs.
Get on.
Did you listen to them?
Yes.
They were okay.
You have the worst taste
in music.
Stop, Khalid.
We can't go this way.
It's a shortcut.
Khalid, I said stop.
My father has tea here
every morning.
You see him?
No.
Fatima.
Fatima, wait.
I want to meet him.
I told you, you can't.
Has he called?
Only to yell at me.
We should run away, just go.
We have our studies, Fatima.
We have to be realistic.
Okay for you.
No one's forcing you to marry.
I just want to meet him.
He has chosen someone for me.
He has chosen.
He might like me more.
You don't know my father.
Daddy.
Daddy, did I wake you?
No, sweetheart.
Daddy, do you dream about me
when you're sleeping?
I dream...
about you...
and your mother...
and your sister.
Fatima said you stop dreaming
when you get married.
She's wrong, sweetheart.
You dream all your life.
It's one of God's gifts.
Understand?
- Give me a kiss.
- No.
- One kiss.
Only one.
They overload these donkeys
and cause accidents. Chaos.
Tea, please.
Okay.
Out the back! Out the back!
19 dead, 75 injured.
El-Hazim have
claimed responsibility.
And the new guy?
Shrapnel in the neck.
He bled to death.
Damn.
Sir.
You have calls
from Corrine Whitman, CIA...
and Mr. Davis
at the U.S. State Department.
Give me Corrine first.
One dead American.
Lina.
Dad, when is Fatima
coming home?
Finish your milk.
Please, Abasi.
Tell her you made a mistake.
It's not the same
as when we were young.
There are rules, Samia.
There are rules.
Look at my sister Layla.
She'll never marry.
Call her, Abasi.
Please.
For me.
I have called.
I've left a dozen messages.
She doesn't answer.
What can I do?
Leave the egg alone!
Have you called your father?
Not yet.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, it's nothing.
What have I done?
I'm proud of you
for standing up to him.
That's my taxi.
Please stay.
I want you in this apartment
by eight while I'm gone.
If my brother knew I was
leaving you here alone...
he'd kill me.
Okay?
See you in a few days.
My grandma has
the middle floor. I'm on top.
I don't want her
to find me here.
She's away for the week.
I have a back way in.
No one will see us.
You okay?
My grandma's room.
Come.
Like jasmine.
Do you sell what you paint?
Some.
I'm getting better.
No.
Those are just drafts.
That's you?
Mm-hmm.
And them?
My brother and grandma.
This is your mother?
She was beautiful.
You are the beautiful one.
You and your brother
have the same eyes.
Where's he now?
Does he visit you?
No.
Not anymore.
Are you hungry?
Come, let's go to the kitchen.
- Peace be with you.
- And with you.
I thought you weren't coming.
Come.
Sir, he's here.
Al Jazeera
is running footage.
Security authorities
have confirmed 19 deaths.
Most of the victims
are women and children.
A tourist video
found at the scene...
shows the source of the blast.
In an email to the station,
El-Hazim has claimed...
Why the hell didn't we get that?
Call Abdou, I want a copy now.
The struggle against
the Zionist and the Crusader...
represents the decisive battle
between faith and infidelity.
Between good and evil.
The destruction of the infidel
and hypocrite is your sacred duty.
When you meet the Apostate you are
commanded to "strike the necks."
The Crusader
talks about freedom.
Jihad is the only path
to freedom.
Do not fear their bullets.
What can they do...
but set your soul free?
On the Day of Judgment...
when you stand before
the Almighty God...
and He asks you...
"Why did you not fight
for the cause of God?
"And for the oppressed. The men,
the women and the children?
"What did you do
with the one weapon I gave you?
"Your body."
What will be your answer?
Will you display the wounds
of martyrdom and walk through
the gates of heaven?
Or, will you hang your head
in shame and roast in the fires of hell?
Success is from God.
May the peace and blessings and
glory of God, the Almighty, be upon you.
Amen.
Praise God.
God is great!
You are Egyptian. Yes?
You are Egyptian.
Put him in the hole.
That's him.
You see?
Heading right for me. The dog.
Is someone trying to stop him?
Wait, wait.
She's blocking him.
The gunshot...
Useless.
Where were you?
Fatima,
what are you doing here?
I was worried.
You can't keep missing classes.
I was busy.
You were busy.
Don't.
Are you seeing another girl?
No.
Then where were you?
- With Omar.
- Where?
At his home. He has a problem.
I am his friend.
Friend.
I'm sorry.
I have to go.
Now?
Stay here.
No.
Please...
stay with me.
I'm sorry.
Leave us.
Is Fatima here?
There's...
There's a problem, Abasi.
I don't know where Fatima is.
But she was staying with you.
I went away...
Away for work.
You left her alone?
When was the last time
you saw her?
Six days ago.
Six days ago?
She's been seeing a boy.
She said he was a school friend.
Just a friend.
What's his name?
I don't know if she's with him.
Khalid.
Khalid who?
I don't know his last name.
I'm sorry.
Khalid.
Smile.
Wait, I want one with Fatima.
Fatima. Come get in the picture.
Smile.
Brothers and sisters.
Sorry to stop the music.
I just need to make
a few points...
before the march tomorrow.
Remember, the streets
will be lined with police.
We must remain calm.
We will show the world...
We will show the world
that we have had enough.
That we won't take it anymore.
Enough!
Khalid!
- Khalid!
- Omar!
Omar!
The boy's name
is Khalid El-Emin.
Khalid El-Emin?
I got it from the school.
Father's in Paris.
Mother's dead.
His brother, Fadil,
had multiple arrests.
We had him for a while.
We let him go?
He died.
Where's the boy?
We don't know.
We're trying to find
an address for him.
Then why are you standing here
like an idiot?
Go!
Find him!
Move!
Khalid, where are we going?
Who is it?
It's Khalid. They've taken Omar.
Open, open.
They took Omar.
Go in the kitchen
and boil some water.
So we can clean him up.
You should not have
brought her here.
What are we going to do
about her?
Leave her out of it.
I'm not going to her house.
You've got to understand,
she is not her father.
Then we will do it another way.
They have Omar.
They will make him talk.
Over.
It is over.
Then...
we must do it now.
Remember your brother.
Who contacted you?
How?
He called me...
on my cell phone.
Do you know
what they will do to Omar?
Do you?
Sorry to wake you, sir.
We have someone
who knows your daughter.
Omar Adnan.
He was arrested
by the riot squad last week.
He knows where the boy lives.
Khalid?
I do this in memory
of my brother.
They overload these donkeys
and cause accidents. Chaos.
Tea, please.
Okay.
Khalid!
Why is he stopping?
Please, he's my father.
Khalid, please.
Please.
He's not going to do it.
Take him out.
Khalid!
When did he die?
God's will.
When?
A week ago.
They were just children.