$ 25,000 first asshole
That would give the white!
Come on!
1 ... 2 ... 3!
My name is Jordan Belfort.
He did not.
'M.
Right.
I am a former member of the class
Average raised by two meters
in a small apartment
in Bayside, Queens.
When I turned 26 years old I was the Chief
my own investment firm.
I made $ 49 million.
What annoyed me because i missed three
million to 1 million per week.
No.
My Ferrari was white as
Don Johnson in Miami Vice.
It was red.
See that amazing house?
It is mine.
In Addition to Naomi and my
two perfect children.
I own a mansion,
private jets, 6 cars, 3 horses.
Two houses and holiday homes
a yacht of 170 feet.
I also bet
as a degenerate.
Drink like a fish,
have sex with prostitutes
Perhaps 5 or 6 times
week.
I have 3 federal agencies
trying to catch me.
By the way ...
I love drugs.
Ok.
Yes.
Like it?
Up, up!
By God, we're going to crash!
Relax.
Are these good?
Yes, I am.
Good job.
Take care of yourself, okay?
Until next time,
brother.
Until next time.
If daily consumption
Sufficient drug
to sedate Manhattan
Long Island and Queens.
For a month.
Mr. Jordan looks good.
I take painkillers 10
to 15 times per day.
For my back pain.
Adderall to stay focused.
Xanax not get nervous
and dozed a little.
Cocaine to get up
morphine again and good ...
Because it's amazing.
Good morning.
But all drugs
God put on this earth.
There is one that is my favorite.
You see ...
enough of this
will make you invincible.
Able to conquer the world
and eviscerate your enemies.
I'm not talking about this.
But This.
The money will not only
buy a better life.
Best food, best cars,
best vaginas.
Also it makes you a
better person.
You can support the church
or a political party.
You do what you eat
to earn money.
I always wanted to be rich.
So let me go back.
22 years old, newly married
and crazy about money.
So what do I do?
I go to the only place I Could
quench my great ambitions.
You're lower than
rubbish in a puddle.
Got a Problem With That?
Jordan?
I have no problem.
Right.
Because that's what
you are.
Rubbish puddle.
Your job is to be a connector
meaning
That marcaras to phone
more than 500 times a day.
Trying to connect to my
with wealthy businessmen.
And until you pass
your trial period
this is all you do.
Sit.
Sit!
Just so you know last year
I made over $ 300,000.
The guy who worked for
made more than one million.
$ 1 million.
I can not Imagine
lout Should be that guy.
Jordan Belfort?
Mark Hanna.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Also, I see you've met
to the village idiot.
Smile and brand.
Do not raise your fucking
head to 1.
Hey, fuck him.
So I re. Nior.
Suck Hanna.
Listen you know trigger actions.
Need an interview?
I'll be the best where
I don, Lord.
I love that.
Had lunch today.
Yes.
But Began to September
at 9:30
Already our customers will be
answering calls.
3 ... 2 ... 1!
A catch!
Want to know how it sounds
the money?
Go to a trading floor
on Wall Street.
That shit rot,
fucking asshole.
I Could not believe as
talking to each other.
I was hooked in seconds.
It was an injection
adrenaline.
Hey piece of shit looks like
actions are today.
In Forty ...
Pick up the fucking phone.
Sorry ...
You're a complete idiot
Hanna.
I do not care as shit
technology works.
Because the only thing that matters to me
is getting rich.
Then 2,000.
Jordan Belfort ...
Time to close this.
2,000 Microsoft.
Going through.
Come with me.
Hold This,
hot.
Here, close the damn.
Close it!
No thanks.
Mr. Hanna, what can I bring in
this glorious afternoon?
Well here I have Hector
the game plan.
We will bring you two Martini.
You know how I like them,
ice.
After just 7 minutes
and a half after that.
We will bring you two more,
then ...
That after two more
every 5 minutes.
Until one of us
faint.
Excellent Sir strategy.
I'm with well water
but thanks.
It's your first day on Wall Street.
Give it time.
Thank you.
Mr. Hanna.
Are you able to get high during the day
and you can even do your job?
How the fuck else
I could do?
Cocaine and prostitutes
my friend.
Right.
I must say I'm excited
to be part of your signature.
Customers who have are ...
Customers rot.
Your Responsibility is only
put meat on the table.
You have a girlfriend?
I am married.
I have a wife, her name
Teresa is. It is a hairdresser.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Think Teresa.
The name of the game.
Move the money
pocket of your customer
to yours. "
But if you can make him win
customer money at the same time
is beneficial for all,
Right?
No.
Rule number one
Wall Street.
Nobody ...
I do not care if you're
Jimmy Buffet.
Nobody knows Whether the actions
They will rise,
down, turn sideways
in fucking circles.
Less us
runners.
It's quite a fugazi.
You know what is That?
Fugazi, wants
say false.
Fairy Dust
does not exist.
It does not matter,
does not matter.
Not in the
periodic table.
It's not real.
Follow Me.
We do not
create shit.
We do not build anything.
No. ..
If you have a customer
I buy shares' $ 8.
And now worth 16 Which
this fucking happy.
Wants to charge, take the money
and run home.
Do not leave it.
Ok ...
Because That would make real.
If ...
What do you do?
Have another brilliant idea.
A special idea.
Another situation,
other action.
To recover its investment
gains and then some.
It will do every time.
Because They are addicted.
You do it again and again.
Meanwhile ...
I thinks he is doing
millionaire, what is true, in part.
But you and I runners.
We took home
cash.
By the commission,
bastard.
Right.
It's amazing sir.
Do not know how excited I am.
Should be.
There are two key.
To be successful in
this business.
First of all.
You must keep peopl.
If ...
Do you masturbate?
If I masturbate?
If ...
If I do.
How many times a week?
Maybe 3 or 4 times.
Those numbers are for rookies.
Personally I
At least masturbate
twice daily.
Once in the morning
after exercise.
Then again after
lunch.
Really?
I want to do but do not
do so.
I do it because i need it.
Imagine trying to
numbers all day.
Decimal points.
Adjusted frequencies.
Damn digits.
All that shit you accumulate
above the shoulders.
Do you understand?
Decays to some people.
You have to hang the turkey
blood flow.
That pace to continue
below the belt.
Done.
This is not advice,
is a recipe. Believe me.
If you do not.
You're going to unbalance.
We will divide into two
and you will fall to the side.
Worse, I've seen this happen.
Lmplosionaras.
I will not implode, Lord.
No. ..
Of course not.
I'm here to stay, you know?
If Implosions are ugly.
If ...
Run to the bathroom and do it
Whenever you can.
When you return good
so, to think
money while doing it.
Second
key to success.
In this package I have a
small drink called cocaine.
Right.
It will keep you alert Between the ears.
It will help your fingers
That mark faster.
Guess.
That's good for me.
Yes sir.
Revolutions, do you understand?
Revolutions.
Keep the client in the wheel.
Never for the park is open
24 hours, 365 days a year.
Every decade, every damn century.
That's it.
It is the name of the game.
Help yourself.
Thank you.
We will.
We are a common
denominator.
Follow the rhythm.
The next six months I met
the inputs and outputs of Wall Street.
Money earned while fucking
I prepared for big.
Then, I was a runner
licensed to end.
Ready to make my fortune.
My first day as a future
master of the universe.
They called Black Monday '
Do not tell me.
By 4pm the bag had
dropped 500 points.
The worst decline since 1929.
I do not mind a European country,
They want to do what.
Our market is here.
Want to say something?
You know what happened?
A damn tsunami.
You're making a big mistake.
Yes, speak to your boss.
When many people hang
you called. Beware of dirty laundry.
I do not know what happens ...
I know.
Shit ...
What the fuck ...
amazing.
My first day as a runner.
Within a month, LF Rotstraut.
An institution since 1899.
It closed its doors.
Wall Street had swallowed me
and Expelled
again.
We can pawn my ring
Commitment.
Necessary.
Bebe.
I do not need.
Say Necessary.
Listen honey.
You will not pawn anything.
OK?
Ok.
What is it you always say?
You'll be a millionaire.
Right.
Let me see this.
I'll find something.
How about this?
What?
Nobody beats magician.
Electronics store.
Repositioning, what do you think?
You will not work there.
But I start something.
Will be wretched if you go there.
Is sales, it will work to
Become Chief.
Not as a stock boy.
Why not?
Because you're a runner.
You Know That nobody hires
Riders now?
Get it?
OK?
This place itself.
What?
What does that say?
Riders.
Corridors
Long Island.
Hi I'm looking for ... to
investment center.
Looking to invest?
No investment center.
An investment center?
Yes, we are.
Hi, here it is.
I'm Dwayne.
Are you Dwayne?
Hello, Talked on the phone.
'M Jordan Belfort.
He broker Rotstraut
New York.
Yeah, take feel.
How are you?
We had a conversation ...
We spoke Earlier, right?
2 hours ago.
If ...
So where are Their
Electronic here?
Electronics?
If Their computers.
No need computers here.
We only use These
Pink Sheets.
Pink Sheets?
If penny stocks.
Companies can not be
listed on the market due to lack of capital.
Its shares are traded here.
Shares of pennies?
Yes, this one here.
Aerodyne.
It is very interesting ...
Aerotyne say.
If, Aerotyne.
Aerotyne.
Actions are hot right now.
They are a pair of brothers doing
technology in its garage.
Maybe They are microwave,
I'm not sure but ...
if you call your landline
answered his mother and is very sweet.
Actually I do not
around them.
Action? 6 cents?
Come on,
Who buys this?
Well to be honest
mostly fools.
Mailmen, postmen always.
Plumbers ...
See our ads in Part
back of a Hustler or Popular Mechanic.
And they say They Can
get rich quick.
Hustler?
Yes, the magazine for girls.
If the nude.
That one.
Yes.
With That fund them
houses,
we help them buy a ring
for your wives, just a boat once.
Is this is regulated?
Why are they here?
Something like that.
Something like that?
The profit margin
is large.
Yes, that's the point.
What was your name?
Jordan Belfort.
Jordan, how much you won
with Actions?
I Gained 1%
good was what I was going to win.
With the Pink Sheets,
is 50%.
Is it 50?
Commission? 50?
Yes, why?
It is a payment for our services.
So if yo ...
shares sell at $ 10,000.
My fee is $ 5,000?
If you sell $ 10,000
of These actions.
Personally you the
free suck.
I hope you pass.
Hi John, how are you?
You sent me a postcard company
a few weeks ago
Requesting information on
That penny stocks had
with a very high potential
Risks low.
Does this sound familiar?
Ok, great. I have reason for my
call today is John ...
just something to cross
my desk.
It is the best I've seen
in the last 6 months.
Within 60 seconds I want to comentártelo.
Have a minute?
Company Name
Aerotyne international.
It is a technology firm
tip of the middle east.
They are awaiting approval
in the next generation of radars
with military applications
and Civilians.
Now, right now John.
The shares are worth 10
cents each.
By the way our Analysts following have
That will be worth much more.
Your profit with only
$ 6,000 investment.
Reach '$ 60,000.
Exactly, Could you pay your
mortgage.
John is one thing That I can you
In this market even promise.
You never ask my clients
I tried for my victories.
I ask you to judge me on my
Because I have a few defeats.
For based Aerotyne
all technical, John.
We are seeing a goal
half-court.
Ok, let's do it.
Comprare '$ 4,000.
$ 4,000 will be
40,000 shares John.
Let me close the deal now and
I return the call
my secretary and confirmation.
John? Sounds good?
Sounds good.
Genial.
John, thanks for your
vote of confidence.
Welcome to Center
investment.
Thanks man.
Goodbye.
How the fuck did you do that?
So easy I '$ 2,000.
The other guys Looked at me like
if I had discovered the fire.
We sold trash
garbage collectors.
It was a lot of money.
The only problem You'll have
is not bought more.
Who cares if
sold them fucking
the way I
saw
money was better
in my pocket.
I knew how to spend it better.
Apology.
That car is yours?
Yes.
It's nice.
Thank you.
Donnie Azoff.
Hi, I'm Jordan Belfort.
It's my pleasure.
I've seen that car around here.
Pretty indeed.
Yeah?
I think we live in
the same building.
Do not you tell?
Yes.
Twelfth floor?
Which one are you on?
Fourth floor.
Couple of kids, lovely wife.
If ...
What are you doing man?
How so?
What you do?
I am a stock broker.
Actions? Broker?
Yes.
I sell furniture for kids.
Good for you.
This right, you do
lot of money?
Yes, I do well.
I try to connect the dots.
Have a very good car.
We live in the same building.
I do not ...
understand, how much
earn money?
I do not know.
70,000? Last month?
Fuck me.
Really.
I also wonder seriously.
What do you make money?
I told you.
'$ 70,000 $ 72,000 good technically.
Last month or
something out there.
Do you make 72,000 per month?
Yes.
Tell you what.
Show me Proof that You have
That amount earned
I quit my job and now,
We?
Hey Paulie, how?
No, everything is fine.
Listen resign.
If I quit his job.
Which was strange,
Knew just.
Do not tell Susan,
It is none of your business.
Were there other things too,
Their teeth as fluorescent.
Do I have to deal with your wife?
Besides his eyeglasses
made him look like a bee.
There Were Also
rumors.
Play some bullshit.
Not because i do not know what
mention is stupid.
About me?
You know people say nonsense.
I do not know hardly
hear them.
What say you?
Something Between your cousin
and you or something.
Do not listen to them well.
I do not care.
Not what you think.
They say you marry
your cousin or something.
My wife ... if my wife
He's my cousin.
But it's not like you think.
Is sister or cousin ...?
Yes, your ... father ...
I is the brother
my mom.
But it is not,
Look, we grew up together.
It developed very well,
you know.
All my friends wanted
mount, you understand.
I thought, I'll let
None of these
idiots take my cousin.
Then That I use to be cousins
to enter it.
I will not leave
someone else's lame.
If someone was going to do,
Should be.
Out of respect, you know?
I get it, you have no fear
That of children, right?
Do you have children with her?
Yes.
We have 2 children.
Well I do not want to intrude
here but ...
Are they right?
They are not retarded or anything.
But there is a great
true risk?
If you know
no 60,
65% That the child risk
is fucking retarded.
That scares me friend.
There is always the Possibility though
They are cousins ??or not.
What if something
well happen?
Basically if the child
out delayed
would take to the field
and say, you're free now.
"Run and be free".
You know.
I'm just kidding.
That is horrible.
Looks like you Believed.
We're taking it to an institution That
I can raise a child and that.
You know, if you're happy
God bless you friend.
I'm not, not married
is happy.
Sorry to hear that friend.
Listen seriously ...
I am grateful for this work.
I'm happy with what you do.
Indeed you buy
a gift.
You bought me a present?
If you buy something.
You're sweet.
This in my backpack.
What do you mean?
We must go back.
Are you Involved?
Yes, it is.
I do not understand.
We're just going there.
I will not do this.
You are crazy.
Let friend.
No!
There's nobody here.
Come here, smokes crack
me brother.
Smoke crack.
Do the fucking crack.
A puff, just one.
That's it.
Smoke.
Let's go.
We must leave
from here friend.
Let's go.
We will run.
Let's run like lions,
tigers and bears!
We will run.
Come on!
Come on, come on.
You marked best
Frank repair shop.
We are closed now.
Please leave a message.
Hello, my name
Jordan Belfort is.
My partner and I are interested
in renting your shop.
Donnie and I were
to go on our own.
The first thing needed
was runners.
Boys experience
sales.
So some were recruited
my city friends.
Sea Otter, who sold meat
and marijuana.
Chester, who sold tires
And Robbie, who sold
grabbed everything.
More than anything marijuana.
Can you bring me ketchup?
He is Brad.
Brad was the one
really wanted.
But not wearing
fine with us.
Enough in itself to
money selling Quaalude.
That became the King
the Quaalude of Baysack.
Have Vagina there or what?
Bring girls ever
Ok?
I teach some of this.
Do you understand me?
Hey Zip!
Tell your sister that
ask for it.
Bring a pair of her panties
the next time you come.
She no longer wants to talk.
Get out of here.
Mama we?
chicken or what?
Mama.
Do you hear me?
It's easier than you think.
All people on the phone they want
and get rich quick.
We get something for nothing.
I once wanted to sell
marijuana about Amish.
You know those who have beards
and no mustache, that shit.
He says he just wants
make furniture.
I do not understand.
What does that matter?
What are you talking about?
Not to put words
in your mouth but you just said
everyone wants
be rich.
You just said that.
What do they talk?
As Buddha, do not care
money.
They just want to wrap sheets.
Do not buy anything.
I'm not talking about Buddha or Amish.
I'm talking about normal people.
Working people
daily.
Everyone wants to be rich.
Am I crazy?
Good but some believe
in that nonsense.
Ketchup please.
Do not want to make money?
I want to make money, right?
I can sell anything.
I can sell lubricant
a convent full of nuns.
So hot that neither
need.
That's the attitude.
Can you sell anything?
Sell ??me this damn pen.
Sell ??this.
Sell ??me the pen.
Can I finish
eat first?
Brad show him how.
Sell ??me this pen,
come on.
What do you sell
this pen?
That's my boy.
This pencil.
You can sell
anything.
Do me a favor, write
your name on that napkin.
I do not have a pen.
Exactly, supply and demand
my friend.
See what I mean?
You need to create.
Make them want
buy the stock.
As if they needed it.
Do you understand?
That's the thing.
All nuns
are lesbians.
What the fuck you talking about?
Think it can not do
with men.
So you must ...
How often?
I ordered 4 times.
Here it comes.
So if it comes.
I know these guys you were not
Harvard graduates.
Robbie Feinberg, the Pinhead.
Took 5 years to finish high school.
Alden Kupferberg, he Sea Otter
Not even graduated.
Chester Ming, a wicked
China man.
I thought Jiujitsu
I was in Israel.
The most intelligent of the group
Nicky was Koskoff.
He attended school
laws.
He said "Rugrat" for his
awful toupee.
Still Dateli youth
hungry and stupid.
Soon.
The rich do.
OMG.
Jordan is ...
Like baby?
God is beautiful.
They are the largest in the world,
but of very good quality.
They are beautiful.
They are.
God ...
What?
Something tell me.
What is it?
I do not know, I just ...
these actions.
These companies.
Companies are garbage.
Well yeah.
Ok.
They are terrible.
Do not worry, I told you
it was completely legal.
I know but will not make more money.
Right?
Sometimes they do.
Sometimes not.
You know how it is.
Do not you feel better if you
you sold it to rich people
having a fortune in money?
Course.
But rich people do not buy
penny stocks.
Just do not.
Why not?
Because they are very cunning.
That's the reason.
What person with a
college
trust this group
Idiots?
Tell him to call back.
I have $ 5,000 in your phone.
But what it sounded
like a bunch of idiots?
What if you could teach
sell to people with money?
Real money.
So I decided to reinvent
the company.
Knights.
Welcome.
A Stratton Oakmont.
You fools will put in the spotlight
to the richest 1
Americans.
I speak whale.
Moby Dicks.
With this script.
Which is their new
harpoon.
We teach all
and every one of you.
To be the fucking
Captain Ahab.
Do you understand me?
Captain who??
Captain Ahab.
The fucking ...
From the book, bastards.
Book.
Get your brain.
We listen, we are a
new company.
With a new name.
A company in which our
customers to believe.
customers can trust.
A firm whose roots
They are so ingrained in
Wall Street.
Our own
founders
sailed in the
Mayflower.
And they recorded the name
Stratton Oakmont.
In the fucking Plymouth Rock.
Get it?
We will do the following.
First launched actions
Disney, AT & T, IBM.
Stable companies exclusively.
Who is
people know.
Once call
their attention.
We let them fuck
dog.
The Pink Sheets,
actions cents.
Where we do
money.
50% commission, baby.
The key to making money in a
situation like this.
It is to position before
close the deal.
Because when we read in
The Wall Street Journal.
It's too late.
And wait ...
expect and who speak first
lost.
Sorry appreciate the call.
I must think about it.
I'll talk to my wife
thereon.
Can I call you back?
They do not know, right?
They have to think,
talk to the wife
With her fairy godmother, the point is that
no matter what they say.
The real objection is that
do not trust you guys.
Why would trust
in you?
Look at you are a ball
greasy seller, right?
So what you say?
I'm saying that if I put
$ 7 in Union Carbine
I'll get to $ 32.
Lnstruments Texas to $ 11,
will increase to $ 47.
It will come at $ 16
and take out $ 41.
You must tell me now,
Chester
buy me 2,000 shares
Dizzy now. Come on!
Honestly, Kevin.
Really?
I do not know,
you called me.
You're a total stranger.
I agree with you.
You do not know me or
I love you.
Let me introduce my
Kupferberg name is Alden.
Robbie Feinberg.
Chester Ming.
I am vice president
Stratton Oakmont.
I plan on being one of the ...
Best Brokers of my signature.
Not have been there if
I'm not ambitious.
Just wanted to say
you seem to be ...
a type quite sincere.
Thank you.
It will not millionaire
nor poor.
What will this deal
is to serve ...
a springboard for
future business, Kevin.
Do you already feel comfortable
me, Scott?
You must be sure that eventually
find a broker on Wall Street.
In one you can trust.
And that can consistently
make you money.
Does that sound right?
If ... your ...
I must say I am
quite impressed.
What do you think?
Kevin.
Give me a chance with a
Kodak action.
And believe me Kevin.
The only problem
you're going to have.
You did not buy more.
Does that sound right?
My wife and divorce
cost me more.
Yeah, let's do it.
Excellent choice Kevin,
How much do you want this time?
They are $ 5.0 '00.
Kevin's try $ 8,000.
It's OK to be 10,000.
10.
Is that okay?
Excellent choice.
Let me close the deal
right now
and I return the call
few minutes with confirmation.
Kevin, welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
Thanks friend,
I'll have a beer.
It was fun.
Take care, Kev.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Shit, I'm a good runner!
That fucking idiot.
The only thing I'm
certain in this world
are the airlines.
Kusho Airlines, are the future
airlines.
Invest now ...
My name is Nicky Koskoff.
- I'm the vice president of Stratton Oakmont.
Judy sorry for your loss.
When did he die?
When the stock falls
few points ...
My grandfather died,
rest in peace.
I leave a lot of money ...
Sunlight was before
such a thing existed.
8,000 shares.
Yes!
25,000.
A very smart decision
I transfer it to my sales associate.
Well!
Veronica!
Veronica??
You passeth with Andrea.
Anyone seen
Veronica?
Did you have a good week?
Closing month.
$ 28.7 million in
gross commissions.
All of the boys
actions!
To celebrate our act
Weekly stupidity.
I offered to our
Adorable Assistant.
Danielle Harrison.
$ 10,000.
To shave your fucking head!
Yes!, You want this?
You want this?
Let's do it!
? That shaved!
Start!
For your guys information
Danielle agree to use this money
for breast implants.
Already a C cup but now
have some fucking
Double D.
Is not this a good business?
It's the best company in the world!
Donnie burning roof
of this crap!
Word spread about us
by Wall Street.
Even in places
I did not want.
It was not long until
Forbes,
the flagship of Wall Street
be called for an interview.
How do you see the future for
Stratton Oakmont?
In a word.
Diversification.
Sounds good, thanks.
I have more than enough, I appreciate it.
Fantastic.
Can we take
a quick photo?
A total knife in the back.
This damn useless,
Look ...
"He Wolf of Wall Street"
so call me, look.
Your hair looks good.
My hair looks good?
Yes.
Jordan Belfort that sounds like a
twisted Robin Hood.
Stealing from the rich to give himself
and his small band of runners.
See it, read it.
Listen.
There is no such thing as
bad publicity, honey.
Read the article bebe.
You look good in a
important magazine.
It seems you do not understand ...
Check out my resume.
Sorry!
Lord please look
my resume.
Move!
That's why everyone wants to Article
work for you now.
What did I say?
Wait a minute.
You want a job?
Talk to me.
Mr. Belfort.
Forbes asked a
superstar.
Each day dozen
Kids are crazy about money.
They came to my door.
If we hired left the
University of overnight
and spent any
money that had
in a new suit made
our tailor in Stratton.
Are you playing right now?
Literally we put them
clothing these kids.
But this idiot came
snooping.
You know every time someone
rises to the top in this world
there will always be an idiot
try to drag it down.
In a few months, we doubled
our quantity.
We moved to offices
even larger.
It was a madhouse.
A festival of greed.
Of equally between
cocaine, testosterone and body fluids.
Yes!
It got so bad.
I should declare the office
an area to get free.
Between 9 and 7 day.
But do not start there.
Indeed madness began
on our first day.
When one of our
Ben Jenner runners.
He walked into the elevator while one
sales assistant sucked it.
Her name was Pam and
in his defense
had an amazing technique with a
wild tongue movement.
A month later.
Donnie and I decided
do a threesome with her.
One Saturday afternoon while
our wives
bought dresses
Christmas.
Eventually Ben
married with it, which was
amazing considering that it
I Suck at the office.
Became depressed and
killed three years later.
Anyway, my father hired Max
to bring order, as the Enforcer.
The doer of the law in
Stratton.
They called Mad Max.
For his bad temper.
He exploding something
as simple as a phone.
Who has the balls to fuck
call on a Tuesday night?
Damn!
You are going to lose.
Please tell me something I do not know.
Hope all week
for this damn program.
And I can not ...
Hello?
But as soon picked up the phone ...
Gene??, How are you Gene?
He left an accent
English.
That would be great Gene.
Goodbye.
It was bizarre.
Fucking asshole!
Well ...
You missed it.
There goes Mad Max again.
Shit!
Okay, tell me what happened.
What happened?
He discovered that it was his mother's sister.
Who is he?
The protagonist.
You know who he is.
She was the sister of his mother.
Was found dead.
Of course not Mad Max had to know
everything we did in Stratton.
There is a large white
throw them and they stick.
He is a white dollar sign,
who give closer
takes more points.
Think this shit right.
If you get hurt,
What happens?
Let's go crazy.
I do not think gets hurt,
has superhuman strength.
I think it will be fine.
You can not see straight
eyes.
Can not see it in the eyes?
It is a fact, I saw it on PBS.
Confused and cables
intersect.
You must do as you see elsewhere.
Like when I see you but actually
I see your chin.
I feel undressed me, but no.
They are like the Mona Lisa,
find eye contact.
No matter where you are
standing in the room.
And that hook, you know.
There is a limit to what
we can do with it.
This allowed throwing things, food ...
Anything.
But for example I would not do.
And the girls play
with him those things.
I think that would ...
Serious thing to ask.
But this guy is interested
at launch.
If I find this to be
his gift, okay?
They were built to be thrown.
As a long dart,
his head looks like a dart.
They are made to be precise.
My God, can we play
bowling with this guy?
That's his brother,
He is dedicated to bowling.
We can put a suit and upload
on a skateboard.
We threw down an alley
to pine trees.
Shit, that's interesting.
Can we bring this guy?
If we can.
It says here that this type
showing his penis.
Instead of growing.
They are very hot indeed.
So be careful
with these little guys.
Safety first.
I want someone with a
tranquilizer
ready to knock
this bastard.
We could bring ...
Pepper spray, tazer.
Gun shot??
No, that will hurt.
I just want this unconscious
I fainted.
I say we keep
with legal trick, right?
But we consider it a
human.
Just consider it an act.
We'll be fine.
Remember the circus of last year
Many types died
but not sued anyone.
How important it must
keep in mind is ...
These things are
gossips.
They meet and backbiting.
It's a good point.
The last thing we need ...
's Get together and say,
mock us.
That will look bad Stratton.
That's why I love you, thinking
shit like that.
When I try to come
as one of us.
That's it.
One of us ...
Jordan, your father is coming.
Something about American Express account.
Get him out of here.
Yeah, good luck.
I'm serious.
Get him shit.
Ok, guys ...
It's coming.
Invent something.
As your advisor ...
'$ 130,000.
Jordan In a month?
'$ 430,000.
In a fucking month.
Relax are expenses
business.
Business Expenses??
Look what you have here.
What?
Look at $ 26,000 for a fucking dinner.
Ok, this has explanation.
It was by a customer.
The Faizer.
If millionaires
of Argentina.
Ordered expensive champagne.
We had to buy champagne.
We took a walk,
tell about it.
If you clear the walk ...
Is the ride?
$ 26,000 in walk??
Does this walk will cure cancer?
In fact if you cured cancer.
That's the problem, so it was expensive.
Shut the fuck up.
Really.
Basta.
Entertainment EJ.
What the fuck is that?
Well, that's ...
What is it Jordan?
I do not know how to describe this.
Jordan is??
It is a prostitution ring, Jordy.
I know.
That's what it is.
Not the perfect description?
That is what it is
but ... any of this.
Was charged to me,
but all of them.
To us?
I was not, explain
this shit.
Are all your shit
charges.
Guys, the company tax
allow the TNA.
Nothing happens.
TNE.
Yes I did.
Not so, said TNA.
I did not.
If you did.
I never said that.
Said TNA is TNE.
Right.
I know you're upset about dinner
and makes sense.
Because we spend a lot of money.
But tne said.
Do not tell me what you said.
Listen to what you said.
Pope, TNA said.
That's what I said.
There is no doubt.
I try to ...
I'm getting closer.
Papa ...
I'm close to the edge.
So I say, I want
open yourself more.
Will kill you.
Max, why you repress?
That's it.
That's it, get out.
No.
Get out of here.
What prostitute accepts
credit cards?
A rich.
Stratton had 3 types
prostitutes.
The first class, the best of the best.
Wooden model.
Cost between
$ 300 to $ 500.
You had to use a condom unless
you gave them a good tip.
Then came the Nasdaq.
They were well
but not great.
Cost between '$ 200 to $ 300.
Finally the
Pink Sheets.
Whores, costing of
$ 100 down.
But you used a condom.
They had to inject with
penicillin next day.
If you are not like the penis.
I'm not saying the
cogiéramos.
Believe me, we did.
Is this album out
again.
It is what it is,
you know too much ...
Entertainment with EJ.
Papa ...
How are things at home?
Well, they're not right.
She just does not ...
Do you understand?
It's like the smell,
attracting
after a time
simply vanishes.
Slightly.
It's supposed to be.
Supposed to be?
So is marriage.
Your mother and I have been
married long time.
Do you think we jumped into bed
every two minutes?
I understand you ...
I want to stay married but papa ...
It's crazy out there,
some girls are ... OMG.
The things that make
Pope now ...
It's another level.
Really?
All are shaved too.
Do not think so.
All shaved.
Are you kidding?
Really.
Bald as a Chinese dog.
No bush?
No bush.
OMG.
DE soon in a week.
Nobody had anything down there.
They are bald brow
down.
Nothing.
Looks done by laser.
That's the world, you see?
I would have liked
after birth.
I was never a fan
bush to be honest.
Really?
Yes.
I do not care.
Papa ...
Pope did not want you to stresses
these things.
Why did not I going to do?
Watch those fools work.
I know you are stupid
but I need
who want to live
like me, you know?
Long live like me.
Jordy ...
One of these days
will have consequences.
You look at me like I was crazy.
This is not crazy,
is obscene.
It was.
In the normal world.
But who wanted to live there?
Let's take this company.
A fucking stratosphere!
Fuck that Maryland.
Fuck them.
Why should they be
our money?
We will not be second to anyone.
It was our second
and big play.
Find companies
to make public.
IPO.
It was the only way these
idiots on Wall Street.
Stop thinking of us
valiéramos anything or not.
We OnClip internationally.
You see, we were different.
We liked to get high
as much as possible.
During our blowout
business.
To stimulate the
flow of our ideas.
So we took these Ludes
as if they were M & M.
Not sure what a Lude?
I will tell you.
Wait ...
Looks like those Ludes ...
This Donnie doing magic
right now.
The Quaalude
Lude or as it is known
commonly.
It was first synthesized
in 1951.
For an Indian doctor.
Points no feathers.
As a sedative.
Prescribed for housewives
problems sleeping.
But soon ...
someone realized that if you resistías
the urge to sleep for 15 minutes.
You drugged fine.
It was not long until
people started abusing Ludes.
In 1982 the American Government
the banned.
Like the rest of the world.
Which meant that
this was short.
No joke, and not even
can buy.
You ran out of luck.
Steve Madden.
Steve.
Remember those ads?
Those girls giant head
with bulging eyes using
those clunky shoes.
My friend from school,
Steve Madden.
His school friend,
Steve Madden was named as
to women's shoes at the time.
All prayed for Wall Street
take your company public.
Except ... Guess
who grew up with him?
Shoes.
My own vice president.
'Diamond' Donnie Azoff.
Steve.
Hey friend.
You have to see this girl.
Watch this.
Mira.
I'd take that girl
so was my sister.
He would give me AIDS.
Want to see the wolf
handle this?
Shit.
Cristy.
Jordan, this is my friend Naomi.
Hello.
Naomi.
It's my pleasure.
Naomi, also.
Have an amazing place.
I think I had never been
before in such a large house.
Really?, There is a beach
beautiful outside.
Blair Hollingsworth.
Hello Blair, is a pleasure.
Your name is Blair?
Yes.
Like the Jet Ski?
Never had it
done before.
Never in your life?
No, never.
Never?
No.
How often do you
ask me that?
Maybe a couple more times.
Ok.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Hello I am Hildy, delighted.
Hello.
Jordan, Teresa needs
your help.
If you tell him to go in minutes.
Tell him that.
Why did not you tell
that to your wife?
I would but I'm having
a conversation here.
You know, I think we should go.
Wait, where did they go?
We have to go,
there are other parties ...
We can stay for a drink.
If, stay by one.
It is assumed that we would go to the other,
so ...
Let's stay for a drink.
Let it stay for a drink.
Stay, do not make much mess.
May.
Like the champagne?
Clear.
Donnie, what the fuck are you doing?
Sorry my friend,
he gets ...
Get out.
I had to.
Well done Donnie.
I can not believe what I saw.
Is this guy crazy.
Ray Ridge is in Staten Island, right?
Brooklyn across the river.
Territory of Saturday Night Fever.
Here's Guinea Gulch.
They call to bridge the
point of the side Guinea.
Do I imagine that
you're Italian?
On my father ...
I'm also Dutch,
German, English.
I am a mix.
Yes you are.
Yes.
I have family still
London ..
My Aunt Emma.
It's the best.
Fully English, you know.
It has a lot of class.
That explains it then.
What?
You.
I mean, you're a Duchess.
The Duchess of Ray Ridge.
Excuse me.
Can you give us a straw
please?
Thank you.
I was a little ...
Surprised you
Cristy pidieras my number.
Why?
Not yet married?
Yes but what?
Is the married people can not
have friends?
Will we be friends?
Yes.
Will you be my friend?
We will not be friends.
Night work
in my designs.
I have a whole line
lingerie.
Nightgowns, bras,
panties.
Do you design tights
for women?
OMG.
Come on Jordan, think of a way
that up to your apartment.
Want to climb
tea or something?
Tea, yes.
Are you hot?
Yes.
That sounds good.
You ...
Of course, if I want
top bearing.
Look, who is this?
Look who it is.
Say hello Rocky.
Hello sweetness.
Ok.
Well ...
Kindle Fire or something
I'll be out in a moment.
Yeah, fire?
Security.
I like your painting, it's ...
God help me,
How do I pick?
Are these good?
If ...
I just try to start the fire.
That's it, you're gone.
Do not get involved.
Go home to your wife.
As you can guess.
I fucked her until she was crazy.
Jesus Christ.
For 11 seconds.
Now do you come?
Yes, I did.
Did you do?
Did you come?
No.
No?
Ok, I'm still so hard
Just give me a moment.
Security.
Let baby.
OMG.
Get out Rocky.
Bad dog.
Give a cookie or something.
This well.
We will.
Keep doing it.
Go play Rocky.
Go.
These crazy.
I could not get enough.
Her vagina was like
heroin to me.
Nor was it just for the sex.
Naomi and eachother.
I say ...
had similar interests
and stuff.
You like that, right?
Yes.
You, get the damn car!
Shit.
Relax honey.
Relax.
Son of a fucking bitch.
Basta.
Please.
That bitch.
Does the bitch party?
Jesus Christ.
What is it?
Shut up, I never knew
you'd be here.
With that fucking bitch?
Does the bitch party?
Just met her there.
Honey.
Who the fuck are you Jordan?
You are a person completely
different.
I made a mistake not
to tell you baby.
Sorry.
Is that what you wanted?
Do you love her?
Answer me.
I felt horrible.
3 days after I ordered divorce
and Naomi moved to the department.
Say what you want.
But the Duchess had style.
I did decorate to Feng Shui
whole place
even hired a butler.
This guy was smart,
sophisticated. Professional.
Really great.
Jasmine??
Yes sir amaze wanted tonight.
Very well.
Good nose.
Except that one time.
OMG.
Hello!
Already Wednesday?
What the fuck?
That's fucked up!
He must have thought we were still
in The Hamptons.
I thought so.
What did they darling?
They were everywhere,
2 types over there on the table.
Another over here.
Four right here.
Are you serious?
Right there?
Why not me
said honey?
Bebe gets worse.
After they left,
review the department.
What?
What baby?
Where is my money?
I do not know where he is.
Where's my fucking money?
Do not know where Mr. Belfort.
I did nothing.
He's a liar,
lies is all it says.
Let's start from the beginning.
Invite friends, right?
Yes.
One thing led to another,
spun out of control.
We understand that.
We do it all the time,
We are fucking degenerate.
Just look at us, right?
But money was stolen
my department.
Just my sock drawer.
Like I said, not
where is your money.
Let's start from the beginning.
Who came?
It was a normal day,
knew again the next day.
Everything would be fine and clean.
I got a little
at breakfast.
I was happy I did
some eggs, some ice cream.
I know Rudy likes
ice cream.
My friend Rudy, so I call ...
Who is Rudy?
Yeah, who is Rudy?
You know who you are, come on.
Does he know who he is?
Yes.
Who is Rudy?
I do not know ...
You were at the club Lollipop
to know who danced.
Do you know who Rudy?
I know no one.
What do you mean?
Was the club Lollipop?
It was the club Lollipop
indeed.
He was on stage
rubbing with everyone.
That's fucked up, I like to dance.
There is perhaps
know many people.
Listen $ 50,000 were
stolen from my sock drawer.
Like all jewelry
my girlfriend.
Where is?
Who the fuck is Rudy?
That fagot Rudy
took my stuff?
Did you?
Answer me.
Ok, now I understand.
This is because I'm gay.
I can see that.
Because you're gay?
My cousin is a fag.
But I'm going on vacation
with him and his boyfriend.
I love them.
Your are in charge right?
Never steal.
Not that I do not fall well gay.
I do not like you you.
Never hire a damn
Mexican in my fucking house.
Shit!
Speaks cursed.
Speak!
I'll drop.
Where is?
Chester and Toby became
about Yakuza against Nicholas.
Totally crazy.
I had to call the police
to avoid being killed.
I gave each $ 1,000.
I told them what Nicholas
had done.
They kicked him
ass.
Thanks again
officers.
It's not like I mattered
the 50,000.
He earned that almost every day
through a hole or other rat.
A rat hole is a friend,
as Brad here.
Who had shares in his name,
for me.
Who are you?
Jack Nicholson??
I was up prices.
The selling and give most
share of the profits.
You guessed it, me.
All cash, no record
in books.
A big scam to
eyes of the law.
This is our new lawyer
Manny Riskin security.
$ 700 an hour to be
the voice of doom.
Listen, if you screw
SEC.
You pierce nipples.
Do not worry, I have
SEC under control.
What do these idiots?
Hey!
What do they do?
We have here a damn SEC.
Exchange Commission
Security and sent
two guys that kicked
out our archives.
The install in our
conference room.
Les put microphones and lower temperature
air conditioning much so
seemed Antarctica
there.
Is it always so cold here?
I do not know.
While they were looking for a weapon
smoking in that room.
I was about to shoot a bazooka
in this.
Featuring our
IPO last.
An IPO is an Offer
Initial public.
It is the first time an action is
the solvent for the general population.
By making this company
something public.
We fijábamos the
initial asking price.
Then sold them to
Return to our friends.
Do you understand?
Look.
Know you do not follow it
I say anyway.
Okay, never mind.
The real question is this.
Was this legal?
Of course not.
But we made so much money
neither knew where to spend it.
What do you do when you do not know
you spend your money?
OMG.
Will you marry me?
Is that a yes?
Are you sure?
Yes, I am.
I am.
Your you are?
Yes.
I did my bachelor party in
the Mirage in Las Vegas.
He flight to there
It was a bacchanal.
One last blast for
guys before you settle down.
Hundreds of people.
50 hookers and 50 more
waiting to land.
Drugs ..
Our plane was
a pharmacy with wings.
After all,
weekend
It cost me $ 2 million.
Including the cost of returning
to furnish the entire 28th floor.
Kiss the bride.
But the wedding was something
out of a fairy tale.
Naomi, my Duchess.
He found his Duke in the Bahamas.
The club ocean barge.
Of course after
the bachelor goodbye, El Duque
need some injections
penicillin for
we can consummate the marriage
safely.
Hi, Barry Kleinman
filming the wedding.
A word for your child.
Jordan ...
Remember what I told you.
Involve your penis and vagina.
You know what you can do.
Jordy!
OMG.
Good, you came!
Jordan.
Look who came.
Aunt Emma's.
Aunt Emma.
God I bet.
How are you?
Nice to finally
know.
In person.
Dust in the nose.
I lived in the 60s fondly.
Enjoy the day.
What does that mean?
I have no idea.
Only one more step.
Where are we going?
Keep your eyes closed.
One, two, three.
What's this?
Your wedding gift.
What?
Honey.
What ...?
Are you serious?
A damn yacht?
My God, baby!
Like it?
These crazy.
Yes.
Sailed for three weeks
Caribbean.
Eventually we got to Long Island
where we buy a house.
7 acres in Gold Coast
Long Island.
The world's most expensive home.
With maids, cooks,
landscape, everything.
Even had two
guards working in shifts.
Both were named Rocko.
It was heaven on earth.
Get up piece of shit.
Who is Venice?
Are you a fucking owl?
Who is?
I have no idea ...
Did you fuck her last night?
What are you talking about?
Of course not, baby.
No!
You said your name in your sleep.
Are you crazy?
Do not even know what that is Venice.
What the hell does that mean?
Venice is the dumbest thing
I have heard in my fucking life.
Venice baby, where are you?
Venice.
Where are you going?
Bebe ...
you're going to play hardball, right?
Jesus Christ.
I like, I like.
Lobito Lobito.
Lobito.
Lobito??
If my baby is
word to stop.
I do not mind your word.
We will.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut up bitch.
Damn bow.
Truth.
Right, I forgot.
Forget it, baby.
Donnie and ...
in a condominium in Venice.
Thus all these
confusion.
Would invest in Italy.
Not in Italy,
California.
Does California?
You're a fucking liar.
Duchess honey.
Do not tell Duquesa.
Do not.
Think not
what you do?
You are now a father Jordan.
Yes.
You're a father now.
But you still act like a child.
Shit!
Damn!
Bebe have anger issues.
Who was the Volo here
at 3 in the morning
a stupid helicopter
and get up to Skylar?
That was you.
Skylar.
Those are nonsense.
Not even you care.
That would have just made that field
Golf, Bermuda grass.
Now you ruined it.
I have to redo everything and deal
damn people with golf.
OMG you have to try
people with golf.
That tragedy, honey.
OMG.
Probably they had
to pay cash.
With your hands,
horrible burden.
At least you did some work
besides using my card all day.
I can not keep up with you
with your professions, honey.
He eras past month
a connoisseur of wines.
You are now an architect
landscapes.
Is that you?, No!
Fuck you!
You dare not throw me
that damn water.
Do not you dare.
Are you okay honey?
Just talk,
Okay?
Let's use our words,
you know.
's Communicate, ok?
Let sweetheart.
Talk to me.
Stop flexing your muscles Jordan,
you look like a fucking asshole.
You should be happy
have a husband
that is in good shape
like me. Right?
Come here.
Give me a kiss.
You look so beautiful, come on.
Besarte??
You look beautiful.
Give me a ...
Fuck you!
Yes, my morning ritual.
First I fought with Naomi
for what I did last night.
Then I got to sweat vapor
drugs out of my system.
After assessing the damage.
Whitened my eyes.
He took my pills
for the back, to start the day.
Then sought to reconcile
with Naomi.
Good morning daddy.
Where's my kiss?
Hello sweetness.
Daddy will get a kiss
both girls?
No. ..
Papi may even
Mommy play.
For a long, long, long time.
Papi is very sorry for what I said,
did not mean anything.
Daddy should not waste their time.
And from now on.
I'm just going to wear skirts
very small in the house.
And something else daddy.
Mommy is very tired
and boring to use
panties.
Yeah?
Yes.
In fact ...
In fact, she has decided
throw them all away.
So look good daddy.
You'll see a lot of this
the house.
If mommy.
But untouched.
What about daddy?
Bebe.
Look at this shit.
A Mommy likes to play
with Daddy.
Any time you have
noticed
something weird about the
bear there?
His eyes seem to be
a little weird, right?
There's something different about your eyes.
If you think that's true.
Say hello mami!
Rocko Rocko and Greet.
Say hello!
Hi friends,
All right?
Everyday, choose the
today to give me problems.
Today was the greatest day in
Stratton history.
He needed to think clearly.
Jordan.
Welcome.
Already Steven arrived?
This was the day we threw
Steven Madden's IPO.
All are gathered here
and determined.
Everything had to work well
and perfect.
What's that guy?
What do you do?
Most history IPO
this firm, what the fuck does?
Are you using a bow tie?
Hello.
How you doing?
Right.
Are you cleaning
the tank?
If I had a minute and ...
You had a minute.
Just today you had to clean it.
Is today the day?
I finished my paperwork and
had a few minutes.
Ok, nice to meet you.
In this day?
Damn bastard,
On this day??
Is this what you do?
Hey all.
Hear.
This is what happens when
what to do today.
Grab your small
michi tie.
Get your things and get out
my office, you know?
Get out!
All their posts.
We are here to
make money.
All their posts.
A gap of wolves.
Just how I like it.
Jordan look what capture
in the lobby, a genius.
Sign Steven Madden.
Businessman shoes
Women.
Thanks to Donnie were going to put
your business to the public.
Stratton Oakmont was
evolve.
It was not trash puddle.
Therefore they should
see you face.
You have to burn them
selling those shares.
OK?
Not only that
Donnie and I were owners
secret 85% from Steve Madden.
Which speaking in terms
legal was not right.
But we did filthy rich
if our troops supported him.
Our work was
mentalizarlos.
But not much.
Hello, if I could ...
For those
I do not know.
My name is
Steve Madden.
We know who you are.
Your name is
in the box.
The shoes,
Show them.
Ok, yes.
Anyway, this shoe.
It's pretty cool.
It is the Mery Lou.
It's what put us on the map,
I would not be here without him.
It is a shoe for fat.
Believe it or not ...
Believe it or not,
Mary Lou is equal
by Mary Jane but is
black leather.
All right.
Applause for Steven Madden and
amazing shoes, we will lift them.
Well there, I apláudanlo.
Has she pulled out of the system?
Have a good evening or what?
I want to take a moment to tell
because Steve is so ...
absolutely brilliant.
It is because this man
is a creative genius.
This ability, this gift
Steve has.
It goes beyond ...
see fashion in footwear.
His real power.
Is to create fashion.
Do you understand me?
Geniuses like Steve come
only once every decade.
I speak of Giorgio Armani,
Gianni Versace, Coco Chanel.
Among others.
Steve come here a second.
I do not realize it.
Steve Madden is the person
more important
in the footwear industry
Women with orders
exhausted all the stores
North America now.
What we have here in
our office.
We should thank the stars
this man is here.
We should be on our knees
right now.
Getting ready to
I suck his thumb.
Just like that, okay?
I chupártelo Steve.
Ok.
All you're going to suck.
This is our
golden ticket
to the Chocolate Factory.
I want to meet Willy Wonka, okay?
I want to be with
Oompa Loompas damn well.
Come out of the fucking stage.
Get out of here.
It's okay to want to be
focus for a second.
See those black boxes?
Called telephone.
I'll tell you a secret
on these telephones.
They are not going to make themselves.
OK?
Without you ...
They are just pieces
useless plastic.
As a weapon without a Marine
trained to shoot.
The keys of the phone.
It depends on each of you.
My knights highly
trained.
My murderers.
My murderers not
take no for an answer.
My cursed warriors.
Do not hang up the phone
to his client
either buy or ...
Die!
Let me tell you something.
No nobility
in poverty.
I have been a rich man
and a poor man.
But I choose life rich
every moment.
At least as a
Rich Man
I face my problems and
I put them back in a limo
using a tailored '$ 2,000.
And a gold watch $ 4,000.
He has it.
Give, give.
Let me go!
If anyone here thinks that
I'm shallow
or materialistic.
Go find work
fucking Mc Donalds.
Because you belong there.
But before you leave this
room full of winners.
I want you to look good to the person
your side, come on.
Because at some point in
not so near future.
When you stop at a red light
in your car battered.
That person is going to reconcile
on your side
in his new Porsche.
With his beautiful wife
aside.
They have voluptuous boobs.
But really who you be?
A nasty beast
with a supply of razors
Pellos filled sitting next to you.
In a car full of shopping
a cheap market.
Will you be sitting next to that.
So listen to me
and listen well.
Are you behind on the
your card accounts?
Well, pick up the phone and
starts dialing.
Your landlord will bounce?
Well, pick up the phone and
starts dialing.
Your girlfriend thinks you're
a useless loser?
Well, pick up the phone and
starts dialing.
I want that deal
with their problems.
Becoming rich.
All you have to
do today.
You get that phone.
And say the words
I have taught.
I will make you richer
the most powerful CEO
the fucking United States.
They should go out there.
I want Steve mess actions
Madden on the throats of his customers.
Until drowning.
Yes!
Until drowning and
purchase 100,000 shares.
That's what I want today.
Sure.
Be fierce!
Be ruthless!
Sean terrorists
the damn phone!
Let's get this damn
the park!
At 1 pm
opened the sale at $ 4.85 per share.
For 1:03 pm were $ 18.
Even large firms
Wall Street bought.
Of the 2 million shares
for sale, 1 million belonged to me
in possession of fake accounts
for my rat holes.
Now the highest price ...
You know what?
Who cares?
As always the point is this.
I $ 22 billion in 3 fucking hours!
Can you believe this shit?
I love this shit.
Jordan!
Barry Kleinman is on the phone
flame Future Video.
Who?
I do not know, you filmed your wedding.
He says it's urgent.
Urgent??,
Who the fuck is it Barry Kleinman?
My God, will you marry me?
Going to bed with me?
Go fuck your cousin.
Barry, what happens?
Listen ...
There is a citation.
Citation??
What are you talking about?
The FBI wants a copy of your marriage.
Is the fucking FBI?
Are you kidding?
Listen ...
Your name is Denham.
It is an agent of the Office
New York.
What is your problem?
It's a Boy Scout.
It's your fucking Gordon Gekko.
Why do you want the video
my marriage?
It's like an invasion
my privacy. Do you understand?
It is intrusive ...
Has pictures of all
your inner circle.
Images, names
people.
You know you want?
Look at yourself.
Want disconcerting to you
and your wife.
For you and Bug
you become a witness.
You want me to betray myself?
Want information
myself.
Good thing I know
everyone in the city center.
Call the Department
of Justice, the DEA.
No one knows you exist.
So calm down.
Do not know I exist?
No.
That is good.
You know who is right?
Yes.
If you would like more information.
Knowing what he knows.
You could go home.
Going home?
Putting mics on your phone.
At home, to get information.
Do not mess with these
types as well.
Do not play well.
Are you crazy?
It's what you do.
For that you pay.
You have a license Detective, you know?
So I make my living
I am no longer a cop.
Do not take away my license,
Okay?
Ok.
If I can not do that,
I can at least? Calling?
Jordan, Jordan.
Do me a favor, will only
call your damn lawyer.
Whatever you do.
Follow the rules.
What you say.
I use it against you.
Do not you understand?
He is ready.
You are silly.
Shit.
I can not get stoned?
Are we talking
or you will be sedated?
At least terminate the Damned
macaroni.
All right.
Do not call.
Hello friends, upload.
Admission is there.
Welcome.
What a nice day.
Welcome aboard.
I'm Jordan, I welcome to Naomi.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Agent Denham,
He is the Agent Hughes.
Like this?
Let me introduce you.
They are Nicole and Heidi.
We will not be shy,
no need.
Do not be afraid.
They are friends of Stratton.
It's my pleasure.
Hello.
His message said he wanted
talk privately.
Yes, I want to talk
private.
One minute please ladies.
Just call if you want something.
We are happy to help.
Are you hungry?
We have pasta, shrimp, lobster.
Whisky or have any
drink they want.
Know that the Office us
eating or drinking.
Course.
Had he been on one of these before?
A boat?
I learned to surf
when he was 6.
Do not tell me, seriously?
I like this
I mean ...
I had extend the average
to enter the helicopter.
See?
Anyway, this is for you.
It is a complete list of
everyone at my wedding.
I know you wanted the video
bed.
Imagine that this would help
to speed things up, right?
Right.
Look ...
My point is that I am aware
that investigates Stratton
but even if I think too much,
I find no reason.
I know we're not conventional,
We are bustling to work.
You must understand that the competition
must ask for a name.
I want you to understand
no ...
do anything illegal.
Not at all.
You can talk to the SEC have gone to my
office 15 times in the last 6 months.
I have nothing to hide.
Well the SEC is an agency
civil regulatory.
We seek criminal.
Right.
You seek criminal
really.
It makes me think that
I investigate me.
Seriously, what do you think we did?
Or do we?
I do not understand.
Jordan can not argue
an ongoing investigation.
I get it.
With that said.
This case was left
on my desk.
For a new administration,
need load
investigating the new company
on the block.
A noisy boys.
I ended up being the idiot
doing research, exactly.
It's just, you know ...
Bug Me
we are the new kids,
that hit Wall Street.
You should see what happens in
larger signatures.
I know all
information.
True Goldman, The Leahman Brothers
its collateral obligations
in actions that nonsense.
It's crazy.
I can tell you step by step
exactly what happens.
Just ask.
I'm available.
Exactly what I wanted to hear.
Do not see why not
and sit a moment
is not profitable for both.
It should be, right?
Profitable for both.
Should.
Look ...
I will give my personal line.
5 days a week just call me,
feel free to do so.
I will.
Genial.
Insurance you do not want?
drink?
Are not you hungry?
Nothing?
No.
No?
Let me ask you a question, if
very personal just tell me to shut up.
Do I try to get your license
running at some point?
Did you mean to try Wall Street?
No?
Who did you talk?
Who the fuck you talk to?
I did a little research,
Do you see what I mean?
Have you thought about what would have happened
to stay the course?
When I travel home on the subway
and I sweat balls
with the same outfit three days in a row.
Yeah, bet I do.
I've thought,
Who would not?
Sure, who would not?
Another personal question
do not need to answer it.
No problem Jordan.
How do you get $ 15 billion dollars,
something?
A year??
Well, shall we say ...
You get a free gun
when you enlist in the FBI.
But it bothers me,
Do you understand?
When you think of people who
built this country.
Working people like you.
Firefighters, teachers,
FBI agents.
At the end of the day
flayed alive financially.
That bothers me.
That's all Wall Street
and this market
for me I think
reward is good, you know?
There are situations in which ...
I can make those situations
better for people.
You know what I mean.
Timing is everything.
Right.
For example I have a boy.
It was a school
environmental science or something.
He was drowning in
student loans.
Above his mother needed
heart surgery.
It was a horrible situation.
Clear.
But what got the market
at the right time.
With the right actions
and the indicated directory.
From overnight
change his whole life.
He put his mother in the best
hospital in New York.
It did not work for her,
but unfortunately he died ...
We gave him the opportunity.
Do you understand?
One form is
the right team and then ...
the overnight.
Your life can change.
How much internal ...?
How much does an internal
in such a deal?
In that situation.
In that transaction
in particular.
One.
Almost half a million dollars.
Would do that for anyone,
you know.
Anyone need
proper guidance.
Can you say that again?
The way you said it.
Likewise.
I do not know what you mean.
You know what I mean.
No.
That thing just Jordan
to make is that,
if I'm not mistaken,
is that you tried to bribe
a federal officer.
Technically
bribed anyone.
Technically it was not ...
No. ..
According to the criminal code
U.S..
There must be an exact figure
for an exchange of services.
That does not serve them well in
court.
I do not listen well.
No, that's the truth.
But I will say this.
Yeah?
The same gentleman who told me that
Did you get you license also
told me you were a straight arrow.
I check my background.
Well ...
when you ride in a boat that seems
James Bond villain.
Sometimes you have to act the part, right?
I think it is time for
the hell out of my boat.
What say you?
Jordan'll tell you something.
Many Idiots
Wall Street I've caught.
They have no manners.
Do not tell me.
Yes.
Her parents are idiots.
Like their
parents before them.
But you ...
Jordan you get
for yourself.
Did I?
Good for you man.
Little Man??
Good for you.
Am I a little man?
Let me tell you something.
Let me tell you something else.
Honestly, it's no joke.
This is one of the boats more
nice where I've been.
I must tell you.
I bet you do.
You know also thought én?
He fucking hero I will be
in office.
When you seize this
damn boat.
Jordan will be very funny.
It's beautiful.
It also brings the girls
beautiful.
It is wonderful.
Okay fuck off my boat.
Sure we will soon.
Sure, good luck road
home on the subway
to see their miserable
and horrible wives.
Heidi Hare lick my caviar
balls in between.
Guys want lobsters
for the trip home?
Poor devils nor can afford them,
bastards.
Hey guys, look what
I found in my pocket.
Look, a year's salary.
Right here, you know how to call them?
Coupons fun.
Coupons are fun.
Switzerland??
What the fuck is there?
Swiss Banks, that's what you get.
It was time to cover
ass.
He had to hide my money.
Sign Rugrat.
I knew a banker
Swiss law school.
But he was in Geneva.
There was no way to make
the sober journey.
I knew that if I took my drugs right.
You could sleep during the flight.
But he must take the amount
adequate w.
4pm to take a few more Ludes.
That began to take effect
when I finished my speech.
My numbness phase.
At dinner I took a couple more,
along with a few cocktails and a few Valium.
My wandering phase.
8:30 to take a couple of more Ludes.
I lost almost all
my motor skills.
This phase was drooling.
By 10 I did not know that
or who was shit.
This phase has no name.
Board the plane one
shortly before 12.
Look at that nice.
Excuse me sir ...
Soon began the contest
sleeping.
Can I see your ticket books?
We do not have tickets.
I love Jesus Christ
get me something.
Hey, relax.
Why's your hand
damn my penis?
He has his hand on ...
I'll wear the belt.
What's on your mind?
Do not do that on a
public place.
I pluck.
Get it out!
I heard that there is a
treasure down there.
Basta.
Excuse me sir.
Please sit down.
Return to your seat.
Why are you upset?
Please return to your seat.
I'll have to call the Captain.
Please sir.
Please sit down sir.
Please sit down.
Ok.
I'm going, stop.
Sorry.
Ok.
. Ire to sleep.
Have you asked or
we ask?
Fasten your seatbelts.
Ok.
We can not take off
if they do not.
Sit and abróchatelo.
Ok.
Can I do for you?
What?
I'll do it for you.
Ok.
Speaks English, do not understand what you say.
Come here.
I will help with his belt.
Sit up, sit down.
Here we go, well here we go.
Hilfe going to come.
Hilfe.
P. ..
Jesus Christ.
Shit.
Donnie.
This is not funny.
Untie friend.
I can not untie.
The Captain will Moor.
You electrocuted.
Why?
Would you people scream.
Shit.
You were on the floor.
Rolling and stuff.
Jesus.
Called Captain Edward.
Would you call Edward?
Yes, I was very upset.
Really?
Luckily it is first class.
I think you're Jesus Christ
a drug problem.
Where are Ludes?
In my ass, do not worry.
I got this.
Thank God.
Jesus Christ, what we do when
come to Switzerland?
This is bad.
I can not breathe, do something
to calm down please.
Shut the fuck up.
Shut.
Ok.
That is good.
Keep doing it.
Shut.
Mr. Belfort.
It is free to go.
Really?
Donnie is when we get
not acting like yourself.
Donnie Librémoslo idiot, okay?
Why do you claim to me?
Listen the only reason you're here
and not in jail is by my friend, okay?
Hilfe!
We're here.
We will.
Jordan Belfort.
Finally.
Nicholas told me so
about you.
Jordan, Jean Jacques Saurel.
It's my pleasure.
Same to you.
You understand that ended up there?
Ok.
Need a larger sofa.
I do not understand. Sorry.
Curious about its laws
banking security.
Wait, yes.
Sorry Jordan.
The Swiss tradition demands
10 minutes ...
Conversation.
If conversation.
Before discussing business.
If ...
Of course ...
get to the point.
What do you know?
Under what circumstances
you would be required to cooperate with the FBI
or the Department of Research
American for example.
Never?
Yes.
How ever?
Unless you want to invade
Switzerland in the coming months.
So we will check your gas
down the street to success.
If the street.
Say it right.
See, this is what I did
in law school.
Champagne.
If, fries ...
That kind of thing.
What wonder stupid Swiss ...
Are you going to fuck?
I understand perfectly.
American shit.
The only way to mess with
a bank here.
If the crime is also being investigated
here in Switzerland.
But there are several Swiss law
that apply to your ...
practices.
From my point of view.
Now you're in paradise.
Told you it was fantastic,
Right?
If the Department of Justice
American
sends us a subpoena.
Become toilet paper.
We would clean your ass with it.
Unless there is an investigation
in fraud actions.
Which is a crime here too,
if I'm not mistaken.
Then, there should be cooperation
on your part.
I think.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Assuming the account is
under your name.
If you were ...
under another name.
A friend, a comrade.
A cousin.
A cousin, yes.
Pariente.
Yes.
Hark well what I said?,
or am I hallucinating.
If ... other.
Are you saying that you use
a hollow rat.
But one rat hole never enter
Switzerland with all that money.
What I needed was a rat
with a European passport.
Jordan ...
Hello, how's my favorite aunt?
Welcome, traffic?
Not at all.
Thank goodness Aunt Emma
I do not need much convincing.
It turned out that the English were not
very different from the Swiss.
Money talks and bullshit
they go by bus.
How do you say recess rat
in English?
If you get into any trouble.
I will come immediately,
do not worry.
I promise.
He keeps us young risk,
Dear? Truth?
Sometimes I wonder ...
If you have money left
it take over you.
Among other substances.
Is it that obvious?
This is darling,
sweat drugs.
That I can tell, I am ...
a drug addict.
I really am,
but I say ...
cocaine, pills whatever
I'll take me.
That's the truth.
I am also addicted
sex.
There are worse things that
be addicted to sex.
Why I tell you
all this?
Sorry.
Because I am trustworthy.
You are, it is easy
trust you.
It's just my job,
you know ...
all these people depend on me.
There are thousands of dollars
into play.
Sometimes I feel like I bite more
than I can chew.
You're a man with
a big appetite.
Yes.
Are you hitting on me?
Yes, it is.
Suppose that ...
I demand to me.
It was my decision.
It is difficult to know how to control the
anxiety, do you understand?
Relax and let go.
Freeing the tension?
If you are seducing me.
Yes.
Fuck.
Yes, release tension.
Suppose we ...
you only need to learn ...
to do what is
natural part of life, you know?
Are you hitting on me?
Stability dear.
Family.
Take care of my niece, baby.
I'll take care of everything here.
Deal.
We literally
lot of money.
Emma could never load
all by herself.
So I thought,
Who else has a European passport?
You're doing very tight.
Brad, as a successful trader.
He spent his winters at
southern France.
Where he met his wife
Chantelle.
A stripper source
Slovak.
He was born in Switzerland.
This is fucked.
Do not tell me.
It will take us as
15 trips.
It could work.
What about your family?
I say ... all have passports
Swiss, right?
She has parents, brother.
Her brother has a wife,
5 people are right there.
5 to 6 trips and ready,
Right?
All are accursed
Swiss, they can.
At least I have a family
dealer shit.
Do not forget me money.
Excuse me what?
Forgot to tell you he has ...
some money.
My money.
I have a couple of million
underway.
When I give you a call arriving
and you can pick them up.
Will you call me?
When you arrive, I give you a call.
For you to collect.
We do not work for you man.
Honey, you got my money
attached to your tits.
Technically if you work
for me.
Jordan need to talk.
I will not, I tell you,
not for him.
I'm not the errand boy, okay?
I understand.
Listen.
He will take you to where I say.
Tell that to that piece of shit.
If you do not like I want,
lose reason and you'll break your teeth.
The teeth of who?
I put the money in
the damn table.
Not you, I'm the reason
this whole deal.
Calm down you fucking idiot.
Fuck his gun.
You're a fucking mule
I have 5 more like your brother.
Shut the fuck up you piece of shit.
You know what else?
You dress like shit.
So fuck you.
Shut up bastard.
Jesus, are you okay?
How do you like pussy?
Who's the fag now?
Are these good?
Hey friend.
The next day Aunt Emma
Volo to Geneva.
$ 2 million in cash
in his briefcase.
What in the big picture was
just a drop.
For the next more over
6 round trips.
Chantelle's family and friends.
They spent more than $ 20 million in
cash without even hesitation.
I have a little more.
Really?
Thank you.
Welcome.
4 bags are like this.
Are You Slovak Slovenian oe?
Slovenian.
Who cares?
You blond.
Park the car, you fucking idiot.
I can not close the case.
A fucking day, just a fucking day.
You could not be sober?
It's fucked up, right?
You must be kidding.
It is a joke.
A joke?
I'm sober.
Jesus Christ.
It is a joke.
Are you stupid?
You came like a fucking maniac.
You know how much attention
call?
I'm not stupid.
I'm smart.
Intelligent??
Do millionaires treatment.
I am intelligent and important.
Unlike you.
A person who does not
low blows.
When scared, okay?
By the way I have not yet received
an apology for that.
I check my messages daily
when I get to work.
But I have only a light off because
not you leave me a message.
You should shut up.
My wife check messages.
I'm calling from the office each
45 minutes.
Already Brad apologized?
Is there a message on the answering machine?
But I have nothing,
well you treat people.
Got a big mouth,
I'll give you a pass just give me the briefcase.
Can I get a pass?
It is figurative language.
OMG.
The Emperor of village idiot.
Wine from village idiot
to give me a pass.
What do they do in town idiot
when the emperor is not?
Is there chaos?
Do people plundered and violated?
What people do
while you're here?
Scroll up and sing.
I have not lost a trial
in my life.
If you come to me again.
Just calm down.
You know what?
I do not think wrong,
I think you'll like.
So you come to me.
What the fuck?
I've noticed that
have something ...
medium rare,
Do you want to kiss me friend?
Jesus Christ.
What is it?
I do not know.
I alert my side
homophobic.
Are you hot for my friend.
Do you understand?
But I will not go into that.
Please give me enough
the fucking case, okay?
Give me the briefcase.
Right.
You have to do me a favor.
What?
You should take this case.
Driving straight home.
You open the briefcase.
You take every
dollars.
Do not leave anything inside.
I want you to have
organized outside of the case.
The footage and the mess by
Slovenian vagina your wife.
Do you understand?
Damn garbage.
Bastard piece of shit.
What do you think now?
Get off me.
Shit!
Fucking asshole.
Do not move.
Back off!
Do not repeat it again.
Drop the briefcase.
Hands up.
Knees.
Knees, sir.
Damn!
Bastard.
Jordan.
I have a surprise for you.
What's that?
20 real lemons.
A pharmacy was closing
in my neighborhood.
Keep this for 15 years.
Are you kidding?
Lemons??
We are going to get really crazy.
When dealing with
Quaaludes.
Lemons 714.
They were the holy grail.
Can you believe it?
OMG.
I thought they were a myth. -
More powerful than anything.
Look at this baby.
Donnie knew how to celebrate.
He said he kept these
for a special occasion.
As a birthday,
something
or my money coming
safe in Switzerland.
So that night my schedule and clean
me free of interfering substances.
It was time to celebrate.
Ok.
So what is the dosage?
I have been told that only
need one.
Here you go.
Health.
Do you feel anything?
No.
It's been 35 minutes.
Maybe develop immunity
after so many years.
This is bullshit.
I do not feel shit.
They're old, are they lost power?
Look at the bottle.
January 1981.
It is Dutch.
Shit.
Take ...
2 more each.
Yes.
Jordan.
If honey?
What do two retarded?
Ejercitándonos honey.
Bo Dietl is on the phone.
Ok.
OK?
Hey Bo, what happens?
Jordan.
Listen to me.
We can not talk here
but I must speak.
Do not mess around?
What?
Listen, damn salt
Jordan home.
Call me a phone
public.
It's a fucking joke
Jordan.
If ...
Shit.
What did he say?
I do not know what the fuck.
I must go!
All right Jordan?
The phone more public
was close
the country club
Brookville.
It was a fortress
wasps.
About a mile from my house.
I'm Bo, what happens?
I'm at a pay phone, what happens?
Listen carefully,
please.
Your friend Brad.
Your friend.
He's in jail.
Why the fuck?
What did?
I do not know what I did.
But my friends in Long Island
they said they found
in a shopping center and
locked him up.
Wait, what mall?
Yes.
It was with Donnie, due
give money to that damn.
Speak to him.
Listen!
Do not go,
listen.
That kind Denham,
FBI agent.
Someone told me that watching
your phone.
From your office and home.
Do not talk about them.
Ok.
Shit, I understand.
I get it.
Jordan ...
Not try to bribe him, do you?
Of course not, do you think
I'm stupid?
What the fuck you say?
I do not understand.
Say it again.
I said ...
What the fuck you say?
Are you high?
Jordan, are you stoned?
Jordan do me a favor.
Stay where you are.
Do not drive.
Jordan.
After 15 years
stored.
Developed lemons
a delayed explosion.
I take them 90 minutes
take effect.
But once they did ...
I skip all phases and
I went straight to the drooling phase.
These bastards were so strong.
I discovered a new phase.
The phase of cerebral pause.
Come on, stand up.
Ok, I can not walk.
It's okay to think.
Think.
What other option is there?
Yes, I can crawl.
I can crawl like Skylar.
Shit, she does
look so easy.
Think bastard, think.
Yes!
I have it.
I got it!
I can shoot.
I roll!
Jordan.
Jordan?
Jesus, where are you?
What?
Do not understand what you say.
You must come home
Donnie is out of control.
This talking to a
chalet.
I do not know ...
I do not understand.
Do I understand Jordan.
Just come home.
Hurry.
It was less than 1 mile
house.
I drove as slowly as I could.
Vi move gelatin
faster.
Have you delayed
$ 2 million?
Stop talking,
Stop talking!
Idiot.
Out of the way, idiot.
Do you hate the $ 2 million?
No hate $ 2 million
Donnie.
By some miracle.
Get home alive.
I had no scratch
nor the car.
Jesus Christ.
What did you take?
What is it?
Jordan What the fuck?
You do it in our house,
I hope you know.
What are you doing here.
You go up, right?
It was what you did.
Piece of shit.
What?
Brad.
Damn ...
What did you do?
Piece of shit.
Fuck you.
Gotcha.
What the fuck happened?
Shit.
Jordan, are you okay?
Donnie.
Donnie!
Donnie, baby not breathing.
Shit I do not know what to do.
Jordan does not know what to do.
Jordan.
OMG is this
Jordan drowning.
Do something, my God.
Jordan is not breathing,
do something.
Move over.
OMG.
Move over darling side.
Come here.
We will.
Jordan, not breathing.
Do something.
Jordan is a father
have children.
Do something.
Yes.
Are you okay?
Mr. Belfort.
What the fuck?
Lord ...
we have to make
questions.
Are they kidding?
Púdranse.
We will stand up.
Get out of my house.
Come on, get up.
I've been here all night,
What do they talk?
Where are you taking him?
They can not enter the
persons house well.
Did you drive your car last night
Sr, Belfort?
Well ...
It may not come
very well.
Out of the fucking way.
Damn.
Did you drive?
That car tonight?
It was a miracle that no
he was dead.
Neither they kill
another person.
The police took me in for questioning
but they could not press charges.
They had no evidence that it was
I managed.
Meanwhile, Brad went to prison 3 months.
By not informing Donnie.
The result, I was free.
But I had my eyes on
like never before.
You're a man with
Luckily Jordan.
Lucky to be alive
and not go to jail.
Do not believe in luck,
Right?
It's time ...
let me call the SEC
and make a deal.
Before you to stay
no luck.
Wait Daddy.
Hello sweetness.
What terms are we talking?
I do not know, you plead guilty to several
security breaches.
Handling actions
sales pressure tactics, etc ...
Do you understand?
You pay a few million in fines.
For the SEC did not bother
until the end of time.
What about Stratton?
What happens?
There is no future, you must go.
Let Donnie take over.
Donnie.
The FBI is another animal.
I pursued criminally.
But if you resign voluntarily.
I think your best friend Denham
stay with his penis in his hand.
Jordan.
What do you think?
You are important,
already won.
You do not have to work anymore.
Want to spend the rest
of your life in prison?
No.
Ok!
Ok, you have all the
money in the world.
Need the money
everyone else?
Of course not.
Then?
I built it.
You know you do.
Built it now
I Preserve it.
Know ...
5 years ago when I started
Stratton Oakmont with ...
Donnie, I knew the day would come
where it should go ahead.
I come with a heavy heart
to tell you that ...
that day has come.
I want to thank you for
their years of service
and admiration but ...
the point is this.
Under the leadership of Donnie together
Nicky Koskoff and Robbie Feinberg
who are in administrative positions
key, this place is seriously
better than ever
I promise.
OK?
This is your family.
Those who are
they come from.
If your relatives came from
damn Mayflower
or on a boat from Haiti.
This is the land of opportunity.
Stratton Oakmont is America!
Everyone knows Kimmy Belzer,
Right?
Sure.
Púdranse.
Let Kimmy,
they did not know is that ...
is one of the first brokers here.
One of the original 20.
Many know the sophisticated woman
it is today.
Woman wearing costumes
Armani $ 3,000.
Driving a new Mercedes Benz.
Woman spends
winters in the Bahamas.
The summers in the Hamptons.
That's not the Kimmy
I met.
The I never knew Kimmy did not have
2 cents to rub between them.
She was a single mother in trouble
with an 8 year old son.
He had 3 months of your income.
When he came to my
and called me a job.
He asked for an advance of $ 5,000
only ...
pay for education
your child.
What did Kimmy?
We will tell.
I wrote a check.
For $ 25,000.
Right.
Do you know why?
Because I believed in you.
Because believe you Kimmy.
Just as I believe in each
of you here.
I love you Jordan.
I love you for you.
I love you.
So do I.
I love you all.
With all my heart.
Really.
For years they've been saying ...
never accept a non-
for an answer, right?
Continue pressing,
never hang up the phone.
Until they get what they want.
Because they deserve.
This fucking deal I'll sign.
I prohibited from participating in the industry
security and Stratton.
My house.
What the fuck is that?
I'll tell you what it is ...
I'm not taking a
response.
Do you know?
They are selling me me.
No backwards.
I'm being a hypocrite
that's what it is.
So ...
You know what?
I'm not leaving.
I'm not going!
Shit.
The continuous show.
This is my home.
They're going to need a killer.
To get me out of here.
They will have to send the
national guard
or a SWAT team.
Because I will not go anywhere.
Fuck them.
Jordan, Jordan.
Come here.
Hey.
What's this?
Is the jungle?
Hi, Irish.
Jordan Belfort just quit
his dealings with the SEC.
He is back in the ocean.
Happy fishing.
He wanted to
big party.
Just when Brad left
prison also.
I apologize, I even offered her
payment for time in prison.
But I said no,
retired.
She did not want anything
of us.
The sad thing is that two years
later he was dead.
Massive heart attack.
35.
The age at which
Mozart died.
Not that I have much in
common but ...
do not know why I said that.
But within days, the citations
began to arrive.
They asked for documents, testimony,
what you imagine you.
Donnie could not drink water
fast enough.
Do these cops want to send
a subpoena?
This is what we do with citations
Stratton Oakmont.
Jedase bastards.
Jedase!
Jedase.
Jordan Belfort.
Alden is a nice name.
Thanks for that.
What kind of name is?
It is my name.
I do not remember that.
OK?
Mr. Ming ...
Thanks for coming.
Can I have one of those?
Can I eat?
Go ahead.
They questioned everyone.
I was low on sugar.
Duro months, it was a damn harassment.
No member was cracked.
What say?
Does not sound.
Sorry do not remember.
Nothing?
No.
No idea.
I do not remember that transaction.
Do you have more food?
Absolutely not.
Is that what you call
so many times ...
You should remember.
Do you remember any of those?
I do not remember any of it.
Abdul??
I do not remember.
It was a long distance call,
Remember?
We have spoken with several employees
of this firm.
Nobody remembers anything from the
IPO of Steve Madden.
It is strange.
Do you remember anything about that?
If ...
Do you remember?
Not at all.
Sorry, I must ask.
Is that your real hair?
Will you say something about it?
Will you comment on my hair?
Would that do?
Personal Questions??
I wonder why
would use something.
Anything else, gentlemen?
I have a medical condition that I
asks drink every 15 minutes.
Please.
We were told specifically
not to stop the country.
So we took our
wife to Italy.
I found it easier to work from there.
Giving orders to Rugrat.
No one could arrest us.
They could not prove that his way
Stratton from my yacht.
Hey Rugrat.
Good morning bald eagle,
How are you?
Listen.
We have a problem, okay?
Your friend ...
Steve Madden is downloading
actions.
What do you say?
Who told you that?
What is it?
He's doing.
Says Steve Madden this
downloading actions.
Who told you that?
They are nonsense.
Give me that phone.
Wait ...
What?
Jordan, listen.
I see the screen and many actions
Steve they are being sold.
Not we should be.
He is the only person with such actions.
Call me back.
Donnie.
Your little friend
I want to fuck, you know?
I want to fuck,
Contact him now!
You do not know anything yet,
not jump to conclusions.
Although he owned 85%
your damn business.
Actions lock your fucking name.
This fucking knew he was
in trouble with the feds.
I wanted to take advantage.
How do you play this?
Contact customers now.
Do they sell the shares
Steve Madden.
We're going down that price,
Do you understand?
Shut up,
is your fucking friend.
Will your company
a pink sheet, you know?
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
A fuck it!
Starts the engine, we're going home.
Bebe.
What happened?
What?
Aunt Emma.
What is it?
Why are you crying?
This dead.
Who?
Aunt Emma is dead.
Are you kidding?
No.
Really?
My God, baby.
Shit.
Honey that's ...
A fucking heart attack.
Life suddenly.
Eliminated from the face
land.
$ 20 million
in your bank account in Switzerland.
She was fine.
It was getting old.
God, it's terrible.
Shit.
It's terrible, was a woman
very attractive.
My condolences.
Yes, we are devastated.
Thanks for your condolences.
How does that leave us as
Please log exactly?
What do we do?
Do not worry.
Before I die I signed a document
naming you as his successor.
Did it!
Fantastic,
that's good news.
Well, that's not all.
What do you mean?
I can not hear you, I have bad reception.
Do you speak English?
Very fast, fast.
Should I go to Switzerland now?
Speaks English,
dammit.
Quiet, ok?
Go get your suit and get your ass.
Please.
Ok.
Wear my ass, yes.
I must say that these Swiss were
a slippery bastards.
In a few minutes I contact a scammer
I faked signature Aunt Emma.
American shit.
Just had to get there
morning.
O lost $ 20 million.
We're going to Monaco.
Monaco??
Now?
We're going to Monaco
for Switzerland, ok?
His aunt just died.
I understand but I must go
Switzerland now for business.
Nothing to discuss, sorry.
They are businesses.
We must go to London.
Why?
Does he funeral?
Love ..
Look ...
I loved your aunt more than
anyone in the world.
Really I do.
But she's dead now
honey.
Is dead and not anger
anywhere.
Even when life will continue
get to London, right?
Captain Ted.
We're going to Monaco, ok?
A Monaco.
We're going to Monaco.
So we go to Switzerland and
do not ask us passport.
We take care of business.
We return to Monaco.
We will air the funeral.
We returned to New York in
3 business days, that's the plan.
I wanted to say that perhaps
we meet storm.
Storm??
Can we handle it right?
It is a 175 foot yacht.
We're not going anywhere unless
he says it is safe.
Are you okay?
It is safe.
You know nothing about storms.
Really?
Your if?
You're an expert.
Torment your credit card.
Okay, believe me.
All right.
Captain Ted Is it okay?
If we're slowly ...
go slowly, they are uncomfortable.
Tell him that it is safe.
We'll be fine,
hatches closed.
We ensure the cover.
Maybe they break
some dishes.
Piper.
That's nothing.
Is not it amazing?
No.
Not really.
The pass well.
We will now Monaco.
Go!
What the fuck happened?
The Jet Ski fell
overboard.
Jesus Christ.
Is forming a wave
25 feet tall.
Let's go to the other side.
We can not.
Why?
We risk
turn us.
I am a professional diver.
Do you hear me?
I am a professional diver,
nobody will die.
I have you baby.
Trust me, okay?
I love you.
I love you, hold me tightly.
Donnie.
Hold on.
Donnie!
What?
What the fuck?
Going to die, I did many
bad things.
I'm going to hell Jordan.
I messed up,
I did very badly.
Go to the room below.
What?
View by Ludes.
There can be 3 feet
water down there.
I will not die sober.
Go get the damn Ludes.
Ok.
Go!
Where are you going?
Hold on baby.
Donnie, are you crazy?
Jesus Christ.
Get away from the window.
I have them, I do.
Best of rescue
by Italian.
Are you fed,
do you drink red wine.
Then you dance.
Did you see that?
That was the plane that I sent
to rescue us.
Do not lie to them, I explode
when the sea entered his motor.
3 people died.
It was a sign from God.
After all
finally got the message.
Do you dream of financial independence?
But do you have all the problems
months by paying your bills?
Do you want a house like that,
but you can not pay the rent?
My name is Jordan Belfort.
There is no secret to being rich.
No matter who you are
or where you come from.
You can too
in a few months.
You only need
strategy.
When he was 24.
I needed a way not only
survive but to thrive.
At first I thought this
kind of thing possible.
But we have house and a
profit of $ 33,000.
Now if you think so.
Think a moment.
But have the guts to go
Jordan Belfort's seminar.
So as they want
make money?
You'll be a millionaire
someday.
Go ahead, make the decision.
He method Jordan Belfort
started working for me.
Why work hard for that.
But it works for you.
It's because you're lazy and you should
Mc Donalds trabajaren.
Nothing prohibits you from
financial freedom.
Nobody stops to make millions.
Do not sit at home
with a lifetime of dreams.
Because that is just.
Change the lives of all these people,
I can do it with you too.
Come to my seminar.
We will take something ...
You're under arrest.
You must be joking.
Hey.
Away from me.
Turn that camera.
I'm shooting a commercial,
bastards.
Turn off the camera.
Jedase, I'm making money.
Pieces of shit.
Jordan will give you legal advice.
Shut the fuck up.
Fuck you asshole.
I leave the bullshit,
I went to rehab.
I am a TV personality.
Sober for 2 years.
And this happens.
Rugrat was arrested in Miami.
Guess who?
Saurel.
Are you going to hit me?
No sir.
I know your country.
What are the odds?
There are about 10,000 bankers
in Geneva.
But Rugrat elect the idiot who
moves arrest in America.
The worst was arrested
for things that did not involve me.
Nothing to do with me!
Something about money laundering
through boat races.
With a guy Rocky Aoki.
You know, the founder
Benihana.
The Benihana cursed.
Benihana Damn!
Why?
Why God?
Why were you so cruel
email to a Japanese restaurant
to make me fall?
The short story is that
Saurel betrays me.
But not before ratting
Brad's wife.
Chantelle.
Who is picked
every time I went to Switzerland.
2 counts of fraud
security.
1 count of conspiracy
to commit money laundering.
21 counts of money laundering.
1 count of obstruction
of justice.
Bail is set at
$ 10 million.
Uncle Donnie is here.
Rocky!
How are you?
Lobo, I hate that dog.
Yes.
It's getting old
is in the house.
You too.
Shit.
Good to see you friend.
It's good.
How are you friend?
You know.
It sucks man.
But I'm holding.
Look at this piece of jewelry.
I can not leave the house,
You know?
I'm turning crazy already.
Cursed Rugrat.
That fag, I can not believe it.
OMG.
I swear I want to hang him
to death.
Irresponsible idiot.
Tell you what.
I'll never eat
a Benihana again.
I do not care who
is the birthday.
How is Naomi?
How are you?
It's in the house if you want to say hello
but maybe not answer.
Naomi, sweetness.
Are you mad at me?
No, you know ... had to
take out a mortgage to pay bail.
Maybe sell things for
pay the lawyers.
It has been a nightmare friend
it's the truth.
What can I do, right?
Anyway, how does this Stratton?
That's more important.
How's the moral?
Are they upset because they have to
make legal money now?
Jordan.
I met members
founders.
They talk about to do.
I support you.
What do you mean?
The house, the money, do not worry.
I support you.
You're my friend, you know you
do for you, right?
Do you know it?
I know.
I can kiss you friend.
Okay, enough.
Basta.
Want a beer friend?
What do you drink?
Shit without alcohol.
What's that?
A non-alcoholic beer.
It has no alcohol.
Are you a beer?
If no alcohol.
But if you take the sufficient
you get drunk?
No alcohol
that's the point.
I do not understand that
talk shit.
I have beer
if you want.
I no longer drink, remember?
I do not drink.
Want to come and suck
lines of dust?
I can not imagine paradise
not drunk himself to death.
If ...
I love it.
What is sober?
It's horrible.
Boring, right?
Too, I want to kill myself.
There is a term we use less
circumstances dictate
I think that applies to this case.
The term is Granada.
Have you heard about Granada?
No.
It is very interesting because ...
It was a nation in an invaded island
by the American government.
In 1933.
Almost 90,000 people.
What it means
is essentially ...
That this case can not be missed.
OK?, So ...
We can insult,
show many things.
Nobody cares.
I will win.
You sir ...
This lost.
As was Granada.
He faces time
real in prison.
It can launder money
get up to 20 years.
Our case could not be stronger
even if we can find a more evidence.
All right.
Hey Jordan.
Jordan.
You're going to rot in jail until
your kids out of jail.
That is not our ambition.
There are other people
also involved.
We believe they should see
the court also.
Because I'm an Offer
in the air?
Look, it has a smell.
What race are you?
Full cooperation.
It gives a detailed list
of all conspirators.
Also used a microphone.
You said you use a microphone?
Microphone.
What does that mean?
Want to rat?
Is that what it says?
No, I want you to cooperate.
No, he wants to rat.
If we want to rat.
That is exactly
what we want.
To rat.
How was the party
Cristy?
Right.
What good.
Baby talk to lawyers
again today.
I have very good news.
These safe.
I knew that.
Yes, exactly.
Never do anything wrong
to start. Right?
Apparently everything the FBI
want from me
is to cooperate.
I have so much information on stock market
and Wall Street that I can
save the government years
problems, not to mention
countless dollars.
It even gets better baby.
Because if I decide to cooperate.
They only give me 4 years.
In this case we can
start from scratch.
Maybe sell the house.
Any fines payable
will be after prison.
So there will be enough
money left over, you know?
The only thing that annoyed me
this is a bit small
thought of having to ...
give information
about my friends.
Like you said, no friends
on Wall Street.
Right.
Exactly, I thought so too fondly because
said eventually ...
everyone will have to give
information in this case.
Maybe at the end of the day even
be a factor.
You know.
This is good news.
Right?
Yes.
I'm happy for you.
What do you mean?
You should be happy
both.
Right?
Yes, of course.
Right.
Come here honey.
No. ..
Please.
Jordan enough.
No, Jordan enough.
I hate Jordan.
Download.
Bebe ...
Do not do that.
You know how much I love you,
Right?
Stop saying that
please.
Do you want to fuck Jordan?
Do you want to fuck me?
Ok, do it.
Go ahead and do it.
I want you to fuck me
very strong.
I want you to do as
if it were the last time.
What are you doing?
Do it baby.
I want you to do baby.
We will.
Do it baby.
I want you to do as
if it were the last time.
Yes.
Yeah?
Would you do it?
Yes.
OMG.
Bebe ...
God ...
Yes.
Drink that was great.
God.
That was the last time.
What do you mean?
That was the last time
we have sex.
What are you talking about?
I want a divorce.
What do you mean?
What does that mean?
What do you divorce?
Let me go, I want a divorce.
Get off me.
You just make love.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
I no longer love you Jordan.
Do not you love me?
Is not that convenient for you?
Now that I'm fucking with the Feds
and a bracelet on my ankle.
Now you decide that you no longer love me.
Is it right?
No.
What kind of person are you?
Tell me.
You married me.
What does that mean?
Jordan, so things will be.
I'll stay with the children.
If you agree to divorce
right now.
I will allow visits.
OK?, Not fight.
We save a lot of money.
I feel that you'll need.
You're not taking my children,
You hear me?
Now talk to my lawyer.
Although you do not condemn.
I have a good chance
to stay with them.
I have news for you,
not sticking with my children.
Ambitious fucking whore.
Fuck you fucking bitch.
You're not taking my children,
You hear me?
Fuck you, you're not taking
my children.
Bitch.
Damn bitch.
Fucking bitch,
piece of shit.
Look Jordan.
Sick.
These sick.
Fuck you!
You're not taking my kids.
Want that fails you?
Look at yourself.
You know what they said
my lawyer?
They said they will go to jail
for 20 years, Jordan.
20 fucking years.
Never really over.
Do not you think?
Do not allow it!
Did not see you again?
Do not you dare touch them.
Do not touch me.
Sweetness.
You come to Daddy, okay?
Come to daddy.
Do not do Jordan.
I swear I'll kill you.
It is well sweetie.
Let's take a trip, okay?
A journey together.
Buckle up.
I told you to take with me.
Damn bitch.
You will not stop me.
You will not.
A trip fondly.
Do not.
Back up.
Violet sees the door.
Mami.
Get out of here.
I'll kill you.
Mami.
No!
God.
God help me.
Mami.
Honey, it's okay.
Honey.
Are you okay?
What is it?
Speak normally.
Breathe normally.
In 5 minutes you forget
that what you're wearing.
Damn.
Shot.
The offender must not commit or
attempting to commit future crimes.
Please let me signs
damn thing once.
Thank you.
Right here?
That will do.
Thank you.
It was not an option.
Over the next 6 hours.
I made a list.
Friends, enemies.
Business partners.
Everyone who knew me or
received a court action.
Lobito Lobito.
The first name
of the list.
It was Donnie.
Jordan, you know how good
are you back in the office?
Is not the same when there are.
It's sad, do you understand?
Damn Steve Madden, right?
I can not not think about it, you know?
Each time you do
my blood boil.
I can not even say his name.
It's disgusting, I grew
with this guy.
Why do this?
Do any you know something about ...
that account?
Do not incriminate,
Wear a microphone.
You know they were $ 4 or $ 5 million, right?
They had to give me those dividends.
Jordan was drunk ...
If of course, stupid.
If they call you,
be sure to contact me.
OK?
Course.
Yes.
Will you eat the last piece?
It's all yours.
Thank you.
So ...
How is this Naomi?
You know how it is.
I hate death.
How about you?
She still lives so ...
my life is fucked.
Yes.
Mr. Jordan.
Mr. Jordan, you have a visitor.
What?
You have a visitor.
I need to get dressed.
Why?
What?
Going to jail.
I'll wear clothes.
We will help you with that.
Ok.
FBI.
Sit down, show their hands
and shut up.
Get your damn hands.
The dress is Chanel!
Give everyone.
In return I was given three years in Nevada.
In a space that neither knew existed.
As my father said 'Mad Max'
Someday will come the consequences.
Apparently I was right.
I think we can agree that
Mr. Belfort behaved well.
In cooperation finish.
Mr. Belfort made the sentence
almost 2 dozen offenders.
I helped recover millions of dollars
to restore
their victims.
The judgment of the court is
36 months in federal prison.
Please escort the defendant.
Sorry.
I have no shame
to admit it.
When you get to prison
I was terrified.
Belfort standing.
But I should not be.
You see for a brief moment.
I forgot he was rich.
He lived in a place where
everything was for sale.
Would you like to learn how to sell?
I have met in my life bad guys.
I'm talking about rock stars,
professional athletes.
Gangster.
I tell you, bad guys.
But this type.
My good friend Jordan Belfort.
It is the bad guy
I know.
So I want you
give warm applause from
New Zealand to my
good friend and the best
coach sales
Mr. Jordan Belfort.
Thank you.
Sell ??me this pen.
It is an amazing pen.
It is for professionals.
Sell ??me this pen.
It is a nice pen.
You can use it to write
many things, like remembering ...
Sell ??me this pen.
Well ...
This pen works and
I personally love.