Richard. Richard.
Yeah?
I think I heard something.
Stay here.
- Richard?
- God...
Ah!
Damn it.
How you feeling, son?
Peachy, aside from almost
shitting myself.
Yeah, must have been
a scary thing
for a man like you.
A civilian, I mean.
His name was, uh, Freddy Russel.
You know him?
I know shit when I step in it.
I'm gonna have to ask you
to come down to the station,
make out a formal statement,
okay?
Okay.
Now what?
It'll go to the grand jury.
They'll look over
your statement,
your wife's, mine,
and they'll nobill you.
What about the courts?
It'll never get that far.
It was self-defense.
He was unarmed.
Well, you didn't know that.
It's called "fear of life."
Uh, legally,
he might as well have been
pointing a gun at you.
Look...
He's a wanted felon.
You're an upstanding citizen
without a record.
Sometimes the good guy wins.
Hmm.
We're gonna have to keep that
awhile, okay?
Belonged to my dad.
He was a good man.
He'd have been proud.
Of what?
My finger slipped.
You okay?
Uh-uh.
Come on, bud.
Let's go back to bed.
Jordan, son, stop jiggling.
Now, you can't take that
to school with you.
- Why?
- Just because.
Because why?
Because I'm your father
and I said so.
- Bang!
- Hey.
You dead!
Don't you say that to me.
I don't want to snap at you,
son,
but I don't like that game.
Come on.
Let's go.
Dane's Frames.
For you, Mr. Dane.
Morning.
Hello?
It's me.
Just a minute.
Richard...
it's all over the school.
The students keep asking me
about it.
Shit.
Maybe you should go home.
I can't.
I have to talk
with the police later.
What the hell for?
Uh...
I don't know.
They... they want a statement
from me.
How are you feeling?
Fine.
I'll see you later tonight,
okay?
Oh, man.
That air conditioner feels good.
Whew.
I hear you got you one
last night.
Back at the paper, they told me.
I couldn't believe it was you
at first.
I didn't think
you had it in you.
Hey, take it easy, Jack.
It's not something I'm proud of.
Well, it's nothing
to be ashamed of.
Some son of a bitch
breaks into my house,
he better be ready to pick
his teeth out of his ass.
Shoot, man, if it was me...
It wasn't you.
It was me.
Now, Jack, if you got mail,
leave it.
Otherwise, I'm busy.
Here you go, y'all.
Y'all need anything else
right now?
Uh, beer.
Little early, isn't it?
Not today.
Right this way.
Howdy, Rich.
How you feeling?
Like a bucket of shit.
Shake it off.
So what happens now?
We bury the son of a bitch.
When?
Tomorrow,
noon, Greenley's Cemetery,
courtesy of the county.
He got any family?
He got a daddy
in Huntsville Prison.
He just got paroled.
Shit don't fall
far from the tree.
And I can get these
installed today?
Mm.
Ted.
Hey, Rich.
We'll be out of your hair
in a little while.
That couch looks hideous.
We can take it back.
I thought we agreed
on the floral theme.
I made a decision.
I'm sorry.
I didn't think
it was a big deal.
I thought we made
these decisions together.
Can we talk about something
besides the couch?
Okay.
Did you see the locksmith bill?
You've reached
the Dane residence.
Please leave your name
after the beep.
Thank you, and God bless.
Here, looking for the base.
Called safe
by the first base umpire.
Got to try to catch him late...
I guess he ran that all the way.
One and two...
Outside...
Amen.
So we got to get here
at 6:00 in the morning...
I am not getting here
Quiet and peaceful, isn't it?
You're, uh,
Dane, right?
Come to watch the shit
go in the hole?
Very Christian of you.
I'm sure this doesn't make it
any better for you,
Mr. Russel,
but I'm sorry for what happened.
He didn't give me much choice.
Yeah.
You're right.
Doesn't make it any better.
Oh, that was a nice picture
of your family in the paper.
Your boy...
he looks a whole lot like you,
doesn't he?
Now, you have a nice day now,
you hear?
Yeah, it's Richard.
Is she free?
Well... yeah, okay.
Tell her not to worry
but to meet me
at the police station.
No, everything's fine.
Jordan, your dad's here.
- Come on back.
- Jordan.
Hey.
Jordan!
Jordan, hey.
Come on. Come on.
Come with me right now.
We're going.
Come with me.
Get in the car.
Come on, son.
Son, come on.
Get in the car.
Did he say anything to you
at the school?
No, he just waved.
- He waved?
- Yeah.
So what do you want me
to do here, Rich?
I want him arrested.
For what?
He hasn't done anything.
He threatened my son.
He said your boy looks like you.
It's not a threat.
He showed up at Jordan's school.
In broad daylight,
in front of witnesses,
and did nothing.
He wants my son.
I know it.
I want protection.
That's not gonna happen,
not without a legal reason.
I'll tell you what I'll do,
Rich.
Unofficially, I'll have a car
stop by your house
every couple hours
over the next few days,
give you a little peace of mind.
He's probably just trying
to scare you.
Don't let him.
What were you thinking?
Richard.
Why even go there?
It was a mistake, okay?
I fucked up.
I don't like that word,
not in front of Jordan.
What are we supposed to do now?
Maybe you and Jordan
should stay at your mom's
for a while
until this blows over.
What if he follows us there?
I don't want to put her
in danger too.
What about your dad's cabin?
No, it's too isolated.
Besides, that's the last place
I want to be.
I want a igloo colada.
Son, don't talk
when other people are talking.
It's not polite.
Eat your dinner.
I say we stay home,
take Jordan out of school
for a little while,
let the cops handle it.
We wait him out.
We already got bars
on the windows and...
- But I don't want...
- Damn it, Jordan!
Get back in the car.
What?
The lock's busted.
Oh, my God.
Go to the Fergusons'
and call the police.
Ask for Price.
What are you doing?
Aren't you coming with us?
- Richard, get in the car.
- Ann, get, now.
Come with us.
I said go.
- Richard, don't be stupid.
- Go, Ann.
Whoever it was
knows his way around
alarm systems.
We know who it was.
Excuse me, Detective.
That goes for everybody.
I was wrong.
I thought he'd move on,
but at least we have
a reasonable suspicion now.
That means I can give you
official protection.
Now, all you got to do
is be normal...
go to work,
take Jordan to school,
be seen.
And everywhere you go,
I'll have someone watching.
So when he makes his move,
we make our move.
So we're the bait.
For want of a better word, yeah.
What do you say, Ann?
Let's nail that son of a bitch.
I got men
hiding out in the woods.
He sees me drive away,
he's gonna think
you're here all alone.
This is Kevin.
He's a good man,
ex-Special Forces.
- Anyone see you come in here?
- Piece of cake.
Kevin's gonna stay here with you.
For how long?
As long as it takes.
What do we do?
You go to bed.
Get some sleep.
You're gonna need it.
I like him when he's sleeping.
Yeah.
He's sweet.
God damn...
It's one of the neighbors
looking for his dog, over.
Any word?
Nothing so far.
Lieutenant, come in.
Yeah. Price here.
Lieutenant,
we just found his car
about 1/4 mile south of you.
Any sign of him?
No.
Well, fan out and see
if you can flush his ass.
Kevin?
He's in the fucking house!
What the hell?
He's in the goddamn house!
Jordan!
Move! Go! Go!
Haul your ass!
Price!
Jordan?
Get the door.
- Let them in the door.
- Ah!
The door's locked.
Somebody go around back.
- I can't get it open!
- Open up, Ann!
Jordan!
Oh.
He's in the woods.
Move. Move.
Thank God.
Oh!
Tracked him down to the river,
but the rain's making it hard.
How'd he get in?
How'd he get in the house, Ray?
He never left.
Son of a bitch
was in the crawl space
the whole time.
Jesus Christ.
We'll get him, Rich.
Don't you worry.
Nuevo Laredo?
Yep, piece of shit
went to Mexico.
Mexico?
Federales picked him up
across the border.
We got him, Rich.
Dragging him back to Huntsville
as we speak.
His age, he'll never set foot
in this county again.
Listen, uh,
we just wrapped the paperwork
on the Freddy file.
Why don't you stop down
and we'll close this out
for good?
Then you owe me a beer,
compañero, okay?
Okay.
That's it.
Sign these last two,
and you're on your way.
All right.
What's this?
It says "Freddy Russell."
So?
So that's not the guy I shot.
Is that some kind of mistake
or what?
That's Freddy Russel.
It's just a bad mug shot,
not very recent.
People change, Rich.
Well, not that much.
You were pretty upset
that night, remember?
Yeah, he died
right in front of me.
I look at pictures of faces
all day.
That is not the guy.
It's called shock, okay?
Memory gets a little fuzzy.
It happens.
Now, why don't you go home
and let me deal
with the police work, huh?
Give my regards to Ann, huh?
Sheriff's offices.
Price here.
Hey, Ray.
This is Richard Dane.
What is it, Rich?
That wanted poster
is bugging me.
It's not him, Ray.
We've been through this.
It's late. I'm busy.
Give it a rest.
Well, just hear me out.
I did, and you're wrong.
Case closed, over.
Now get some sleep.
Sheriff's office.
Yeah, Lieutenant Price, please.
Sorry. He's not here, sir.
Can I take a message?
Come on.
Bring him down here.
Move along.
Let's go.
Keep him quiet.
That's it.
Get him out.
Get down.
That's good.
There you go.
Going down.
Get down.
- Down.
- Get down.
Whoa.
What happened to your shoes?
Oh.
I drove out and checked
on the cabin yesterday.
Must have stepped in some muck.
I thought you didn't like
going there.
Yeah, I know,
but I figured
I got to clean it out sometime.
And?
My father
didn't leave much behind.
There you go.
Richard?
I didn't kill your son.
Fuck you.
Look, I think the cops
have been lying to us both
all along.
Where's my shoe?
The cops are up to something,
right?
Something to do with your son,
with you.
Why do they want you dead?
How should I know?
Same reason you do.
Look.
Something's going on.
They used my family as bait
to find you.
Now, I want to know why.
Did you take my lighter?
No.
Well, where is it?
What's the matter?
You scared?
Huh?
When's the last time
you heard from your son?
Oh, it's been a good long while.
He was about the same age
as your boy.
I could have left you
on those train tracks,
but I didn't.
I didn't kill your son.
Who you gonna trust,
the cops that just tried
to kill you or me?
All I know is what I'm told.
And I'm told I got nothing left.
I didn't kill your son.
So you say.
Okay.
You're coming with me.
Ah...
Dig.
Do it.
Ugh. Jeez.
That ain't him.
That's not Freddy.
God...
Jesus.
Who would do that?
Somebody who didn't want him
identified, ever.
Come on.
Get out of there.
What do we do now?
We?
Yeah.
I'll pay you back.
- Hey.
Ben.
Russel.
Long time.
I need some help.
It's about my son.
Good morning.
Ray.
You got a minute?
Yeah.
What do you need?
I was wrong to hang up on you
the other night.
I want to apologize.
Oh, forget it.
No, you were right.
I was all worked up
over nothing.
No, you were concerned,
and you were kind of right.
See, Freddy...
he was wanted.
He dyed his hair.
He was wearing contact lenses.
That's why you were confused.
Well, I'm just glad
his old man's headed back
to prison.
Any day now.
I'm sure you're doing
everything you can.
I appreciate that.
Important thing is, he's not
a threat anymore, right?
Can I help you?
You think you could corral
this little filly
in a frame for me?
Kind of a rush job.
It don't have to be too fancy.
You're busy, Rich.
I'll catch you.
All right.
- Sounds like old Ben's
got himself
in a real shitstorm this time,
and he's dragged you
right in there with him.
Who are you?
Name's Jim Bob Luke.
Luke Detective Agency,
Houston, Texas.
This one made it all the way
to the Houston paper.
Front page.
Mentions Freddy four times,
just in case you missed it.
This is six weeks ago.
Buried on the back page.
Mentions Freddy once.
So he turned
state evidence, then?
And your boy found himself
on the ass end
of a federal case.
Now, we know Freddy
ain't no saint,
but if he's messing around
with these boys
in the Dixie Mafia,
they some bad dudes.
How far do you want
to take this, Ben?
If he's alive,
I want to see him.
All right.
Well, I got some hunches
on that.
I want to feel them out first.
But first thing,
we got to relocate.
If Price is as slick
as his mustache,
we got to get the old hoss here
out of the county.
What do I do?
For now, just go home,
you know, act dumb.
Let me do some legwork,
and when I get Russel
settled somewhere,
I'll... I'll give you a call.
Hey, thanks.
Thanks.
Over here.
Wanted to buy you a drink,
partner,
for bringing Holly back
in one piece.
Yeah.
Last time, he blacked her eye.
Someday,
someone's gonna settle...
I'd like to do it myself.
At one time, a Singapore Sling
would have been the only answer.
What?
No, no, no, no.
Say that again.
You broke up.
I-I can't...
No, I'm...
I'm catching every third word.
Say it again.
Here you go.
All right, thanks.
What'd you find out?
Well, I made a bunch of calls.
I got this gal
I used to run with.
She works in the office
of the FBI.
It seems Freddy
is assigned to
the witness relocation program.
You know what that is?
They give people a new start,
new name, new place...
mob informers and shit.
Yeah, you got the picture,
framer.
They're the ones
that set you up.
So over the last couple years,
your son's been running
with the Dixie boys,
doing whatever Mafia types do.
And the shit gets
way over Freddy's head,
and the law
comes down on him hard.
So to keep from going
to the slammer,
he starts to sing
like a little bird
against his old buddies,
the Dixie boys.
Now, you don't want to fuck
with the Dixie Mafia.
And the feds know that,
so they make Freddy a deal.
They'll hide him
if he gives them what they need.
So they faked it.
It's beautiful.
If the Dixie Mafia believes
that Freddy is dead, well...
What's the use of gunning
for a dead guy, right?
Good plan, don't you think?
Then who's in that grave?
Yeah, and where's my son?
Well, that's a good one.
Oh!
That would be for me.
These things are amazing.
You seen these?
Ah, fuck, you've been
in prison forever.
Jim Bob.
You're breaking up.
Hold on.
Okay, that's better.
Go ahead.
You should really be scared...
I need another beer.
Well, if it ain't Josey Wales.
Hey, kill any banditos lately,
cowboy?
Jack, you're drunk.
Leave me alone.
Ah, let me buy you a drink.
And you can tell me
about how you...
I don't want your drink, Jack,
and I don't want your company.
Let me tell you something,
Mr. Dane...
Ahh!
Oh, God!
Hurts, doesn't it?
Hey. Hey. Let him go.
It's not a good idea.
You didn't have to do that.
Well, I didn't want to see you
damage the fella.
Can we get three beers?
In Washington,
it has been established that
persons who have recently died
have been returning to life
and committing acts of murder.
Widespread investigation
of morgues and funeral homes...
Hoss, if you want to see your boy,
we got to move.
You can stay at my place.
Human victims...
Y'all are leaving?
This whole operation's being run
out of the Houston office.
That's my hood.
Freddy will be close by.
Behind locked doors...
I'm going with you.
That situation has now changed,
and we're able to report
a definite...
I still don't know who I shot.
Civil defense machinery
has been organized
to provide rescue stations
with food, shelter...
I have to tell my wife
something.
And protection
by armed National Guardsmen.
I don't know.
Seems kind of sudden,
doesn't it?
Well, this is a good
opportunity for the shop.
Uh, have you been drinking?
Yeah, I stopped
and had a couple.
I'm celebrating.
If I get this contract,
well, it'd be big.
You're serious about this,
aren't you?
Mm-hmm.
Well, how long
will you be gone for?
Just a couple days,
no more than a week, I figure.
I don't know.
I don't like the idea
of you going to Houston
and leaving me and Jordan
all alone.
Well, they got him, Ann.
Don't make me sound girly.
Well, don't act girly.
Don't tease me, Richard.
Well, you should be happy.
I've been waiting
for something big like this.
Well, will it stop you
from moping around the house?
Maybe we can go
on a vacation after,
someplace cool?
It's been a while
since we've been away.
Yeah.
We could drop Jordan
at your mom's
and have us a little adult time.
Hmm?
You want to do it, Sparky?
You haven't called me that
since high school.
- Mm.
- You are drunk.
Drunk and randy...
I thought
that's how you like me.
Let's get us some java.
When you said
he was a pig farmer,
I thought you were kidding.
Morning, boys.
Come on in,
and I'll make you some bacon.
The DMV issued
162 new driver's licenses
to males in Freddy's age range.
Out of that stack,
93 of them poor bastards
is married.
So of the single dudes,
47 of 'em is Caucasian,
and a whole of 28
around 6 feet tall.
Well, any of 'em got blue eyes?
Grand total of two.
Well, what about them?
Why don't we start with them?
Already did.
Well, at least the first one.
And?
That sorry son of a bitch
still lives with his parents.
But the other one...
this one right here...
one Frank C. Miller,
blond, blue-eyed,
6 feet and change,
the same Mr. Miller
who just ordered cable
and a phone line
at his new house
outside of Houston.
And previous address unknown.
That's not bad for a pig farmer.
Well, when I crack this case,
I might just let you
frame the headlines, framer.
Best way to find out for sure...
call him.
No, I want to take a look
at him first.
Come on, you cranky old bastard.
Just call him up.
I ain't calling him.
That's the house right there.
That's not the color I pictured.
Well, we're not even sure
it's him yet, are we?
No better time than the present.
You make it sound like
it's some kind of showdown.
Well, in a way, it is.
- I have to make...
- Watch out!
- Ah! Shit!
- Damn!
What the fuck?
Jesus!
What in the dog shit
is wrong with you?
Don't you have any mirrors
on this damn Pinto?
Do you know how to use them?
Who's gonna pay for...
we could split it.
Ah!
Oh!
You... ah!
Hey!
You want some of this?
Huh?
That's for my car.
And that's for my hat.
Ben, check him.
God damn.
Tore my fucking head off.
It ain't Frankie Miller, is it?
No, smart-ass.
Huh.
Good thing he wasn't in
an OK Corral mood.
Goddamn piece of shit Pinto!
What's that?
Home movies, looks like.
Shut up!
Ah, he's moving.
"Batting Practice"?
Let's get a look at his swing.
Take that gun and shoot
that fucking dog, will you?
She's cute, man.
Is this your first...
ask her if this
is her first time.
Hey, it's me.
Uh, I'm in Houston,
and everything's fine.
I got a meeting
in a little while.
I'll call you later
and let you know how it went.
Yeah, there you go.
Okay.
Love you both.
Get on top of him.
Yeah, I like that.
Yeah.
How old... how old are you?
She ain't even old enough
to drive.
What did she say?
So he's a pervert.
Let's turn this shit off.
Whoo!
Yeah!
Hello?
Let's tell him
we got the wrong house
and we can't find the guy
or some shit.
What about Freddy?
You saw that trunk.
There are a lot more tapes
where that one came from.
Doesn't that matter to you?
Well, yeah,
it matters to me.
But we can't tell Ben
about any of it, not yet.
About what?
It ain't nothing
we need to jump into right now.
What's on the tape?
Do yourself a favor, hoss.
Huh?
How do you work
this fucking thing?
She's cute, man.
Is this your first...
ask her if this
is her first time.
Ben?
Hey.
Open the door.
Open the door, Ben.
Put the gun down.
Would you put the gun down, Ben?
We could go to the cops
and show them the tape.
Well, it wouldn't do any good.
They know what their boy
is doing.
He is protected.
But he's killing women.
Prostitutes who cross
the border illegally,
and nobody cares.
How long you known him?
We were in Korea together.
He saved my life.
He never said
he was in the service.
I don't know whether
you've noticed it or not,
but old Ben ain't much
on the small talk, is he?
Stubborn as a mule, though.
Get some rest, boy.
All right.
What the fuck?
I got cows in that pasture.
What are you gonna do
when a dog goes bad on you,
bites somebody
or hurts somebody?
There's only two things
you can do, right?
You either chain him up
or put him down.
But which do you think
is more cruel?
Huh?
You talking about killing
your own son?
That's crazy.
Well...
I can't very well
chain him up, can I?
I need a drink.
Haven't even had
my goddamn coffee yet.
Son of a bitch.
Thank you, darling.
You got it, baby.
Have you given any thought
as to how you're gonna do
this thing?
Well, it ain't rocket science.
What about the big Mex?
If he's there,
we'll shoot him too.
Oh, good.
Well, I'm glad you got a plan.
I was worried that
you were just gonna wing it.
You got a better idea?
Not yet,
but I'm working on it.
Just remember, he's my son,
and I'm pulling the trigger.
Good luck.
Hey, there.
Hey.
Ho! Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I didn't see you.
That's okay.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
- Okay, ice cream?
- No.
- No?
- Potato sauce.
Potato sauce?
And his low throw allows...
Glad the trip went well.
I hope you get the contract.
What?
I said I'm glad
the trip went well.
Man on first and third...
Oh.
Takes the plate.
Here it comes,
the two-and-two pitch.
Hits it sharp!
Going back! Going back!
It's out of here!
I'll tell you...
Call.
What do you got?
Show 'em.
Framer's back.
Well, how about that?
The video store is a cover.
Your boy's got more brains
than you do, Ben.
Must take after his mama.
Okay, framer, go in there
and look for exit doors
and side rooms,
things like that.
You got it?
And just act normal, all right?
What about the Mexican?
Just be quick about it.
Okay, okay.
Hey.
Is there something
I can help you with, sir?
Yeah, uh...
You have
a foreign films section?
Don't carry nothing foreign
but Jap and Mex stuff.
Uh, that's right,
just Japanese and Mexican fare,
uh, some British too.
We got limey stuff?
George, I prefer you not use
offensive terms like that
if you're gonna work for me,
okay?
Yes, sir.
I didn't mean nothing by it.
Sorry.
Uh...
It's all right.
Is there anything else
that I can help you with today?
Uh...
Yeah, uh, what time y'all close?
11:00 p.m., sharp.
Shit.
All right.
Chicken?
No, they out of the chicken...
only beef.
Oh, actually, hey, you know,
I just got this new release in
from, uh...
what...
You all right?
Yeah.
They close at 11:00.
Ben.
Eenie, meenie.
Here.
Just in case.
All right, that's them.
Let's make this quick.
Just tell us when.
Oh, shit, shit, shit.
Oh, fuck.
They got company.
I don't like this.
Let's take 'em all on.
- There's six of 'em, Ben.
- Ooh!
We don't know how many more
are on the inside.
Ah, fuck 'em.
Ben.
We're gonna do this
the right way.
Are you feeling me, Ben?
Take the gun out of my ear, Jim.
I'm feeling you.
Wait. Look.
All right, see ya.
What do we do?
Follow 'em.
All right.
This must be where they do it.
Lot of cowboys down there, Ben.
You want to rethink your math?
Fuck the math.
Looks like there's only
gonna be one left outside.
That means five on the inside,
plus the girl.
Count to ten,
and then one of you
step out and get his attention.
I'll do the rest.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six...
You're actually counting?
He... he said to count.
Damn.
Oh, shit.
Hey.
All right, boys,
it's Howdy Doody time.
Hey, hey.
I'll be upstairs.
Yeah, I'll be upstairs.
This guy...
so I told you I'm coming.
Hold on.
- Tell me again.
- I told you already.
Get me a drink.
What was that?
Get your ass back down here!
No! No, no.
Ah!
Ah! Fuck!
Fucking shot...
Who the fuck are you, man?
Fuck!
Fu...
Thanks.
Hey, up here, boys.
Ah!
Fuck!
Go down!
Shit.
Ah!
It's all right.
Shh.
You're all right.
It's okay.
- Fucker!
- Ah!
Ben.
Take the shot.
Freddy...
I... I'm Ben Russel.
I'm your father.
I came here to kill you.
Are you really my dad?
Far as I know.
~ COrrected by Dragonborn ~
♪ Wait, wait ♪
♪ I never had a chance
to love you ♪
♪ Now I only want to say ♪
♪ I love you one more time ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ Just a moment ♪
♪ Before our love will die ♪
♪ 'Cause I ♪
♪ Must know the reason ♪
♪ Why we say good-bye ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ Just a moment ♪
♪ And tell me why ♪
♪ 'Cause I ♪
♪ Can show you loving ♪
♪ That you won't deny ♪
♪ I said wait ♪
♪ And show you loving ♪
♪ Like it was before ♪
♪ 'Cause I ♪
♪ Won't let that feeling ♪
♪ Walk out through the door ♪
♪ I said wait ♪
♪ Just a moment ♪
♪ And try once more ♪
♪ 'Cause, babe ♪
♪ I need to hold you ♪
♪ Like I did before ♪
♪ So if you go away ♪
♪ I know that I will follow ♪
♪ 'Cause there's
a place inside ♪
♪ My heart that tells me ♪
♪ Hold out ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ I never had a chance
to love you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ If only our love
could show you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ I never want to be
without you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ No, I never had a chance
to love you ♪
♪ Now I only want to say ♪
♪ I love you one more time ♪
♪ So if you go away ♪
♪ I know that I will follow ♪
♪ 'Cause there's
a place inside ♪
♪ My heart that tells me ♪
♪ Hold out ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ I never had a chance
to love you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ If only our love
could show you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ I never want to be
without you ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ No, I never had a chance
to love you ♪
♪ Now I only want to say
I love you ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ I beg you to wait ♪
♪ No, I never had a chance
to love you ♪