That's not what I'm
saying, you imbecile.
God, you completely
misrepresent my ideas!
Why am I even bothering
talking to such idiots?
Boris, calm down.
No, don't tell me to...
I am calm.
Don't jump on us
just because
we don't understand
what you're saying.
I didn't jump on you.
It's not the idea behind
Christianity I'm faulting,
or Judaism,
or any religion.
It's the professionals who've
made it into a corporate business.
There's big money in the
God racket. Big money.
Here we go.
- We know, Boris.
Hey, the basic teachings of
Jesus are quite wonderful.
So, by the way, is the original
intention of Karl Marx. Okay?
Oh.
Hey, what could be bad?
Everybody should share equally.
Do unto others. Democracy.
Government by the people.
All great ideas.
These are all great ideas,
but they all suffer
from one fatal flaw.
Which is?
Yeah, what's that?
Which is they're all based
on the fallacious notion
that people are
fundamentally decent.
Give them a chance to do
right and they'll take it.
They're not stupid,
selfish, greedy,
cowardly,
short-sighted worms.
They do the best
they can.
Speak for yourself, man.
Speak for yourself.
All I'm saying is
that people make life
so much worse
than it has to be
and, believe me, it's a
nightmare without their help.
But on the whole, I'm sorry
to say, we're a failed species.
I wouldn't go
that far.
Not Ed.
That's why this
woman you like, Joe,
so what if she's
an embalmer's assistant,
so she stinks
from formaldehyde?
For Christ's sake,
you got to take
what little pleasure you can
find in this chamber of horrors.
A little formaldehyde,
okay, but she reeks of it.
You know, they don't
know your story.
Boris, tell them
your story.
My story is,
whatever works.
You know, as long as
you don't hurt anybody.
Any way you can
filch a little joy
in this cruel,
dog-eat-dog,
pointless, black chaos.
That's my story.
No. That's not...
Tell them the story.
Tell them.
Yeah. Tell them.
You just want me to say
it again, so they can hear.
Who?
- Them.
- Who's them?
You see something out there?
- Where?
What are you?
An imbecile?
There's an audience full
of people looking at us.
An audience?
- What's he talking about?
You feel you're
being watched.
They paid good money for
tickets, hard-earned money,
so some moron in Hollywood
can buy a bigger swimming pool.
Okay, you're saying there
are human beings out there
who bought tickets
to watch us.
Well, mostly they're
interested in me, I have to say.
Yeah, they're just sitting
there. Don't you see them?
Some are eating popcorn, some
are just staring straight ahead
breathing through their
mouths like Neanderthals.
So they're there
to listen to your story?
Total delusions of grandeur.
Completely.
Why would you want
to hear my story?
Do we know each other?
Do we like each other?
Let me tell you
right off, okay?
I'm not a likeable guy. Charm
has never been a priority with me.
And just so you know, this is not
the feel-good movie of the year.
So if you're one of those
idiots who needs to feel good,
go get yourself
a foot massage.
Mom, that man's
talking to himself!
Come away, Justin.
What the hell does it all mean anyhow?
Nothing. Zero. Zilch.
Nothing comes
to anything,
and yet there's no shortage
of idiots to babble.
Not me. I have a vision.
I'm discussing you.
Your friends, your co-workers,
your newspapers, the TV.
Everybody's happy to talk,
full of misinformation.
Morality, science, religion,
politics, sports, love.
Your portfolio,
your children, health.
Christ. If I have to
eat nine servings
of fruits and vegetables
a day to live,
I don't want to live. I hate
goddamn fruits and vegetables.
And your omega-3's and the
treadmill and the cardiogram
and the mammogram
and the pelvic sonogram
and, oh, my God,
the colonoscopy!
And with it all, the day still
comes when they put you in a box
and it's on to the next
generation of idiots
who'll also tell
you all about life
and define for you
what's appropriate.
My father
committed suicide
because the morning newspapers
depressed him.
And could you blame him?
With the horror and corruption
and ignorance and poverty
and genocide and AIDS and
global warming and terrorism
and the family-value morons
and the gun morons!
"The horror," Kurtz said at the
end of Heart of Darkness.
"The horror."
Lucky Kurtz didn't have the Times
delivered in the jungle,
then he'd see
some horror.
But what do you do?
You read about some
massacre in Darfur
or some school bus
gets blown up,
and you go,
"Oh, my God, the horror!"
And then you
turn the page
and finish your eggs
from free-range chickens.
Because what can you do?
It's overwhelming.
I tried to commit
suicide myself.
Obviously,
it didn't work out.
But why do you even want
to hear about all this?
Christ, you got
your own problems.
I'm sure you're
all obsessed with
any number of sad
little hopes and dreams.
Your predictably
unsatisfying love lives.
Your failed
business ventures.
"Oh, if only I'd
bought that stock!"
"If only I had purchased
that house years ago!"
"If only I had made
a move on that woman."
If this, if that.
You know what?
Give me a break with your
"could haves" and "should haves."
Like my mother
used to say,
"If my grandmother had wheels,
she'd be a trolley car."
My mother didn't have wheels.
She had varicose veins.
Still, the woman gave birth
to a brilliant mind.
I was considered for
a Nobel Prize in physics.
I didn't get it.
But, you know,
it's all politics,
just like every
other phony honor.
Incidentally,
don't think I'm bitter
because of some
personal setback.
By the standards of a
mindless, barbaric civilization,
I've been pretty lucky.
I was married to a beautiful
woman, who had family money.
For years we lived
on Beekman Place.
I taught at Columbia.
String theory.
What's the matter, Boris?
I'm dying!
What is it?
Should I call
an ambulance?
No! No, not now! No, not tonight!
I mean, eventually!
Boris, everybody dies.
It's unacceptable!
Your panic attacks are getting
more frequent and more intense.
You have to go
back on your medicine.
I'm not going back
on my goddamn medicine.
I won't have my mind
befuddled by chemicals
when I'm the only one who sees the
whole picture for exactly what it is.
Where's the goddamn vodka?
Boris, I have clients to see
tomorrow morning.
It is 4:00 a.m.!
Clients. Right.
Wealthy bankers.
To design their
chic apartment,
to fill it full of art and
expensive possessions,
so they can
flaunt their money
and be in the top 1% of this
shameful, violent, prejudiced,
illiterate, sexually repressed,
self-righteous nation!
Christ, it is 4:00 a.m.
Can you spare me this sophomoric tirade!
I'm a man with
a huge worldview.
I'm surrounded
by microbes!
And what about me?
Am I a microbe?
Is our son at Yale
a microbe?
Let's face it,
Jessica, okay?
Our marriage hasn't
been a garden of roses.
Botanically speaking, you're
more of a Venus flytrap.
You are a very difficult
man to live with.
Is that why you
had an affair?
I didn't have an affair.
It was a brief interlude of
infidelity, and it happened years ago.
You still can't forget it!
I see everything so
clearly now. Everything!
I married you for
all the wrong reasons.
What's that
supposed to mean?
You're brilliant.
I wanted someone to talk to.
You loved classical music, you
loved art, you loved literature.
You loved sex!
You loved me!
Those sound like pretty
good reasons to me!
Yes! Exactly! That's the
problem! That's the problem!
It was rational,
it made sense!
I don't know
what went wrong.
When you examine it, there
is so much right about us.
On paper we're ideal.
But life isn't on paper.
Boris?
Boris, what are you doing?
Close the window!
Boris!
Can you believe I hit the canopy?
I hit the goddamn canopy.
Months in the hospital! Moron
doctors! Look. Look at this limp.
I never had a limp before.
Meanwhile, I divorced Jessica,
moved downtown and gave up.
I eke out a meager living teaching
chess to incompetent zombies.
Checkmate,
you little patzer.
Hey! He's only eight years old,
Mr. Yellnikoff.
You're supposed to
be teaching him...
He'll be an
incompetent idiot at 58.
More important than
how I make my living,
is why I bother
to live at all.
Nights, I have trouble sleeping
and hang out on Mott Street,
trying to explain
to cretins that
while a black man got
into the White House
he still can't get
a cab in New York.
Almost 100 years after
the abolition of slavery,
a man couldn't play
a game of baseball
in the big leagues if
his skin color was black.
You're harping
on one point.
Oh, good. Okay, forget
blacks. Take Jews.
What?
- Here we go.
For years they restricted
the number of Jews
in schools,
medical schools.
In America, as much
as they hated blacks,
they hate Jews
even more.
Blacks they were scared
had too big a penis.
Jews they hated,
even with little penises.
For God's sake,
I'm eating here.
You!
I've been looking for you.
I want to talk to you.
- Who are you?
Did you pick up a
chessboard full of pieces
and hit my son with it
at his lesson today?
That idiot's your son?
Do me a favor. Don't send
that cretin to me anymore.
I can't teach an
empty-headed zombie chess.
I'll have you know that
he is a very bright child.
In your opinion.
Which is skewed, because
he's your unfortunate issue.
So you threw
a chessboard at him?
I didn't throw it at him.
I picked up the board and
dumped the pieces on his head
as an object lesson to shake
him out of his vegetable torpor.
You wait until my husband
gets back from Florida.
What's he doing in
Florida without you?
He will punch you
in the nose.
Her husband's in
Fort Lauderdale.
He's probably hanging out with
naked coeds on spring break.
He tells her it's
a business trip.
Your son's an imbecile.
Teach him tiddlywinks, not chess.
You handled
that beautifully, Boris.
You know,
you should open
the Boris Yellnikoff
Charm School.
Let's get out of here.
It's late. I'm tired.
Good night, Boris.
What? What are you doing?
Where are you going?
That's it?
Sir?
- Hey! What?
What the hell
are you doing?
My God, you scared me.
For God's sake!
You creep up on me like that,
you little vagrant.
What do you want?
Can you help me
get something to eat?
Oh, God, no,
I don't carry any money.
Now, come on, you can tell that to
your partner, wherever he's hiding.
Please, I'm so hungry!
Back up! Back up!
I haven't had anything to eat all day.
I think I'm going to faint.
Yeah, listen, I'm wise to
that scam, little girl, okay?
I know about professional
beggar school.
Please, I'm desperate.
God, stop that! You look terrible!
What's wrong with you?
Just... All right.
Come up for two minutes.
That's it. And then...
And then go.
Thank you!
Two minutes, okay?
That's it.
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday, dear Boris
# Happy birthday to you #
Is this your birthday?
You don't know you have to sing
Happy Birthday twice
to get the germs off?
You said you were starving.
What do you like?
I like oysters,
blackened redfish,
gumbo, crab legs,
black-eyed...
Are you nuts?
What do you think I'm running?
A Creole restaurant?
How about
a can of sardines?
Oh, yes, please.
Gumbo.
So what's your name?
Melody. Melody Celestine.
Melody Celestine.
Melody Saint Anne Celestine.
It's French.
My mama's family was from New Orleans.
I'm from Mississippi,
Mr...
Um...
Muggeridge.
Lionel Muggeridge.
Mr. Muggeridge.
Eden, Mississippi.
You ever hear of it?
No, I haven't.
Not even the people who
live there have heard of it.
So...
So what are you
running away from?
Home.
Could you be more specific,
Melanie?
Melody. Melanie was
from Gone with the Wind.
Oh, yeah. I preferred the
one who played Scarlett.
Why? Melanie was the nice
one. She marries Ashley.
Ashley.
What an imbecile!
I couldn't stand him,
I couldn't stand his wife,
that goody two-shoes,
sexual nothing.
Scarlett, bitch that she was,
with those green eyes...
You know, I came in first
dressed as Scarlett O'Hara
in one of the pageants.
Pageant?
- Mmm-hmm.
My mom always used to keep me
busy in all these beauty contests.
That's why I didn't
get to schooling much.
All right, my advice
to you, go back home.
Oh, no,
I'm never going back home.
You're a
brainless little twit
who won't last
three days in New York.
You'd be dead
now of starvation
if I hadn't a heart
as big as all outdoors.
I can't go back home,
Mr. Muggeridge.
All right,
stop calling me Muggeridge.
But that's your name.
No, it's not my name.
My name is Boris Yellnikoff.
I was using an alias.
I thought, who knows,
you might be from the
Taliban or something.
Can I stay here?
Stay here? What are you?
Nuts? How old are you?
I'm 21.
Twenty-one? Yeah.
You're 21 like I play for
the Yankees. Twenty-one!
You're a professional
athlete with that limp?
Oh, Christ!
All right, look,
I don't want to go back.
Okay? I want to make a
new life here in New York.
You'll wind up a prostitute,
like those Asian girls
who come here
full of high hopes.
And then they wind up
turning tricks to keep alive.
And many of them are
actually good-looking.
That's so funny you just mentioned
tricks! You know, I do magic.
I do. I can show you.
I just need...
Do you have any
silk handkerchiefs?
Yeah, you know, some
other time, you're...
Look, you're a sweet kid.
Stupid beyond
all comprehension,
but you'll
never survive here.
You got nothing going
for you. Zero. Zilch.
You know, you may be beauty
contest material in the Deep South,
but this is the big time.
Here, you're a three.
A five maybe
after you bathe.
Did you get that limp
playing for the Yankees?
Imbecile child.
Brainless inchworm.
I didn't play
for the Yankees!
I was being
sarcastic before.
Oh, you...
I took it seriously.
Yes.
I usually get jokes. At the church's
social, I was the comedian twice.
I've a way with jokes. Yes.
- Really?
Spare me
and just get out.
No, Mr. Muggeridge...
Stop calling me Muggeridge, okay?
I already explained that!
I know, I know.
I'm sorry. I just...
I just need a place to stay for a
few nights, till I get on my feet.
I don't have
anywhere to go.
And if you throw me out and
I wind up an Asian prostitute,
that's gonna be
on your conscience.
I give up.
Sleep on the couch, imbecile.
I'm too tired to prolong
this brutal exchange
between a bedraggled microbe
and a Nobel-level thinker.
Keep out of my way.
I will, I promise.
I'm just gonna use the
little girl's to freshen up,
and then I'm gonna
go right to sleep.
Yes, yes, use the little girl's.
Freshen up.
Don't forget to
tip the attendant.
I won't.
Thank you so much, Mr...
Oh, what?
You were going to say Muggeridge again?
- No!
It's Boris Yellnikoff!
You call me Muggeridge one more time,
I'm gonna throw you
out the goddamn window.
Do you mind if
I watch a little TV?
Yes, I do, simpleton.
I just like to turn some
on at night to unwind.
Yeah. You touch that dial,
I'll unwind your head with my bare hands.
How about that?
Did you hear about Boris?
- What?
I tried to call him
yesterday
and a woman
answered the phone.
No! Who is she?
He got conned into
letting some little runaway
bed down in his apartment while she
looks for a job and gets settled.
Apparently she's never
been to New York before
and she's asked him if
he would show her around.
Boris is going to be sightseeing?
- Yeah.
Not a chance.
- No way.
No way.
My whole life
I've lived in New York,
I never wanted to
go to Grant's Tomb.
Now I know why.
- Why?
I should never go
to a tomb, ever.
My mom brought me
up to believe that
the good Lord has a plan
that we're all a part of.
He has His eye
on the sparrow.
Yeah, I pity the sparrow.
I'm not getting into
heaven, though. I sinned.
You? You're kidding.
You sinned?
I made love
before I was married.
Oh, my God.
Plenty of my friends have, but in
my house, that's just unforgivable.
I just couldn't
resist Bobby Klaxon.
All right, okay, spare
me the details, all right.
No, it was
really beautiful!
I mean, he was just this pretty boy
guitar player in this amazing rock band.
I mean, if you think
you're a genius,
he can double
on the drums.
No! Doubles on drums?
Yeah.
All the girls had a crush
on him, but he liked me.
He was so sweet
and sensitive,
and he caught the biggest
catfish in Plaquemines County.
I wondered who
caught that catfish.
Hey, you know,
my mom always told me
that it was gonna
hurt the first time,
you know, she said it was,
you know,
it's a woman's duty to just
lie down, bear it and...
You know, she said there were
a lot of perversions involved,
and that, you know, it's
God's will, you shouldn't do it
unless you were married and
you planned to have kids and...
She said it could
be dangerous,
but I just felt
like it was
the most natural
thing in the world.
You know,
it just felt right.
And all the little extras were just
fun. It wasn't complicated at all.
And I think Bobby
really liked it,
because he was going to
dump his Betty Jo Cleary,
this girl he was
going steady with.
But I wouldn't,
I wouldn't hear of it.
It was just what it was,
you know,
it was a nice moment behind
the tent at the fish fry.
That is the most disgusting
story I've ever heard.
You and this adenoidal guitar
player slaking your lust
at some barbaric
social function.
You don't like
to make love?
No, I do not. No.
That's crazy!
Boris, do you want to
be buried or cremated?
All right, I really don't
want to talk about that. Okay?
I think I want
to be cremated.
All right,
will you shut up, cretin?
There's no worms.
What is this?
A knish.
And what's it made of?
I've been eating these things
for years, they're delicious.
I don't know
what's in them.
I don't want to know what's in
them. Don't even talk about it!
Oh, my God!
The horror! The horror!
Boris!
Are you all right? What happened?
- No, I'm not all right.
Are you sick?
- No.
Did you have a bad dream?
Yeah, it was terrible.
Come here. It's okay.
- Oh, I can't...
Oh, baby, you're sweating.
Come sit down.
Night sweats.
I get them.
I used to think
it was AIDS,
but it's just that I have
a morbid fear of the dark
and you turned
my night-light off!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Does your stomach hurt?
Could it be the kwish?
Knish! Not kwish.
Well, here,
I'll put something on TV.
I saw the abyss.
Don't worry,
we'll watch something else.
Oh, this is...
- Yeah.
Fred Astaire. Yeah.
Leave that.
That's good.
There,
that's it, okay?
Can we get
the hell out of here?
Oh, my God, that's it!
It's the actual one!
I've only seen it
in pictures!
"Bring me your tired,
your poor, your huddled masses..."
I'm surprised you know
that, terrible as it is.
I closed with it for the Miss
Greenwood, Mississippi pageant.
I think it's so moving.
But the huddled masses were
never welcomed with open arms.
Soon as they came over,
each ethnic group
was met with
violence and hostility.
Each one had to claw
and fight its way in.
People always hated foreigners.
It's the American way.
Our pageants like to focus on
the positive things about America.
Yeah. The blacks were
kidnapped from Africa!
Chained in ships!
My daddy says that America bends
over backwards for the blacks
because we feel guilty,
and it's crazy.
Oh, yeah, your daddy.
Your daddy's a cracker.
He's a bigot moron.
Your daddy!
Well, you're probably right,
'cause you're a genius,
but for a little Mississippi girl
like me, this is really exciting!
So what kind of genius
are you, anyway?
What kind?
Yeah, what are
you genius at?
Quantum mechanics.
Yeah, but what field?
Like, music?
When you see
kids tossing a ball,
does it ever make you
miss spring training?
All right, I've never played for
the Yankees. Do you understand that?
I have never
played any sports
whatsoever in my life!
Okay? Ever!
Joe, Leo, you gotta help me
out. I can't take it anymore.
Just kick her out.
Can you believe it's
been a month already?
A whole month?
God, time flies.
Well put.
Well, at least
is she pretty?
She's won some
beauty contests.
No.
Tall? Short? Blonde?
Describe her.
Well, she's blonde.
Nice height. Nice eyes.
Didn't quite realize how blue
they were that first night.
Her face is a little
more symmetrical
than I had
originally conceived.
She's not a ten.
In a pinch, six.
Good in bed?
How would I know?
I just want her out.
Can I ask you
to dance with me?
It's too crowded.
I don't mean now.
In a few minutes,
the dance will be over
and everyone will go home.
Well, the band
will go home, too.
Why, there'll just be the two of us left,
and we can imagine the music.
We can pretend there's a
big orchestra of violins
and they're playing
just for us as we dance.
You know, it's been proven
television eats away the brain.
Oh, hi! Shoot,
I was gonna surprise you!
What? What's all this?
I'm making you
a special dinner.
Really? For me?
- Yeah.
And me, 'cause
we're celebrating.
We are? What is it?
Crawfish!
I found some at the market.
Jesus. It's stinking up
the whole house!
No, they're so good.
You'll love them.
Listen, Melody, seriously,
we have to talk.
Oh, yeah. I know. We'll talk
over dinner. It's almost done.
Melody, you're a very nice
young woman. Really, very nice.
You have a lot of
nice attributes,
but, you know, you just can't
continue to stay here ad infinitum.
Yeah, yeah, but that's
my news. Guess what?
I got a job! I can
start paying you rent.
Rent? I don't want
you to pay me rent!
I want my life back.
What kind of job?
I start tomorrow
as a dog walker.
A dog walker? Oh,
my God. Seriously...
Melody, don't you think you should
go back home and finish high school,
maybe even go to college?
I thought the other night you
were talking about how America has
one of the worst education
systems in the Old West.
No, no,
the Western world.
Yeah, right, exactly,
and how most colleges just
turn out mindless zombie morons.
You could benefit
from classes.
I think
the crawfish are ready.
What is that song?
They played that song the first
time I went out with Jessica.
Where did you go?
We went to a dance.
We were both students
at the University of Chicago.
She had a high IQ
and a low-cut dress.
Boy, they really don't
write them like they used to.
Oh! That's a cliche.
Ah! Good, Melody.
You caught it.
Well, you always get
so mad when I do them.
Yeah, I shouldn't really.
Sometimes a cliche
is finally the best way
to make one's point.
Boris,
what would you say
if I was to say
that I was developing
a little crush on you?
I'd say don't.
Why?
Because anything deeper,
more significant between us,
is out of the question.
Because why?
Because it's
too preposterous
to even dignify
with an answer.
It is?
Every single thing
is against it.
Our ages, our backgrounds,
our brains, our interests.
Not to mention,
I have no desire
to have a relationship
with a woman, any woman,
nor any urge to make love,
nor any desire to be anything
but isolated
from the world.
And, you know,
you're a beautiful girl
who should be meeting normal
healthy men and going out.
Yeah, but I don't like
normal healthy men.
I like you.
I...
You're hallucinating!
I'm sure you'll make
some man very happy
at a fish fry
or a dog fight
or however you
people spend time.
You really think
I'm beautiful?
I admit I didn't give you your
full due at first, physically.
However, as only
a great mind can do,
I've reassessed
my position,
and changed my mind.
So you could never
think of marrying me?
Have you lost your mind?
Why on Earth would you even
fantasize about such a thing?
What could I offer you, but
a bad temper, hypochondriasis,
morbid fixations, reclusive
rages and misanthropy?
And what could you
offer me?
A character out of
Faulkner, not unlike Benjy.
The answer to
your question is no.
I think you should stay here for
a while, accumulate some money,
and then find a place of your
own, and move on with your life.
Well, what about your life?
Let me teach you
something about love. Okay?
Naturally, there are exceptions
to what I'm going to say,
but they're the
exception, not the rule.
Love, despite
what they tell you,
does not conquer all. Nor
does it even usually last.
In the end, the romantic
aspirations of our youth
are reduced to
whatever works. Okay?
Why do I think your bark
is worse than your bite?
Cliche, Melody.
Oh, I don't care! If the shoe fits,
wear it, and that's another one.
We need to talk
for a minute.
Can you believe this little
inchworm setting her sights on me?
Yes, yes, we had
some pleasant moments.
Some dinners,
some walks in the park.
I gave her the benefit of my
vast knowledge and experience.
Tried to impart to her
the perceptions and values
of a truly
original mentality.
I only wish I could do
a Pygmalion on her.
But if Henry Higgins
ever tried to
transform Melody
Saint Anne Celestine,
he, too, would have
jumped out the window.
Come on.
Oh, boy! New friends.
- I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah.
They like each other.
It's okay.
I rather like dogs.
Well, I'm more of
a cat person, myself.
I just do this
professionally. Sorry.
I never met a
professional dog walker.
Really? It's not really the
career that I want, but...
What do you want to do?
I'd like to work
with children.
You're very pretty,
you know that?
Shut up! Thank you.
Can I ask your name?
It's Melody.
Melody Saint Anne Celestine.
What a beautiful name!
Mine's Perry Singleton.
It's nice to meet you.
- Yes, nice to meet you.
May I walk along
with you?
I don't see why not,
you know,
since we're all
doomed anyway.
Pardon me?
Well, you know,
everything ends.
I don't think I follow.
Well, you know, it's like
the cosmos, or eternity.
Whichever's bigger. I just know
that we're all flying apart.
What is that? What is
that? Is that a move?
Well, I thought
your bishop was...
My bishop what? What?
You patzer, you earthworm!
How many times do I have to tell
you? You don't take that pawn.
That's called the poisoned
pawn, because look!
Boris!
- Look what happens!
Sorry, Mr. Yellnikoff.
-Yeah, you're sorry, you're sorry.
Use your head next time,
you won't be sorry!
Boris!
Yeah. Do your homework next
week. Don't waste my time.
Hey!
- Poisoned!
I got off work early
today and I thought
maybe we could
walk home together.
Maybe I can make black-eyed
peas and crab cakes for dinner.
No, I'm not hungry.
What's the matter?
My ulcer's been
killing me all day.
I thought you
didn't have an ulcer.
No, I said they can't find an
ulcer, not that I don't have one.
Those malpractice
medical mental midgets.
They drop that endoscope
down my throat
and probe me
like coal miners,
and they always
come up with nothing!
Well, guess
what happened today?
I got to talking to
this boy on the job,
and he asked me
out on a date.
Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
I could tell he
liked me right off
and we went and had coffee and
just had, you know, funny banter.
You know what banter is,
it's like flirty talk.
Yeah, yeah,
I'm familiar with banter.
Yeah, so, anyway, he
asked if I had a boyfriend.
I said, "Not really." He said,
"I'll pick you up Friday at 8:00."
What do you think?
Great. I just hope he's
not a Ted Bundy, you know.
A who?
You have to keep an eye
out for serial killers.
He's not a serial killer. At
least he didn't mention it.
Yeah, well,
you have to be careful.
Sometimes they put you in the trunk
of a car and you can't breathe.
I'm not...
I'm serious.
I told him your theory
about capital punishment.
What did you say?
That it should include people that
don't pick up after their dogs,
people who ride their
bikes on the sidewalk,
people who call
mothers "moms" and...
I can't remember them all,
you have so many.
How do I look?
- Subnormal.
Why? What's wrong?
That's an awfully
aggressive ensemble.
You looking to wind up
in an abortion clinic?
I want
to look nice.
Just kind of
give him an idea
of what he might be in for
if he plays his cards right.
Oh, yeah?
What's he in for?
All the stuff with a
woman that you reject,
because you're a genius
and you're above it all.
But I happen to be
pretty sharp, too,
and I have a natural talent
in the field of fooling around.
Yeah, well, I just hope
you're saving your money
so you can move out quickly, you
know, now that you're working.
Hi, Perry!
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
I got stuck on the train.
No, it's fine.
Come on in.
This is Perry.
Hi. Your daughter is very
lovely, Mr. Celestine.
I'm not her father.
Grandfather?
Perry, I told you I was
staying with a friend.
So what do you do, Perry?
He's studying. Investments
and investing things.
You got any
identification?
Pardon me?
You know, driver's
license, birth certificate.
No, sir. I never carry
around my birth certificate.
Why would I?
Be careful, Bundy
sometimes posed as a banker.
Oh!
I'm just gonna go finish getting
ready. I'll be right back.
Melody tells me you're
a very brilliant man.
If an IQ of 200
is brilliant.
She explained to me your theory
about life being meaningless.
Don't let it
spoil your evening.
Okay, let's go, Perry.
Okay.
Hey! Come here.
Don't give him any
information about me.
Like what?
You know, dates, credit card
numbers, blood type, things like that.
Goodbye, Boris.
Oh, and hey, if I'm not
here when you get back,
don't worry.
Oh? Where are you going?
Out.
- Okay, fine.
Yeah, I have friends, too.
- Okay. Yeah.
I even heard the opening's
supposed to be good.
Yeah, they are. Have
you seen them before?
No, no. This is my first
concert in New York.
You didn't tell me that.
Get the hell out of here.
In America, they have
summer camps for everything.
Rich kids, basketball
camp, magic camp.
Tennis camp.
- Tennis camp. Movie director camp!
They should have
a concentration camp.
Two weeks mandatory
for all kids growing up,
so they would
finally understand
what the human race
is capable of.
Brilliant! Except who'd send
their kid to a concentration camp?
A responsible parent who wants
their child to grasp reality.
All right, all right, all
right, let's change the subject.
Meanwhile,
Harry Lawson died.
Harry Lawson?
Yeah, I heard.
Yeah. Just celebrated his 51st birthday.
- Really?
What a great chemist.
But he was a smoker.
A smoker. The minute a person dies,
he's a smoker
or overweight.
Hey, I got news for you, thin
non-smokers die, too. Okay?
Abstinence isn't
going to save you.
You're pleasant tonight.
What are you talking about?
Where's Melody tonight?
She's out listening to some
eardrum-busting bilge posing as music.
I thought you were
going to kick her out.
Well, hopefully this guy tonight
will take her off my hands.
You know, why not?
I mean, she's pretty.
Now she's pretty?
What? I'm just saying she's not
atrocious-looking. That's all.
I'd say a seven or eight.
Anybody here?
Oh, you're up!
Yeah, I just got in.
And what did you do?
I went dancing at a Latin
club. It was limbo night.
Shut up!
You were talking about
people and politics
and all that stuff
you guys like to hate.
How was your date?
It was a big washout! Yeah.
- Really?
This particular rock
band wasn't any good?
I don't know how
you can differentiate?
No! No, the music was fine.
Just that guy and
his friends! I just...
What?
Well, his taste! He just...
He likes everything.
Life, love, human beings!
And the couple that we double-dated
with, they were just protons!
Protons?
Do I mean protons?
Cretins!
Cretins, that's
what I mean.
Yeah, they didn't know the
first thing about string theory.
I think you're
a little drunk.
I did have a few drinks.
But can you blame me? Hanging
out with those inchworms?
I mean, they actually think that
love is the answer to everything.
I told them about Jethro
Paige from back home.
He got caught doing it with a
sheep. Making love with a sheep.
And they were all
laughing and everything,
but I just looked at them
and said, "Folks,
"as Boris would say,
whatever works."
What are you looking at?
Unbelievable.
The chance factor in life
is mind-boggling.
You entered the world
by a random event
somewhere along
the Mississippi.
I, having emerged
through the conjoining
of Sam and Yetta Yellnikoff
in the Bronx,
decades earlier.
And through an astronomical
concatenation
of circumstances,
our paths cross.
Two runaways
in the vast, black,
unspeakably violent
and indifferent universe.
Can you believe I married
her? What possessed me?
This search in life
for something
to give the illusion
of meaning.
To quell the panic.
All right,
so it's been a year.
Three hundred and sixty-five
days of married life.
And you know what? Not the
worst year of my life, either.
What are these?
They're grits.
Seriously?
- Mmm-hmm.
They're actually disgusting.
She's cheerful,
not demanding.
Okay, not as brilliant
as Jessica,
but not as ambitious
and predatory, either.
Jessica's problem was she made up
in ego what she lacked in superego.
But not Melody.
She likes being a nanny. She's
happy with other people's kids,
so mercifully she doesn't
bother me about having our own.
Once a week we see a movie.
Maybe she doesn't understand
everything I take her to,
but she tries and
she's a good sport.
She sits up nights with me
when I have my panic attacks.
She keeps me company
at the emergency room
when I'm convinced my
mosquito bite is a melanoma.
Yes, my life
is circumscribed,
but I manage
to avoid stress.
I've achieved
a delicate balance.
And as long as
I can maintain it,
I feel less inclined
to ending it.
# You heard what I said
# No turning back now #
Oh, no, no, no.
Unacceptable. Come on, this is not good.
- What?
I like music
I can dance to.
I know, I know,
but this is brutal.
Here, you know
what I want you to do?
Put this on. Okay? And then when
I come out, we'll discuss it.
All right, I'll try.
It's Beethoven's Fifth!
Think of the music
as fate knocking on the door.
Maybe a little story
will help you appreciate it.
Fate knocking
on the door.
Mother?
- Melody!
Oh, it's you!
Oh, my God.
It's my baby!
I finally found you,
praise Jesus!
How did you find me?
Oh, my prayers
were finally answered!
I can't... You're just the
last person I expected to see.
Well, when you
least expect it,
fate has a way of
knocking on your door.
Yeah, it does. Okay.
Oh, you have a bag.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was trying
to find you, honey.
Why?
I came to
find you, honey!
You did?
Oh, we searched
and searched.
The police looked
for clues.
Everything led
to a dead end.
Whoa!
How we worried. I developed
crow's feet from the worrying.
Now look here.
I had a little work done.
Mother,
I left you a letter.
I told you
I'd be all right.
Melody Saint Anne, I'd
hardly call this all right!
Well, what's
wrong with it?
What's wrong? What's
happened to your senses?
Everything's wrong. You're
living like a sharecropper.
But it's clean
as a whistle.
I clean it myself
every day.
You clean?
You don't have a woman?
Boris can't
really afford help.
Who?
- Boris.
Who's Boris?
My husband.
What?
That's right, Mama,
I got married.
And he's taken you
to live here?
No, no,
I moved in with him.
Oh...
I have to have a drink.
I need to sit.
I need an anesthetic.
Okay, okay, have a seat. We
don't have any bourbon or nothing.
Just bring me the drink with the
highest volume of alcohol you have.
You know, Mama,
I'm kind of happy.
Kind of happy?
You leave
a loving home in Eden,
run off with
some crazy kid,
I'm guessing
he's a rock musician
who can't earn a respectable
living, and you wind up
in this decadent city,
living in a rattrap.
This is exactly
why I ran away.
Why, why, Miss Sweet Pea?
Why did you forsake
your loving home?
Because, Mama, you're...
You're overbearing. That's
it. You're overbearing
and you fail to
see the big picture.
What big picture
are you talking about?
I don't know.
All I know is that nothing moves
faster than the speed of light,
so you may as well relax.
I'm just gonna have
a little moment of prayer.
Mama, you're still caught up
in that Christian superstition?
# Happy birthday to you
What's that?
That's Boris.
It's his birthday?
No, he's just
washing his hands.
# Happy birthday, dear Boris
# Happy birthday to you #
Who's this?
Boris,
this is my mother.
Mother, my husband.
Mama! Mama!
Walk her around, she's
obviously a boozehound.
Mama, are you all right?
Did he drug you?
- What?
Are you on sodium pentothal?
- No.
That's what they do,
the secular humanists.
It's uncanny. She's exactly
the kind of moron you described.
You are not the
gentleman I was expecting.
I'm sure not.
I'm sure you'd be happy
if she married the guy who
caught the biggest catfish
in Plaquemines County.
I'd be happier if
she married the catfish.
No, you see, Mama,
Boris is a genius. Okay?
He doesn't have a lot of
patience for us inchworms.
We, we inchworms.
- We.
Some genius.
I was almost nominated
for a Nobel Prize.
That's right, Boris. And what
was it for again? Best Picture?
I need more booze.
You know, you never
said how you found me.
Oh, Melody. I have a
sad tale to tell you.
What happened, Mama?
Your father left me.
Oh.
Aren't you shocked?
No.
And with who,
of all people?
My best friend, Mandy.
- Your best friend, Mandy.
How did you know?
- Oh, Mama.
It was as plain as the nose
on your face. Cliche, sorry.
At first I thought he
was acting peculiar,
because things was going
so bad for us, darling.
How often did you
have intercourse?
Are you going to close
that insulting mouth?
By bad, I mean he
lost a lot of money
in the stock market
after you left
and we were forced
to sell the house.
You sold the house?
- I'm sorry, yes. We took a beating,
because we were
so desperate.
And then he lost his job, the
company went out of business.
And then we spent all our
savings on medical bills,
'cause I came down with
a case of the shingles!
Oh, my God.
Christ, this is like Job.
No locusts?
Darling, I turned to
Jesus in a deeper way
than I had ever
done in my life.
I prayed and I prayed,
every day and every night,
asking God to help me.
Let me guess what happened,
your shingles got worse.
I said, "Lord,
just give me one sign
"that all my suffering
is for a purpose."
I said, "Please, God,
just say something."
"Break your silence. I
can't take any more misery!"
Nothing, right? And all that money
you put in the tin box every Sunday.
Abortion is murder, that's
the long and short of it.
That's how I feel. Well...
- Even if the woman is raped?
Why are you wasting
your breath, Brockman?
You're dealing
with an aborigine.
You don't mind
killing the unborn,
but when some fiend
has raped and murdered,
you're against giving him
that big old injection?
Well, not me,
Mr. Genius,
and I don't care how many
Academy Awards you've won.
I've never won
an Academy Award
and I've never played
for the Yankees!
Where's the little girl's? Thank you.
- It's back there.
Don't forget to sing The
Star-Spangled Banner before you sit.
Oh.
Excuse me.
I realize
this is forward,
but who's that beautiful
young girl you're with?
May I ask why
you want to know?
Well, because
she's very beautiful.
And I'm assuming
she's your daughter?
What did you say
your name was, darling?
Randy. Randy Lee James.
- Randy Lee James.
Nice to meet you.
It's too good. I think they're
putting mayonnaise in here.
No, they can't put
mayonnaise in hummus.
Hello.
Oh, thank you.
Who were you
talking to?
I wasn't talking
to anybody. Nobody.
Listen, listen, I want
to go someplace fun.
Take me someplace fun!
It's New York! Let's go.
Boris, where can I
take her that's fun?
How about
the Holocaust Museum?
Oh, for God's sake, Boris.
- No.
Oh, the wax! The wax figures.
- Oh, yes.
Yes, yes, let's go. Come on.
- Let's do that.
It was so nice to meet you, Leo.
- You, too. Have a nice day.
Bye. Bye, bye.
Bye. Have fun!
You know, I have to say, even with
a textbook right-wing mentality,
your mother-in-law has
beautifully shaped breasts.
You know,
you're a man of learning,
of cultivation of
aesthetic sensibility.
This is what you take away
from the school-prayer hokum
and "my country right
or wrong"? Her bosom?
It's not just her bosom. Her behind
is also beautifully contoured.
Well, I'm sure you'll have no
problem getting her into bed.
She's vulnerable, she's stupid
and she's been abandoned.
Personally, I lose
all erotic inclination
when the woman's a member of
the National Rifle Association.
It's pear-shaped.
Degas used to
distinguish between
an apple-shaped behind
and pear-shaped.
And I'm a big fruit eater.
Melody.
- That's so weird.
Oh, my God.
Oh, hello.
They're made out
of real wax, too.
Oh, it's Billy.
Billy...
Billy Graham!
Oh, sweet pea,
sweet pea,
this is the kind of man
you should be married to,
not that Communist
who sings Happy Birthday
every time he
washes his hands.
How long are
you staying, Mom?
Honey, I don't know
where else to go.
I have nothing
to hold onto.
Nothing! I have to
have something.
I mean, I'm never going to attract
a man again, but you can. Yes.
I don't want to
get in an argument.
Honey, I met a young man today
who is perfect for you.
Mom!
- Yes. Listen to me.
He is talented,
handsome, sweet,
and he has the proper reverence
for life and its higher purpose.
What are you
talking about?
Face it, Melody, Boris is
not like a real husband.
He's more of an outpatient
and you're his keeper.
I really wish you
hadn't showed up, Mom.
His name is
Randy Lee James.
Who?
This delightful young actor.
He fell in love with you
at first sight.
He did. He did.
- Mom, I'm married!
I refuse to recognize it. What are
you doing with a gimpy chess bum
who has to sleep
with the light on?
How'd he get that limp?
He jumped out the window
and his suicide didn't work.
Well, you can't win
them all. Now, listen,
I have a good lawyer who
can get all of this annulled.
All of it. Yes. Yes.
- No, no, Mom, no, you're crazy!
Oh, hello.
# Happy birthday, dear Boris
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday to you #
Who could be calling
at midnight?
Could be burglars,
casing the place.
To steal what?
Your Flomax?
Hello?
Oh, hi.
Yeah, just a second.
It's for me?
- Yes.
Don't give away
any information about me!
Hello?
Oh, hello, Leo.
It's Leo Brockman.
Brockman?
Really?
Well, that sounds wonderful.
Well, yeah,
Sunday's fine. Yeah.
3:00? Well, 3:00's perfect.
Okay. Yeah.
See you, darling.
"See you, darling"? "See you,
darling"? Oh, God, poor Brockman!
Good night, y'all.
I'm going to say
my prayers.
I'm praying
Brockman has herpes.
That was
so wonderful!
I never in my life saw a
movie in Japanese before.
Did you like it?
- Oh, yes!
I've never seen a movie
made by a foreigner.
John, my husband, took
me to see stupid movies,
which was
all there was.
How do you say this?
"Chateau" what?
Meyney.
The what?
- Meyney.
Meyney?
- Yeah.
It is so delicious.
I'm glad you like it.
What do you do?
What do you do, Leo?
I teach philosophy at the
university around the corner.
Tell me something.
Is Boris really a genius?
There was a time when he
was a very fine physicist.
Yeah, your daughter's
very good for Boris.
It's my theory that
she keeps him going.
Would you like to see some
pretty pictures of Melody?
Ooh. Goodness.
Well, all right.
Okay.
Look, here they are.
Look at these.
Right there, that's where
she is Miss Natchez.
Wow.
- Look at her. And she was Miss Tupelo.
Oh, God!
Look how gorgeous she is!
She's so beautiful.
I love her! I love her!
Very lovely.
- I was so proud of her.
These pictures are
kind of interesting.
I know!
She's just gorgeous!
And she has this... She's
just my little sweet pea.
I mean the photos.
Did you take them?
Yes. Yes.
And this?
That's our house.
Well, it was.
Is there more wine?
Yeah. You took all these?
Yes, with my
little old Kodak.
Uh-huh.
These are outstanding.
I mean, there's such a sense
of texture and composition.
In these? No.
No, I mean it. I know
what I'm talking about.
I occasionally write about
the aesthetics of photography.
Oh, my God. I have to
tell you something.
Aside from
Melody's career,
there is nothing,
nothing in the whole world
that gave me more pleasure
than taking those snapshots.
Of course, John...
Cheers.
John hated them and
didn't want me to do it.
Why?
- Well,
he actually was fine, and
then I set up this darkroom
and he thought I was, like,
squandering all this time on silliness
and I guess he
had a point, but...
I mean, nowadays,
who uses a Kodak anymore?
It's a little Kodak, and I have
to tell you something, it is...
It is so simple to use.
It's tiny!
I picked it up at,
like, a garage sale
and it just is so much better
than those big foreign ones.
No, they're pretty good.
They've got a real
haunting quality.
They're very primitive.
I really think you should talk
to my friend Al Morgenstern.
He runs
a photography gallery.
Why?
Have you got more of these?
Oh, Lord, yes.
You know, all my travels
with the pageants.
I have the kids
and the towns
and the winners.
And the losers!
The losers are the best. And
then I have all these show folk,
the twirlers,
the magicians,
the fire eaters, you know,
things like that.
They're amazing. They've
got such an original quality.
I'll talk to Al
first thing in the morning.
Oh, no. You know, I think
you're making too much
over a little gift the
good Lord Jesus gave me.
That's not the only gift
He gave you.
You know those clean-cut,
churchgoing young men,
who are model kids,
and good to their neighbors
and quote the Bible,
and never do a wrong thing,
and then one day,
for whatever reason,
they grab a rifle,
go to a tower
and pick off
everyone in town?
Okay, this is her,
but sexually.
She slept with Leo Brockman,
never having been to bed with
anyone before but her husband,
and suddenly, the genie
was out of the bottle!
She liked sleeping
with Brockman,
and she liked sleeping
with Brockman's friends,
Brockman's acquaintances, Brockman's
acquaintances' acquaintances.
Brockman took
her photos to Morgenstern.
He loved them.
He decided to show them
in his gallery.
When he did, everyone
thought they were great.
A brilliant primitive.
Soon Morgenstern would
become smitten with her.
First she moved in
with Brockman.
Then she moved in
with Morgenstern.
Then she moved in with
Brockman and Morgenstern.
She started dabbling
with collages.
Small ones at first,
but they would become bolder.
She started
dressing differently.
Soon all her
deep-rooted beliefs
went right down the toilet,
where they belonged.
She experimented with exotic
pleasures. A new Marietta was born.
The one thing that remained
constant, she hated her son-in-law.
Well, there's some
pictures over there.
Yes, maybe that.
Okay.
What do you think, Mom?
I'm not sure, you know,
it's for this collage,
and I've had this vision in black
and white of nude men, women,
body parts, squares.
That sounds confusing.
Well, it's an homage
to lust. Yeah. To lust.
Excuse me.
Hi, I need
a female opinion.
Which of these two would a young
woman prefer? I can't decide.
I don't know.
They're both so beautiful.
It depends.
What type is she?
Well, she's quite young
and very lovely-looking.
Blonde hair.
Blue eyes.
Yeah, but what's she like?
Well, okay.
She's from the South,
although she lives
here in New York now.
Really?
- Yeah.
And she's a nanny. I mean,
well, to tell you the truth,
she's actually
living with some man.
I mean, they're married, although
he's not the best she can do.
And she thinks she loves
him, but it's only because
she mistakes his pessimistic
despair for wisdom,
believing he's a genius.
I'd say she's more of a
nurse to him than a wife,
because he's
much older than she is.
That sounds so familiar.
I just can't...
I can't put my finger on it.
It's sort of like mine, actually. Yeah.
- It is?
I mean, not exactly, but I can't
help but seeing some similarities.
I'd say that one.
Okay.
Here.
Here what? For me?
- It's for you.
Yes, I thought I'd buy
you something lovely.
Oh, no, I can't accept
a gift from a stranger.
Well, why not?
I'm married.
Yes, but it may
not last forever.
Well, you know,
nothing lasts forever.
Not even Shakespeare
or Michelangelo
or Greek people.
I mean, even as we're standing
here talking right now,
we're just flying apart
at an unimaginable speed.
Gee, I never
thought of it that way.
Yeah.
Should we be holding each
other so we don't fall?
Well, you have to hold
onto whatever love you can
in this cruel existence.
Speaking of love,
I've been in love with you ever
since that first moment I saw you,
and met your mother at the
Mogador Cafe many months ago.
Oh, you're... You're...
Did my mother...
- Randy James.
Oh, the actor! Of course.
I can hear your accent now.
Oh, my mother talks
about you all the time,
and she's always telling me
I have to meet you
and I'm saying, "Why?
Why do I have to meet him?"
"But he's so good-looking!"
And, yeah, you are.
Thank you. I've moved to
New York permanently now
and I live in a houseboat
with a friend of mine.
You live on a boat?
- Yes, I do.
I'm very romantic by nature,
so I live on a boat
and I read and think
and play my flute...
Mom?
- Oh, be still, Melody.
There's nothing wrong with
expanding your horizons.
I certainly expanded mine.
You know what?
I'm really sorry, but...
I think that my mother badly
gave you the wrong impression,
because I'm
happily married.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, she's not, Randy.
She's nursemaid
to a roach. He is.
Goodbye, Mother.
Goodbye, Mr. James.
I told you you'd
get the hang of it.
Okay, you know what? Let's
just stop. Let's stop.
Let's stop. Yeah, yeah, yeah, stop, stop.
- Stop?
Yeah. I need to sit for a minute.
- All right.
You know, I'm just doing
it for the aerobics, anyway.
Otherwise, it's moronic.
I think it's relaxing.
Relaxing? What? Are you
kidding? It's too nerve-wracking.
To mingle with all those
sub-mentals on bicycles?
It's like driving a car.
Those hostile, belligerent
morons all get driver's licenses.
Of course, to have children,
you don't need a license.
No proof of anything.
You need a license to fish.
You need a license
to be a barber.
to sell hot dogs.
You know, you read about these
poor kids, beaten and starved,
you wonder, why are these
parents allowed to even have them?
Okay, Boris, Boris.
You know, sometimes I
think you're so determined
not to enjoy anything in
life, just out of spite.
You know, like a child
who's throwing a tantrum,
because he can't
have his own way.
Wow! Listen to you!
That's a reasonably
wise insight
for a simple-minded
type like yourself.
Honestly. Yeah, you surprise and
delight me sometimes, you know that?
I really don't know what I'd
do without you, seriously.
What are you doing
with that?
This? Nothing. I just
got it at the flea market.
Who needs
an antique handkerchief?
I thought it was pretty.
Yeah, but God knows throughout
history who blew his nose in it.
Marietta? Honey?
- Yes, darling?
I think you should include these
photos at your opening next week.
I love those photos.
Al, what do you think?
I chose those.
Oh, you did?
- Absolutely.
Sweetheart, you've managed to make...
- Thank you.
...an existential
statement about
sexual perversity and human freedom.
- Who? Yes.
It's so full of erotic
imagination. Okay, hold on a sec.
Oh, thank you so much!
Thank you!
Marietta?
Who is it?
- Somebody named Randy Jones?
Oh, Randy, Randy James.
Hello? Hello? Hey!
Young man, hello, hello!
Listen, she's going to be
at Uniqlo at around 3:00.
You can run into her
and try your luck.
You know, she saved
the handkerchief you gave her,
so it's not
a hopeless cause.
And I'm telling you, I saw
fire behind her eyes. Fire.
Yeah. Good luck, darling.
Who was that?
- Oh, nothing. Come on, gumbo! Let's go.
Who'd have ever
thought that gumbo
would become my
favorite dinner?
All this and
she cooks, too.
Oh, my God! Hello.
So I guess you just happened
to be shopping here. Right?
Well, I was buying this
shirt, if you must know.
Uh-huh.
You like it?
It's okay.
- Just okay?
I thought it'd
make me look dashing.
Looks aren't your problem.
Oh, no? What is?
You're too forward.
I think about you a lot.
Well, I don't
think about you.
So what's it like
being married to a genius?
Who wants to know?
I'm sorry. I don't mean
to be a boor, I just...
Just that,
well, you know.
It has its
pluses and minuses.
Yes?
And what are the drawbacks?
I don't know.
I mean...
Well, naturally,
with a very advanced mind,
you find a lot of things
wrong with everything
and, mainly, he just
doesn't like people.
You know, he says at
the rate they're going,
they're going to make
themselves extinct.
Right.
It can just be exhausting being
around a genius all the time.
So what are the pluses of being
the wife of such a dazzling mind?
Well, he's smart.
You said that.
He's clever.
Uh-huh.
He really means well, you know?
He's just a little crazy.
I guess the good part is
that I'm the wife of a genius,
which I never really
thought I could swing.
Why not?
I guess I thought
I'd have to be smarter.
You want to see my boat? I mean,
my friend's boat, where I live?
I don't think
that's a good idea.
I dreamt about you
last night. I...
Don't use that line.
Because Boris said
that he dreamt
about me last night.
And I really doubt it's
mathematically possible
for me to be in
two dreams at one time.
It's down there,
on the right-hand side.
Well, this is it.
It's not much, but it's home
and I don't pay rent, so...
This is kind of sweet,
living on the water.
It rocks
just the tiniest bit,
so I sleep
like a baby on it.
Randy, I don't know what
I'm doing here! I'm married!
That doesn't mean I can't
have feelings for you.
You don't
really know me.
Yes, but I'm a romantic and I
believe in love at first sight.
Well, that's true. You know,
Boris says that love isn't logical.
And I adore
the way you talk
and the funny things
you say.
Where can it lead?
Let's drink to
love at first sight.
I can't. When I drink, I get
very silly and touchy and...
That's what
your mum said.
That's why I bought the
bottle. She's quite a mum.
Don't use that locution.
It's for inchworms.
Sorry.
Is that you
in the picture?
Yeah. That's me in
Juno and the Paycock.
I bet you're
a really good actor.
I try. Although
I'll never be a genius.
You certainly are handsome
enough to be a star.
Thank you. I'll cherish
that compliment.
Oh, my God.
- What are you thinking?
Entropy.
- Entropy?
Yeah, entropy.
Boris explained it.
It's why you can't get the
toothpaste back in the tube.
You mean,
once something happens, it's difficult
to put it back the way it was?
I mean, Boris says
love is all about luck.
I think so, too, but
isn't that just because
we're young and we think
we're going to live forever
and then we grow old
and get diabetes, and...
Maybe.
Look, I do agree
there's not much
you can be sure of
in this world, but...
Have you ever heard of
Heisenberg's Uncertainty Principle?
I've heard of it, yeah.
You know, the observer
influences the experiment?
Uh-huh.
It's just like
when my mother makes love to
one of the guys she's living with
a certain way
when they're alone,
but when she's in front of the
other guy, she does it differently.
Is that Heisenberg?
I had no idea
he was so sexual.
Wait. I always carry
some Viagra with me.
That's all right.
I eat a lot of red meat.
I really like the way
these pants fit.
Hey, are you okay? You
seem awfully quiet lately.
Yeah.
We're going to be late
for Mom's gallery opening.
I hope you're not
coming down with anything.
You know, Brodsky's
kid's got the measles.
Can you still
get the measles?
I had a shot
when I was younger,
but how long
does it last?
Who's that?
I don't know.
I'm not expecting anyone.
Melody!
- Daddy!
Oh, my little girl,
I found you!
Oh, Lord, your mother and
I searched and searched,
but then we
ran out of leads.
I used every connection
I had at the police force.
We even called the FBI!
But you're okay.
Things are going to be fine
now. Your ordeal is over.
What ordeal?
You were abducted! Tell
me if my theory is correct.
You were chloroformed
by polygamous Mormons.
They took you off to
be someone's bride!
I was not abducted. Didn't
anybody read my letters?
Yeah, but I assumed you were
forced to write them at gunpoint.
Who's this?
- Who are you?
This is Boris,
my husband.
Boris, your who?
He's my husband.
I'm Mrs. Boris Yellnikoff.
Who are you?
- I'm her husband.
You want to pass out here
or go in the living room?
Where's your mother?
What do you care?
You cheated on her
and then dumped her for Mandy
Blackburn, of all people!
I made a terrible mistake, I
committed the sin of self-indulgence.
I've come to beg your
mother's forgiveness.
You might want to
rethink that, Daddy.
I want to see her.
I see death
by culture shock.
You can tell me, Melody, she
has every right to hate me.
And she does, believe me.
I can handle the truth.
Does she hate me?
Well, it was a pretty awful thing
you did with her best friend.
Then she hates me?
Yes, yes, she hates you!
I can't stand this.
I hate you
and I just met you!
Lord, you tell me this
creature took you to bed?
No, no, no, no.
Actually, she took me.
Yeah, when I met Boris,
he hated sex.
Yeah, think of it,
Mr. Celestine.
The absurd choreography,
like a sewing machine,
up and down, up and
down, up and down,
toward what end?
Making more children?
What the hell are
you talking about?
Reproducing the species over
and over. Toward what goal?
Carrying out
what moronic design?
What happened to Mandy?
It was a mess,
a nightmare.
Lord, I've sinned!
Please forgive me.
Why do all the religious
psychotics wind up
praying at my doorstep?
Can you tell me?
Lord, in Your infinite
mercy, I've done wrong.
You want to tell him,
or should I?
Tell me what?
Daddy, there's
nobody out there!
Honest.
You're praying to no one.
You're wasting
your breath,
just like you're gonna
be wasting it on Mom.
What? You're telling me
she met another man?
Not just a man.
- What?
Daddy, you couldn't
expect her to not,
you know, move on with
her life and, you know...
Oh, Lord.
What's he like?
He's got four arms
and two noses.
You better butt out,
stranger!
Melody will tell you
I don't need my shotgun
to be a whole
passel of trouble.
Now, I want to
see Marietta!
Now, Dad,
try and remember,
you haven't
seen Mom in a year.
A year is not forever. How
much can a person change?
And with that,
they entered the gallery.
I had more people
than I knew what to do with.
Everybody said,
"I'll be naked with you, Marietta!"
And I was like, "Okay."
Oh, my God.
Marietta?
John Celestine! Look
what the cat dragged in.
Marietta, what happened to you?
- Oh, my God!
Well, darling,
it's you that absconded.
He showed up at the door
today. Whoa, whoa. "Absconded"?
Yes, yes, with the
promiscuous whore
who called herself my best friend.
- Darling, I'll be...
I'll find you.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
It's over, Marietta. Mandy
and I were a terrible mistake.
I've come back for you.
Well, honey, I'm in the
middle of my opening.
Yeah, Dad, this is Mom's
exhibition. Isn't it great?
Exhibition of what?
Well, the collages.
What? She's thinking
of buying this pornography?
I got news for you,
she's the pornographer.
Marietta, who are you?
John, you never
understood me, honey.
Your vision never extended
beyond the backyard.
You always had
your gun clubs
and your fishing trips
and football.
You never took a little
minute to find out about me.
And you were always too
busy putting her in pageants
and coaching her speeches and
teaching her baton twirling!
Yes, yes, that's true. I was
sublimating my own creative needs
and forcing them
on our daughter.
You were what?
Yes, she was sublimating.
Sublimating.
Honey, why don't you go
on back to Mandy Blackburn?
Her pygmy mentality is
much closer to you now.
Much closer.
- Yeah. Well, I can't go back to her.
Oh, why not?
She cast aspersions
on my manhood.
What are we talking? Size?
Duration? Erectile dysfunction?
Would you mind
your own business?
Marietta, how could you
forsake your own family?
I want us all back home
to start over.
I'm a different woman, John.
I can't believe what
I'm seeing. I mean...
Your clothes are different, your
speech is a little more affected,
but deep down,
I know you're the same
pretty, small-town, God-fearing,
churchgoing, pie-baking...
I'm living with two guys.
...Girl Scout mom.
You're what?
I'm an artist. I don't bake
pies. I don't go to church.
I do collages,
sculpture, photography.
I live in Manhattan
with two men who I love
in a very happy
menage a trois.
A what?
We all sleep together.
A menage a trois.
I knew we should never
trust the goddamn French.
It's amazing, Melody.
Thousands of years ago, ancient
peoples, Egyptians, Romans, Mayans,
were walking home,
just like us,
discussing where should they
eat or making small talk.
"Hey, we just bought a great
house on the Nile with a yard,
"overlooking the
Pharaoh's new pyramid."
Boris...
- Or, "My physician says
"peacock tongues are bad for your heart."
- Boris...
Or, "I'm worried I can't get my kid
into a really good Aztec preschool."
What the hell does it
all mean now? Zilch.
But they thought
it was important.
Boris, can I talk
to you for a minute?
And I was raised
in a religious home.
Job's wife was my favorite
character in the Bible,
because she chose death
rather than
obsequious acceptance,
like that masochist
she married.
Boris, Boris, can we
sit down for a second?
Well, but we have to
go home.
I know, but come here.
I have to say something.
But we always
go home now.
I know. I know. I know we
have a standard routine.
I need to have my drink,
and a shower.
And, you know,
you see it as routine,
but for me the consistency helps
keep me from becoming unnerved.
I know you require
a certain ritual.
And then after the shower,
our dinner,
but not crawfish pie
again.
I got indigestion
from it last time.
I thought I had
thyroid cancer.
Boris, I met someone else.
I've fallen in love.
And then some Beethoven, maybe
some Schubert for a change,
but, you know...
You met someone else?
I'm not saying I don't have
very deep feelings for you. I do.
You met someone else?
Yes.
And you want us to live in a
threesome, like your mother?
Boris, when you found me,
I was very young.
You're still very young.
Yes, but I've grown.
I've grown so much.
And mainly because of you.
Yes, it's true.
I have been very patient
with your
phenomenal ignorance.
You can always count
on me for anything.
I just...
I guess I'm at a very
impressionable age, and I...
I can't think of a way
to say this well.
You don't have
to say it well.
I want to.
I completely understand.
I do.
This does not run counter
to my convictions that
love relationships are
almost invariably transient.
I don't really think
that's true if they're right.
Really?
You have your own ideas?
Just a couple. You know,
they're not very deep, but...
As cruel as life is, I miss
participating in the world.
And I even miss people, even
the inchworms and the cretins,
because I don't
really think they're bad,
I think they're
just scared.
I think you're making
the correct decision.
Boris...
- I mean it.
I'm a profound and sensitive
soul with an enormous grasp
of the human condition.
It was inevitable you would
eventually grow tired of
being so grossly overmatched.
Greatness isn't
easy to live with,
even by someone of
normal intelligence.
You're upset.
I don't expect you to
understand. How could you?
Believe me,
if I can understand
quantum mechanics,
I can certainly comprehend
the thought process
of a sub-mental
baton twirler.
Boris...
It's okay.
I knew this day would come.
I really did.
The universe is winding down.
Why shouldn't we?
Again!
I'll have another, too.
She left me.
Can you believe it?
What am I talking about?
I left her. She's alone.
Now, no matter which way she
turns in bed, she's got a husband.
My wife left me, too.
I'm sure she was beautiful,
just like my wife.
Norman?
Norman was gorgeous.
He was the greatest runway
model Versace ever had.
I thought you said
your wife.
We were married
in Holland.
You married a guy?
What else?
But that would make you...
What? A widow?
Norman didn't die.
Not a widow, a...
Gay?
A member of the...
Of what?
The homosexual persuasion.
My God.
You make it sound
like a religion.
Yes. If it's a religion, you
could call me devout. A fanatic.
But that's a sin
against God's law.
God is gay.
He can't be. He made the
whole universe perfect.
The oceans, the skies, the beautiful
flowers, the trees everywhere.
That's right.
He's a decorator.
But what do you miss about
him? I still don't get it.
Everything.
His face.
His kindness,
his sense of humor.
Our mutual passion.
The way we'd dance and he'd
dip me back and kiss me.
Jesus.
Why did he leave you?
She leave you. Norman.
He wants to live in Paris,
and I can't leave
my sick mother.
Is your mother a woman?
She used to look
like Marlene Dietrich.
What's the difference? They all
hurt you in the end, every woman,
whether they're
male or female.
Why did yours leave you?
I left her for her best
friend, but it didn't work out.
Why not?
Can I be perfectly
frank with you?
I don't shock easily.
I couldn't make love to her.
Why not?
It was fine at first, but then I
lost interest. I wanted Marietta back.
Which is funny,
because in the last years,
I really didn't have a lot of
sexual interest in Marietta.
That happens with you heteros.
We always have interest.
Christ, if I'm going
to be honest,
you know, I never,
ever really had
a burning sexual desire
for Marietta.
Why'd you marry her?
It was the thing to do.
Everybody where I lived,
you had a wife
and children and...
Can I really level with you?
Of course.
John. John Celestine.
Of course, John. I'm Howard
Cummings, nee Kaminsky.
I married Marietta,
because I was afraid.
Of what?
The way I felt towards the
tight end on the football team.
No.
Every time he got in the line
of scrimmage and bent over.
Bartender, another round
for my friend and me, please.
Can you believe
I blew it twice?
I jumped out the window and
landed on a woman walking her dog.
She got hurt.
I got off scot-free.
Don't you realize
the consequences
of your actions
impact on other people?
Oh, come on.
Seriously.
No. What if you had
committed suicide?
Think, think if
you didn't exist,
how the world would suddenly
change in ways you can't imagine.
Oh, my God.
You know what?
You sound like
that movie they ram
down your throat
every Christmas.
What?
- What if the guardian angel
had saved Jimmy Stewart,
and Jimmy Stewart was
the guy who smoked in bed,
and he lived and caused a
fire that killed 60 people? So?
How about that? Everybody's
life is still worth saving?
Even if it's Christmas?
Come on, seriously.
You must have a very dim
view of the human race.
Oh, the human race.
They've had to install
automatic toilets
in public restrooms,
because people can't be
entrusted to flush a toilet.
Come on, flushing a toilet!
They can't even flush a toilet!
Visiting time is over.
What? You're kicking me out?
Yeah.
Seriously?
- Yeah. Absolutely.
All right, listen. Honestly,
I'm really sorry about all this
and is there anything I can
do to make this up to you?
Can I get you something?
What can I do?
If I can ever walk again,
you can buy me dinner.
What do you do, Helena?
Me? I'm a psychic.
I'm sorry. Really?
I was born with a very rare
gift. I can see into the future.
If you can see into the
future, how come you didn't know
I was gonna jump out a
building and land on top of you?
Maybe I did.
Happy new year to you.
We're so excited.
Howard is selling the gym,
but we're going to open up an antique
shop in Chelsea. Yeah. Art deco.
We're going to have a wonderful
collection of movie posters.
Can you believe
this cracker?
This red state
Neanderthal?
This mindless zombie of the
National Rifle Association?
My shrink says
that the guns were all
a manifestation of
my sexual inadequacy.
Yeah, if it weren't
for sexual inadequacy,
the National Rifle
Association would go broke.
He's moved in with Howard
Cummings, nee Kaminsky.
And not only is
he sleeping with a man,
soon he'll be
celebrating Purim.
More important,
for the first time
in his adult life,
he's happy.
I should have known why I
was failing you, Marietta,
not fulfilling
your womanly needs.
Which turned out to
be quite considerable.
Mine, too, but not with the sex
I'd been raised to be attracted to.
You're like
a changed man, John.
Your whole personality
is sunnier.
If only it had
been that way.
I couldn't when I was
making love to you.
I was a square peg
in a round hole,
you should pardon
the metaphor.
Well, I just hope
you two lucked out
and found the right person
in each other.
I know I lucked out.
What about you, Boris?
As you would say in the crude
fashion of your generation,
I totally lucked out.
It just shows what meaningless
blind chance the universe is.
Everybody schemes and dreams
to meet the right person,
and I jump out a window
and land on her.
And a psychic yet!
I mean, come on, talk
about the irrational heart,
not to mention I've developed
a fondness for grits.
I have a question, am I
a member of my generation?
Yes. Don't worry.
I'll explain it to you.
Hey, hey, hold on! Hold on!
The ball's about to drop!
Come on!
Ten,
nine,
eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three,
two, one!
Happy new year!
I happen to hate
New Year's celebrations.
Everybody desperate
to have fun.
Trying to celebrate
in some pathetic little way.
Celebrate what?
A step closer to the grave?
That's why I can't
say enough times,
whatever love
you can get and give,
whatever happiness
you can filch or provide,
every temporary measure
of grace, whatever works.
And don't kid yourself,
it's by no means
all up to your
own human ingenuity.
A bigger part of your existence
is luck than you'd like to admit.
Christ, you know the odds
of your father's one sperm
from the billions, finding
the single egg that made you?
Don't think about it,
you'll have a panic attack.
Boris, what are you doing?
Who you talking to?
What? There's people
out there watching us.
They're out there?
Yeah, yeah,
they're watching. What?
Please, Boris...
- You know...
Well, there was
when we started.
I don't know
how many are left.
Does anybody see
anybody out there?
Out there? No!
No!
Boris!
- No!
See? I'm the only one
who sees the whole picture.
That's what they mean
by genius.
Come on.
Happy new year, Boris.