MEGA DENG COOPER MINE, INDIA
Watch out, watch out!
Welcome my friend!
- Great to see you!
- Glad you made it
This can't be Ajit.
He's a little man
already. Unbelievable.
I hope you're
hungry, Adrian.
I'm famished. How
are you, Aparna?
I made that fish
curry you love.
I can't wait.
She gets more beautiful
every time I see her,
Why is that?
Strange, isn't it?
But her fish curry
is still awful.
You were mysterious
on the phone.
Why didn't you attend
the conference?
I will show you, Adrian, sir.
Satnam. Stop sir-ing me.
How deep do we need to go?
11.000 feet.
Searched all over India
for this dig.
Used to be the deepest
copper mine in the world.
Remember my brother Gurdeep?
He's a student now.
Namaste, Dr Helmsley, sir.
Adrian. It's just Adrian.
Just don't pour too much, okay?
How do you work
in this heat?
You've come on a good
day, my friend.
Sometimes it can
be 120° F.
I want you to meet
Dr Lokesh?
Fellow of Quantum Physics
at the University in Chennai
- Namaste
- Dr Helmsley
So, what are we
looking at?
These neutrinos are
acting normally. No mass,
no electrical charge.
They pass through
ordinary matter
almost undisturbed.
Your message said
the count doubled
after the last
solar eruptions.
That was last week.
But this happened
two days ago.
The biggest solar eruptions
in human history.
Causing the highest
neutrino count
we've ever recorded.
My God.
That's not what
worries me, Adrian.
For the first time ever
the neutrinos are causing
a physical reaction
That's impossible.
Ah!
That feels very good!
Please, follow me.
You wont believe this.
This water tank goes
down another 6000 feet.
It looks like the neutrinos
coming from the sun
have mutated into a new
kind of nuclear particle.
They're heating up
the Earth's core.
And suddenly act
like microwaves.
Ladies and gentlemen.
As promised:
No speech!
Just a "thank you".
Because tonight, with your
extraordinary generosity,
we have raised
1.7 million dollars.
It's okay.
- I work for the White House.
- I don't care who you are, sir
This is a black tie event.
Scotty!
Hey, Adrian, I thought
you were in India
What's going on?
- I need your jacket
- What?
I gotta speak
to Anheuser
- I don't wanna give...
- Give me your damn jacket!
Take it, please.
Easy! That's a
600 dollar jacket.
Mr Anheuser?
I need to talk to you.
Do I know you?
Sorry sir, my name is
Dr Adrian Helmsley
I'm a deputy geologist
at the Office of
Science and Technology Policy
Excuse me, fellows.
You know that this
is a fund-raiser,
not a frat party, right?
It's extremely
important, sir.
It always is. Here is
what I want you to do:
Make an appointment
or even better,
Have your boss bring it up at
the quarterly science briefing
There's a good plan.
I just traveled 20 straight
hours to get here, sir.
I haven't slept in two days.
You need to read this, sir.
You need to read it now!
Let me guess.
National geology crisis?
Excuse me.
Who do you
report to?
Lico Vasos
Not anymore.
Al, bring the car around.
You may wish you
took a shower.
You're about to meet
the president.
What's going on?
Get that to the office.
G8 SUMMIT, BRITISH COLUMBIA
Good morning.
I would like to
meet privately
with my fellow
heads of state.
Mr  wishes to have
his interpreters present.
Mr President,
I can assure you
Your English is more
than sufficient
for what I have to say.
Mr President.
Six months ago, I was
made aware of a
situation so devastating
that at first
I refused to believe it.
However,
through the concerted efforts
of our brightest scientists,
we have confirmed its validity.
The world
as we know it
will soon come
to an end.
CHO MING VALLEY, TIBET
This dam project will create
many new jobs.
The Party and Country will
assist in your re-location.
Grandma, give me
your hand.
But where are
they taking us?
It'll be alright.
Brother!
Grandma, I will send you money.
Who can write?
Who can read?
Who can weld?
EMPIRE GRAND HOTEL, LONDON
Has His Highness
had an opportunity
to study the dossier?
You must understand
I have a big family, Mr...
Isaacs.
One billion dollars is
a lot of money.
I'm afraid the amount
is in Euros,
Your Highness.
MUSÉE DU LOUVRE, PARIS
I put a lot of faith into
your organization.
It's a perfect
replica, Roland.
There are too many
fanatics out there
that could damage her.
Just think about
the beautiful
Buddha statues they
blew up in Afghanistan.
Our Heritage Organization
has already made selections
from the British Museum
and Hermitage.
I guess she'll be safe now,
tucked away.
Hidden, in some bunker
in Switzerland.
Perfectly safe, Roland.
Only infrared analysis can
reveal the difference.
But it's still a fake.
This mass suicide was actually
discovered by a documentary crew
here in the ancient
Mayan city of Takal
Now the victims,
and we've seen many,
are said to have adhered
to the Mayan-Quiche calender,
which predicts the
end of time to occur
on the 21st December
of this year,
due to the suns
destructive forces.
Thank you, Mark.
Strangely enough, scientific
records do support the fact
that we are heading for
the biggest solar climax
in recorded history.
MANHATTAN BEACH, CALIFORNIA
Many people believe
that the Mayan Calender
predicts that there's supposed
to be a galactic alignment...
I'm a dead man.
Hey, Kate, I'm practically
on the freeway right now.
Yes, I'm rolling towards
you as we speak.
Would you relax?
I'll be there any second.
You know it's a vacation and not
a doctors appointment, right?
It's supposed to be fun.
You remember fun,
don't you Kate?
Do you remember
where you were
when it stopped
being fun for you?
Got it.
Bug spray?
Oh yeah, cause it's mosquito
season in Yellowstone.
I got a whole bunch. I gotta go,
I'm in a bad reception area.
Woah, man. Would you
look at that?
Sick
Merrill, I told you.
We have to move back
to Wisconsin.
These little mini-quakes are
really getting on my nerves, Randy.
Come on, a little surface crack, you're
not gonna be inconvenienced by that
Surface cracks, I've got a
plastic surgeon for that
No kidding. Thank God for
those shake-proof coffee mugs.
They show the true nature
of us Californians.
We'll not bow to these little
inconvenient things like surface quakes.
Do you have a funny mini-quake
story and want to share it?
Call Lisa & Randy at 555...
- Hi daddy!
- Hi baby
- How are you sweety?
- Good
Jackson, what is this?
- Please don't call me that.
I'm your dad.
Taking them camping
in a limo?
Okay, great. What happened
to your temp job?
Better hours, more
time to write.
What about sleeping, have you
been doing that lately?
I've said it a
thousand times.
No lipo on Fridays.
It's too messy.
Hold on.
- Morning Jackson.
- Hi
- Nice ride.
- Thanks.
Have a nice trip. Remember,
watch out for the bears.
- Bye, Gordon
- Love you, Honey.
Bye
Okay, so...
- You tell him.
Tell me what?
She needs to put these on every
night before she goes to sleep.
Still?
Yes. Your 7 year old daughter
still wets her bed.
Maybe that's something
you should know.
- Love you
- Love you, Mom.
- Hey
- You okay?
They really were looking forward
to spending some time with you
I know.
So don't be on your
computer all the time.
Got it.
Love you!
- So this time we'll hit Japan.
- So?
Now you can visit
your boy, Will.
Afternoon, ladies!
Are you even
listening to me?
Unfortunately I am, Harry.
I heard from Audrey you're
a grandpa now.
Would you mind keeping your
nose out of my family?
You're cramping my style, baby.
There we are.
So he married a Japanese girl,
how's that the end of the world?
Come on Tony, you should
at least go see him.
- You see your boy?
- Not as much as I'd like
DC is a long way, but
at least we talk
About what?
Life.
And how short it is.
What the hell was that?
- Hello?
- Laura?
Laura, can you hear me?
Roland, is that you?
Laura, they lied to us.
I've arranged a press
conference for tomorrow.
I will tell everyone the truth
about what is going on.
What are you talking about?
The art you collected
is not in the Alps.
Those tunnels are empty.
I have proof!
Laura, can you hear me?
I'm losing you, Roland.
YELLOWSTONE
NATIONAL PARK
- I liked that song.
- We lost it.
...the west coast with
all those surface cracks,
I told myself: Charlie,
get your stupid ass
to Yellowstone.
I don't want to miss all the
fun when it finally goes.
Let me tell you, there's been
government people flying
in and out all morning and
trust me, they do not look happy.
Always remember, folks...
- It's weird.
Can you believe
he said that?
What are the odds?
We're not seeing the soil
liquefaction we'd expect
or any evidence of
fracture propagation
within the tectonic plates.
- English, doctor.
- The seismic activity
on the west coast is
not caused by tect...
regular earth quakes.
And these surface cracks
have nothing to do
with shifting fault lines.
Are you suggesting this
could be the beginning
of the Joline operation?
- Dr Helmsley is flying to
Yellowstone to collect
more data, sir.
We've been following the schedule
you established, Mr Helmsley.
The most important schedule
in the history of mankind.
Now you're telling me we
have to throw it out?
Yes, sir.
I was wrong.
Do you know how
many times I've heard
those words
in this office?
Zero.
Did you see this?
I'm sorry Mr President.
She insisted.
It's all over the news.
We are learning more about
this deadly car explosion,
The director of the French
National Museum
was scheduled to hold
a press conference at
the Louvre this morning.
Coincidentally, his death took
place in the same Paris tunnel
where Princess Diana
died in 1997.
We are continuing to
follow this story...
Laura, I don't believe
you've met Dr Helmsley.
I just talked to him Dad,
and he told me...
the organization I
work for is a sham.
Why would he say that?
You look just like your mother
when you get upset.
- Did I ever tell you that?
- Every time I get upset.
Daddy, a man was killed.
Honey. Please sit down.
Only a dozen people
in this administration
know what I'm
about to tell you.
Dad, what's going on?
An unprecedented
international endeavor
is under way.
At this point 46 nations
are invested in this thing.
Laura's a smart girl.
She'll understand.
That thing in Paris.
We're not involved in
any of that, are we?
"We"?
Who the hell is "we"?
What are you
talking about?
What we need to do is
focus on this time line.
So when do we let
the country know?
What do you mean?
- The people, sir.
They need to know.
Well of course
they do. Listen.
Your job is to figure out when
this is all gonna fall apart.
My job is to figure out how to
retain some type of government
after it falls apart.
Until then we don't have
time for anything
except those jobs. Okay?
Call me when you have
any news from Yellowstone.
- Cute girl, huh?
- Sir?
The First Daughter,
I saw you looking at her.
- I wasn't looking at her
- Better move fast kid
The end is near.
Your chopper's ready.
They're waiting
on the south lawn.
- Daddy, where are we going?
- This special place I know
Actually, it's a place
where your mom and I
used to hang out a lot.
I don't want to know
where you and mom had sex.
I'm not ready
for that, Jackson.
Stop calling me that,
it's creeping me out.
What's wrong with "Dad"?
Daddy, look at this.
That wasn't here before.
What did I do?
Go get your hat.
Can't you see the signs?
There used to be
a lake here.
Doesn't look much
of a lake to me.
I know. The whole
damn thing's gone.
Come on, let's
check it out.
Great.
Subjects have now
entered hot zone.
What is that?
It's the U.S. Army.
All manner of
government vehicle
are converging
on subjects.
You're in a
restricted area, sir.
We need you and your
family to come with us.
Right. Okay, we're gonna
go with these guys.
That'll be fun, huh?
This is wild.
This is really wild.
This is unbelievable.
2700° C at 40.000 feet?
I know, it sounds
completely implausible.
Nonetheless, we're noticing
an increase of almost 0.5%
- Per day?
- No.
Per hour.
Dr Helmsley, we arrested
some tourists in the hot zone.
I'll take care of it.
Let's get Satnam on the
communications link.
Cross reference the data.
It's a national park, there's
not supposed to be fences.
What's going on here?
We're geologists.
You usually go digging
with machine guns?
Major, I'll take care
of this, thank you.
So what happened
to the lake?
Well that's what we're
trying to find out.
We think the entire area
has become unstable.
I think you should take
your kids and leave, Mr...
Curtis.
You're not by any chance
the Jackson Curtis who
wrote "Farewell Atlantis"?
The very same.
It's actually dedicated
to my mom.
I read a couple of your
short stories in college.
Your father is a
very talented man
Listen up.
It's amazing.
I'm reading your book.
I'm around day 300,
the shuttle has just
lost communication
with Earth.
You're one of the lucky
few who bought it.
- I didn't buy it.
- No?
My dad gave
it to me.
Let me ask
you something.
Do you think those people
would behave so selflessly
knowing that their own
lives were at stake?
I hope so.
The critics said I was naive,
an unabashed optimist,
but what do
they know, right?
It was a great pleasure
meeting you.
Mayor, could you escort
these good people
to the camp
grounds, please.
This is yours.
- Thank you
- Yes, sir.
- Take care.
- Okay
He was very nice.
You're just saying that
cause you like my book.
Looks like that boy
of yours is gonna be
smarter than any of us.
What's wrong?
I sent Satnam the
temperature readings.
My colleagues in Argentina
and Ontario have
almost identical data.
It's so hot here we've
had to seal off the mine.
Did you double check
the numbers?
I triple checked,
my friend.
I wish we were
wrong, but
we're not.
The Earth's crust is
destabilizing.
It's too early.
Adrian. You have to
begin the evacuation.
My God.
All our scientific advances,
our fancy machines,
the Mayans saw this coming
thousands of years ago.
I thought we'd
have more time.
Okay.
Okay, I want you to
pack up your family.
I'm gonna arrange
an airlift from Delhi.
Thank you my friend.
And good luck.
Ajit.
We are going
on a big ship.
Wait. Wait, wait.
Sorry. One question.
What did the government
guys say to you?
They don't like us going
over their fences and
that the whole area
back there is unstable.
"Unstable"?
They said "unstable"?
That's funny.
Let's go.
"Unstable".
It's not just
Yellowstone, sir.
Temperatures are rising
with incredible velocity
in hot zones across
the globe.
Are you absolutely sure
about this, Adrian?
Once we give these orders,
there's no going back.
I'm afraid there's
no longer any doubt.
We have to save
what we can.
And we have
to move now!
There's mosquitoes in here.
Did anybody spray the tent?
I'm gonna get that
spray tomorrow.
They just like you because
your blood's so sweet.
Dad, you said you wouldn't
work on your book.
What?
I'm not, I'm doing
something else.
Okay.
Did you really need
all these hats?
Where are
your pull-ups?
I have them on.
Who gave you this?
Mommy?
No, Gordon gave it to me
for my birthday.
A cell phone is something
we got to talk about
As a family.
What family?
It hurts my feelings when
you say stuff like that.
Go away.
Adults get hurt feelings too.
No way.
...tell the truth.
Thank you, Bill.
What is your question?
I wanted to know, where
is all this gonna start?
Well, something like this could
only originate in Hollywood.
They have the earth cracking
under their asses already.
Our family believes in the
gospel of the lord Jesus.
We have nothing
to fear, Charlie.
Good for you, Bill.
Thanks for calling.
This is Charlie Frost
reporting live from
Yellowstone National Park,
soon to become the worlds
largest active volcano.
I'll be right back, folks.
Do you mind
if I join you?
I wanted to ask
you something.
I only got a minute.
Pickle?
I was listening to the broadcast
and I was wondering
what exactly is it that's
gonna start in Hollywood?
It's the Apocalypse.
End of days.
The Judgment Day. The end
of the world, my friend.
Christians call it The Rapture,
but the Mayans
knew about it, the Hopis,
The I Ching, the Bible.
- Beer?
- Yeah.
So look, I gotta eat.
Why don't you
download my blog?
It's free. Of course, we do
appreciate donations.
In ancient times, the Mayan
people were the first
civilization to discover
that this planet had
an expiration date.
According to their calender,
in the year 2012 a
cataclysmic event will unfold,
caused by an alignment
of the planets in our solar system
that only happens
every 640.000 years.
Oh, not again.
Neat, huh? I did all
the animation myself.
Just imagine the earth
as an orange
You lure them in
with humor.
Then you make
them think.
Our sun will begin to emit such
extreme amounts of radiation,
Screw you bastards.
That the core of the earth
will melt at the inside
part of the orange.
Leaving the crust of our
planet free to shift.
In 1958 Professor Charles
Hapgood named it:
"Earth Crust Displacement"
Albert Einstein
did support it.
People will get it all, the
forces of Mother Nature
will be so devastating
It will bring an end to
this world on winter
Solstice 12-21-12.
Always remember, folks.
You heard it first from
Charlie Frost.
You'd have to keep a thing
like this under wraps.
Just think about it.
First, the stock market would go.
Then the economy: Boom!
The dollar: Boom!
And then pandemonium
in the street.
War, genocide.
Boom Boom Boom!
Bullshit. Nobody could keep
that big a secret, Charlie.
Somebody would blow
the whistle
An every once in a while,
some poor sucker tries.
Like these guys.
Boom! Boom!
Every one of these
guys: Dead! Dead! Dead!
Woah, that's
Professor Meyers.
He ran the Atlantis
Shuttle Program.
Did you know him?
- Yeah, he helped me out
with research on my book.
Well, that must have been
before his accident.
- Meyers is dead?
- Yeah, two months ago.
He was one of my
most avid listeners.
He had it all figured out.
Everything the government
was doing, where, why.
He even sent me a map.
A map for what, Charlie?
What's the map for?
They're building
space ships, man.
Shit, man, I have to go.
I gotta get back to Earth.
- Do you have a beer?
- This is my last.
- Alright, I really enjoyed
most of this.
Thank you so much.
- Guess what, they're
selling seats!
- Put me down for three.
- No! Guys like you and me
don't have any chance.
You'd have to be Bill Gates
or Rupert Murdoch
or some Russian
billionaire.
Keep it down, my kids
are sleeping.
Get them out of Yellowstone.
It's gonna get ugly here.
Why don't we
make a baby?
We're not making a baby
at the supermarket.
Hands off the
merchandise.
Honey, woman give me
thousands of dollars
to handle their boobs.
You get it for free.
You always act strange
after he shows up.
I'm not acting strange,
I'm looking for macaroni.
So why did you stick with
him so long anyways?
Can we just give
it a rest, please?
- He's the father of my children.
- Oh, come on, Kate
You gave up med school so
you could have Noah.
You practically raised him
and Lilly by yourself
while he sat glued to a
laptop writing that junk.
It's not junk!
He's published.
Oh, published.
Right, I forgot.
422 copies.
- Did you see that?
- See what?
Kate, listen, we have to
keep working at this.
Our relationship.
I don't know, Honey, I feel
like there's something
pulling us apart.
Grab the pole!
Kate, don't let go!
Do you have anything
for mosquito bites?
Before or after?
- I'll get before and after.
- Stop scratching or you're
gonna get it all infected.
...and I had to make a quick
stop at the grocery store...
It's Mrs Birnbaum
She's my teacher.
She's on TV!
...market which was open
for business at the time
but fortunately there are no
fatalities or injuries reported.
It really is a miracle
that no one got hurt.
Hello? Hi mom.
Did you see what happened
to our supermarket?
She wants us to
come home.
Is this even possible?
We worked every
option through the night.
The good news: consensus
is that 4 of the Arks
will be operational in time.
- Only 4? You call
that good news?
- We can save over
400.000 people.
To me, sir, that's nothing
short of a miracle.
But we have to initiate
the boarding process now.
Thomas. We don't
have a choice.
You have got to
convince them.
According to the
latest information...
- Please continue, Adrian.
- Thank you, sir.
The temperature of the
subterranean crust,
that is the cement that holds
our landmass in place,
Is increasing at a rapid rate
much faster than anticipated.
As a result we've observed
extreme polar instability
The magnetic fields
have decreased
by more than 80%
in the last 48 hours.
How much time do we
have, Dr Helmsley?
Two, maybe three days,
if we're lucky.
How can you speak about
luck in such a situation?
Apologies, Mr Prime Minister.
I meant no disrespect.
I'm afraid the
longer we wait,
the more luck
plays its part.
My friends.
I recommend we
evacuate immediately.
If any of you
have objections
Please speak now.
In the blue corner:
38 victories, 34 knockouts,
The fighting machine
from the Ukraine
The undefeated number
one ranked
heavyweight challenger:
Mr. Zultan Balashin!
- Yuri!
- Zultan!
I feared you would
not come.
He needs to concentrate
now. Mr Karpov.
You shut up while I talk
to my boy, understand?
- Yes, Mr Karpov.
- Good. That is good.
Zultan, listen to me.
We are fighters,
we never go down.
No matter how
hard they hit us.
Kill the bastard.
Let's get ready to rumble!
ATTENTION:
START BOARDING PROCEDURE
Yuri, where are you going?
Yuri!
CalTech believes that the
fissures running through
Westwood has released most
of the surface tension.
Life in the city will
soon return to normal,
Mayor Gonzales said...
Okay guys.
Almost home.
Rise and shine.
Alright, you're free.
Mommy!
Hi, sweetheart.
Gordon!
Hey, buddy boy.
Had a good time?
God, I missed you.
- Who wants pancakes?
- Me!
Thanks for bringing
them home early.
Yeah.
Pancakes?
Late for work.
- Yes, hello?
- Curtis, where are you?
- Just back from vacation, sir.
- Good. That is good.
I will send a jet to pick
up Alec and Oleg.
Yuri bear. Tell him to bring
the rain coat for Caesar.
It's in the Range Rover.
- Curtis?
- Yeah
Get my boys as
fast as you can.
I'm hurling towards
you as we speak, sir.
Good. That is good.
- Curtis, you're late.
- Good morning to you too.
Be careful with our stuff.
Don't get your dirt
on it. Idiot.
Took you a while,
Mr. Curtis.
What's your problem?
Be more careful.
He did that
on purpose.
Have a safe trip,
you little bastards.
Now you're
laughing, Curtis.
But we have tickets
to go on a big ship.
We will leave,
and you will die.
Did you hear that?
The authorities in L.A.
say there's nothing
to worry about.
I'd love to see their
faces when Malibu
and Beverly Hills sink
down into the Pacific.
Where will they plug in
their electric cars then?
Hey!
- Is this your plane?
- Yeah
- Are you a pilot?
I want to rent it, okay?
I'll give anything you want.
Here, take this very
expensive watch.
My neighbor gave it
to me when he
thought I was gonna
be somebody.
...CalTech, that in the
last 36 hours we have
basically zero earthquake
activity in Southern California,
which is very rare.
Unlike the tough characters
I have portrayed in my films...
Hello?
Hey. Stop what you're doing.
- Jackson?
Listen to me. I've rented
a plane, pack up the kids,
I'm gonna be there
in 5 minutes.
What are you
talking about?
We're gonna have
a regular Saturday.
Noah has music at 2:00
and Lilly has karate.
You expect him
to remember?
Kate, California
is going down.
- Pack up the kids now!
- They just got back.
God, you sound like
a crazy person.
The governor just said
we're fine now.
The guy's an actor, he's
reading a script!
When they tell you
not to panic
That's when you run!
Will you call me back
when you calm down?
Mommy, why are you
acting so crazy?
Finish your pancakes,
Al Capone.
...it seems to me that
the worst is over.
Hold Mommy's hands!
Let's go!
- I think it's safer under here!
Get in the fucking car!
Come on, kids!
Get in. Get in.
My hats!
Buckle up!
Sorry.
Jackson. Hurry up!
Look behind you!
Oh God.
Get out of the way!
- Move it!
Hold on, dear.
Come on,
you old bags!
We gotta get to Santa
Monica Airport.
Take the freeway. It'll
be half the time.
Yeah, right.
We gotta get to the other
side of the freeway.
Dad, look!
They've just been upgraded
to a 10.9 by Harvard.
What does CalTech
have to say?
The city of Pasadena
was wiped out.
Just a few
minutes ago.
This is coming in live
from Coachella Valley
near Joshua Tree.
That huge canyon,
It wasn't there
this morning.
100 miles further North,
same thing.
The San Andreas Fault
is shifting.
Yes.
And all major sister
faults in the bay area.
The whole Pacific Plate
is destabilizing.
Come on!
- Who's that?
- Our pilot.
Dead pilot!
Gordon!
You can fly!
I've only had a couple
of lessons in a
single engine
plane only.
- You're the guy!
- No, I'm not the guy!
Trust me!
You're the guy.
I'm not being
modest about this!
Come on, kids.
Gordon's gonna
get us out of here.
That plane has
multiple engines.
Jackson!
- T's and P's
- TNP?
- What?
- Temperatures and Pressures
- Let's go!
- My preflight check
Let him concentrate,
Jackson.
He has no experience.
Thank you.
Gordon! Go!
Go go go!
We're not there yet.
- Punch it!
- We need 85 knots.
- 80 is good!
- Let's do it.
Okay, we're up.
Lilly, go sit with
your brother.
How did you know
this would happen?
It's not just California.
The whole damn world
is going to shit.
I met this crazy guy
in Yellowstone
But he's been right about
everything so far
He said the government
is building these ships,
space ships,
I don't know what,
but something...
- Space ships?
Yeah. Places where
we could be safe.
He knows where they
are. He's got a map.
- Jackson...
- Kate, trust me on this.
Guys. Look.
But it ain't the end
of the world, Buddy.
It's only the end
of this song.
It's been a gas, been a
flip, been a hell of a trip,
But it ain't the end
of the world.
Oh yeah!
- Thank you. Thank you.
- You got fans, Tony.
There's a call for you, Harry.
Want me to take a message?
No, thats alright.
Yeah, hello?
- Dad?
- Adrian!
Remember I told you
about that dam in China?
- Yeah.
- It's happening, Dad.
They'd probably shoot me
if they knew I told you.
Nobody's gonna
shoot you, son.
They need you.
The President has
ordered us to
clear out the
White House.
About time somebody
cleaned up that mess.
Where are you, Dad?
What is the course of
The Genesis right now?
It's all good, Adrian.
Don't you be worrying
about your old man.
You have more important
things to do now.
You know...
Your mom and I...
We had one hell of
a great life, son.
And the best
part about that...
We had one hell of
a great kid, too.
This Genesis is a pretty
big ship, son.
Don't you write your
old man off just yet.
Besides...
You know I couldn't
leave Tony alone.
That old fool can't keep
decent time by himself.
I love you, Dad.
I love you too, son.
God knows I do.
Herb. I want a double.
- Harry...
- I need a double.
Thank you, son.
After 25 year on
the wagon.
Are you out
of your mind?
- What are you doing?
- Gotta go.
That's against
regulation!
Anything?
Yeah, there's fuel.
Fill her up, I'm gonna
gonna go find Charlie.
Daddy, wait, I wanna
come with you!
No Lil! No!
It's alright, I'll take her.
Just fill it up
I'll be right back.
Jackson, hurry please!
I'm standing here at
the highest point
of what is the rim
of the worlds
largest super volcano,
Mount Big Horn.
Charlie!
I can only hope
that all of you have
made your peace
It's gotta be around
here somewhere.
- Let's go back, Daddy.
- No no no
We gotta find Charlie,
cause he's got a map.
It's like a secret map.
Like in pirate movies.
We gotta work
as a team, okay?
- Okay
- Okay, come on.
Call Mom. Tell her we're
gonna be 5 minutes late.
- Noah.
- I need to talk to Mom.
- It's Lilly.
- Sweety, where are you?
- Hi Mommy
- Let me speak to Daddy
He cant talk right now.
He's driving really fast.
- Ouch!
- Lilly?
Who is that? Who's
speaking in the car?
He's not in the car,
he's on a mountain
waiting for fireworks.
Fireworks?
What fireworks?
Daddy, over there.
Good job, Lilly.
Let me talk
to mom now.
- Hey! We got him.
- Bring back my child!
You stay here.
I will go talk to
the pirate, okay?
Charlie!
What are you doing?
I thought you were toast.
No no no! Where are
the space ships?
No way you can
make it there.
We have a plane.
You can come with us.
But we gotta leave
right now!
Fly birdies!
Is this your kid?
Where's the
god damn map?
Where's the map?
- It's in the camper.
- Where in the camper?
Map section. On the
conspiracy shelf.
Dewey Decimal System.
Between Roswell...
and Marilyn Monroe?
It's starting.
You sure you don't
wanna come with me?
So beautiful,
I'm gonna stay.
Good luck.
This marks
The last day of the
United States of America
Final hour of all mankind.
As we will be visible from
the Milky Way as a tiny
little puff of smoke.
I'm watching the Earth
crumble before my eyes.
The giant ash cloud
created by this
super volcano
will first envelop Vegas,
and then St. Louis
and then Chicago,
and then at long last,
Washington D.C. will
have its lights go out.
That guy is crazy,
right Daddy?
Don't think so.
This is ridiculous.
It's been over
half an hour.
- The guy is a nut job.
- Stop it.
Noah, give me
the phone again.
Daddy. What was that?
Nothing. Nothing.
I have goosebumps,
people!
I wish you could see
what I'm seeing, people.
I wish you could be
here with me!
Oh, baby!
Bring it on!
Always remember folks:
You heard it first
from Charlie!
Daddy, it's following us!
Get down on the
ground and hold on.
Don't look back.
Just look at me.
- Do I look scared?
- Uhum.
Hold on baby.
Hold on tight.
Daddy, we're on fire!
There they are!
It's them.
It's them!
Mommy!
Shit.
Hang on baby.
Hang on
Mommy.
- Lil, grab my hand.
- Come on, Noah.
Lilly, you okay?
Everybody on? Ready?
- Jackson!
Where is he?
What's he doing?
No!
- Daddy!
- No!
Hey. We have to go.
No, we're not
going anywhere!
Kids, buckle up.
We're leaving.
He's my dad.
We're gonna wait!
No!
Daddy!
Wait! Wait. Roland,
I see something.
It's Daddy!
Slow down!
Jackson, come on!
Grab!
We're running out
of runway.
For God's sakes, Kate,
pull him up.
Reach for my hand!
- Come on!
- Daddy!
Right. Here we go!
Faster. Faster.
Hang on
- Go faster!
- I'm trying!
Okay. We're good.
We're good.
So. Now that you
got your map,
where are we going?
CHINA
We're gonna need
a bigger plane.
You just said that, Mom.
You just said that.
You don't remember that
you just said that?
That's okay.
Listen, Mom. I'll call you
next week, same time.
Okay? Take care now.
Take care of yourself.
Sir. I think you
need to see this.
I thought they'd give
you an extra ticket, Sir.
They did.
But my mother is almost 89.
She's in a wheelchair.
And she is easily confused.
And I am confident
that she'll want to
meet her maker
- on her own terms. Okay?
- Yes, sir.
- Who are you bringing?
- Nobody.
My ex-wife said she never
wanted to see me again.
So be it.
We could bring people
that contribute.
...has been damaged by a
series of major earthquakes.
The death toll is expected to be
well over 2 million people.
The devastation in Rio de Janeiro
is beyond imagination.
Two 8.5 tremors have left the people
in the street fighting for resources.
In the last hour we received this
video from Globo News, Brazil.
What's happening? My God!
The statue of Christ is collapsing!
Fear and chaos have spread
throughout the globe.
As in London, where the 30th
Olympic Games has been suspended.
Hundreds of thousands are marching
towards 10 Downing Street
demanding a lift of the information
blackout proposed by the Prime Minister.
Thousands of calls to the switchboard.
We had to shut it down.
We're receiving reports
from all across the globe.
Millions of distraught masses are
gathering in public places everywhere,
converging in
desperate prayer.
Preachers of many faiths
have taken their message of
the end of the world to
the streets all over the U.S.
Repent.
There is still time.
Kind of gaulling when
you realize the nutbags
with the cardboard signs
had it right the whole time.
All these people
out there, sir.
Shouldn't we be issuing
warnings now?
Only when the boarding
process is complete.
That's the plan.
British Columbia
2010, remember?
Sir, those plans were
drawn up 2 years ago.
Okay, everybody out.
Come on, get out.
Wasn't it also decided that
people have the right to
fight for their lives,
best way they can?
After we get everyone
on board, Adrian.
I think that's wrong.
Want to tell everyone
they're doomed?
There'd be anarchy.
You want to jeopardize the
departure of the president?
Our mission is to assure the
continuity of our species.
My question:
Can I count on you?
Can I?
What?
The Yellowstone Caldera
has erupted, sir.
The ash cloud will reach
Washington in 7 hours.
We've got to get away.
Where is the
president, Sally?
Said he wanted to spend
some time alone.
- I think he's at the chapel.
- He's going to church now?
He's praying, sir. Which is
not such a bad idea.
Mr. President. I need
to get you on
Air Force One
immediately.
Give me a moment
with Adrian.
No disrespect sir, we
do not have time.
Make time.
Did you ever meet
my wife: Dorothy?
No sir, I never had
that honor.
She was in and out
towards the end
The night before she
passed on, she took
my hand and told me:
"I think you should
have a lottery"
"Everyone should have
a chance to go"
Maybe that's what we
should have done.
I'll be the last president of
the United States of America.
Do you know how
that feels, son?
No one could have saved
the country, sir.
And I think, I think people
have a right to know.
Don't worry, I'll
take care of that.
Go on now.
Not without you, sir.
Get on that plane, son.
It's a brave new world
you head into
And a young scientist will
be worth 20 old politicians.
We should go to my parents
house in the Rockies.
This isn't one of your crazy
stories, now. Right, Jackson?
How the hell are we going
to make it to China?
Hey, Gordon.
Without Jackson we wouldn't
have made it out of California.
Noah, please.
Be careful with
the landing gear!
Easy gringo, I know
what I'm doing.
Attention!
The National Guard
has informed us that an
extremely hazardous
ash cloud is headed for
the city of Las Vegas.
Where are you going?
Move! You can't
stay here.
- I have a plane here.
- It's not safe.
So you got positive
confirmation on this?
Thank you,
I understand.
The President
is not coming.
So, the Captain won't
abandon his sinking ship.
That's his choice,
and a noble one.
I have also
just learned
that the Vice
President's chopper
went down in the ash
cloud outside Pittsburgh.
Fortunately, we have
protocols to follow.
What about the Speaker
of the House?
In this chaos, I have
no idea. Where is he?
He's the Commander
in Chief now, sir.
This is one flight he
shouldn't be late for.
Tell the Captain
we're taking off.
Sir, you don't have
the authority.
Who got the authority?
You? You got the authority?
You couldn't even keep
your damn mouth shut.
You betrayed top secret
information.
What the hell are
you talking about?
You told your father
everything,
put this entire
plan in jeopardy,
Good thing for you
the old man could
keep his mouth shut
better than you.
Don't look so shocked.
We had to monitor
everybody who knew,
How do you think we kept
it a secret for so long?
So you just killed anybody
who tried to talk?
Anybody who tried to talk
was not just an enemy
of the state. They were
an enemy of humanity.
The director of the Louvre
was an enemy of humanity?
After he called a press
conference he was.
Jesus, what did
you think?
We're all just gonna
get on board,
hold hands and
sing Kumbaya?
Sit down and
buckle up.
Excuse me, is my father
in the Command Center?
President is on
the line, Dr Wilson.
Thank you.
Where are you?
You never would've gotten
on that plane if I told you.
But you said that
you'd be here
Darling, listen to me.
Do you understand how
much strength it gives me
knowing that you
will survive?
The only thing left
to do now,
is tell the truth
to people.
At least if they know,
families can say
goodbye to each other.
A mother can comfort
her children.
And a father...
can ask his daughter
for forgiveness.
Whenever you're ready,
Mr President.
My fellow Americans
This will be the last
time I address you.
As you know, catastrophe
has struck our nation.
Has struck the world.
I wish I could tell you
we could prevent
the coming destruction.
We cannot.
Today, none of us
are strangers.
Today, we are
one family,
stepping into the
darkness together.
We are a nation of
many religions,
but I believe these
words reflect the spirit
of all our faiths:
"The lord is my
Shepard. I shall... "
People! Get away from
the doors and windows.
What are we gonna do?
You tell me.
- Dr Silberman?
- Tamara!
What are you
doing here?
She's a patient,
Honey.
Excuse me, I have a
private plane out there.
Karpov! Yuri!
You knew. This whole
time you knew.
You've got a way out of here,
right? You got a plane?
My family, take us
with you. Please!
Boss, boss.
I found us a plane.
An Antonov.
They were just
about to take off,
but the tower
didn't let them.
Can you still fly
that thing?
Sure, Boss, but
I need co-pilot.
Gordon's a pilot.
No, I'm not.
Yes he is. Great pilot.
Let's go.
Good. Let's go!
Jackson, stop
saying I'm a pilot.
You can't go out there.
Come back!
Move back, people!
Wow, that's
a big plane.
It's Russian.
Let's move everybody.
Come on!
- Gordon, where are you?
- Let's go!
Up here, Gordon.
Hurry up!
Oh my God.
- Woah, look at these.
- Las Vegas auto show.
We had VIP tickets
for this.
That's fantastic, let's go.
Check the main bus
for hydraulics,
I'll balance the tanks.
What?
Okay, okay.
I'm trying.
Tower to Antonov, what
the hell are you doing?
Shut down immediately.
- Caesar, shh.
When I say "go"
we push all this down
at once, okay?
- Okay.
- Go!
Antonov, abort take-off.
You do not have clearance.
I repeat, you
must abort.
What the hell
was that?
I don't know, but
it's not good.
- Push!
- Pushing! Come on!
We're going down!
It must be the...
Take over.
What do you mean,
take over?
- Sasha!
- Relax.
Now!
Jesus.
- Oh God
- I think I got it
- Sasha, now!
- Take a deep breath.
Pull!
Was that the Eiffel Tower?
I think so.
Ladies and Gentlemen.
We're on our way to China.
Good. Very good.
Do not believe in
something simply
because you have
heard it, Nima.
But great Lama.
Tenzin is my brother.
He works inside
the big tunnel,
where the ships
are built.
But what is there
in your wisdom,
great Lama,
if Tenzin is right?
What if our world is
indeed coming to and end?
It is full, great Rinpoche.
Like this cup,
you are full of opinions and
speculations.
To see the light
of wisdom,
You first must
empty your cup.
Be careful with
the clutch...
It tends to slip.
Grandpa, Nima is here!
Grandma, I got a message
from Tenzin...
He want us to meet
him in Cho Ming
at the work camp.
He says he can get us onto
the ships he's working on.
What are you
talking about?
Tenzin works
on the dam.
Grandma...
...the dam is a ship.
The government lied to us.
There will be a big flood!
We must pack up
right away.
Nima? Who gave
you a truck?
We took a trip on the
Liam Song ferry once
Grandpa threw up
the whole way.
Let's eat first.
Hey, look, the new Bentley!
Our father had one on order.
He was supposed to
get it next year.
But then he canceled it.
Because of the ships.
How many cars does
your family have?
My mom's boyfriend
has a Porsche.
Our parents are
divorced too.
Found a hat.
She has a thing
for hats.
I was just like
that at her age.
They made me
feel safe.
So, how did you meet
Dr Silberman?
As you can see not the
same way you did.
My boyfriend asked me
to get them done
But he's not
your husband?
We are not married.
And probably
never will be.
For the boys.
They seem to like
each other.
Yeah, I guess.
Tell me, Mr Karpov,
how much did you pay?
One billion Euro.
Per seat.
That's disgusting
- Oh yeah?
You know, Curtis, I wasn't
always a businessman.
I am a boxer.
Was my only playing
when I was boy
back in Murmansk.
And my coach,
his name was also Yuri.
He always said:
"If someone wants
to beat you...
...he has to
kill you first"
That's very nice.
But tell me, what
would you have done
if you were rich
like me?
Look, they are
wonderful children.
OK guys. The plan is
to refill in Hawaii,
so sit down and
buckle up.
Gordon and I
will do the rest.
Oh God.
Go get the guys.
Guys, there's a...
You might wanna...
- What is that?
- The state of Hawaii
Not good. That is
not good.
How much fuel do
we have left?
Not enough.
We have to make a
water landing
Somewhere in
South China sea.
Great, at least we won't
need a landing gear.
- What about it?
- We lost it all, in Vegas.
Dr Wilson,
may I come in?
I'm not very good
company, I'm afraid.
- Doctor...
- Please, call me Adrian.
All those people
we left behind.
They don't stand
a chance, do they?
I believe that nature
will choose for itself,
from itself, what
will survive.
Just like you, preserving
those great artworks.
Our culture is our
soul, and that's not
dying tonight.
Come on, I contributed
to this cover up.
The Da Vinci, Picasso,
they're in.
But if you're some nobody
you don't stand a chance.
It's not necessarily true.
Did you ever hear of a writer
called Jackson Curtis?
Wrote a book,
"Farewell Atlantis".
What do you think the
chances are of an
unknown writer who
barely sold 500 copies
making it aboard
this plane?
- I don't understand
- I mean call it chance
or faith or nature,
doesn't matter
This book is part of our
legacy now. Why?
Because I'm reading it.
Dr Helmsley, please report
to the situation room.
Who is it?
- Hello, I'm sorry.
Who is this?
This is Yoko Delgado.
Do you want to
speak to my daddy?
Yes, please.
Who should I
say is calling?
- Tell him, its his father.
- You're my grandpa?
Yes, sweetheart, I am.
Daddy, grandpa
is on the phone.
Mr President, Sir.
- What's the matter, sweety?
- She can't find her daddy.
Why don't you two get
comfy on that couch?
I'll find your daddy.
Who can help me with
missing persons?
Sorry, man, I'm really
busy right now.
I mean of course, sir.
Sorry, Mr President.
- Don't worry about it, you're
doing a great job, son.
What's happening?
The Capitol has
been hit by a 9.4
Lost communication with
the White House, sir.
- Where is it centered?
- North Chesapeake Bay.
Mr Anheuser, Russian
president on the line, sir.
Excuse me.
We just entered
Chinese air space.
That's affirmative,
Mr President.
Until communication
is restored,
I suppose I am
in command.
It appears that all
other heads of state
are en route, with the
exception of the
Italian Prime Minister,
Who has also
decided to
stay behind and
trust in prayer.
Earths crust has begun
to shift, Dr Helmsley!
- By what degree?
- 1.2°. Still moving.
So, what happens next?
The movement of our land
masses comes to a halt.
Let's see a simulation.
Expect the formation
of gigantic tsunamis.
Proportional to the magnitude
of corresponding quakes.
Pull up the Japanese
sea border.
Yes, sir.
My dad's on a cruise
ship out there.
But I guess you already
knew that.
Sir, we've recorded
two underwater quakes
at 7.9 and 8.2.
From what we have just
learned, Tokyo seems to
have taken the full
force of the earthquake.
At this point unconfirmed
reports indicate that
large areas of land
are under water.
Please stay tuned
for further...
Tony
I called.
I was too late.
Maybe they got
out of town.
You never know.
I'm coming home,
Dorothy.
Anything?
Nothing but static.
Not even an
emergency signal.
Can't think about what's
going on down there
Remember that old Beetle
we used to camp in?
But you'd never
get the roof up.
We definitely
traded up.
Tried to find our old
spot at Yellowstone.
When I went camping
with the kids, but...
I couldn't find it.
Do you think
people change?
By people, do
you mean me?
Yes.
Do you think you've changed
since we separated?
I seem to eat a lot
more cereal now.
You always had
tunnel vision.
You could just block
everything out and write.
You blocked us out.
Do you love him?
I love him enough.
All global ground communication
is ceased, sir.
The only signals our
satellites are picking up
Well there's a piece
of good news.
Any updates, Doctor?
We expect the tsunamis to reach
land fall on every continent.
The Cho Ming area will
be impacted in
approximately 6 hours.
It looks like the crust
have shifted by almost
23 degrees to
the southwest.
The data also shows
the Earth's poles
have reversed their
magnetic fields.
These are their
new positions.
You're telling me that
the North Pole
is now somewhere
in Wisconsin?
Actually, thats the
South Pole now.
Engine failure.
2 of 6 are down.
You must get ready.
- How long do we have?
- 18 minutes. Maybe.
Better wake
up the kids.
Da.
Why do you
hate Gordon?
Hey. Come on.
What are you talking about?
I don't hate him.
You don't like him either
That's because I don't
know him well, maybe.
But I do.
He's really nice once
you get to know him.
You should talk
to him more often.
You guys would get
along really well.
You like him a lot, huh?
I'll do my best.
I promise. OK?
I'm really proud of you.
Really proud of you.
Is it time?
Yeah
Dad, what's wrong?
Sasha's gotta land.
It's gonna be a little bumpy.
Maybe a little wet.
Daddy?
Hold her steady.
Daddy, I'm not a
really good swimmer.
Hey, that's alright. It's
what you got this for.
It's like being in
a swimming pool.
Only it's got more cool stuff.
It's got a whistle, a light.
I thought we were
going to China.
No, we gotta
land here.
So that's what
we're gonna do.
We're just gonna
all stay together.
No we're not,
we're gonna die!
No, we're not.
Promise?
I promise you, we'll
all stay together,
no matter what happens.
Jackson, Yuri.
I think you better
come up here
I'm gonna go check
this out.
- Dad, dad!
- I'll be right back
We gotta buckle
up. Let's go.
Don't ask me how
that happened
There is no more
ocean, and we're
pretty close to where
we wanted to go.
It's like the whole world
shifted by 1000 miles.
1578 to be exact.
It's called "Earth Crust
Displacement Theory"
Professor Hapgood 1958.
Way to go, Charlie.
What was that?
We just lost our
last two engines.
I'll shoot for that glacier.
It's going to
get rocky.
Listen, it's gonna
sound crazy,
but here's what
you have to do.
Get up! Follow me!
Yuri, what are you doing?
We are taking the Bentley!
Not yet!
Not yet.
Almost there.
Get in the car.
Okay, go now!
Pull!
No no no no no
Go, Jackson.
We gotta wait
for Sasha and Gordon.
Go! Make sure
everybody gets
off the plane before
I touch down.
What about you?
I'll be fine. I have to
touch this plane down.
What are you
waiting for? Go!
There he is.
I see him!
Come on lets go.
- Where is Sasha?
- He said he's fine
We should get out of here
before he touches down.
Don't go!
Go Jackson, go.
It wont start.
Shut up everybody!
Engine
Start
Voice control.
Sold me on it.
Welcome, to the People's
Republic of China.
- Good to be here.
- Say hi, kids.
Hi
- What color are your passes?
- What?
What color are your
boarding passes?
I have green cards.
- For my boys and me.
- What?
Yuri? Yuri!
Yuri. It's a mistake.
A joke, eh?
What? You think I didn't know
about you and Sasha?
May God bless that poor
bastard's soul.
I'm sorry guys.
Good luck.
Come on, boys.
Maybe with money
we could bribe them.
You got a billion Euros?
Dr Wilson. I'm Captain Michaels,
Skipper of the American ship.
Please accept my sincere
condolences for your father.
Thank you, Captain.
Anheuser. Your party
is the last to arrive.
There's been reports of
severe damage, Captain.
What's the status of
Ark number 3?
We haven't done a
complete assessment yet.
Looks like we lost it.
No toothbrush.
Only books.
When I was a kid my dad
was on the road a lot.
He'd always leave me
a box full of books.
I'd get an ice cream cone
for every book I read so...
I was a fat kid.
I find that very hard
to believe.
No, its true, my high school
carrier was 2000 books
Zero girlfriends.
I didn't even kiss a boy
until I was in college.
They were all too
scared of my dad.
Leave it to the Chinese.
I didn't think
it was possible.
Not in the
time we had.
That's Ark number 3, sir.
The roof collapsed
during the shifting
of the Earth's crust.
Jesus Christ.
Hey, what's going on here?
I have a green card for
my boys and me.
I want to speak to
your supervisor.
I am the supervisor.
Get back with the
other green cards,
or I'll have
you detained.
What he said about you
and Sasha, is it true?
Sasha was worth a hundred
times a man like Yuri.
I should have listened
to you, Dr. Silberman.
I actually liked the way
I looked before that
monster talked
me into it.
Did you know he asked
me for a discount?
He payed in installments.
Cheap bastard.
You hear that?
Over there!
Stop!
How were all these
people chosen?
Same way your Arc was.
By experts from all
over the world.
We had geneticists
determine the perfect
gene pool we need
to repopulate.
These people were chosen
by geneticists?
All green card holders
Please proceed to
hangar D-4
Looks to me like their check
books got them on board.
That's right, Dr Wilson.
Without billions of dollars
from the private sector
this entire operation
would've been
impossible.
We sold tickets?
What about all
these workers?
They all get passes?
What? Life isn't fair?
Is that it?
If you want to
donate your passes,
to a couple of Chinese
workers, be my guest.
Captain, I want a
pre-launch briefing.
All international
teams present.
What the hell?
What is this? They could've
fit 10 people in here.
Satnam, where are you?
- On the Nampan Plateau.
- What?
There's a tidal wave
coming from the east.
It's gigantic.
Satnam, what
happened?
We never got
picked up, Adrian.
The airlift
never came.
Goodbye, my friend.
Satnam
- Where are we set up?
- Over there.
Give me the satellite
images from Napam, India.
What's happening?
Satnam was talking
about another wave,
coming from the east.
- Holy mother of God.
So the flooding
will hit earlier?
The second wave
is closer?
Plug in the new data.
Satnam didn't
get picked up.
What?
A lot of people didn't get
picked up in this chaos.
This is not a conspiracy,
Helmsley.
Your predictions haven't
exactly panned out,
have they, Doctor?
It's ready.
Oh God, its 1500
meters high.
When will it
get here?
Talk to me, Hemsley,
when will it hit?
Adjust the countdown.
28 minutes, 10 seconds
to impact.
My God.
Captain.
I need to speak to the
other heads of state.
- Right away. Taylor?
- Aye, Captain
Standing by. Ark 6, stand by.
Ark 7, stand by.
This is Carl Anheuser
acting CIC on 4,
Yes sir
Requesting emergency
conference T-99.
He thinks the world of
you, you know that?
He's a great little man.
Yeah
I always wanted to have
a family of my own.
You're a lucky
man, Jackson.
Don't ever forget it.
CHO MING UTILITY GATE
Who are they?
We found them alongside
of the road.
Send them back!
I am a follower
of our great
Lama Rinpoche.
You know I cannot do that.
You don't have to
take all of us.
Please just take
my children.
I'm begging you.
Why should
I do that?
Same reason you
sent for your family.
Please just the children,
you don't have to take us.
Please!
Please. Oh my God.
Please. I don't know if you can
understand what I'm saying.
As a mother,
I'm begging you.
Please take them.
Please.
We are all children
of the Earth.
My plan will not work
for so many, Grandma.
We will take them all.
Attention.
All construction workers.
They're opening
the mountain.
They are leaving
without us.
Get back. What did
I tell you!
They are leaving
you behind too.
Please be patient
Follow me.
We have to hurry!
They are leaving!
Initiating security
procedures.
Excuse me. Where can I
find Adrian Helmsley?
He's on the bridge.
This way.
Tenzin wait!
Grandma, we're
almost there.
Green lights on
pressure, Mr Anton?
Green lights across
the board, Captain.
Why do they
have anchors?
Because they're not
space ships. They're Arcs.
Let's go.
Mr President.
You've got to see this.
Stop.
Engage the support
mechanisms.
Aye-aye, Captain.
Engaging supports.
Just exactly how long
are these things
expected to hold us
in place, Captain?
They're just meant
to withstand the
first impact of the
waves, Mr Anheuser.
Down there Oleg,
you go first.
Caesar!
Good boy.
Come to Mommy.
Caesar!
Mommy, where's Tamara?
Daddy look!
Tamara!
Oh my god, what's
happening out there?
Anheuser convinced the other
heads of state to launch.
Mr. Anheuser
We have to stop
this madness.
Make sure the other
bridges can see me.
What do you think
you're doing?
I know exactly
what I'm doing.
Ladies and Gentleman,
this is Dr. Adrian Helmsley
Chief science adviser to
the late President Wilson.
Could you please turn up
the volume, Mr Hoffman.
I know we've all
been forced to make
difficult decisions to save
our human civilization.
But to be human means
to care for each other
and civilization means
to work together
to create a better life.
If that's true, then
there's nothing human
and nothing civilized about
what we're doing here.
Dr. Helmsley's passion
is admirable,
But I remind you that
we have very limited
resources and extremely
limited time.
Ask yourselves, can
we really stand by
and watch these
people die?
I read a quote
two days ago.
The author is probably
dead by now. But he said:
"The moment we stop
fighting for each other"
"Thats the moment that
we lose our humanity"
And in order to save
the human race,
we have and obligation
to stick to this plan
which every nation on this
flotilla signed up for.
They're in God's
hands now.
Officer, you turn that off.
That is an order,
sailor. Turn it off!
Don't you dare touch
that button, young man!
Have you completely
lost your mind?
Look at the clock!
We have barely
15 minutes left!
Do you want to be
responsible for the
extinction of the
human race?
Can you handle
that, Adrian?
There's a young astrophysicist
from India who's the
reason we are all here.
Oh, for God's sake.
He's the one who
discovered it all.
He connected all the dots,
we all owe him our lives.
I just learned that
he was killed with
his family in a Tsunami
in eastern India.
He was my friend.
And he died in vain.
Everybody out there
has died in vain.
If we start our future
with an act of cruelty,
what will you tell
your children?
If my father were here,
he would open the gates
The people of Russia
along with...
China
and Japan
Agree
To open the gates!
The United Kingdom, Spain,
France and Germany,
and I believe I may
also speak for the
Italian Prime Minister:
We vote to let these
people come in.
Captain Michaels.
Please
This is your Captain.
In a few moments,
we will open the gates.
Phew, it stinks.
They are opening
the gate. Come down!
Noah. Move it!
Noah! Noah!
Mom, something happened.
Come on, God damn it!
Give me your hand!
- Reach for it!
- Help me!
Gordon!
Stop!
Climb!
What's wrong
with the gate?
Looks like it didn't
run the full cycle.
We're checking it out.
Order, please!
4 minutes to impact
We're all loaded, Captain.
Then let's lock it up. Now!
Oleg! Grab
my hand!
No, no, no
HYDRAULIC MALFUNCTION
Something's jamming the
hydraulics, Captain.
Well then get it out
for Christ sake.
I can't fire up the
engines until we
get a good seal
on that gate.
Captain, we have a breach
in the zoological bay.
Can you zoom in?
- Yeah.
I know those kids.
What is happening?
What's going on?
Where did they
come from?
There. Through the
hydraulic chamber.
Captain, I think we
found the problem!
- Who are these people?
- No, wait!
He's injured.
Something must've
gone wrong.
Are you kidding me? Of course
something went wrong!
Congratulations to
the both of you.
Might have gotten us
all killed, but as long
as your conscience is
clean, right Helmsley?
Captain, get an emergency
team down there,
I'll meet them at the
hydraulics chamber.
You know your way
around here? Lets go!
1 minute to impact.
Captain?
Cho Ming airfield
has been hit.
Put me on emergency
comm, Mr Taylor.
This is the Captain speaking
We expect to be impacted
by water shortly.
We need to
go this way.
All stations prepare
for impact.
Pressure just climbed
80 Pascal.
Surface compression of
valve sensors, Captain.
Track Dr Helmsley.
Out of the way!
Excuse me.
Tenzin. Almost there.
Nima. What happened?
Tamara!
Will you take
the kids please?
Which way?
We can't get there!
Water is entering the stern.
The rear of this ship is
flooded and will seal up
one compartment
at a time.
Where's Gordon?
No?
We gotta go back!
We have to go back!
Mommy!
Help!
Run!
Go over, Lilly!
Caesar!
Lilly, take him!
Mommy!
Is there another way to
the hydraulics chamber?
Where does this ladder go?
- To the zoological pens
- Okay, let's go!
Professor?
It's Air Force One.
The mid-ship anchor
support is hit.
Can you stabilize it?
The bow anchor
is giving in.
Captain, the turbines
aren't responding.
So override it.
Hit the override.
We cant start the engine
until we close that gate.
Help me!
Help!
Momma!
- Are you OK?
- My mommy is in there.
Please help her!
We'll get to your
mommy, sweetheart.
They're doing everything
they can, okay?
Can we talk to her?
I'm gonna try
to connect us.
We have to stop
the bleeding!
How about my belt?
- Here Mom!
- Mr. Curtis? Jackson?
Help! Hey!
It's Adrian Helmsley,
we met at Yellowstone.
Thats great. Open
the God damn door!
Your daughter
is with me!
- Lilly?
- Where's Noah?
I'm right here, Lil!
Impact warning
30° West.
45° East.
Target elevation
29.035 feet.
29.000 feet? What the
hell is at 29.000 feet?
We're headed straight
for the north face
of Mount Everest,
Mr. Anheuser.
And if we can't
start our engines,
we will not survive
the impact.
Jackson, you're sealed off!
We can't get to you!
There's something
blocking the hydraulics
If you can't get it out,
none of us are gonna make it
Dr Helmsley,
look at this.
It's completely submerged
down there and there's
no way for them
to get any air.
Theres no other way!
But it's a suicide
mission, sir!
I know where it is,
I'll give it a try.
Dad, wait, I wanna
go with you!
- Dad, I wanna help you!
- No, no, no.
- You are helping me.
- Dad, please!
Remember when Lilly
was born and you wanted
to be introduced
as her big brother?
Well, she's scared now.
She needs you
more than ever.
If you're safe, I know that
she's safe. Do you understand?
You can help me out
the next time.
We caused this thing,
it was us.
I gotta go
check it out.
Can you hear me?
No
Press down!
Press down with
your hand!
Don't stop.
Keep pressing!
No!
Distance to impact:
1.850 meters
There he is!
- Captain!
- We have a visual!
I think we found
the problem.
Show us the
hydraulics chamber
God dammit! I told you
to stay up there!
I just wanted to help.
Alright. Hold the light.
We're right under
the air pocket, okay?
How did you know
I needed help?
Grandpa, Grandma...
I'm sorry.
I could not save us
He has gone back in.
He will fix it.
There's no way.
Don't lose faith, brother.
Dad!
We're gonna die!
Great job! You light the way
and I'll go for the cable.
Distance to impact:
400 meters
Underwater ridge ahead!
We're going to run
aground, Captain!
Sir, the gate is sealed!
That's affirmative, Captain!
- Anton, start the engines.
- Aye-aye Captain. Full reverse.
Captain! We're not
gonna make it!
Distance to impact:
15 meters.
Reverse motion
activated
Distance to impact:
10 meters.
20 meters.
Hard to port!
We did it! We did it!
- Where's Dad?
- He was right behind me
Any word from the
hydraulic chamber?
Where is he?
I thought you said he
was right behind you.
He was!
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
He was right there!
Dad. Dad!
Come on, Jackson.
Come on.
Please, please.
He did it!
DAY 27 MONTH 01 YEAR 0001
Shuttle Atlantis.
Our last day.
All we can hear is the sound
of our own breathing.
That reminds us we are still
sharing our memories,
hopes and ideas.
And isn't it funny?
Just this morning we worked it out
Somehow or another,
we all have relatives
in Wisconsin.
The end.
It's good.
I thought you
would like it.
Tell me Dr Wilson:
Apart from books and art.
Do you think there's
anything else
we might possibly share?
In the future?
Are you asking me out
on a date, Dr. Helmsley?
You know my diary
is pretty full.
Actually...
Yes, I was.
Dr. Helmsley to
the bridge, please.
Dr. Helmsley
to the bridge.
Come here.
Ladies and gentleman,
this is captain Michaels speaking.
In a few minutes I will give
orders to unseal the decks.
At 23:45 last night,
our sister Arks
number 6 and 7
have joined our course.
For the first time
on our journey,
we will have clear skies.
As you know our
passenger count
is way over capacity.
So please, be careful
when you step out
and of course...
enjoy the fresh air.
Can I hold him?
Sure, he can be your
dog too if you like.
Thanks.
Where have you
been all my life?
Gift shop.
Oh, Adrian. Excellent.
I called because we just got
our first satellite feet.
The equalization of the
oceanic... seabeds
has not turned out to be
as extreme as we expected.
The waters are receding.
Much faster
than we thought.
Thank God. And...
This is hard to believe,
but the Himalayas
are no longer the
roof of the world.
It's now the
Drakensberg mountains
of KwaZulu, Nepal.
The entire African
continent has just risen
7.000 feet, and unlikely
they are even flooded.
That's why they call it
The Cape of Good Hope.
We've already set
course for it.
Daddy, when will
we go back home?
Well, we talked
about that.
We're gonna
find a new home
out here somewhere.
Right?
Wherever we're all
together. That's home.
Right? You are scared?
I am not.
No more pull-ups.
Nice.