Here Lies Dobby
It's beautiful here.
It was our house.
We used to come here when we were kids.
We only use it as safe-house.
What's left from us, at least.
My uncles thought these
things keeps evil away.
But they were wrong.
I need to talk to goblin.
How are you?
- You buried the elf?
- Yes.
It brought me here.
You are...
Pretty unusal, is it?
How did you come by the sword?
It's complicated.
What about Bellatrix Lestrange thing
that should be in his vault at Gringotts?
It's complicated.
The sword presented itself to us,
in when to need.
We didn't steal it.
There is a sword in madam Lestrange's vault.
I think it's identical to this one.
But it is a fake.
It was placed there this past summer.
Actually, never suspected it was a fake.
That because replicate is very convincing.
Only a goblin who can recognize that this is the true Sword of Gryffindor.
Who is thier acquaintance?
Hogwart Professor.
As I understand that he's now headmaster.
Snape.
If there was a fake sword in madam Lestrange's vault..
Why?
There are more than of a few
curious in vaults of Gringotts.
And in madam Lestrange's vault as well?
Perhaps.
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vaults.
- It's impossible.
- Alone, yes.
But with you, no.
- Why should I help you?
- I have gold.
Lots of it.
I've no interest in gold.
And what?
That.
That is my price.
Are you thinking that sword we spoke
about in madam Lestrange's vault?
Well, she was terrified when she went in there.
She keeped asking me,
what else was taken?
I  bet you antything, thats Horcrux in there.
Another piece of his soul.
Let's find it, and kill it, and we will
once that closer to killing him.
And once we find him,
how we supposed to destroy it, if you gave the sword to Gringotts?
I'm still working on that part.
He's weak.
Harry!
Mr. Ollivander..
I need to ask you a few questions.
Anything, my boy.
Anything!
Would you mind identifying this wand?
We need to know if it's safe to use.
Uhh... walnut
Dargon Heart String.
12.75 inches.
Unyie...
Unyielding.
This belong to Bellatrix Lestrange.
Treat it carefuly.
And this?
Hawthorn.
An unicorn hair.
10 inches.
Reasonably pliant.
This was the one of Draco Malfoy.
Was?
Is it not still?
Well, perhaps not.
If you want it from him.
I sense its allegiance has changed.
You talk about wands,
as if they have feelings...
can think!
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
That matter has always been clear to
those of us who've studied the wand-lore.
And, what do you know about the deathly hallows?
It's rumored there are three.
The elder wand, the cloak of invisibility,
that hide you from your enemies..
and the resurection stone, to bring
back your love ones from the dead.
Together, they make one the Master of Death.
But, few truly believe that such objects exist.
Do you?
Do you believe they exist, sir?
Well..
I see no reasons to put
stock into an old wives' tale.
You're lying!
You know once exists.
You told him about it.
You told him about the elder wand...
and way to go looking for it.
He tortured me.
Besides...
only convey rumors.
This...
This not telling how will he find it.
He has found it, sir.
We'll let you rest.
He's after you, Mr. Potter.
If it's true what you say,
and he has the elder wand,
I'm afraid,
you really don't stand a chance.
I supposed to kill him, before he finds me, then.
You sure that's hers?
Positive.
Well?
How do I look?
Hideous.
You can give that to Hermione to hold.
Alright, Gryphook?
We're relying on you, Gryphook.
If you get us pass the guards into the vault...
The sword is yours.
Madam Lestrange.
Good morning.
Good morning?
Good morning?!
You'd better drip more of Lestrange,
not a school girl!
Hey!
Easy!
If she gives us away, we must swear
to use that sword to slit her own throat.
Understand?
No, he's right.
I spoke stupid.
Okay.
Let's do it.
I wish to enter my vault.
Identification?
I hardly think that would be necessary.
Madam Lestrange.
I don't like to be kept wating.
[Ron mentaly thinks]:
I know..
I know she's being impostor.
I'll get my wand.
Harry..
What do we do, Harry?
Madam Lestrange,
would you mind presenting your wand?
And why should I do that?
It's the bank's policy!
I'm sure you understand, given current conditions.
No! I most does really not understand!
I'm afraid, I must insist.
Hereuia!
Very well, madam Lestrange.
If you would follow me?
What is that, Gryphook?
Gryphook?!
Well done, Hermione.
Oh, my!
You two like you, again.
Thetys downfall washes
away all enchantment.
Can be deadly.
Get outside.
Just out of interest,
is there any other way out of here?
No.
What the devil are all you doing down here?
Thiefs!
You gave up of your...
That doesn't sound good.
Bloody hell!
That seems cranky ogre.
Here.
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears this noise.
That's barbaric!
Blemous.
It's bloody.
Accio horcrux!
You seems you're gonna try
this here, won't you?
That kind of magic won't work here.
It's in here, Harry.
Can you feel it?
That's it!
Up there!
They had an enchantment here.
Everything you touch will multiply.
Give me the sword.
Stop moving!
Do it!
- We had deal, Gryphook!
- The cup for the sowrd!
I said I'm gonna get into it,
but I didn't say anything about getting you out.
Gryphook! Please!
Gryphook!
Hey, beast!
If I would get it,
this is Cyrco Bogglor.
That's unfortunate.
We can't just stand here,
not to move right here.
Should be a brilliant one.
I've got something,
but it's mad!
Reducto!
Well, come on, then!
Relashio!
Keep moving!
Now what?
Reganta!
Hold on.
That was brilliant!
Absolutely brilliant!
We're dropping!
- I say we jump!
- When?
Now!
He knows.
'You know who'.
He knows we've broke into Gringotts.
He knows what we took,
and he knows we're hunting Horcruxs.
- How is he know?
- I showed him.
You let him in?
Harry, you can't do that!
Hermione, I can't always help it!
Well, maybe I can.
I don't know!
Never mind!
What happened?
Well, he's angry...
and scared too.
He knows, if we find and destroyed
all the Horcruxes, we'll be able to kill him.
He'll try all the ways and will let nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.
And there's more.
More of it at Hogwarts.
What?
You saw it?
I saw the castle.
And under of the Raiven Klue.
It must have something to do with her.
We have to go there, now!
Well, we can't do that!
We've got to plan,
we've got to figure it out!
Hermione, when have any of
our plans ever actually worked?
We plan, we get there,
all hell breaks loose.
He's right!
One problem..
Snape is headmaster now,
we can't just go from the front door!
Well, we'll go to Hogsmeade,
to Hadteod.
Take the secret passage into cellar.
It's..
There's something wrong with him.
It's like, you know,
in the past..
I've always been able
to follow his thoughts.
And now everything just feels disconnected.
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.
Maybe he's getting weaker.
Maybe he's dying!
No!
No, it's more like he's wounded.
If had a thing he feels more dangerous.
- Right here. Come on!
- Search everywhere.
Go, move!
Faster!
In here, Potter.
Come on, move!
She can't look at him.
- For second we were close.
- I know. Dumbledore!
Harry?
Why I do see you in this?
Bloody fools, what did you think in coming here?
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?
You're Aberforth, Dumbledore's brother.
It's you who I've been seeing in here.
You're the one who sent Dobby.
- Why've you left him?
- He's dead.
Sorry to hear it.
I liked that elf.
Who gave that to you?
The mirror?
The Dungs' Fletcher, about a year ago.
Dung had no right sending that to you.
It belongs..
Sirius...
Albus told me.
he also told me you'd likely be act off,
if you ever found that I had it.
But, ask yourself;
Where would you be if I didn't?
To you have any others much?
From the Order?
The Order has finished.
'You know who' has won,
anyone who says, otherwise he's killing themselves.
We need to get into Hogwarts, tonight.
Dumbledore gave us a job today.
Did he knew..
it's a nice job,
and easy.
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
We think the last one is inside the castle.
But only with your help we can get in.
What a job my brother has given you, it's a suicide mission.
Do yourself a favior, boy.
Go home!
You'll live a little bit longer.
Dumbledore trusted me to see this through.
What makes you think you can trust him?
What makes you think you can
believe anything my brother told you?
And in other time he's with you..
did he ever mentioned my name?
Did he ever mentioned hers?
- Why should he...
- Keep secrets.
You tell me?
- I trusted him.
- That your boys answer.
A boy goes chasing Horcruxes is on the wood alone.
A man who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
You're lying!
Not just on me, it doesn't matter.
To yourself as well.
That's what a fool does.
You don't strike me as a fool, Harry Potter!
So, I ask you again, there must be a reason.
I'm not interested in what happened
between you and your brother.
I don't care that you've given up.
I trusted the man I knew.
We need to get into the castle tonight.
You know what to do.
Where have you sent her?
You'll see.
Soon enough.
That's your sister, Ariana.
Isn't it?
She died for a young, didn't she?
My brother sacrificed many things, Mr. Potter.
On his journey to find power.
Including Ariana.
And she was devoted to him.
He gave her everything.
But time.
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.
He did save our lifes twice!
Gave us his eyes on the mirror.
That doesn't seem like someone who is giving up!
She's coming back.
What's that with her?
Neville!
- How did you come?
- Hi!
This is nothing.
Seamus is worse.
Hey, Ab!
With more peoples are coming through.
Don't remember that it was on the map.
That's because it was never existed until now.
The 7 secret passages were sealed off,
before the start of year.
This is the only way enter and out, now.
Grounded of death eaters and Dementors.
How about what said about Snape the headmaster?
I've never seen him.
It's the Carrows who is watching 'em out for.
The Carrows?
Yeah. Brother and sister.
They're trying apply the discipline.
They like punishment, the Carrows.
They did that to you?
Why?
Today's Dark Arts was telling to
practice on Cruciatus curse.
On first years.
I refused.
Hogwarts changed.
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?
Hey, I've brought up..
for you a surprise.
No more of Aberforth's cook's gonna help.
We'll be surprised if you got us a desalination.
- Oh my!
- Harry!
Give up a news to Remus and
Spread that Harry is back.
Okay, okay!
Let's not kill him with this group huging.
...do you read? we've a new weather report.
Lightning has chucked. I repeat: Lightning has chucked.
What the fun, Harry?
Okay..
There's something we need to find.
There's something hiding here, in the castle.
And it might help us to defeat
'You know who'.
- Alright, what is it?
- We don't know.
- Where is it?
- We don't know that either.
Our realizes are not much to go on.
That's not to go on.
I think it has something to do with Ravenclaw.
It'll be small, easily can sealed.
Anyone have any ideas?
Well, there is Rowena Ravenclow's lost diadem.
Oh, bloody hell!
Here we go!
lost diadem of Ravenclow?
Hasn't anyone heard of this?
It's quite famous.
Yes. But, Luna, it's lost.
For centuries.
There not person alive today who've seen it.
Excuse me, can someone tell me what bloody diadem is?
It's a sort of crown.
You know, like a tiara.
Harry!
Hi, there.
6.1 inches and can't see me?
It's like I'm Frankie Verci.
I'm her brother!
- She only want you, Harry.
- Shit up, Seamus!
What is it, Ginny?
Snape knows... he knows
that Harry is in Hogsmeade.
Many of you are surely wondering,
why I have summoned you at this hour.
It's came to my attention,
that earlier this evening..
Harry Potter was sighted in Hogsmeade.
Now..
should anyone..
student or staff attempt to aid Mr. Potter?
They will be punished in a manner consistent with
the severity of their transcription, further more.
Any person found have
knowledge of these events...
who fails to come forward...
will be treated as equally guilty.
No one?!
If anyone in here has any knowledge of
Mr. Potter's movements this evening.
I invite 'em to step forward.
Now!
It seems to spike your excusive defensive strategies..
you're secuirty problem solving
from us, headmaster...
I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
How dare you stand where he stood?!
Tell 'em how it happened that night?
Tell them how you looked in the eye..
a man who trusted you, and killed him.
Tell them!
Harry.
Potter?
I know that many of you are want to fight.
Some of you might even think to defy this wise.
But this is foolish.
Give me Harry Potter.
Do this and this will be ended.
Give me Harry Potter,
and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
and you will be rewarded.
You have 1 hour.
What're you waiting for?
Someone grab him!
Students out of bed!
Students in the corridor!
They're supposed to be out
of bed, you blithering idiot!
Sorry ma'am.
As it happened, Mr. Filch..
Your arrival has loosed appertunate.
If you would, I'd like you please, to lead Ms. Parkinson
and the rest of Slytherin house, from the hall.
Exactly where is it I'll be leading them to, ma'am?
The dungeons would do.
Alright, come on! Come on!
I assume you have a reason for returning, Potter.
What is it you need?
Time, Professor.
As much as you can get me.
Do what you have to do.
I'll secure the castle.
Potter..
it's good to see you.
It's good to see you too, Professor.
Harry!
Hermione and I were thinking,
it doesn't matter if we find all Horcruxes.
What do you mean?
Unleast we can destroy it.
So, we were thinking...
Well, Ron was thinking, it was his idea.
It was completely brilliant
You destroyed Tom Riddle's
diary with the basilisk fangs, right?
Well, me and Hermione might
know where to find one.
Okay.
Okay, but take this.
That way, you can find me when you get back.
Where're you going?
Ravenclaw common room,
Gotta start somewhere.
Harry!
Harry?
Let me get it straight, Professor...
you actually give us
a permission to do this?
That is correct, Longbottom.
That's blowin' up!
Boom!
Wicked!
How are we gonna do that?
Why don't you confirm with Mr. Finnigan?
As I record, he has a particular
proclivity for pirate technics.
I can bring it down.
That's the spirit!
Well, you go.
You do relize, of course, we can't
keep out 'You know who' definitely.
That doesn't mean
we can't delay him.
And his name is Voldemort.
Filius you might will use it.
He's come to try to kill you, either we!
Piertotum Locomotor.
Hogwarts is menaced.
Men of borders protect us.
Do your duty...
to our school.
I always wanted to use that spell!
Ontejo Maxamm Biyanto Dory.
Harry, wait!
I need to talk to you!
- I'm a bit for you, Luna.
- You don't know where are going.
You're waisting your time!
Look, we'll talk later, okay?
- Harry?
- Later.
Harry Potter, you listen to me right now!
Do you remember what Cho said
about Rowena Ravenclow lost diadem?
There is no person alive who've seen it.
It's obvious, isn't it?
We have to talk to someone who is dead.
It's very impressive, isn't it?
If you want to find her,
you'll find her down there.
- Aren't you coming?
- No.
I think it's best, if you two talk alone.
She's very shy.
You're the Grey Lady.
The ghost of Ravenclaw tower.
I do not answer to that name!
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
It's Helena, isn't it?
Helena Ravenclaw,
Rowena's daughter.
Are you a friend of Luna's?
Yes.
And she told me you will be able to help me.
You seek my mother's diadem?
Yes.
That's right.
Luna is kind.
Unlike so many of the others.
But she was wrong,
I can not help you!
Wait, please!
I want to destroy it!
They never learn.
Such a petty.
My Lord..
shouldn't we wait?
Begin!
I thought you want to do this to it.
Right, Helena?
You want to destroy it?
My mother has wanted
to destroy it many years ago.
The Strange Boy, what a strange name?!
Tom Riddle.
But he lied.
He's lied to many people.
I know what he had done!
I know who he is!
He defiled it, with dark magic!
I can destroy it.
Once and for all.
But only if you tell
where he hide it?
You do know where he hide it?
Don't you, Helena?
You just have to tell me.
Please!
Strange!
You remind me of him a bit.
It's here, in the castle.
In the place where everything is hidden.
If you have to ask..
you will never know.
If you know..
you need only ask.
Thank you!
Tell Professor McGonagall.
Remus and I will handle the castle.
Yes, sir!
Eddie, with second thoughts, tell Professor McGonagall
would might need one or two more ones to side.
It's the quality of who has conviction
as to terminate the success...
not the number of followers.
Who said that?
Me.
You okay, Freddy?
Yeah.
Me too.
Harry's talk as snakes.
You know it?
No, of course, no!
Yeah?
You and whose army?
You do it.
I can't.
Yes, you can!
Neville!
That went well.
Get inside!
Ginny, Neville!
You alright?
Never better!
I feel like I've been spitting fire!
Did you see Luna up there?
Luna?
I know.
Bloody hell!
We'll never find him on this.
Here he is!
- He's just..
- Brilliant!
He just vanished.
I sure that I saw it.
Maybe he's gone to the room of vault.
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
You said that last year.
That's right, I did.
Let's go.
Brilliant!
Come on!
Well, then..
what brought you to here, Potter?
I could ask you the same.
You have something that's mine.
I'd like you back.
What's wrong with the one you have?
It's my mother's.
It's powerful, but it's...
not the same.
Doesn't quite understand me.
You know what I mean?
Why don't you tell her?
Bellatrix?
You knew he's me.
You didn't say nothing.
Come on, Draco!
Do not be a coward.
Do it!
Easy!
Expleiona!
Avona Getarta!
This is my girlfriend,
you bloody nuts!
Do it!
Go, they've set the bloody place on fire!
Come on!
This way!
We can't leave them!
He's joking, right?
If we died for them,
Harry, I'm gonna kill you!
Harry!
My Lord?
Avara Kadabra!
Come Nagini, I need keep you safe.
It's the snake.
She's the last one.
It's the last Horcrux.
Look inside him, Harry.
Find out where he is,
if you find him, we could find the snake.
And we can end this!
My Lord..
Might be there is less...
I should not be more pretend to call off this attack.
Simply seek the boy.
Yourself.
I do not need to seek the boy..
before the night is out, he will come to me!
Do you understand?
Look at me!
How can you live with yourself, Lucius?
I don't know.
Go and find Severus.
Bring him to me.
I know where he is.
Come on!
No!
You have performed extra-ordinary
magic with this wand, My Lord,
in the last few hours?
No!
No! Now, I am extra-ordinary.
But the wand resist me .
There is no wand more powerful
Ollivander himself has made it.
Tonight, when the boy comes.
It will not fail you, I am sure ..
It answers to you,
and you only.
Does it?
My Lord?
The wand, does it truly
answered to me?
You're a clever man, Severus.
Surely you must know...
- Where does true loyalty lie?
- With you..
of course, My Lord.
The Elder wand cannot serve me properly,
because I am not its true master.
The Elder wand belongs to the
wizard who killed it's last owner.
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.
While you live the Elder
wand cannot truly be mine.
You've been a good and faithful servant, Severus.
But only I can live forever.
My Lord...
Nagini, kill!
Wait!
Take it...
Take it, please!
Give me something!
Quickly, a flask. Anything!
Take them to the Pensieve.
Look at me...
You really have your mother's eyes.
You've fought valiantly,
but in vain...
I do not wish this. Every drop of magical blood
spilled is a terrible waste.
I therefore command my forces to retreat...
In their absence,
dispose of your dead with dignity,
Harry Potter, I now speak directly to you.
On this night, you have allowed your friends to die
for you, rather than face me yourself.
There is no greater dishonor.
Join me in the Forbidden Forrest...
...and confront your fate.
If you do not do this, I shall kill every last man,
woman and child who tries to conceal you from me.
Where's everybody?
Harry?
Oh, come on!
Don't be sad on it, she's passed.
There, she's gone.
Freak! Come here! I'm gonna tell mommy!
You're freak!
You're freak, Lily!
Come here!
She's jealous.
She's ordinary and you're special.
That's not true, Severus.
Gryffindor!
- Hi, I'm James.
- Hi, I'm Lily.
Just like your father.
Don't say a word against my father!
Masters shall be reunited once more!
Severus.
Don't kill me!
The prophecy did not has said it's woman.
It spoke about a boy born in the end of the July.
Yes, but it's her son!
intends to hunt them down and kill them.
Hide him.. hide them all.
I beg you!
What well you give me in exchange, Severus?
- Anything.
- Harry...
Harry, you were so loved.
So loved!
Harry, mama loves you.
Dada loves you.
Harry, be safe.
Be strong.
Avara Kadabra!
You promised to keep them safe.
Lily and James...
for their faithing in the wrong person, Severus.
One like you.
The boy survived.
He doesn't need protection,
the Dark Lord has gone.
The Dark Lord will return.
When he does, the
boy will in terrible danger!
He has her eyes.
If you truly loved her...
No one, can know.
I shall never view
your best dids, Severus.
Your word?
Can you rescue your life
everyday to protect the boy?
Don't tell a word, that's my father!
James Potter, lazy, arrogant.
- My father was a great man!
- Your father was swain!
Drink it, it will content the curse to
your hand, for the current day.
- It will spread.
- How... how long?
Maybe a year.
Don't ignore me, Severus.
We both know Lord Voldemort has
orderd the Malfoy boy to murder me.
But if he fails, I should presume
the Dark Lord will turn to you.
You must be the one to kill me, Severus.
It is the only way.
Only then, will the Dark Lord trust you completely.
Will come a time, when Harry Potter,
must be told something.
But you must wait, until Voldemort is at his most vulnerable.
Must be told what?
On the night, Lord Voldemort went
to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...
Then, Lily Potter obstacle between them...
the curse we bounded.
And when that happens, a part of Voldemort's sould..
contained itself in the only living thing he could find...
Harry himself.
There's a reason Harry can speak with snakes...
There's a reason he can look into Lord Voldemort's mind...
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.
So, when the time comes..
the boy must die?
Yes.. yes.
He must die.
You've kept on his life, so he can
die at the required moment?
You've been raising him like a pig for slaught.
Don't tell me now, that you've
grown up care for me.
Lily!
After all this time!
Always.
So, when the time comes..
the boy must die?
Yes.
He must die.
And Voldemort himself must do it.
That is a sensual.
- Where've you been?
- I thought you went to that forest.
I'm going there now.
Are you mad?
No...
You can't give yourself up to him.
What is it, Harry?
What is it you know?
There is a reason I can hear them.
The Horcruxes.
I think I've known it for a while.
And I think you've known that too.
- I'll go with you.
- No, you kill the snake.
Kill the snake, and it's just him!
I'm ready to die.
Resurrection Stone.
You've been so brave, sweetheart.
Why you're here?
All of you?
We never left.
Does...
Does it hurt?
Dying?
Quicker than falling in sleep.
You needed this, son.
I'm sorry.
I never wanted any of you to die for me.
And, Remus, your son?
Others will tell him, what his
mother and father died for.
One day, he'll understand.
You'll stay with me?
Until the end.
Anybody will be able to see you?
No.
We're here, you see.
Stay close to me.
Always.
No sing of him, My Lord.
I thought he'd come.
Harry, no!
- What are you doing here?
- Quite!
Harry Potter...
the boy who lived...
come to die.
Avara Kadabra!
You can't help...
Harry, you wonderful boy..
you brave-brave man!
Let us walk.
Professor, what is that?
Something beyond our limit of help.
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.
And exactly where are we?
I was gonna ask you that.
Where would you say where we are?
Well, it looks like King's Cross station.
Only cleaner..
and without older trains.
King's Cross, is that right?
This is as they say, 'Your Party'.
I speak to you know as I relized it, you and Voldemort..
has been connected by something out of the fate.
As said by Godric's Hollow orders many years ago.
So it's true then, sir.
A part of him lived with in me, doesn't it?
'Did'.
It has been destroyed many moments
ago by Lord Voldemort himself.
You were the Horcrux you
never ment to make, Harry.
- I have to go back, aren't I?
- Oh, that's up to you.
- I've a choice?
- Yes!
We're in King's Cross as you said.
I think if you are so desired,
you'll be able to bring the train.
And where would it take me?
On.
Voldemort has the Elder wand?
True.
And the snake is still alive?
Yes.
And I've nothing to kill it with?
Helping always will be given at Hogwarts, Harry.
To those who ask for it.
fraze.I've always surprised myself
on my ability to turn a freeze.
Where's my not so humbling opinion...
I'm the most exhaustible sorcerer magic.
Capable of causing inflection
injury and therapies.
But I would in this case..
and turn my original statement to this:
Help, will always be given at Hogwarts.
To those who deserve it.
Do not grieve to the dead, Harry...
grieve to living.
And above all...
all those who live without love.
Professor, my mother's Patronus...
It was a doe, wasn't it?
As the same of Professor Snape's.
It's curious, don't you think?
Actually, if I think about it..
it doesn't seem curious at all!
I'll be going now, Harry.
Professor?
Is this all real?
Or it's just happening inside my head?
Of course it's happening
inside your head, Harry.
Why should that mean, it is not real?
Professor?
What should I do?
My Lord, My Lord..
are you hurt?
I don't need you help.
The boy...
is he dead?
Is he alive?
Draco, is he alive?
Dead.
Who is that?
Hogwart is carrying?
Neville, who is it?
Harry Potter!
- He's dead!
- No!
No!
Silence!
Stupid girl!
Harry Potter..
is dead!
From this day for..
you'll put your faith in me.
Harry Potter is dead!
And now it's the time to declare yourself.
Come forward and join us...
or die!
Draco!
Draco.
Come.
Well done, Draco.
Well done!
Well, I must say I hoped for better.
And who might you be, young man?
Neville Longbottom.
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can
find a place for you in our row.
I wanted to say something.
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd all be
fascinating to hear what have to say.
- Doesn't matter that Harry is gone.
- Sound down, Neville!
People die everyday!
Friends, family.
Yeah..
we lost Harry today.
He's still with us.
In here.
So as Fred, Remus...
Tonks..
All of them.
They didn't die in vain.
But you will.
Because you're wrong!
Harry has died for us.
For all of us!
But he's not over!
Cavreco!
Come on!
All remain in the castle.
We have to kill the snake.
Hey, Neville!
Not my daughter, you bitch!
Hey, you were right..
when you told Professor Snape
that wand won't serve you.
It was always...
I killed Snape!
Yeah, but what if the wand never belonged to Snape?
What if it's loyalty has always
belonged to someone else?
Oh, come on, Tom...
let's finish this as the way we started it.
Together!
Die!
This boy is a big fella.
Harry!
Why it didn't work for him?
The Elder wand?
It answers to somebody else.
When killed Snape, he thought
the wand will become his.
But the thing is..
The wand never belonged to Sanpe.
It was Draco who disarmed Dumbledore
that night in the Astronomy tower.
From that moment on, and the wand answerd him.
Until, at the night when I disarmed Draco.
At Malfoy's house.
So, that means...
It's mine!
- What should we do with it?
- We?
Just saying, that the Elder wand.
The most powerful wand in the world.
With that, we'll be invisible.
19 years later.
Together.
- Bag?
- yeah
Jumper?
I'm gonna miss you.
There they come.
Dad?
What if I have gone to the Slytherin?
Albus Severus Potter.
You're named after two headmasters of Hogwarts.
One of them is a Slytherin.
And he was the bravest man I ever known.
- What you say if I am...
- At Slytherin house...
will gain a wonderful young wizard.
Look, listen...
If it really means that much to you,
you can choose Gryffindor.
The sorting hat takes your
choice into account.
-  Really?
- Really.
-  Ready?
-  Ready.
One more time, do that move.