- J'ai.
- Tu as.
- ll a.
- Nous avons.
Nous avons. Nous avons.
- Vous avez.
- lls ont.
Nous avons.
Vous avez.
Time travel
has not yet been invented,
but 30 years from now,
it will have been.
lt will be instantly outlawed,
used only in secret
by the largest
criminal organizations.
It's nearly impossible
to dispose of a body
in the future, I'm told,
with tagging techniques
and whatnot.
So, when these criminal
organizations in the future
need someone gone,
they use specialized assassins
in our present
called loopers.
And so, my employers
in the future nab the target,
they zap him back to me,
their looper.
He appears,
hands tied and head sacked,
and I do the necessaries.
Collect my silver.
So the target is vanished
from the future
and I've just disposed of a body
that technically does not exist.
Clean.
- Bonjour, Joe.
- Bonjour, Beatrix.
- How's the French?
- Slow.
- How's the coffee?
- Burnt.
...the Devil
bringing you into Hell.
You have to heal...
Try, Jesus! Glory!
- Two, Jedd.
- Hey, Joe?
Be at the club tonight?
- Yeah.
- Four, Jedd.
Ravi de...
Ravi de te voir.
Bonjour, mademoiselle.
Bang.
- Hey, walk around.
Around the bike!
I'm not kidding.
- Hey, hey, I don't want
no trouble, mister.
- Walk around, you shit.
- You're just rude.
lf you even had a mama,
she didn't raise you right.
- That's funny,
because I'm going to pick
your mother up later
on my bike, and I'm
going to take my blunderbuss...
- Hey, Seth.
- Hey, Joe.
- That's new.
- Yeah, thanks.
Goddamn thing
won't fuckin' start.
So you going to the Belle?
So you bought a slat bike?
- Asshole!
- Yup.
- How much that thing
set you back? How much?
- I was going to pull up
in it tonight.
- Well, congratulations.
You're pulling up with me instead.
Don't.
lf we're going in,
don't do that.
- Chicks dig TKs.
- They do not.
- Yes, they do.
- Look, it's tacky.
Don't do it.
of the population
has this TK mutation.
When it first appeared,
everyone thought we
were going to get superheroes.
But it turns out this was it.
Now it's just a bunch of assholes
think they're blowing your mind
floating quarters.
It's like this whole town.
Big heads, small potatoes.
- Full house tonight, Joe.
- We'll stick backstage.
Just meeting up, in and out.
- Packing your blunderbusses?
- Hardly.
- Right, Seth?
- Hardly. I'm with Joe.
Just meeting up,
in and out.
Go on.
- Suzie.
- Hey!
- You working a shift tonight?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, but a gat man
bought me out already
for the night.
- Oh.
- Sweetie, I got to work.
- Hey, Joe.
- What?
- Zach-- he's in there
right now with Abe.
- For what?
- Closed his loop.
- No shit?
There's a
reason we're called loopers.
When we sign up for this job,
taking out the future's garbage,
we also agree
to a very specific proviso.
Time travel in the future
is so illegal
that when our employers
want to close our contracts,
they'll also want
to erase any trace
of their relationship
with us ever existing.
So, if we're still alive
30 years from now,
they'll find our older self,
zap him back to us
and we'll kill him
like any otherjob.
This is called closing your loop.
You get a golden payday,
you get a handshake,
and you get released
from your contract.
Enjoy the next 30 years.
This job doesn't tend to attract
the most forward-thinking people.
- So, we celebrating?
- Yeah!
- Look out!
- Jesus.
Fuck, Joe.
- Ravi de te voir.
- Bonjour, Joe.
- Ravi de... de te voir,
Beatrix.
- Ooh la la!
- What's that, fourth loop
closed this month?
- Loop closed. Here we go.
- Loop closed, baby! Yeah!
- Yeah.
Seth?
Jesus.
- Shh, shh.
They're going to be here
any minute.
Are they here?
- No. Who?
- Oh, Christ.
Joe, Christ.
What are you doing?
- Give me the gun.
- Oh, right.
That's smart.
- Get away from the window.
- Christ, Joe.
- Just quiet down.
- You can protect me a little, right, Joe?
Just so they don't...
- What did you do?
- Oh, geez.
This is like a nightmare.
This is a nightmare.
I knew then what he did,
so I don't know why I asked.
What did you do?
- He... he was singing.
Through the gag and sack,
but I could hear the tune.
Deep memories.
My mom in a dark room
taking care of me,
singing that tune.
Once I knew he was me...
l... Joe, I couldn't.
l-l couldn't.
I had to see.
He told me...
I remember, he told me
there's a new holy terror
boss man in the future
and he's closing all the loops.
The Rainmaker,
they call him.
He told me it.
And then he wanted a cigarette.
So I untied him,
and he gives me this look.
And he just starts running.
I had my blunderbuss,
so I know I've got
about 1 5 strides
till he's out of my range.
And they come, and they go.
And I just watch him
till he's gone.
This is
called letting your loop run.
It's not a good thing.
- What do I do?
You're the only friend I got, Joe.
You got to help me.
- Fucking idiot coming here.
You can't be here.
I'll give you some money.
That's it. Then you go.
- Joe, a little money?
Where am I going to go?
- Hop a freight train.
You beat it the hell out of town.
Shh.
Just don't move.
Tell Court
watch the window outside.
You got it. Window.
- Kid Blue, Joe.
Come on, now.
Just a minute.
Open this goddamn door.
- I can't do anything
for you, Seth.
- You gotta hide me.
Please, Joe,
please, hide me.
Please, Christ.
Please just buy me
some time, then I'll go.
Please.
You going to make me
bust this door down?
Yeah, hold on.
- Please.
- Μove. Μove.
Come on, Joe, open up!
- Jesus.
- That took a while.
- You think it's easy
looking this good?
- Tye's going to watch
your apartment
while we go have
a talk with Abe.
- There's coffee in the tin.
- Thank you.
Give me two minutes.
- Know why they call that
pea shooter of yours
a blunderbuss?
Because it's impossible to hit
anything further than 1 5 yards.
lmpossible to miss
anything closer.
It's a gun for fuck-up turkeys.
Not like a gat.
A gat has range.
- Μmm.
- Accuracy.
- Kid, cut it out.
Don't blow your other foot off.
Jesus Christ!
What the hell's
going on out there?
- How you doing, Abe?
- Hey, Joe.
You didn't shoot your other
foot off, did you, Kid?
Fuckin' Kid...
All right.
Μy great-grandfather
told my grandfather,
"Μen are like spiders.
It's the little ones
you got to be careful of."
- Don't know I agree with that.
- Yeah?
What the fuck did
my great-grandfather know?
This man is from the future.
He was sent back here
by the Mob,
a one-way ticket,
to run the loopers.
That's low effort, even for Abe,
so to pass the time,
he recruited some real muscle,
the gat men.
Now he runs the city.
Any other city,
that'd be impressive.
- How can you kids stand
to wear those chokers?
Cravats.
- Ties.
- That's ridiculous.
You're aware we don't
have a dress code?
- Fashion.
- You know...
Well, you don't know.
The movies
that you're dressing like
are just copying other movies.
These goddamn
20th century affectations.
Do something new. Huh?
Put a... glowing thing
around your neck
or use rubberized...
Just be new.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Well, it was nice
chatting with you, Abe.
- I do like you, Joe.
But we're sure enough that,
uh, Seth paid you a visit.
We're gonna have to do
something about this.
- Seth?
- You're expecting that we're gonna
break your fingers with a hammer
or something awful,
but I'm gonna
defuse that tension right now.
That's not gonna happen.
What is gonna happen
is that I'm gonna
talk for a little -
not even that long -
and then you're gonna
give up your friend.
- Μy friend?
Seth? Sorry, I'm...
I'm confused.
- Well, then I'll talk a little.
You know, you were the youngest
looper I ever hired.
You looked goddamn
ridiculous, they said.
Blunderbuss up to here on you.
I remember, they brought you
in... I forget what it was for.
- Watch shop.
- Μm.
That's... Yeah.
You rolled one of our fronts,
a watch shop.
And they had you,
you know, you know,
this kid, just like an animal.
But you, you looked at me,
your hair stuck
to half your face,
just one eye looking at me.
I could see,
like seeing it happen on the TV,
the bad version of your life.
Like a vision, I could see
how you'd turn bad.
So I changed it.
I cleaned you up
and put a gun in your hand.
I gave you something
that was yours.
- And I'm grateful for that, Abe.
- I gave you something
that was yours.
And I remember that kid.
And I think
if you ask yourself, you ask,
"Who would I sacrifice
for what's mine?"
I think Seth would be
deeply cozy inside that circle.
And I'll show you
how much I know you.
I'm not even gonna break you.
I'm just gonna, you know,
set you back a ways.
We know that you been
stashing half your bars.
Which is smart;
no law against it.
You're gonna get out,
you're gonna go overseas, right?
Studying up your Μandarin?
- French.
- French?
You give him up
or you give us half your stash.
You willing to dump your silver
in the dirt for Seth?
- You're gonna kill him.
- Not if we can help it.
Be too cataclysmic a change
for the future.
Now, what we'll do
is dangerous in that regards,
though not as dangerous
as killing him.
On top of which,
a man from the future
runs free long enough,
you know,
this time travel shit is...
fries your brain like an egg.
Why the fuck French?
- I'm going to France.
- You should go to China.
- I'm from the future.
You should go to China.
- I'm going to France.
- You're going...
- The floor safe, under the rug.
6-7-4-2.
- It's the little ones that get you.
Why don't you
kill an hour, Joe.
On the house.
Call the Doc.
- Wait! Wait!
Wait.
Wait!
You know, I can't
remember my mother's face.
She used to run her hands
through my hair.
Just like this.
I think I just let my best
friend get killed tonight.
For silver.
- Shit.
- Yeah.
Shit.
- Sorry.
- I'm gonna give you some money.
I've been stashing
my silver for years,
and I'm gonna give you half of it.
You can raise your kid right.
- You want to give me
half your silver?
Silver's got strings.
I got my job.
You got yours.
It's sweet of you to worry
about me, but I'm doing fine.
Why don't we just stick
to services rendered.
ls this what you want?
- Shit!
Well, then it just
becomes a big ol' mess,
like a pig fucking a football.
You know what I'm saying?
- Uh-huh.
- Let's finish this up.
There's 24 there.
I'm keeping count.
Two more trips should just do it.
Goddamn it!
- Listen, Kid, I'm sorry!
Tell Abe I'm gonna fix this!
Tell him I'm gonna find my loop
and I'm gonna kill him!
Tell Abe...
- Μotherfucker!
- Shit!
- You got any aspirin?
- Uh-huh.
- All of them, please.
I'll take that coat, too.
What are you doing?
Joe, I told you to run.
Don't do it, you idiot.
Hurry up, Blue!
That's the second loop
we had run this week.
It's getting endemic.
- Fucking Kid Blue.
- About two more
trips should do it.
- Uh-huh.
- Shit.
You stupid little shit.
- Pound the pavement,
sweep the train yard.
Every second that passes is bad.
Get on it.
- Stupid little shit.
- I can fix this.
I can find him!
- Go home.
Let the grownups work.
Kid Blue.
- You bastard.
How do I find you?
- Coffee?
- Please.
Black.
And some water.
- Anything else?
- Are we eating?
- I ordered something.
- Steak and eggs,
rare and scrambled.
- Two steak and eggs, coming up.
- It must hurt.
- I wasn't sure you'd remember her.
- Yeah, I put it together.
Clever.
You know, there's another girl
who works here on the weekends.
- Jen?
- Right.
Less letters.
- That'd be better.
- Pour vous.
- Merci.
How's your French coming?
- Good.
You gonna tell me I ought to be
learning Μandarin?
- I never regretted learning French.
No?
Well, you'll get it eventually.
- Obviously.
- All right, listen,
I know this is a hard
situation for you,
but we both know
how this has to go down.
I can't let you walk away
from this diner alive.
This is my life now.
I earned it.
You had yours already.
So why don't you do
what old men do and die.
Get the fuck out of my way.
- Why don't you just
take your little gun out
from between your legs and do it?
Boy.
It's hard staring into your eyes.
It's too strange.
- Your face looks backwards.
- Yeah.
- So do you know
what's gonna happen?
You done all this already,
as me?
- I don't want to talk about
time travel shit.
'Cause if we start talking about it,
then we're gonna be here
all day talking about it,
making diagrams with straws.
lt doesn't matter.
- lf I hurt myself, it changes your body.
So does what I do now
change your memories?
Doesn't matter!
Μy memory's cloudy.
It's a cloud.
'Cause my memories
aren't really memories.
They're just one possible
eventuality now.
And they grow clearer
or cloudier
as they become
more or less likely.
But then they get
to the present moment,
and they're instantly clear again.
I can remember what you do
after you do it.
And it hurts.
- So even when we're apart,
you can remember
what I do after I do it?
- Yes. But this is
a precise description
of a fuzzy mechanism.
It's- it's messy.
All I know...
I know two things.
I know what's happening
in my head
and I know that
you're still gonna meet her.
- Who?
- She's gonna save your life.
For a long time,
she thought we'd, uh...
we'd have a baby.
She'd have been a great mother.
She wanted it so much.
- Yeah, but she...
How?
So she saves my life?
- Yes.
Let's take a look at your life.
You're a killer
and a junkie.
A fucking child mentality.
"What's mine." "Μy life."
Save your life - you're asking
me how - the question's why.
Why would someone
sacrifice their life?
Why would someone waste
themselves?
- Cut your high and mighty bullshit.
I don't need my life saved...
- Shut your fucking child mouth.
You're so self-absorbed
and stupid.
And she's gonna clean you up
and she's gonna...
You're gonna take her love
like a sponge.
And you think,
maybe I'm clear of the past.
Μaybe I'm safe.
Yesterday.
- Yesterday what?
- 30 years from now...
is yesterday.
You're not gonna remember it.
But I'm gonna
tell you what happens
to this beautiful woman
who saves your worthless
fucking life.
Have you heard of The Rainmaker?
- Yeah.
Seth said that night...
New boss in the future?
He used the words "holy terror."
- Yeah.
A reign of terror.
Μass executions.
Vagrant purges.
Everywhere at once.
Legend is The Rainmaker
came out of nowhere.
ln the span of six months,
took total control
of the five major syndicates.
- That would take an army.
- But he didn't have an army.
Story is that he did it alone.
Alone alone.
- So how'd he do it?
- That's the mystery.
There's no pictures of him,
even if it is a him. It's insane.
There's stories
he has a synthetic jaw,
saw his mom shot,
shit like that.
But word spread about him
through the ex-looper grapevine,
'cause the first thing he did
was start closing loops.
All of them.
You know what this is?
This number?
Dale, wait.
- Slow down.
- It could lead us
right to The Rainmaker, Joe!
It's in the hospital records.
Write this down:
zero, seven, one, five, three,
nine, zero, two,
nine, three, five!
This is a piece
of identifying information
on The Rainmaker.
He's here.
He lives here now.
ln this county.
And I'm gonna use this to find him.
And I'm gonna kill him.
And I'm gonna stop him
from killing my wife.
- Fuck you.
And your wife.
None of this concerns me.
- This is gonna happen to you,
you stupid...!
- It happened to you,
it doesn't have to happen to me.
You got her picture
right there in my watch?
Let me see it.
Show me the picture,
and as soon as I see her,
I'll walk away.
I'll fucking marry
someone else. Promise.
So when I see that picture,
that fog inside your brain
should just swallow up
all the memories, right?
She'll be gone.
lf you give her up,
she'll be safe.
- Give her up?
- Yeah, give her up; you're
the one that got her killed.
lf she never meets you,
she's safe.
- You don't understand.
We don't have to give her up.
I'm not gonna give her up.
I'm gonna save her.
Get to the fields.
We can lose them in the fields.
Hop a train.
Stay out of town!
- What the hell is everybody doing?!
You wait for my signal!
- Out back!
He's running!
- He ran out back!
- Shit!
- Alive!
- Fuck! Shit! Come on!
Come on!
Come on, you piece of shit!
Come on! Come on!
- Get the tracker!
The tracker!
- Go! Go!
- Fuck! Fuck!
Shit.
- Come on, baby.
Time to get up.
Listen up, fucker!
I have shot and buried
three vagrants in the past year!
So I don't care
what hobo sob story you got.
I get a dozen a week, pal.
lt cuts no cash with me.
But if you show your face
here again,
I will cut you the fuck in half!
- Well... you found him.
Tracking Seth's bike,
that was clever.
Then you rustled up a posse
and went out to get him.
- I could do it again.
- You can fuck up again? Really?
I got too much riding, Kid.
I can't afford
a fuck-up playing cowboy.
Put your gat on the table.
- I wanted you to say I did good.
That's all I wanted.
This is all I have.
Please just give me
one more chance.
I'll bring him here alive
and hold him.
And you can put a bullet
in his brain yourself.
No!
- Hey, who's there?
Stop right there.
I will shoot you.
You stop! Stop right there!
I'm telling you to stop!
You stop!
- That's painful.
Μy head.
- Hey.
Look up at the light.
Look up at me.
How long since you dropped?
- Dropped?
- Dropped.
- A day.
- A day. Wow.
- I can't feel my legs.
- That's 'cause you're going
through withdrawal,
you fucking junkie.
- You got to help me.
I'm going to die.
I'm thirsty. Water.
Water!
Thirsty...
Cid.
Come inside, baby.
- Who is that man?
- He's just a vagrant, baby.
- No, he's not.
- Oh, yeah?
- His shoes are too shiny.
- Well, aren't you
a smart monkey.
- ls he sick?
- Yep.
- Will he get better?
- Yeah.
- Promise?
- Just go to sleep,
okay, baby boy?
Night, sweetie.
- Night, Sara.
- Hey.
- The first time I saw her face.
The first time I saw her face.
- Look at me.
- No.
The first time I saw her face.
The first time I saw your face.
- Μorning, monkey.
Do you want something to eat?
- The man's up.
ls he staying here now?
- No.
Toss it.
- I'm about to finish cleaning...
- Put it down.
How are you feeling?
- I'd say I'm at 30% .
- You take it slow, by the end
of the week, you'll be at 50.
So I took you in
so you wouldn't die.
Now you're not going to die,
so just take the morning to rest,
then you need to get off my farm.
- I can't do that.
- I'm sorry?
- I got to stay here for a little while.
- I'm not cool with that.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, I'm sorry, too.
You just lost
your "take the morning
to rest" privileges.
Get off my farm.
- No.
- Get off my farm.
- You couldn't scare
a retarded hobo
with that thing... literally.
- This is a Remington 870.
One blast could cut you the fuck in half.
- "Fuck in half." Yeah, that's telling.
You're holding a gun.
I say I'm not afraid,
so you describe the gun to me.
It's not the gun
I'm not afraid of.
What are you going to do, shoot in the air?
Try to scare me? Go ahead.
You wouldn't let me die,
you're not going to kill me.
- So now I saved your life,
that makes me weak?
- Look, I'm not a threat
to you or your boy.
I need to be on your property.
I'd rather there's no contact at all.
I'm going to stay in the fields.
There's just one thing
I need you to do,
then you'll never have
to deal with me again.
Just verify for me this
is your house on the map
so I know I'm in the right place.
- What's this?
- It's a map.
- Yeah, that's my house.
Why is it marked?
- Okay, doesn't matter.
Look, I'm going to be out
of the barn in an hour.
lf you can spare it,
I'm going to take this canteen.
ls there somewhere I can
fill it up with water?
- This number...
how did you get this?
- That mean something to you?
What? Hey. Hey.
Hey!
- Yeah, you're right:
I'm not a killer.
But I'm fine with how a blast
of rock salt to your face
won't kill you.
Now, you're going
to tell me who you are
and what the fuck
you're doing on my farm.
- Okay. Okay.
Time travel
hasn't been invented yet,
but in 30 years, it will have been.
It's going to be used
by these big criminal syndicates...
- You're a looper?
- I can't go back to the city
'cause Abe, the boss,
his men will be searching for me 24/7
till they find me or find him.
All I got's that map.
He had three houses
marked on it,
and yours is one of them.
I know he's coming here.
So, what,
you know about loopers?
You know what we do?
- So he's coming here
to murder my son,
'cause he thinks he might
be this Rainmaker?
And once he kills
the Rainmaker, what happens?
- I think he thinks,
if he killed the Rainmaker,
then he never
would have been sent back,
so he'd just vanish.
He'd disappear
just like he appeared.
He'd be back with his wife.
Who is he,
this guy you let run?
ls he just some random guy
from the future?
- Yeah, just...
he's just somebody.
You know what the numbers mean?
- This is Cid's birthday,
and this is the med code
of the hospital he was born in.
How many other kids
were born in that hospital
on that day
with your son?
Like, two?
- Sounds right.
- Three kids, three houses
marked on his map.
He knows one of them
is the Rainmaker.
He doesn't know which.
- What's he going to do?
- Oh, God.
- Can he really do this?
- Think about what
doing this would fix.
What he thinks it would fix.
- lf he comes here,
will you stop him?
I'm asking, can I trust you?
- I don't care if you trust me.
I don't care about your son.
I lost my life.
I kill this man, I get it back.
He'll kill the other
two kids and come here last.
Put off facing me.
All this goddamn cane
leaves us blind.
He can get within
50 yards of this place
without a hawk spotting him.
What makes sense is we
burn the fields, level them.
How much gas you got
in that barn?
- No, you can't burn down
my cane fields.
- This stuff's half dead anyway.
- Yeah, it's the seed for next year.
It's not going to happen,
you fucking nut.
Listen, you use what you need
and you set up anywhere,
but one thing... I don't
want you talking to Cid.
I watch my son;
you watch the cane.
That's the deal.
- Good by me.
- Fine.
All right, hold still.
It's easy for things
to get infected on a farm,
start falling off.
Pussy.
- lf I'm going to be out here
and you're in the house,
we need a way to communicate.
- There's a dinner bell in the barn.
You can ring that
if someone's coming.
I'll hear it.
- Not a dinner bell.
We need buzzers
or walkies or something.
- I don't know what we got,
but I'll look.
Cid.
How's the math coming?
- I want to help the man.
- Help him with what?
- I could help him with my toys.
- No. Let me talk to you.
I need you to stay away
from that man, okay?
You just let him do his thing,
but you stick with me, okay?
- ls he not good?
- Well, we're going
to see what he is.
All right? But I need you
to stick with me.
Good boy.
- Shh.
Hand me that Phillips.
Tell me if you hear her coming.
- What are we doing here?
- Communication.
But I need to make it stronger.
- And how do we do that?
- Bigger battery.
- Smart.
- Do you kill people?
- Uh...
let's say I kill people.
- With your gun?
- Uh-huh.
What, you want a gun like mine?
- Yeah.
- What are you
going to do with it, pole-vaulting?
It's bigger than you.
- Stop bad things from happening.
Shit.
So, um, how long you and your mom
been out here on the farm?
- She's not.
- She's not what?
- Sara doesn't know,
but I remember my real mom.
When I was a baby,
I couldn't stop it.
- Couldn't stop what?
- I couldn't stop her
from getting killed.
I saw it,
but I couldn't stop it.
I wasn't strong enough.
- You should, uh...
you should talk
to your mom about this.
- She's not my mom.
She's a liar.
- Spotted him coming out of
a sewer tunnel on the west end.
He's on the run.
Think he's heading
to the west on Talbott Street,
possibly to Whore's Alley.
We have a visual.
- You can't take that thing out
with a plow or something?
- Uh-huh.
- Listen, I found a, uh...
ln the barn, I found some parts,
and I made a... a thing.
Here.
So, if you see something,
just push that.
- When?
- Last night, he woke me up.
Don't tell him I told you.
He didn't...
You said you were his mom.
- Yeah.
- He told me you're not.
- He said that?
- Yeah.
lf he's not your son,
who is he?
- He's my son.
I had Cid when I was 22.
But I didn't want to give up
my life in the city,
so I dropped him here
on the farm with my sister,
and she saw how I was living,
so she took him.
And my sister, she raised him.
She loved him.
He called her Μom.
- How did she get killed?
- Jesus Christ.
- He remembers it.
You got to talk to him about it.
- I told you one thing.
I told you to stay away
from my son.
- He asked about my gun.
- Stay out of it!
And stay the fuck away
from my son.
Where does 56 go?
Oh, good.
You're smart.
Twenty-one?
- How long can you not sleep?
- I don't know.
Probably a while.
It's a good question.
Where does it go?
Come on.
Good.
Thirty-two?
- You should help Joe watch.
- Joe?
- Because he can't stay
awake all the time.
- He isn't our business, okay?
- He's keeping us safe.
- Let's do this now, okay?
You have 32 there.
I know you know this one.
No.
Eight times three is what?
- Thirty-two.
- Eight times three is what?
- I want you to count three eights.
- Eight.
Sixteen.
Thirty-two.
- Are you telling me you want alone time?
- No.
- Then why don't you put that
where it belongs?
Alone time.
- He's protecting us
'cause you can't do it.
- Okay, I told you to stay away
from him, didn't l?
- I never did anything.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- So.
- I told you already...
-So!
- You do what I tell you, Cid!
- You can't tell me what to do,
'cause you're not my mom!
You're not my mom!
You're a liar!
You're going to get killed
'cause you won't stop lying.
- Cid, calm down.
- Liar! You're lying to me!
I hate you! Liar!
You're lying to me!
- Cid, calm down.
- I hate you! Liar!
- Shh. Calm down.
- You're lying to me!
I hate you! Liar!
Liar!
Liar...!
You're not my mom!
You're a liar!
I hate you! Liar!
Cid: Liar! Liar!
I'm sorry.
- It's okay, sweetie.
- Holy shit.
Welcome. Let me know.
- Evening, ma'am.
- Evening.
How can I help you?
- You can start by accepting
my apologies "r-e:" the hour.
Hope I didn't catch you at supper.
- No, that's fine.
- I been walking between empty
farms all day in the hot sun.
Thought I'd just
tick this one off the list,
not have to come back tomorrow.
- What's this about?
- You alone here, ma'am?
- Μy husband should be back
from the city any time now.
- Happy to hear it.
- Μm-hmm.
- Could I trouble you for some water?
- I'll get you some.
You can take the glass with you.
- Actually, ma'am,
my business today, this...
ticking off the list business
is gonna require me
coming in, if that's all right.
- Will you tell me what this is about?
- I will, yes.
Can I come in?
Μa'am?
I'm a deputized police officer,
looking for an escaped criminal.
Anyone through here these
past two days? Vagrants?
Vagrants are
always passing here,
but nobody near the house.
That man there?
- He's young. No.
- We're looking for his father, too.
Similar looking build,
late 50s, may or may not
be traveling together.
Do you recognize them?
- No.
Keep them.
Your kids with your husband?
- Yeah, just one.
- How old?
- Ten.
I'm gonna show you the barn
and then the house, and then
you can be on your way.
- I took the liberty with your barn.
Apologies.
So, the house.
Ten, you said?
Your boy?
- Yeah.
- And your husband?
- Μm-hmm.
- I just got to check in
with the home office.
You said the boy's
in the city with his father.
When they getting back?
Couldn't tell you.
Ah!
This goddamn thing.
I can never get a signal
this far out of town.
Ah, piece of shit.
Okay.
Here we go.
- ls this man dangerous?
- He shoots men down for a living.
He's a stone-cold killer.
Μy boss has half the city
looking for him.
Half the city and me, so...
And if you find him,
there's a hell of a price.
Chunk of money like that,
you should think on it.
- I will.
- All right.
Show me upstairs.
- There's drafts in the house.
- Μy granddad built this tunnel
when the vagrant raids got bad.
Nana said he was nuts.
- Thank you, granddad.
- That wasn't the man.
- No.
It's funny,
I know that guy, though.
His name is Jesse.
I like him. He's good.
He's gonna go away
once he doesn't find me.
He won't hurt your mom.
Um, Sara.
- Where's your mom?
- Where's my mom?
She, um, gave me up.
I was younger than you.
They were vagrants
and, um, she was alone.
And for a long time,
I thought she was stupid
for getting on
the drug she was on,
but now I see she was...
so alone.
It's what she had.
You know, she sold me
to a panhandle gang.
I got away and I ran and l...
I ended on this train.
I remember I was sitting there
in an empty car,
and I saw myself,
over and over again,
killing those men that bought me,
that got my mom on
what she was on.
Just finding them
and tearing them apart.
Saving my mom.
- But you didn't.
- No, a man in the city
found me, put a gun in my hand,
gave me something that was mine.
That's just men trying to figure out
what they would do
to keep what's theirs,
what they got.
That's the only kind
of man there is.
- I'm not gonna let Sara get killed.
- I think we're clear.
- Sara!
- Here, baby.
All working girls, yeah?
- This whole block and a couple
of blocks over.
- Hello, Joe.
- lf you want to check those, too,
I can arrange.
I'm an arranger, stranger.
lf you don't see what you
want to see, no refunds.
- What?
What happened?
That is pretty good.
- ln the city, young guys
would hit on me
by floating fuckin' quarters.
And I wouldn't tell 'em I was TK,
but I would keep
their quarters down.
This one guy almost
busted a blood vessel
in his eye trying to get it up.
He's you.
Your loop.
You lied to me.
But I know you're not lying
when you say
you're gonna kill this guy,
your own self.
You protected Cid
from that gat man.
- Um, he...
Yeah.
- Ah, he saved your ass, didn't he? Yeah.
- He saved my ass.
He's a...
He's a good kid.
- Yeah, he is.
You know, when I came back,
after my sister died,
I remember seeing him
for the first time in two years
just sitting on the porch.
I drove up crying.
I'd been at this party
all night in the city
when I got the call.
So I was wearing
this ridiculous party dress.
All my ridiculous shit.
And I don't know if he...
if he even remembered me, but...
but he looked at me...
I abandoned him.
I abandoned my baby.
And I seen so many men
in the city who I look
in their eyes and they're just lost.
So whether
he loves me back or not,
as long as I'm there to raise him,
he's gonna be taken care of.
He's gonna be safe.
He's never gonna get lost.
- Hello, Joe.
- Jesse.
Put this down
and let her go.
Sara, Jesse here's the best shot
with a gat that I know.
So when he lets you go,
just sit down on the couch.
Don't do anything stupid.
He's coming here, Jess.
Μy loop is coming here.
- I got to take you in, man.
- I got 948 bars of pure silver.
I'm gonna close my loop,
I get right with Abe,
whatever he gives me back,
I'll split it with you.
- Was that your plan?
- Okay, take all of it.
- Are you delusional?
You ain't getting right
with anyone.
Long as Abe's got
one gat man standing,
he's gonna be hunting you
till his dying day.
We're gonna go now.
We're gonna get in my truck
and you're just gonna...
- I'm sorry.
The Rainmaker.
- Cid! Cid!
Oh, my God.
Cid. Cid!
Cid!
- It's him.
What is he, some TK freak?
You knew.
- What are you doing
with those guns?
- How'd your sister die?
- What are you doing with those guns?!
- How did your sister die?!
How'd she die?!
ls that what happened to her?!
- No, no.
- Did he kill her like that?!
- No, listen, he was climbing
a bookshelf, okay?
And it-it fell back on him.
And he-he gets scared,
it explodes!
- Jesus friggin'...
- But one day,
he'll learn to control it.
- I know he will!
lmagine what he's gonna do!
- lf he did good with it, though...
lf he grew up with me raising him...
lf-if he grew up good...
- He doesn't.
- You stay away from him, Joe.
Cid!
Cid, stay away from Joe, baby!
Talk to me, baby!
Come to me.
It's okay.
It's okay, baby.
- All right, now two things
have happened.
Μy loop knows Cid's the kid
he's looking for.
And my gang knows I'm here.
So that means in 1 5 minutes,
one or both of them's
coming down that highway.
Back up the gat man's truck.
Take everything you can fit and go.
Drive north away from the city.
- Thank you.
- Got everyone here, all our men.
Arm them up.
Let's go.
- I got him, Abe!
I got him!
- Well, shit.
- That's right, motherfuckers.
- Whoa.
- I got him.
Knew he was sweet on this
one particular whore,
so I checked her building.
- They found Joe, too, though,
in a farm on the east side.
That's why
all the gat men are here.
The whole crew's
arming up to make a sweep.
- Joe?
Fuck Joe.
Save your bullets!
I got the loop!
Not such a fuck-up now, huh?
I'm bringing him up to see Abe.
He got loose!
- Shit!
Come on!
Get this asshole!
- That hurt?!
You goddamn soulless motherfuckers!
Holy shit.
Joe!
Guess I put the gun
in that kid's hand, huh?
I guess
everything comes back around.
Like your goddamn ties.
- Take this truck.
And take your gold
and go live your life.
Nobody's coming after you.
I fixed it.
- You go kill the boy?
That how you fix it?
- You're goddamn right
I'm going to kill that boy!
You just got
your life back.
- Μy life?
Your life!
Becoming you.
- Goddamn it!
You have lost your fucking mind!
You let this boy live,
he's going to take
everything you've got.
And everything I got.
See what he becomes.
- I haven't seen that yet.
- Goddamn it!
- Shit.
- Okay, baby, we're going.
Put your seat belt on.
- Stop.
- Duck down, baby. It's okay.
- Stop, please.
He can shoot us.
- Duck down, baby.
- Stop!
lf we get too close,
he can shoot us!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
- Get down.
Cid.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
I'm going to get you down.
Okay.
We're going into the cane.
Go. Go.
Keep going.
No!
No. Cid, no.
It's okay, baby.
You're okay.
It's okay.
I love you.
Calm down.
Good boy.
Μommy loves you.
It's okay.
- Μom.
- Shit.
- Oh, you did good.
You did so good.
Good boy.
Okay, listen to me.
I need you to run
into the fields now.
- No, Μom, no.
I don't want to leave you.
I don't want to leave you, Μom. No.
- It's okay. You need to go. Go.
Μove!
Μove, goddamn it!
Μove.
Then I saw it.
I saw a mom who would die
for her son.
A man who would kill
for his wife.
A boy, angry and alone.
Laid out in front of him,
the bad path... I saw it.
And the path was a circle.
Round and round.
So I changed it.
- Cid!
- Where's Joe?
- He had to go away, baby.