Every time I pass through Texas ,
I looked down ...
and rethink what
she was doing to me .
Six weeks I just
think of the woman .
Then when we landed at Edwards ,
turns out she had run away with his employees .
So I parked my car  ,
and go to ...
You're telling it , Kowalski .
He also blurred bring your '74 GTO .
Please report the status of a prototype jetpack .
Five hours of unused and new power reduced by 30 % .
Convey my thanks to Engineering .
Except for minor damage in the roll axis ,
His jetpack fine .
Engineering say thanks .
Tell me about the '67 Corvette .
What can be reused ?
- Quite a story about the Corvette , Matt .
- Okay , Engineering .
Thank you , Doctor .
Shariff , report status .
Probably  Z1N replace the battery module .
to be so specific ?
They were a little worried here .
Oh , no , no , Houston . Do not worry .
Anxiety is not good for the heart .
Houston , panel ready to be activated .
panel is turned on , upgraded and functioning well .
The Board  thank you , Shariff .
Welcome .
When returning , you will immediately holiday .
Matt , could you see what was done
Mission Specialist Shariff up there ?
Apparently he did dancing the Macarena .
That scenario might guess
The best in my mind .
Dr . Stone, Houston here .
Medical record body temperature dropped to 35.9
and the mean heart rate of 70.
What do you feel ?
Houston , I'm fine .
Restraining vomiting in zero gravity
proved more difficult than it seems .
Dr . Stone, Medical advise if
you want to go back to Explorer ...
negatives , we had one week here , Houston .
Let's just finish this .
been accepted ?
negatives , we did not get anything here, Doc .
Try again .
No, still nothing .
- Houston , could you please turn off the music ?
- Kowalski ?
does not matter .
Thank you , Kowalski .
Now , Houston ?
Negative .
What might you  misinterpretation of the data ?
We did not receive any data .
Engineering advised to do
physical checks on the faulty component .
What happened ?
What  here ?
Visual examination  not found
damage to components .
The problem may come from the communications panel .
It seems likely that the problem  .
Engineering recognizes that you
already warned this would happen .
It makes us owe an apology .
We should have listened to you , Doc .
- like you have to improvise .
- Will do.
- How long is about time ?
- One hour .
Amazing , install your system at Hubble
The main goal of this mission is ...
So we appreciate your patience , Doctor .
Kowalski , we know you do not care
with things like this , but ...
Just so you know , because of the delay , no longer
you will break the record Anatoly Solovyev .
- like you less ...
- 75 minutes ?
It never crossed my mind.
Matt ...
an honor .
Okay , back to you , Houston .
Enjoy your last trip .
May I assist Dr . Stone move the panel ?
- Help appreciated .
- Permission granted .
Thank you , Houston .
- May I join ?
- Of course .
How do you feel ?
.
This week is heavy .
If it 's any consolation , I let it all
except when my kidneys first trip .
Shit .
sorry .
I used to work in the basement of the hospital lab
where everything fell to the floor .
Thank you .
Well , you're the genius here .
I'm just a pilot .
Well , call me a genius if I succeed
put this board in the next hour .
- Explorer , here Houston .
- Please , Houston .
NORAD reported that the Russian satellite
was destroyed by a missile .
collision produces a cloud of debris .
Moving at the speed of 20,000 mph ...
debris it does not lead to lintasanmu ...
- we 'll let you know if there is progress .
- Roger, Houston .
- Should , should we worry ?
- Let them down there were worrying .
- Explorer , please go to Cargo Bay .
- Stand by.
So after working with NASA ,
Do you like us ?
It was such hope is not in charge , huh ?
I'm glad they did not decide
flow of funds for my research .
- How long have you been practicing ?
- Six months .
holiday too ?
So , what about the system scanner ?
No , I 'm enjoying
the beauty of the Ganges .
Houston , I 've used it in the hospital ,
but that this is a prototype .
Preparing  lock .
Look , they do not sell the prototype .
Although at that beautiful blue eyes .
My eyes are brown .
Now your eyes are blood red .
Kowalski , this cool or not ?
hard to believe he is a graduate of Harvard .
That means one thing .
It could be the landscape .
What do you like to be here ?
Keheningannya .
I'm getting used to it.
Excellent  .
Houston , based on initial inspection ,
communication panels will soon die .
What I should break the connection to the Auxiliary ?
You're the expert , Doctor .
It's your decision .
Houston , I have a bad feeling about this mission .
Please  described .
It's the same feeling with
Mardi Gras 1987 .
Understandably , not surprisingly Control
know the story of Mardi Gras ...
Please proceed .
That first day , and I walked down
Bourbon street , looking for my sister .
street was full of people , I thought there might be
I'm going to find this girl .
Continue to Override .
Then suddenly I saw it ,
and he was there ...
and he was holding the hand of a man
short hairy , wearing a margarita .
Then I realized this man is not a man .
My girl holding hands ...
ISS Houston here .
- Explorer , here Houston .
- Please , Houston .
Abort mission . Repeat , abort mission .
Start an emergency separation process of Hubble .
Start Reentry procedures ( back to Earth ) ,
ISS began the emergency evacuation process .
Understandably , Houston .
Matt , right back to the Explorer .
Repeat , right back to the Explorer .
Accepted , Explorer .
Prepare " Airlock " ( air lock )
- Airlock enabled . Ready to receive .
- Houston , explain .
Debris from the missile hit  produce a chain reaction .
Hit other satellites , and generate new debris .
Moving faster than a bullet heading toward you .
- Got it all ?
- Understood .
- Stop job, Dr. . Stone.
- No, its board is starting the process .
- I will not ask you again .
- Just a second .
No  soon , now .
Turn off .
That's an order .
Okay , sorry . I 'm done .
Done .
- Kowalski , began the process of separation from Hubble .
- All right , Shariff , let's do this .
All right , man .
- Houston , what the situation is ?
- Looks like it's a big chain reaction .
's been confirmed it is a side effect of accidental
when Russia destroy their own satellites .
- They destroy their own satellite ?
- The right to dispose of .
Most spy satellites are damaged ,
Now destroyed .
- Explorer , ready to let go of the HST .
- Releasing in 3 , 2 , 1 .
- Explorer , the latest data already entered .
- What does it say , Houston ?
Not good , most of us die system .
chain reaction of debris that
uncontrollable and spread rapidly .
Many satellite  hit ,
and they continue to fall .
- Explain " Many satellites " .
- Most of them were destroyed .
communication system is dead .
Hope the communication will be back in a few moments .
- Kowalski , I see the coming of debris 9 o'clock .
- Most people in North America lost Facebook .
Explorer , hope communication will
connected again after the disturbance .
Roger, Houston .
Explorer , here Kowalski , confirm contact
visual debris . Debris was fast approaching .
Dr . Stone asked for faster transportation .
We have to go ,
Go , go .
Houston , Explorer , do you hear ?
Explorer , Dr. . Stone need transportation to the Bay Area .
Explorer , do you hear ?
- Explorer , asked permission to pick up Dr . Stone?
- Please , Kowalski .
Houston , to Explorer , you hear?
We miss Houston .
- We have to get out of here .
- Need help ?
- No, do not wait for us .
- Loss !
- The crew aborted, the crew fall .
Houston , here Explorer , you hear?
Explorer hit .
Explorer , do you hear ?
Explorer , enter , Explorer !
astronaut , remove yourself from the structure !
Dr. . Stone, disconnect yourself from the structure !
Dr . Stone, Release !
You must escape !
Stone , you must be off or you
will fly away !
- Listen to my voice ! You need to focus !
- Can not be !
- Do it now !
- Well , I'll try !
Dr . Stone, do you hear ?
Repeat , do you hear ?
Yeah , I hear ya !
I'm off !
I do not know , I'm spinning in circles ,
I can not ...
Sorry , I'm confused ,
I can not say anything .
I do not see anything .
.
- You can see the ISS ?
- No.
You have to focus , give me direction ,
Give me kordinatnya !
- I can not breath ! I can not breath !
- Give me kordinatnya .
Dr . Stone, did you hear ?
Did you hear ?
The plane was badly damaged .
There are people there .
I can see the China Station .
No, it was the International Space Station ( ISS )
ISS , you hear?
ISS , Houston ?
Lieutenant Kowalski , are you listening ?
Explorer , you hear ?
Houston , do you hear ?
Houston , Mission Specialist Ryan Stone here , I'm ...
Separated from the structure and I floated ,
Did you hear ?
Anyone ?
Please listen .
Please  .
Yes , Fl. Kowalski , yes .
Yes , Fl. Kowalski , I'm here .
Yes , I heard , I'm here .
I'm here .
Turn on the flashlight ?
Here , here .
I'm here .
- I'm fine .
- Report status .
3 !
3.7 Psi .
O2 mu , mu 02 status report .
oxygen decreases , down fast,
down to number nine .
- No, eight percent .
- Okay , you're breathing too fast ...
You burn oxygen , we do not want it ,
I want you to calm down , understand ?
- Yes , understood .
- I'll be there .
Please hurry up .
- Keep holding the flashlight , Dr . Stone.
- Sorry , sorry .
I got you . All right , now ,
I'm going to tie you to me .
I know you never realized
how handsome I am .
But I want you to stop seeing ,
and help me tie it .
- Okay ?
- Okay .
Well , here it is .
Well , you should rather stay away from the jet ,
I will give a little boost .
- No, no , no .
- Not encouragement , little buffeting .
No, no , no !
See ? Wherever you go , I go .
Better  .
Let's get out of here .
- Damn !
- I know , it 's me.
- Shit .
- You burn oxygen .
We return to the spacecraft ,
What about the plan ? Understand ?
Fuck !
Well , understandably .
Houston , here Kowalski . Dr. . Stone
and I will get back to Base ...
could convey the Explorer to prepare
" Airlock " for the arrival , understand ?
Houston , here Kowalski , are you listening ?
Houston , this blind calls , here Kowalski .
- They can not hear us .
- We do not know , so we continued to talk .
If anyone is listening , maybe he
will save your life .
Set your clock for 90 minutes .
Why 90 ?
Well , if Houston calculate
speed was 50.000 mph debris ...
While connected to our orbit , then there
90 minutes until we hit again .
O2 dropped to six percent .
I was really scared .
Why do not you slow down ?
Houston , calls the blind , here Kowalski .
Our location approximately 900 meters from the Explorer .
Dr . Stone and I will secure
Mission Specialist Shariff corpse ...
and back to the plane .
Can I secure it ?
Understandably  .
Where is he ?
Catch him !
I try !
- Pull him .
- I get it .
Try to keep your balance .
I can not activate the rocket boosters
if you two are moving to and fro .
Hope you have insurance , Houston .
Damage Explorer ,
really badly .
- Not yet known if there are survivors .
- O2 down to five percent .
This is it , watch out edges .
Houston , blind call , you hear?
Mission Specialist Dr.  . Stone and Mission Commander
Matthew Kowalski are two people survived the SDS 157 .
sorry because I did not obey. I should have
stop when you instruct it to me .
We will also hit hit , nobody
can you do to change it .
Hey  .
Yes ?
Well , we must go to
space station ...
There  ...
bit far ...
We must use the " Escape Pod " them ,
Soyuz to return to Earth .
Agree ?
Dr . Stone?
Agree  .
Okay , you go first .
Oh , God .
Houston , calls the blind , here Kowalski .
Dr . Stone and I decided to go to the ISS ...
Using one pod Soyuz for Reentry .
ISS , can you hear us ?
You are rescue missions .
O2 down to two percent .
We will soon be up .
Beautiful , is not it?
What ?
sun rises .
Actually I do not really miss him .
So where is your house , Dr . Stone?
Ryan , where is your house?
house ?
Down there .
On Earth .
Where did you get up your tent ?
Lake Zurich .
Where is it ?
Illinois .
Illinois ?
Central time zone part .
not be any harder , huh ?
At 8 pm .
What do the people
in Lake Zurich at 8 pm ?
I do not know .
I will not survive ,
I just melambatkanmu .
Oh , you're going to survive .
Come on , Ryan .
It's at 8 pm .
You just left the hospital
after a 18 hour shift .
Driving home ?
Radio .
I listen to the radio .
That's it , let me guess ...
NPR , classical , Top 40 ?
Regardless , I do not care , as long as they
do not speak , I'm just driving .
Where are you driving ?
I'm just driving .
What do you miss down there ?
Is there a Mr.  . Stone?
.
Nothing special someone ?
Someone down there is looking up .
Thinking ?
Ryan ?
I 've got a daughter .
He was four years old .
He was playing at school , slip ,
he hit his head and died .
tragic .
notified when I 'm driving , so ...
Since then , that's what I did .
I wake up ...
Go to work ...
and driving it ...
O2 down to one percent .
I 've got good news and bad news .
good news , we are only five minutes from the ISS
and I know where it stores the Russian vodka .
That's good , because I ran out of fuel here .
bad news , less than 10 minutes
I broke the record Anatoly , and ...
What ?
I ran out , my low pressure oxygen tanks ...
Tangkimu run out of oxygen , but you still
have a supply in your shirt .
- All right .
- You have to suck it up , now .
Slow down , do not rush .
Sip , Ryan .
Houston , we could see the ISS
The station would have been evacuated ,
because the first Soyuz gone.
Soyuz  both suffered damage to its surface ,
and his parachute had opened ...
and its use as an " Escape Pod "
for Reentry , very unlikely .
yet , I'm not kidding about the fuel ,
The remaining may be up to 2-3 encouragement .
If we 're lucky .
Stabilize  .
Shutter ...
Shoot !
Wait , you must put the brakes on .
No, boosters are up.
We're going to hit hard ,
Grip on whatever you can.
What should I do ?
strap connection regardless !
Apart !
Search  grip !
Hold something !
Ryan !
Grab my hand !
I 'll catch you .
I 'll catch you!
Shit !
No, no , no !
I got you .
Hold on , I 'll pull you .
- Listen , Doc .
- Hold on , I 'll pull you .
- Ryan , heard .
- I 'll pull you up .
- You have to let go .
- Not !
rope is too loose , I'm pulling you with me .
You have to let go ...
- Or we'll both die .
- Not going to let it go , we are fine !
.
Ryan , release .
I'm not going anywhere .
It's not your call .
No, please, do not do this .
Please, please do not do this .
Please do not do this .
You will survive , Ryan .
!
I 've got you .
Ryan , do you hear me ?
Did you hear ?
Materials bakarku too little .
Bakarku too little material .
Go to the station .
You see " Airlock " it ?
Ryan ...
Above you ...
you see it?
Yes , I saw it .
I saw it .
Good , that's where you should go .
Yes .
You inhale CO2 , you will lose consciousness .
Go to the station .
Okay .
I immediately there .
See point in the distance ?
- It is China's Space Station .
- Yes .
You must use the Soyuz to get there .
Aircraft  Chinese rescuers his name Shenzou .
Shenzou ?
No problem .
The protocol is the same as Soyuz Reentry .
right .
You also have never operated Soyuz ?
Only in the simulator .
Glad to know .
But I crashed it .
That simulator , for which he was made .
Always  .
I always crashed .
Luckily it on Earth .
It's not rocket science .
Tomorrow at this hour you will be returned to
Lake Zurich with a great story .
Do you understand ?
Ryan , understand ?
I will operate the Soyuz and pick you up .
- Not .
- I 'll pick you up .
- I 've gone too far .
I'm afraid it will harm you .
Ryan , you have to learn to let go .
I want to hear you say
" I will survive " .
Come on , Ryan .
Tell .
I will survive .
right, continue .
Why use the name of Ryan
for a woman ?
My father wanted a boy .
You already approaching " Airlock " ?
- yet .
- Continue .
Looks like we are getting far distance .
- You're interested in me , right?
- What ?
Well , people tell me I have beautiful blue eyes .
You have a ...
You have beautiful blue eyes .
My eyes are brown .
- You want to hear the good news ?
- What ?
I will break the record Anatoly .
and I think my record will last very long .
I 'll pick you up .
Yes , Lord .
Wow .
- Hey , Ryan ?
- Yes .
You should see a tributary of the Ganges .
Amazing .
Where are you ? Where are you ?
Communication , communication ...
There , all right .
Matt , Ryan here , you hear?
Matt , I did it , I was at the station ,
Did you hear ?
Come on , Matt , talk to me .
Tell me where you were , say your position .
Where are you ? Give me direction ,
Just tell me what you see .
Oh , come on , you never silent since we left
Cape Canaverall , now you silent ?
Talk to me , tell me something ,
Anything, I do not care .
Hey ...
Tell me about Mardi Gras ,
Tell me about the hairy man ...
Tell me what happened .
What's wrong with a hairy man ?
Please, talk to me .
Houston , blind calls .
Mission Specialist Ryan Stone 's report from the ISS .
Our communication with Mission Commander
Matthew Kowalski has been lost .
No radio transmissions .
No visual contact .
Understood ?
I'm Ryan Stone , the sole survivor ,
of the SDS 157 .
What is it now ?
Fire .
Alright .
Where , where ...
Where its power button ?
Undocking ( Moving aircraft from the dock )
Undocking .
Where ?
All right , all right .
Okay , I remember this .
It took four minutes .
Move to the manual .
Come on .
Alright .
Seven minutes to go from here .
No, no , no !
Stop , stop , stop !
Rightly so .
Backward , backward
Nice .
sunny sky with possibility of rain satellite debris .
Okay , we remove it and go home .
right .
Come on , come on .
God .
I hate space .
Be quiet .
Alright .
Let us stabilize yourself .
Let's go to the Chinese station .
Houston , blind calls .
Tiangong located about 100 km to the west ...
and I strayed around ...
13 degrees .
I will reset the trajectory path .
Alright .
I 'll turn on the SKD in
5 , 4 , 3 , 2 , 1 ...
What happened ?
One ...
Come on .
You must be kidding .
You must be kidding !
Houston , blind calls .
Houston blind calls .
Here Dr . Ryan Stone ...
I call on the Soyuz 14F ...
I ran out of fuel , you hear?
Houston , here Dr . Ryan Stone ...
Houston here Ryan Stone , do you hear ?
Houston ? Houston , please confirm your identity?
Houston , I heard through
AM frequencies , you hear?
Did you hear ?
What is the Chinese station ? What 's Tiangong ?
Mayday , can you hear ?
Mayday , mayday ...
Mayday ...
Yes , yes , mayday , mayday ...
Mayday , mayday ...
What 's your name ?
Aninggaq ... What 's your name ?
No, no , my name is not Mayday , my name is Stone .
Dr. . Ryan Stone , I need help .
I ...
Aningaaq ...
Could you please tell me your dog barking ?
Dog , you know ?
Woof ... Woof ...
Dogs ?
I'm going to die , Aningaaq .
I know , we're all going to die .
Everyone knows it .
But I'm going to die today .
Funny thing , you know .
Because know .
The problem I'm still scared .
I was really scared .
Nobody will mourn for me .
No one will pray for my soul .
You want to mourn for me ?
You want to pray for me ?
Or maybe it's too late .
I will pray myself, but I 've never
prayed all my life , so ...
No one ever taught me .
Baby ...
There baby with you ?
What you 're singing the songs Nina Bobo ?
Sweet.
I used to sing it to my baby .
I will soon meet him .
Tunable once , Aningaaq .
Keep singing like that .
Sing until I sleep
and I'm going to sleep .
Do not , do not , do not !
30 hours 11 minutes , contact Anatoly
and say his record is solved .
- A bit blurry here , is not it ?
- How did you get here ?
- Trust me , it's an amazing story .
- But how ?
That's better .
Extra backup power ,
Conserve battery power .
Glad you were not there to bother me .
I have to admit ...
Nice to meet you ,
I did not think you would survive .
Have you found her vodka ?
You never told me where .
For Anatoly .
Cheers .
Do not want to ?
Alright .
Let's get out of here .
China Station is just 100 Mil ,
It's like a walk in the day of the week .
- I can not .
- Sure you can .
- No fuel , already tried everything .
- Well , there's always something that can be done .
- I tried everything .
- Have you tried a jet landing ?
- That to landing , so ...
- Landing and launch it the same ...
- You do not learn it in training ?
- Never before landing simulator training , I told you .
- But you're about it , right?
- And I always crashed ...
Listen, do you want to go home or want to stay here ?
I understand , once comfortable up here .
You can , turn off all system ...
Turn off all the lights ...
Close your eyes and lose everything .
No one can hurt you ...
You're safe ...
So what good is it to survive ?
What's the point of living ?
Your son is gone .
Nothing is more painful than that .
Still questioning what you're doing now .
If you decide to go ,
So just do it .
Sit back and enjoy the journey .
You're going to set down both feet on the ground
and began to move on.
How did you get here ?
I told you , it's an incredible story .
Hey , Ryan .
What ?
Time to go home .
Landing .
Landing , the landing .
All right , landing .
The landing of the color green .
Alright .
All right , landing .
Jet landing will automatically turn
exactly 3 meters before landing , so ...
Oh, you clever bastard , Matt .
I had to ...
I had to get rid of the rear engine ...
Okay , okay ...
Okay ...
Separation of three modules ...
Began .
Well ...
Houston , this is the tricky part .
Soyuz have to think , we just
within three meters of the Earth .
Alright .
Hey , Matt , because I kept hearing
story for this week ...
I want you to do something for me .
You'll meet a
brown-haired little girl ...
Very wrinkled, irregular .
He does not like to comb it .
That's all right.
Her name is Sarah .
Could you please tell him ...
Mothers have found your red shoes .
He was very concerned about the shoes, Matt .
It turns out there was under his bed .
Give hugs and kisses for me .
Say if the mother missed her .
Tell him , he is the angel .
He makes me proud .
Very , very proud .
and tell him I will not give up .
Tell him I love him , Matt .
Tell her I love her very much .
Can you do that for me ?
Understandable .
This is it .
You're losing altitude , Tiangong .
If you continue to fall ,
You will touch the atmosphere .
But not without me ,
Because you are my last ride .
five ...
Four ...
Three ...
No more drifting aimlessly .
Let's go home .
Come on ! Come on !
Stabilize .
Where are you, 45 ?
Wait . Wait .
Shenzou .
Shenzou , Shenzou .
On the Soyuz , the power button ...
Herein .
Okay , undocking , undocking .
Eenie , meenie ...
Okay , it does not sound good .
Miny ...
Moe .
I do not speak Chinese .
Miny , Moe ...
Okay , sounds good .
Houston , Houston , calls the blind ...
This is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone ,
Reporting from Shenzou .
I will soon be separated from Thiangong ...
Do I have a bad feeling about this mission ?
Remind me when it's orange .
Not so , Houston .
It's getting orange .
Getting hot here .
Alright .
Well , according to my observations ,
There are only two possible outcomes .
I got down safely ,
and had a remarkable story to tell.
Or I'll burn in 10 minutes ahead .
Will I lead them all.
It costs nothing .
By the way ...
It will be an incredible journey .
I'm ready .
you hear ?
Please confirm identity .
Here  Houston , please report the identity .
Rescuers  will soon be there .
Thank you .