Some people swear there's
no beauty left in the world. No magic.
Then how do you explain the entire world
coming together on one night...
...to celebrate the hope of a new year?
Ready.
Pull!
Ease it off. Ease it. Gently.
Well done, boys. We'll pack up the tarp.
Looks like it's gonna be a beautiful day.
Hello, Your Majesty. Ha-ha-ha.
We wanna see a show of strength...
...from the
New York City Police Department.
Good morning,
this is Ryan Seacrest here in New York...
...where the crowds of revelers are already
beginning to arrive in Times Square.
I'll be coming at you all day on radio...
...and all night live from the center
of it all, so bundle up and stay tuned.
Good morning, Claire!
They need you up here for an interview.
This is Claire Morgan. She's in charge.
Mind giving us a sound bite
for the newscast?
No, I'd be happy to.
I'm talking to Claire Morgan, the new vice
president of the Times Square Alliance.
So big night.
Well, I'd say that's an understatement.
Over a billion people all over the world
will have their eyes on us tonight...
...as the ball drops, so I'd say that
qualifies as a very big night.
Am I looking in the right spot
for camera?
Oh, um...
We're radio.
Right. Of course.
This is 14th and Park.
Oh! Oh! Uhh.
Are you all right, lady? Are you all right?
Here.
No, I'm fine, I'm fine, I'm fine. Go away.
Yeah, what's up, girls? How you doing?
All right?
Yo, I see you, player. Ha.
Oh, oh, hey, Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Yeah, you too.
Sign this, but you can't check in
until tonight.
No problem. We'll be back tonight.
- We're gonna win the money.
- Oh, of course you are.
What money?
Oh, the first baby delivered in the new
year at this hospital gets 25 grand.
No, no, no, honey.
I think it's much less than that.
- No, it's 25 grand.
- Twenty-five grand?
Honey, you're mistaken. It's much less.
Plus, after taxes and all the red tape,
you end up with no money.
Did I mention the news cameras
in your face right after giving birth?
That's horrible. It's not worth it at all.
It's 25 grand. They could put the camera
in my hoo-ha and it'd be worth it.
In your hoo-ha!
In my hoo-ha.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Mr. and Mrs. Byrne?
- That's us.
- Right this way.
Come on, Grace. Let's go home.
Hmm.
Okay. Let's figure out how to induce.
- I will ask the Internet right now.
- By command.
This could pay off my student loan.
Okay, honey, the hallway looks great.
Very festive.
This could be a little higher.
Hand me that tape.
Here you go. It looks beautiful.
You did a nice job.
Why you volunteered to decorate the floor
I'll never know, but it looks great.
Oh, hush up.
Come on, we gotta get dressed for work.
- Let's call in sick.
- Mm.
- Hey, Paul.
- My dog.
- What are we doing tonight?
- You're working.
I'm not. So leave me alone.
Randy, listen to me, don't do this
right now. Don't go into your black hole.
It's midnight on New Year's Eve.
We have to do something.
Not an option.
What, are you still on this anti-New Year's
kick, bro? Get over yourself. Now.
You know what? It's not a kick.
It's a core tenet of my being.
Like I said, I get the day off...
...so I'm gonna hang in our apartment
by myself and do nothing, and love it.
It's my job as your best friend
to just ignore you right now...
...because you sound crazy.
I'm not being crazy!
Okay, I'm gonna find something so epic
that you will not be able to say no.
Hmm.
I got a funny feeling, Paul,
that I'm gonna say no.
You want to throw the challenge flag
in my face? Okay. I'll call you back.
Save your minutes.
Now we're talking.
By the power vested in me
by the state of Connecticut...
...Rory and Trish,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may give kisses to the missus.
My cousin will pay you.
Oh. Congratulations to both of you.
That was just beautiful.
Thank you all for coming.
We wanted to save money
for the honeymoon.
Well, you're the last of us, Sam.
Roam the plains of Manhattan and carry on
the legacy of late-night barhopping...
...and casual sex with random women
in good shoes.
- Which Rory will never know again.
- Mm.
For better or worse, I can see why
the man's crazy about you.
Aww.
I'm out of here.
- You can't stay for breakfast?
- Rain check.
Office has been calling all morning.
I really gotta get back.
- I got that big speech tonight.
- What about the girl?
- What girl?
- The one you met last New Year's Eve?
- Are you gonna meet her tonight?
- It was a year ago. We've moved on.
Hey, look at you two.
All married.
- Here they come!
- Congratulations!
No, no, no. These two. Here.
- All right. I'll see you.
- Bye, Sam.
Hey, there's someone out there
for you too, buddy.
All right.
Okay.
All right. Our first event
with linen napkins.
Not only are we now eco-friendly, but this
will be our biggest A-list party to date.
I know it's cold, okay? But we cannot
mess this up. So you gotta focus.
- Where is Ava?
- She thinks she saw a celebrity somewhere.
There's gonna be more celebrities
here than rehab.
Okay, Sunil, make sure we have
all the booze on this list.
Find Ava and then I'll meet you
in the lobby after I scout the kitchen.
Ava!
- Take a picture with the bus.
- I'm freaking out.
- Ava, there is no time for freaking out.
I can't help it. Do you see that bus?
I saw it when I went to his concert.
It's Jensen!
That's Jensen's bus?
The Jensen?
That's fantastic.
- I love it.
- Aah!
- Ohh!
- Yee!
Keep jumping!
You are very sexy, but don't stop.
Bouncy, bouncy, bouncy!
Now don't be sad
'Cause two out of three ain't bad.
Jensen! Jensen! Jensen!
You know, I know him personally.
Everybody, let's get as much prep
done in the kitchen as possible.
And any sauces that need to get done
can start now.
And I'll check the deliveries
up in the lobby. Oh.
Anyone who can, can you please help Sunil
and Ava unload the truck? That'd be great.
Ay-ay-ay. Laura.
You're not going to believe who is here.
Jensen.
How did you know? Are you psychotic?
It's "psychic." And do me a favor.
If you see him...
...tell him to avoid the blond in
the kitchen with the really big knife.
Ay, Laura, do you know him?
It's good to see you, Laura.
Are you still there?
Do you think Jensen will sign a banana?
I don't have any paper.
All right. Working on those
resolutions, huh?
- No.
- Okay.
I have a delivery here
for Mr. Jonathan Cox.
Do you work here?
No. I work for a courier service.
I've been delivering packages to you
for about, I don't know, a year now.
But I think this is maybe the first time
you've ever looked me in the eye.
How you doing?
Sorry.
That's actually an old resolution.
Make more eye contact.
So those were New Year's
resolutions, huh?
Looks like a long list.
You better get on it.
I don't know, maybe next year.
Whoa. Jeez! Are you serious?
That is a hot ticket.
- Really?
- It's amazing.
They have the best food, the best music.
They got so many single girls.
And it's a masquerade, so you don't even
have to worry about their faces.
You kind of just use your imagination.
If anybody tries to kick you out,
or even asks who you are...
...you just straight-up lie.
What are they gonna do?
It's brilliant.
It's like Facebook, but real.
I remember who you are now.
Right, exactly.
Anyways, I would give my left...
Well, maybe next year.
Oh, there she is.
- You ready?
- Let's go talk to them.
- Hey, Hailey. You good?
- Yeah, we're good, Seth.
All right. Well, let's go, fellas.
We need to scout our pen on 54th
and head home to gear up for tonight.
- I'm gonna see you there, right?
- Yeah, definitely.
- Well, I'll see you there.
- See you.
- Ooh.
- You are so gonna kiss Seth tonight!
I really just, like, haven't even thought
about it at all. It's no big deal.
Do you know how to kiss?
They have a video on the Internet
that shows you.
Two. One for regular kissing,
and one for passionate kissing.
All right, guys. Yeah, I know how to kiss, so it's fine.
It's not a big deal. Okay, we...
Hey, what about your mom?
What's she doing?
Got it!
Oh, and remember, it's just a quarter of an
inch at the center back of the collar, okay?
Okay, let me take a look at that.
Kim, is that your New Year's dress?
Oh, it's just something I'm working on
for a rainy day.
You should wear it tonight.
Maybe you'll scare up a little action.
That's highly doubtful.
The only action I've got is Hailey and me
watching the ball drop at midnight.
Last New Year's Eve she was
with her father. So it's my turn.
- Wanna join us?
- Wow, really tempting.
I don't think you understand.
Hailey likes staying in with me.
All dancers on-stage!
- Go.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Five, six, seven, eight.
- New York.
- New Rochelle.
- New Brunswick.
- New York... New York City.
New Haven.
New Britain.
New Hartford.
New Jersey?
New York!
New York. Turn right.
Left for New York.
Oh! Oh.
Oh, my nose.
Airbags deployed.
The genny truck's not arrived yet.
Will someone tell me why it isn't here yet?
Make sure Jensen's on schedule
for his soundcheck.
He's playing some party,
but this is Times Square.
She's a little on edge today.
Ready for the confetti test.
Brendan.
Good to see you.
I thought you were with your family.
I was, then I realized you wouldn't make it
through the big night without me.
- Wow, I'm really touched.
- Heh.
I'm trying not to say this,
but if I screw up...
- You won't.
- I don't know. I'm not off to a great start.
The generator truck is late.
I mugged for the camera during
a radio interview. Can you believe it?
You'll make it happen.
And you'll make it on time
for your meeting.
- We're not talking about my meeting.
- And why not?
I should've never told you about that.
Look. Come here, lookit.
They're testing the confetti for tonight.
Don't just dump them!
Float them in the wind.
It should be magical.
I'm so glad you're here.
Laura, I know you're upset. All right?
- Mr. Jensen, I play piano.
- I just play.
Thank you, thank you.
- Laura, it's been a year already.
- I have nothing to say to you, Daniel.
- "Daniel."
- She knows Mr. Jensen.
Hello, secrets.
Look at me. Just look at me.
- That was quite a slap.
- I've been plotting that slap all year.
How I would walk up to you
when you least expect it...
...and slap you across the face
for leaving me like that.
And you know what?
It wasn't nearly as satisfying
as I thought it would be.
- Aah!
- Ooh.
- That was closer.
- We're just fooling around.
- I like fooling around too.
- Come back.
I tried to call you.
You never called me back.
I left you tickets, you never showed up.
Talk to me, damn it.
- Just talk to me.
- Just talk to him.
Because it's New Year's Eve,
you want another shot at it?
You walked out on me, Daniel.
I think that says it all.
I didn't even get to make you
one dinner in that apartment.
You walked out before I unpacked
the first bag of groceries.
Celebrities. They're just like us.
Mr. Cox? Is there a reason
you asked me to work today?
- It's your job.
- Of course.
It's just that it's New Year's Eve...
...and I thought maybe you wanted
to give me my end-of-year bonus.
- Seeing that it's the end of the year.
- Oh.
Right. Almost slipped my mind. Mm.
- Glad to remind you, sir.
- Well, unfortunately...
...it has been a tough year
for Ahern Records.
I don't have to tell you.
Music piracy, blah, blah, blah.
Have I got your name right?
Yes, it's just that I wanted to use
my bonus to book a trip.
Well, that might get you to Staten Island.
Maybe next year.
It's just that I already booked
my two weeks' vacation time.
Two weeks? Did I sign off?
You don't need to, sir.
It goes through Human Resources.
No, it goes through me. And I can't do
without you for two weeks.
You can have one week.
Well, then...
...I'll take two weeks...
...and my stapler.
I quit.
You can't quit, it's Grammy season!
I...
I almost died today, sir.
No, no. You look fine.
Can you get me a coffee?
Don't forget the sugar!
Come on, three stars! I need three stars!
Jonathan Cox's office. Please hold.
- Look out!
- Oh, God. No, don't.
I have hated him for leaving me like that.
- No, don't do the egg.
- Then he just shows up...
...on the biggest night of my career!
What kind of karma is that? Huh?
What, that you made love with Jensen...
...or that you're catering
the biggest party in the city?
Because all I'm hearing is good.
- Can I do one?
- Yeah.
- The expensive eggs?
- They feel good.
Oh.
Oh, that was so sissy.
I'm delicate girl.
Dr. Trokin to Radiation Therapy.
- Hey, doc.
- Yes, Mr. Harris.
I haven't asked you for anything, have I?
No. No, you haven't.
No chemo...
...no radiation, nothing that could
give you an extra couple of months.
So then you owe me one.
Sure, Mr. Harris. What do you need?
Did I tell you why I picked this hospital?
Because of the quality of the doctors?
The roof has a great view of the New
Year's Eve ball drop in Times Square.
I heard you say
I was living on borrowed time.
I don't recall telling you that.
I heard you tell the nurses.
I'm dying, I'm not deaf.
Well, you've certainly surprised us,
Mr. Harris.
But be honest, there really isn't anyone
we can notify? No one at all?
The only people who ever cared about me,
I pissed off long ago. There's no one.
Doc, come on.
Call it a dying man's last wish.
Please, come on. I've been hanging on this
long just so I can see the ball drop...
...one more time.
- You know, it's cold out there.
- I'll live.
- You can see it much better on TV.
- I don't wanna see it on TV, doc, please.
As much as I'd like to help you, it's against
hospital policy to allow anyone on the roof.
Just forget it. Forget I asked.
- Okay. If there's anything else you need...
- No, nothing.
- ...just have the nurses page me, okay?
- Yeah.
Okay.
See if you can get him to eat something.
Did he change his mind?
Nope. No treatment,
just palliative meds at this point.
- I guess it's time for hospice.
- No time.
Well, is he gonna make it
until tomorrow?
It's doubtful.
Another thing that chaps my ass about the
holiday season is all the fake niceness.
Like, today I received 50 text messages...
...with a generic "Happy New Year"...
...from people who hit "send"
to their address book.
Most of them I haven't heard from
since last year. Call me back.
Oh, hey, hold the elevator.
- I'm going down.
- Oh, wait, wait.
- Honestly...
- Me too.
Yeah, I tore down the decorations.
According to the lease agreement, you're
not supposed to decorate the hallways.
Not my decorations.
- Yep.
- No, no, no. This can't be happening.
I have somewhere that I need to be.
Hello? Hello? Hello?
- Wait, this thing is dead!
- It doesn't work.
Well, call the super.
He doesn't work either.
- No reception.
- Oh, no.
Oh, you're the new girl from 5B.
Why aren't you more panicked
right now?
Oh, I don't know. I don't really
have anywhere to be.
Hello? Hello, this is 5B! This is 5B!
I'm stuck in this elevator!
I'm gonna be late for work.
False alarm, dear ones.
- But everything's okay, right?
- Oh, everything looks very good.
Hmm...
We close both eyes so that
we may see through the other.
Close them.
No.
Hmm.
Labor could be any day now.
Any day?
Don't worry, I know you wanna have
a very natural childbirth...
...no epidural, no pitocin, we're gonna
use the hypnobirthing techniques.
We were actually just kind of wondering
if we could schedule a C-section.
Just, you know, kind of get this show
on the road, am I right?
- Yeah.
- Uh, we were thinking, um...
...maybe tonight-ish.
Midnight-ish. Uh...
- Right? Griff, right?
- Yeah.
We were both thinking that
maybe tonight could work better.
- If we could do tonight that would be great.
- Tonight?
Hmm.
You want me to come in on New Year's Eve
at midnight and perform a C-section?
Is it New Year's?
- Oh, boy. Weird.
- It is. Yeah.
- I completely just forgot.
- I did too.
- I think with all this.
- Pregnancy brain.
We were never really New Year's people.
We're more Memorial Day people.
Let me be clear.
I will not schedule a C-section
just so you can win some money.
The couple who was in here before
offered to split the winnings with me.
And of course I said no.
Frankly, I'm surprised that you would
even suggest this, Tess.
What if we went 60-40?
- Seventy-thirty.
- Yeah.
You are dangerously close
to a rectal exam.
Oh, that's not good.
Mom, I wanna go to Times Square
to watch the ball drop.
Well, I plan to avoid this entire section
of the city tonight.
Well, I don't want you to stay.
I want you to go home.
- Ouch.
- There's this guy in my history class.
His name is Seth, and I've been hoping...
I have this, like, sick dream that, you
know, we'll get to hang out at midnight.
And then, of course,
I'll come right home.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm just... I'm not comfortable allowing you
to stay in Times Square at night alone.
- Period.
- End of discussion, got it.
Sorry. Come on.
- You know, I'm 15!
- I know, Hailey.
This is not a training bra!
And this is not Girls Gone Wild!
MY gosh.
Mom, you know,
I'm an honors student, okay?
I don't drink or do drugs, and I'm trying
really hard to be the perfect daughter.
- But it's like you don't trust me.
- No, it's not you I don't trust.
Then who do you not trust, Mom?
You don't trust the world?
Or is it just New York
because it's a big scary city?
Have you ever been to Newark?
Look, Mom, the world doesn't scare me,
okay? It's just getting good.
I wanna start living in it.
You used to.
Brady Finley in Times Square.
It's before noon and they're already
predicting record-breaking crowds.
I'm with Miss Morgan.
We're bringing the media to the roof.
Hey. You okay?
- Fine.
- You're not afraid of heights, are you?
- A little.
- Let me be accurate.
You're afraid of heights
and you run the ball drop?
Well, I think it's what makes Claire
the best for this job.
- Let's do that thing we worked out.
- Yeah, let's do that.
- Officer Nolan.
- Yes, sir.
Be careful here.
This is precious cargo, all right?
Make a hole, people.
- Oh.
- Oh, are we all getting picked up?
- Sure.
- No, no, no.
No, no, no.
Okay.
I'm okay. Ha-ha.
Okay. Where were we?
Uh... Oh, the ball.
Since 1907 there's been
a Times Square ball drop.
The first ball was made
of wood and iron...
...and had only 100 25-watt light bulbs.
Okay. Let's light this baby up.
Ready?
- Oh.
- Hey!
- It worked!
- Beautiful.
Okay, so this evening we are gonna raise
this ball to the very top of the pole...
...where it will stay until 11:59.
And then the countdown begins.
Can you fix it?
- No. And don't you want to know why?
Because the complicated machine
behind me isn't called a fix truck.
It's called a tow truck.
That means I put the big hook under the
broken car and take it anywhere you want.
- Which is where?
- New York City.
No again.
Not today and not me. I've got big plans
with my lady friend tonight.
Sign there.
Can you at least tow it
to a mechanic nearby, please?
Nearest mechanic is 10 minutes away.
- Whatever, that's perfect.
- Let me finish.
He's 10 minutes away, but he's closed
today. Everyone's closed today.
I guess you know since you're
dressed like Penn & Teller.
As far as the car goes, you're SOL...
...which means "something out of luck,"
but I don't curse.
I can't be SOL. I've got a big speech
at the company party tonight, okay?
This is very important.
- I've got something important too.
- Like what?
Me and my girl are gonna crush
a 12-pack and watch porn.
- Ms. Withers?
- Oh.
Did you call in a delivery of something?
- Ingrid.
And actually...
...I'm your next job.
I bought you for the day.
Bought me for the day, huh?
Oh, Ms. Withers. I think I should be
offended, but I'm just too intrigued.
My New Year's resolutions.
Mm-hm.
I just took care of the first one.
You quit your job?
- All right.
- If you make these come true by midnight...
...you get these.
For me?
Holy sh...
Whoa. Whoa, okay. Put these down.
Don't flash those around.
Everybody can see them. Seriously.
You called the right guy.
I'm in. Let me see number two.
What is it? Whew.
"Go to Bali. Breakfast at Tiffany's."
You wanna save a life.
Are you kidding me?
Impossible. I don't understand
what you're talking about.
I don't understand what
you want me to do here.
Use your imagination.
We're gonna need a bigger boat.
You know, you don't have to sit like that.
You can put your legs around me,
or you can hold onto me.
No, I'm okay.
All right.
Señor Jensen, I'm here.
And I brought you some enchiladas.
They're very spicy.
Thank you.
Listen, Ava, I was hoping maybe
you could help me out.
What is it? Is it writer's block?
Because if it is, I've been jotting
down these lyrics.
They're in Spanish now,
but I can translate them.
Come, come. Come here.
No, not like that. Really. Just...
Help me convince Laura
that I made a mistake.
- When?
- It was last New Year's Eve.
What did you do to her?
Nothing. I asked her to marry me.
That's beautiful.
But then I got cold feet.
I wasn't ready for it.
That's horrible.
You were the one who proposed.
In my country when a man
gets down on one knee...
...it's because he wants to get married
or he's been shot.
Sometimes it's been because of both.
No, no. It's just that it all came at me
too fast and I wasn't ready for it.
I had to go back on the road,
and I just didn't wanna deal with it.
You should have talked to her.
That's what women like. We like to talk.
I tried. I just can't get a word in
edgewise between slaps.
Do you want to know what I think?
Well, I sure would.
Ay. Hi, Laura.
This is not what it looks like. No.
- No?
- No.
It's not my ex-boyfriend telling our
whole sad saga to my new sous-chef?
Yeah, pretty much that's what it is.
Uh-huh.
- Be strong.
- Mm.
- Hold your ground.
- Yes.
But don't look into his eyes because
they're beautiful. He has, like, a blue...
Bye.
Truce?
Truce.
Breakfast at Tiffany's.
Done.
- Cheers.
Take a New York taxi ride with no traffic.
Done.
Did you hear the new record?
No.
Yeah.
What'd you think?
Ugh. You know, I wanted to hate it.
I really did. But I loved it.
I thought it was great.
Except for the picture you chose
for the cover.
It was a little too much bronzer.
Well, as always, I could've used your help.
I'm a little overwhelmed and frazzled
by this job tonight...
...so I apologize for slapping you.
The second time.
I'm sorry I ran, Laura.
Oh, Daniel.
You sprinted.
I mean...
Laura, can I see you?
I gotta get back to work,
focus on tonight.
What about tomorrow?
We're going back on tour
and I'd love it if you'd come with me.
We could fix this.
Yeah, sure. I'll go pack a bag.
Meet you at the bus?
Come on.
I can't go back on tour with you.
I did your life. I have a life too.
You really don't get it, do you?
What's there to get?
I'm ready to commit.
I'm ready.
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
I'm ready to commit to what I really love:
My work.
I can't do this again with you, Daniel.
Nope. Still no reception.
So how can you have nowhere to be?
Isn't it obvious? New Year's is the worst
night to go out. It's total amateur night.
People who don't drink or go nuts all year
suddenly going all Kanye on you.
It's like a war zone.
Because they have something
to be excited about.
I have something to be excited about.
Oh, oh, oh.
Who were you gonna kiss at midnight?
Oh. And then it's one big giant letdown.
See, that's the problem with New Year's.
Everybody builds up such high expectation that
they're inevitably, utterly disappointed.
Hey, can you get through
that ceiling hatch?
I am not Spider-Man.
Clearly. Clearly.
If I just climb right through there,
get out that window.
And we're gonna be out of here.
I am gonna do it.
Lift me up. Lift me up.
I don't have all day.
There you go.
- Oh.
It's a lock.
Oh, I have a nail file.
I'll file it with my nail file.
I'll file through it.
Ugh. You're a groupie?
Put me down.
I got hats and horns and hazarai.
I got streamers...
- Hey, Marvin. Hi. Happy New Year.
- Hey, Kim.
- Mom, can I go tell my friends?
- Sure, yeah.
Go ahead.
So Hailey and I
are having a party tonight.
Hey, wait up.
- Hey. Um...
- Hey.
I can't come.
What? Hailey, what do you mean?
Half the history class is going.
- I know. It's just my mom won't let me.
- You serious?
I know. I sound like I'm 12, I know.
All right, where's your mom? Maybe I...
- Hi. Hi, Mrs. Doyle.
- Hi.
You look lovely today.
You seem like a nice boy.
I'm just not comfortable with Hailey...
...spending tonight in Times Square
unsupervised.
Right. With all due respect...
supervision is for kids, you know?
We're young adults.
Who are you calling?
- You're Rose Anderson's son, right?
- Yeah.
Yeah, we serve together on your
school's academic booster club.
Oh. You know, I think she left her cell
phone at home. She gonna go out tonight.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Happy New Year.
Yeah. Happy New Year.
You wanna say goodbye?
So?
Hailey, I tried. But she fights dirty.
Yeah, I know. Welcome to my life.
- Bye.
Ladies, let's go. Yo.
Ladies, let's roll out!
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
What is this neighborhood? Is it safe?
Give it a chance.
"Give Paul a chance."
I don't like it here.
Maybe this is a really bad idea.
I'll just give you the tickets.
Give Paul a chance.
Just give me a chance and I'll show you.
What I can do.
Ingrid Withers...
...go to Bali.
It's Bali.
It's Brooklyn.
It's a spa.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. We really can't take you
this early yet.
Dr. Morriset says that you're not ready.
You'll have to come back in a few hours.
We may not have been ready,
but now she's eating anchovies...
...which the Internet claims induce labor.
If only you can keep it down.
Yeah, but it really doesn't go that fast.
- No. I can't do it. I can't do it.
- Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I tried. I can't do it any more.
You need a breath mint.
Hey, Risa. So we are ready
to check in now.
They're checking in?
Hey. Good to see you again.
You must be joking, because inside
I'm laughing really, really hard.
You really think you can come into this
at the last minute and steal our money?
I'm sorry, are you being serious?
You are even a bigger numbnuts
than you look.
This little fish won't save you.
You probably don't even know
that yams can kick-start labor.
Well, yeah, actually, we do.
In fact, at this moment, my wife is
full of yams, but thank you.
Crammed with yams.
Snap. It doesn't.
It stops pre-term labor.
- Did he just snap me in a maternity ward?
- Yes.
You're a really hostile guy.
Where do you work, the DMV?
No, I run a charm school.
Oh, yeah? Where's your charm school,
Guantanamo?
It's on 48th and Madison,
you should come by.
Because you could really
use some charm.
- He actually works at a charm school.
- No way.
Ah. Prince of Charming.
Hello, vision in pink.
Can we check in now?
Well, actually,
the ultrasound says it's a no.
She's not ready either,
so you'll all have to come back later.
I'm sorry, James.
It's not your fault.
- I'm sorry too.
- Right.
- Also, it's on now, Prince Charming. Yeah.
- You bet.
What are you doing, honey?
Oh, it's on.
- I'm sorry?
- Oh, no.
What's on?
Oh, yeah, this?
- It's on.
- Come on. Let's go, honey.
Nobody wins when pregnant women fight.
Come on. Come on.
Something's on. Heh-heh.
I know you gave up your
own plans tonight just to be with me.
I can't become your everything, Mom.
Please don't become a Piper's mom.
A what? "A Piper's mom"?
What, you mean like Joanna?
Yes, Piper's mom.
She hides in the bushes every day...
...just to make sure that Piper
goes to school. It's nuts.
- Come on. I'm not that bad.
- Mom, you've stopped trying.
You're being clingy and mean,
because you don't have a man in your life.
You really gotta find somebody.
Look, Mom, you're a hot woman.
If you'd just, you know,
lose the clogs, maybe?
I'm sorry, but I am trying.
And I would like you to try.
Just have our New Year's party.
- And toot-toot, Happy New Year!
- Okay. Mom! Mom! No more.
I'm over it.
I'm over it and I'm over you.
Why are we at the church? You were
supposed to take me to the rental car shop!
Hey, James Bond,
I need one more signature.
For what?! What am I even signing for?
So you can get your car back.
Right there. Initials.
Keep the pen, it's got my name on it.
Didn't I tell you that
all the rental places close at 3?
I've got you covered.
There's your ride right there. Hey, Edwin.
Hey, Harley. Hey, Sam.
Hey, he's the pastor.
Yeah, that's right. It's the earmuffs.
- So my cousin here tells me you need a lift.
- Cousin?
I'm taking my wife and kids to see the Radio
City Rockettes. We do it every New Year's.
Ever seen the Rockettes? Tch-tch.
Happy to give you a lift.
You want to pitch in for gas?
- Hell, yeah. I'll pay for all the gas.
- Don't say "hell," he's a pastor.
Show him the book.
Give me my pen back.
I'll never understand people with hair.
Thank you, Harley.
There she is.
How much gas are we talking about?
What's your credit-card limit?
ICU, how can I help you?
Hi, Mr. Harris.
How you doing today?
Right.
You've been here for weeks.
First no radiation, now no chemo. Why?
What's the difference, you know?
Why delay the inevitable? I don't know.
When I was a photographer in Vietnam,
I'd see death all the time.
Nothing prepared me for this.
I promise I'm gonna make you
as comfortable as I can, okay?
Just get me to midnight and we're even.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Honey? I've been thinking.
Hailey?
I fought so hard for custody.
Hey, I got hats here!
What do you need? Yo! Scarves, hats!
Happy New Year! Here, pick a hat.
Go ahead.
Keep walking, then. Go ahead.
Marvin!
- Kim!
- Hailey!
- Up.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, yo. Happy New Year!
Poppers, streamers, horns!
Hailey!
Calling you.
Hey, it's Hailey.
Leave me a message
and I'll try and get back to you.
I think she decided.
- You got a hat.
- You got a dog.
Oh, it's a big responsibility.
Yeah, but you gotta give it a chance.
Give it a chance, right?
We'll give him his shots.
You can pick him up Monday.
Or you can wait and think about it.
No.
- I'm done waiting.
- Yeah!
We're gonna make each other
very happy. Aren't we?
What are we gonna name him?
- Um...
- Something manly like Kong.
How about Mr. Snugglepuss?
"Snugglepuss"?
You can decide on a name later.
Anyways, look what you just did.
Saved a life. Check.
Take a trip around the world.
It's a bit of a cheat. But check.
It's 6:00 here in Times Square.
And now to host tonight's festivities,
Mr. New Year's Eve himself:
Ryan Seacrest!
Thank you very much.
Hello, New York City!
I'm Ryan Seacrest.
Are you ready to see the Times Square
ball being raised?
We've been joined by several
members of the Times Square Alliance...
...as they get ready for the ball drop.
I know you're nervous,
but you have to look up, Jeffrey.
Here we go!
Uh-oh.
That's not supposed to happen.
Sorry, friends,
we have a bit of a hiccup here.
We'll just sort that out, no problem.
Stay with us, we'll be right back, okay?
We will have it up and running
momentarily, right?
Yeah. It's... There's...
- Please? Please.
- Yes.
I'm starting to feel a little bit of pressure.
Pressure's not great to feel.
And it messes with my hair.
And I need my hair to be up. Like the ball.
Go, guys, go. We gotta fix this
by midnight. Go, go, go.
Whew. This would never have happened
to Dick Clark.
- Can't you show me one special trick?
- I'm not a magician.
- Okay?
- Are you in the Secret Service, mister?
Duncan.
So, what's the speech about, Sam?
Like I said, I haven't even written it yet.
I guess I'm still looking for
the inspiration.
What inspires you, Sam?
- Pizza.
- Excellent.
Sweet.
Okay, thanks.
Welcome to the Queens Museum...
...featuring the New York City miniatures
depicting all five boroughs.
Walk all five boroughs in one day.
Crossing that off the list.
Yo, Randy, I know you said you didn't
wanna come out tonight, but listen.
I made a deal with this lady
for four tickets to Ahern's VIP party.
I don't know what her deal is, man.
She's just...
...like, a couple sandwiches
short of a picnic. You know?
Like a little bit pathetic.
In, like, a cute way.
So, dude, please, please
call me back, bro.
I need you. I need my wingman
at this party. Hit me back, bro.
Okay. All right, next up...
...is to be amazed.
Which is very vague.
I will be amazed if I can come up
with something. But I will.
I don't wanna do this any more.
What are you talking about?
I'm pathetic...
...dude.
Hey.
Wait, where are you going?
Staten Island.
- Miss Morgan, we're not sure what's wrong.
- How long will it take to be sure?
I don't know. A couple minutes,
a couple hours, maybe more.
We don't have a couple of hours.
We only have midnight.
I have one job tonight. To make sure...
...even if I have to do it with my own two
hands, that ball descends at midnight.
You can't move midnight.
Why are you looking at your shoes?
You're not telling me something.
What are you not telling me?
We need Kominsky.
The Kominsky?
Tess?
Tess? You in the bathroom?
What are you doing?
Yoga. It's supposed to help.
I'm no expert, but seems like that would
send the baby in the wrong direction.
Let me help you.
Oh...
- Did you get it?
- Yeah.
And I got a discount
with my vet school ID.
You'll make such a good
veterinarian someday.
Thanks. And if you were a horse,
I'd know what to do.
Of course, if you were a horse,
we'd never get invited to dinner parties...
- ...and I'd be married to a horse.
- Ha-ha-ha.
This smells awful.
- Drink it.
- Mm-mm.
What? It's castor oil.
Mary Poppins swore by this.
Mary Poppins also danced
with cartoon penguins.
You first.
You're a coward.
- Mm. Mm.
- Hmm. I'm sensing a thumbs down.
Ugh. Mary Poppins sucks.
Well, you forgot about
the spoonful of sugar. Ooh.
- What was that?
- What was what?
Oh, my gosh. My water broke.
- All of it?
- Oh.
Well, what do you think?
Well, that's too early.
Can you turn it off?
- And how do you suggest I do that?
- Yoga?
Get upside down. You can do a downward
dog or an upward dog. Do one of the dogs.
- Okay, we need to pack!
- We have packed.
- Okay, calm.
- Taxi!
- I don't think we're gonna get one up here.
- Right, we gotta go where the cars live.
- Pants, I need pants.
- Okay.
These are your pants.
Give me the cute pink ones.
Don't throw them at me.
Okay, so I'll meet you there?
You should come with me.
- We should both go.
- Oh...
Lady with a baby coming through.
Taxi! Pregnant! Taxi!
Okay. Want me to help?
Honey, I spent my whole life
living in New York City.
I think I know how to get a taxicab.
- Yeah.
- No! No!
Hah. Good job, homeboy.
All right. Plan B. Hold this.
- Ch!
Be here now.
Taxi!
You're doing great, honey.
- You're doing great.
- Oh!
Can't we pedal faster?
- Hey, buddy, can you go a little faster?
- This is my faster.
Haven't you been here all day?
- When do you go home?
- Just before midnight.
Ah.
You know what, I don't care about
all that hoopla and stuff anyway.
So no big plans? A party or...?
Nope.
No hot date? Pretty girl like you.
Well...
...maybe.
But right now you're my hot date.
- Why?
- Pardon me?
Why would you wanna be nice to me?
I'm an ass.
I spent my entire whole life being an ass.
And I don't know how to stop.
Well, you know what, Stan?
Maybe being an ass is the reason you've
gotten every single thing you ever wanted.
Not everything.
I'm sorry I called you a groupie.
We're stuck in an elevator together.
You're not gonna talk to me at all?
Fine. We can talk.
But as long as we're making
assumptions about each other...
...why don't I give it a shot?
You grew up in suburban
fill-in-the-blank.
You went to la-di-da liberal-arts school.
You didn't have enough drive
to get a real job...
...and then you grew half a beard...
...and moved to Manhattan
on your grandmother's inheritance.
And now you think that just because you
moved somewhere that makes you cool...
...but the truth is,
is that it doesn't. Okay?
Because you're just some wannabe
hipster who judges everything...
...because you're too scared
to take a chance on anything.
And, you know, my guess is that
this whole hatred for New Year's...
...comes from some
boring-as-hell prom queen...
...who broke your heart on New Year's Eve
in high school. So, what, am I close?
Suburban Maryland.
Tufts University.
And I am a comic-book artist.
You draw?
I illustrate.
And it was in college...
...when she broke it.
And this beard took me
like a year to grow.
Cold coffee?
Last year there were so many speeches,
I had to get outside.
So I actually went out
and got a pizza. Heh.
Did anything else happen?
Oh, my. Something else did happen,
didn't it?
- Yes.
- Is it R-rated?
Dad.
- I met a woman...
- Oh.
...and she was extraordinary.
It's gonna have a goosebump ending.
Take your time telling it,
because here comes the traffic.
Extraordinary build, huh?
I have to get to this party.
Welcome to the Brooklyn Museum and
the Ahern party. Please pull right up, sir.
Put on 'em ball
When they sleep at the Macy's.
Penny. Penny. Just quick one picture.
Right over here!
Tied over money like Seacrest
Put it on my life, baby.
I can make you feel right, baby.
- Excuse me.
But I might drink a little bit
More than I should tonight.
And I might take you home with me
If I could tonight.
You're an actress, right?
Yeah. I've played a nurse, a cop,
a teacher.
How about playing a waitress
and getting me a drink?
Go ahead. Scoot, scoot.
And now, your hostess...
...the president of Ahern Records,
Mrs. Rose Ahern.
Welcome to the Ahern Records
Masked Ball.
What better way to end this year,
both good and bad...
...than with the very, very best...
...and you all know exactly who
I'm talking about.
So I'll simply say that coming up
on this stage very soon...
...one of the hottest names
Jensen!
I went to Juilliard...
...and I am a backup singer.
Not a back-of-the-tour-bus groupie.
- Randy, a.k.a. Mr. Moron.
- Heh.
- How long you been a backup singer?
- Too long.
Oh, I just got hired for tonight...
...but I was hoping that he would ask me
to go on tour with him. But...
You could sing something for me.
Oh, no. Ha-ha-ha. No.
The only time that I do performances for
audiences of one is when I'm in the shower.
- Well, you...
- Don't say anything.
Anxiety is now the prevailing mood
here at One Times Square.
The ball is still in a state of stuck.
...As officials await the arrival of
electrical whiz Lester Kominsky.
Oh, I'm sorry, I don't speak Spanish.
I'm from Ohio.
- Your coffee.
- Thank you.
The eagle has landed.
- Kominsky's here.
Make a hole, people. Move.
Kominsky.
I'm Claire Morgan.
Oh, no. Kominsky.
- Kominsky's here, yes.
- Yes.
Oh. Thank you so much for coming.
Yes, it's good.
- You fire me.
- No, no. No, that was someone else. No.
So, what do you think it is?
- Short.
- What's short?
A short in the ball.
You got it.
- Sounds pretty straightforward.
- Mm-hm.
Easy to fix.
- Then you fix.
- No.
Not so easy.
This ball has 3500 lighting clues.
Cues. He means cues.
You have to find the light
that went out in over 3000?
- Mm-hm.
- Wh...?
Have we not progressed past the Christmas
lights that go out if there's one bad one?
My question also and then I get fired,
so that's all.
Oh, wait. We need you.
I need you.
Okay. Then I go visit my ball
on the roof. And...
These TV peoples here?
- Yes.
- Oh.
Here.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Good. Thank you.
Please enjoy our New Year's Eve
entertainment...
...as we go to Ginger Adams and some
young revelers in the 54th Street pen.
Ginger.
This little boy is lost.
Go with the nice lady.
- What's your name?
- Scott. I can't find my mom.
Whoa! Who lost this kid?
I did, I did.
I'm coming, Mom.
- I got him.
- Take it easy.
- Be careful.
- Whoa, thattaboy.
Watch it!
Mom, look at me.
I got him. I got him.
Hey, is she here?
I haven't seen Piper's mom,
but I know she's around here somewhere.
- Who are you gonna kiss at midnight?
- You, baby.
I'm flattered, but I'm also spoken for.
We now go live to New Year's headquarters
for an update on the situation.
Hello, I'm Claire Morgan
of the Times Square Alliance...
...and, as you all can see...
...the ball has stopped halfway
to its perch.
It's suspended there to remind us...
...before we pop the champagne
and celebrate the new year...
...to stop...
...and reflect on the year
that has gone by.
To remember both our triumphs
and our missteps.
Our promises made and broken.
The times we opened ourselves up
to great adventures...
...or closed ourself down
for fear of getting hurt.
Because that's what New Year's
is all about.
Getting another chance.
A chance to forgive.
To do better, to do more,
to give more, to love more.
And to stop worrying about
"what if"...
...and start embracing what will be.
So when that ball drops at midnight...
...and it will drop...
...let's remember to be nice
to each other.
Kind to each other.
And not just tonight, but all year long.
Thank you.
I want to hear the rest of your story.
We talked for... It felt like hours.
- You boink her?
- Dad.
- You're talking to a man in a tuxedo.
- I can't talk like that in front of a lady.
- He's a gentleman.
- We talked, all right?
I went on and on about the business
and how our stock had just gone public.
She stops me, she puts her hand
over mine and she says:
"That's all great, but how's your heart?"
"How's your he...?" Who says that?
- I mean, I never met anyone that said that...
- Please. Please.
Did you at least kiss her?
Yes. At midnight.
And that's it?
Well, I went to the restroom a little
bit later and when I came back...
- ...she was gone.
- Oh.
- She left something on the table.
- Naked picture?
Let me see.
Read it out loud, Maude.
"Things are complicated.
If you're still thinking about me
in a year...
...meet me back here
at La Gambina Trattoria...
- ...at midnight next New Year's Eve."
- Midnight next New Year's Eve.
You memorized it.
You're gonna meet her, aren't you?
Yeah, I don't think so.
I mean, I don't even know her name.
You're afraid.
She's not gonna be there.
It was one night. It wasn't even real.
But this napkin is. And you've been
carrying it around for a year.
I mean, you went out
for a slice of pizza...
...and you may have run into the one.
You know what that is?
- Insanity?
- Not insanity.
Serendipity. Hmm?
- And you don't mess with serendipity.
- What's the worst that could happen?
She doesn't show up,
you go back to your party.
Oh, that's not it at all, is it, Sam?
You're afraid that she will show up.
I'll tell you what.
I'll take care of this for you.
- I can tap this.
- He can tap this.
I'm gonna step up and tap this for you.
Look, I'm a widower.
- Right?
- Forgive him.
- Hey, sis.
- Have you heard from Hailey?
- Calm down. What, is she AWOL?
- Yes.
It's New Year's Eve. She's a teenager.
She's being her mother's daughter.
- Can you hold on for one second?
- Yeah, sure.
I can't see.
I was never that defiant.
I mean, you should've seen
the way she looked at me.
I'm confused.
I thought you had plans tonight.
I sort of did.
But I chose to be with Hailey...
...and now she's gone.
I'm not really worried about Hailey.
I'm more worried about you.
If you're not working...
...you need to have some fun. Let your
hair down. Leave the clogs at home.
Oh, great, more clog commentary. Ooh.
Goodness. I'm so sorry, sir.
Listen, Paul, right now, all I really
need to do is just find Hailey.
All right, look.
She's a good kid, okay?
If she did happen to call her cool uncle
to say where she'd be...
...she may, in fact, have said
the 54th Street pen.
But please don't rat out the cool uncle.
Paul, thank you. Thank you so much.
Thank you. Excuse me.
Wait, wait! Sis, hold on.
- I got a huge favor to ask.
- Anything. What, what, what? What?
"Be amazed."
I got it.
Ingrid, please don't let this
whole thing be ruined...
...because I'm a big-mouthed idiot.
I'm sick and tired of being that guy.
Please, Ingrid.
Please.
Come with me.
Come on! Let's go.
On one condition.
- Whoo!
- Yeah, there you go.
Here we go!
- See? All right, right turn. Lean into it.
- Aah!
Lean, lean, lean.
That was a nice speech.
- Well, I was just trying to save my job.
No, I don't think so.
I think you were talking about you.
Okay, maybe I was,
but all I can do is reflect...
...and try and do better next year.
Or sooner.
Now, why'd I tell you about him?
I'm a New York cop.
People, they tell me things.
I'm sure he's forgotten it by now.
You should go.
I don't move until the ball moves.
This is so exciting.
In my entire life,
I have never won a contest before.
And I'm also excited about the baby.
I think that's the most exciting thing.
- Anchovy man.
- Yam liar.
- Grace, I'm gonna sign us in, okay?
- I'll just be right back.
- Griffin Byrne, checking in.
- Schwab, very proud to check in this hotel.
I'm sorry about James.
He's very competitive.
Well, I should apologize too.
I really didn't mean that anything was on.
Ooh.
- Contractions?
- Six minutes apart.
We have five minutes apart.
- Cervix?
- She has one.
- Four centimeters dilated.
- Four? We are five... Six... Seven!
Maybe eight.
Don't you show your head to me
young lady!
Not yet! Papa will tell you
when it's time, okay?
- Oh, please don't yell at my vagina.
- Oh, I never will.
It's amazing.
She really listens to James.
She just crawled right back up in there.
The nurses will take you to your rooms.
Gentlemen, to your corners.
And, ladies, may the best va-jay-jay win.
Good luck.
- Let's see it. Ha-ha-ha.
- Let's see it.
La la la
Okay. Okay. Okay. I'll sing.
- You don't like my voice?
- You draw. I'll sing.
Laura, can we take a break?
Jensen's going on in a minute.
Do you want to go see?
No. I'm a professional,
I can't be seen gawking at the talent.
Well, I'm gonna gawk.
Ahh. I'm gonna try to get close to
the stage to get spit and sweat on.
When the road gets dark
And you can no longer see
Let my love throw a spark
And have a little faith in me
And when the tears you cry
Are all you can believe
Just give these loving arms a try, baby
And have a little faith in me
Have a little faith in me
'Cause I've been loving you
For such a long time, girl
Expecting nothing in return
Just for you to have a little faith in me
You see, time
Time is our friend
'Cause for us, there is no end
All you gotta do
ls, baby, have a little bit of faith in me
I said, I will hold you up
I will hold you up
I will hold you up now
All you gotta do
ls have a little faith in me
You see, time is our friend
Oh, baby
Have a little faith in me
All right, let me see.
Let me see.
That's me?
I look crazy.
- Do you have any other hobbies?
- Ha-ha-ha.
Hey.
There you...
You're so good.
You always were.
I'm not really that good.
Yes, you are. Yeah.
I was thinking about the ball drop...
...and how that always
used to be our thing.
Remember when I took you to New York
for the first time?
We watched the ball drop together?
You remember?
That was our night.
And I promised you we'd bring...
We would go back there...
Well, another promise I didn't live up to.
I'm sorry.
Now, why did I leave you?
Stan, I'm Aimee.
Remember? Nurse Aimee?
Hmm?
Oh. Right.
Right. Aimee.
Call me back or I'm gonna give away
your ticket. I'm gonna give it away.
Paul, it's me, Murray. Are we ready to go?
Let's go!
Ladies and gentlemen,
one-night-only engagement.
Radio City Music Hall is proud to present,
on her resolution tour:
Ingrid Withers!
Just hear those sleigh bells jingling.
Ring-ting-tingling too
All right.
- Oh, my God. Whoo!
- Bravo!
Bravo!
Are you amazed?
I'm amazed you got me to do this!
Amazing!
"Be amazed"? Check.
Come on, it's lovely weather
This is great.
This is great. Okay.
Okay. Let me down now.
We've been stuck in here for hours.
I can't believe nobody's found us yet.
- We could have our own party.
- Hmm.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, come on!
We got to do something to get you
out of your New Year's Eve funk.
We're at a party.
Mm.
You're standing on one end of the room
alone, and I'm on the other.
- We've never met.
- Ooh.
And the countdown begins.
You start scanning the room
for cute girls...
...amongst the sea of couples.
- Cute girls.
- Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Finally, you see me.
- Our eyes meet.
- There you are.
We smile tentatively at each other.
- Six.
- Tentatively.
Then we start walking
towards each other.
Five.
Finally, we meet.
Four.
Just as it's about to be midnight.
- Three.
- Two.
One.
Oh.
- Hey!
- Now you come.
Hmm.
See, I told you I'd have it fixed.
In just eight hours.
Phone's broken.
Hey, you didn't, uh, you know...
That's not why we put the bench in.
Oh, no, no. It's not like that.
Yeah, it's always like that.
- This was not like that.
- Oh, it's always like that.
- We just met on...
- All right. I'll check out the video.
Okay.
All right! Come on in.
- Looks like you still might make your gig.
- Yeah.
So Jensen's playing at Times Square?
Yeah. With or without me,
so I should really get going.
Okay.
- See you.
- Yeah. Happy New... Uh...
I'll see you.
Uh...
Let me...
Sorry.
Hold the elevator.
Sorry. Let me just...
This gate is a bitch.
- Mrs. Lifflander, you've been working out.
- Thank you.
Hey, you forgot"!
Oh, this is amazing,
I can totally see him.
What?! He's coming out?
You can see him?
Okay, if you try to see, I can't see.
Look with your other eye!
Oh, hostility, that's good.
Yes, now we're getting somewhere.
I can't see the baby. I can see that couple
trying to steal our money.
Oh, this is great, babe.
So, look, if I do this, that means
they're having their baby.
I don't care about the money any more.
What?
- Hey, Griff?
Come here.
- You are disturbing her calm zone.
- You're disturbing my calm zone.
What? Uhn.
I need you to focus.
I'm just trying to squeeze a giant Escalade
out of a compact fucking parking spot!
Nice.
Swearing helps sometimes.
But now we're gonna use our words, right?
- We're ready to go.
- Uh...
Bye, I love you.
- Time to take the children to the playroom.
- Come on, guys.
Next time I see you, you're gonna
have a baby sister. I love you.
- Bye, Mommy.
- Bye.
- A lobster?
- Yeah.
Dissolve.
Assuage.
Very good. You are the channel.
I am the perfect channel.
- Perfect channel.
- Ooh...
Okay.
- Change the channel. Change it!
Mm-hm.
Click, click, click.
- Watch it.
- What happened to the steps there? Hey.
It's been a real treat getting to know you
and the family. Grandpa Jed.
Very cool, very horny.
You got a chance to see how
the other half lives, huh?
You make the other half look good.
Ah. You seem to have a pretty fun life.
It has its moments.
- Remember, follow your heart.
- All right, I will. I'll see you.
- You have to let me in!
- I'm sorry.
You need a pass to get back there.
I'm practically related to him.
We're both from Jersey.
- Is this the 54th Street pen?
- 56th. 54th is that way.
- You have to let me in.
- Without a pass, I can't.
Hailey's coming.
- Yeah.
We're getting closer, folks.
Hope you're staying warm.
This is it. This is as close to
the ball dropping as I can get you.
Hey, good luck with that last one,
all right?
No.
- I figured that was a long shot.
- A long shot? What are you talking about?
Going to Bali? That was a long shot.
Let's get this out of here, okay?
Man, I don't even know whose
this is, bro. I'm just saying.
Thanks.
Make a list of your own.
Don't wait as long as I did.
Pow, pow, shwing.
Thank you. Mm.
Good bye.
- Have a great time.
- You too. Happy New Year, Ingrid.
Whoo.
Any ideas who you might
want to kiss at midnight?
Oh.
- Hey, Laura!
- Ha-ha-ha.
- They're raving about the food out there.
- Great.
I hear this is a first for
the music industry.
Sam's here.
- He is.
Sam!
- Oh, hey, Alyssa.
- I'll get your favorite drink?
- Thank you.
Hey, Mom.
Sorry I'm late.
But I made it.
Thank you for wearing
your father's tuxedo.
- Perfect fit, huh?
- You look so handsome.
Hey there, iPod. How are you?
All your pretty little girls are here.
I'm starting to think I need more...
...than a pretty a girl with nothing
to say, you know?
Did maturity just walk into the room?
Well, maybe, maybe not.
You know what you're gonna say
to these people?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Coming up next on the main stage,
Ahern Records recording artist, Jensen!
- Where's Jensen?
- Still waiting on him.
But the president of the Times Square
Alliance would like a word.
- Mr. Buellerton's here?
- He's right here.
Mr. Buellerton. You wanted to see me?
Yes, Claire.
You spoke eloquently about the ball
getting stuck.
- You assuaged everyone's fears.
- Thank you.
- Except mine.
- Oh, of course.
Now, I like assuagion, but I don't
think you realize what's at stake.
Oh, I do, sir.
You're about to let down
the city of New York...
...the country, the whole world,
unless you get that ball fixed.
With all due respect, sir, I've been watching
the ball drop since I was 5 years old...
...and it's one of my most favorite
family memories.
We'll... We'll be sure to get this fixed.
"We'll"? "We'll"?
You remember the '86 Mets-Red Sox
World Series?
No.
Bill Buckner let a ground ball
go between his legs...
...and the Sox lost the game,
and eventually, the World Series.
Now, very few people remember
who was on the field that day...
...but everyone remembers
that Buckner missed the ball.
A baseball's a lot smaller than your ball,
which is not dropping.
Right. I'll be sure that I don't drop
the ball on the ball drop.
- Whatever you said. Anyway, fix it.
- I will.
Or you'll hear a speech about the new vice
president of the Times Square Alliance.
Okay. I'm not gonna let you down,
or the world. I promise, sir.
Um, okay, I'm gonna check on Kominsky.
You find Jensen.
Somebody get me Jensen!
- Hey, sorry I'm late.
- Okay. Who are you?
I'm Elise, one of Jensen's
backup singers.
Where's Jensen?
I don't know.
Go take the stage. That way, that way.
- Where is he?
- Still no rock star.
Hey! 5B! Hi.
- Hey. Hi. Randy.
How'd you get in?
They think I'm Jensen's drummer.
Because I told them that.
Here. You left this on the elevator.
I didn't know if it was lucky or something.
And also it's a balance thing.
So if you dance while you're singing,
you'll need your balance.
Thanks.
You came all the way here to bring me
my rubber bracelet?
Sort of.
And to say happy New Year.
Happy New Year, Randy.
Oh, you also left something else
on the elevator.
Glad you remembered that.
Background singers report to stage.
I gotta go. Ha-ha.
Okay, well, go watch.
- For you, I will be your groupie.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Hey! Nice pajamas.
Background singers report to stage.
Keep them busy. Try doing the wave.
If Jensen doesn't show up,
you're gonna sing.
- Jensen's here.
- Where?
- He's not happy.
- Oh. Why would he be?
Mr. Jensen, hi.
What seems to be the problem?
Yeah, I saw your speech on TV today.
I'm Claire Morgan.
I'm the one that hired you.
Hi. Boy meets girl...
- ...boy screws up, boy loses girl.
- Oh.
Um... ls there any way I can help you?
I don't think so.
Well, it is New Year's Eve.
Anything's possible.
Not this time.
I think I really screwed it up.
I don't think I deserve a second chance.
You know what that feels like?
Actually, I do.
I have the same situation
going on right now.
Um...
Maybe all this is too much for her, huh?
I don't know. Maybe...
Maybe all she wants is to not have to
share you with the rest of the world.
Sounds familiar.
- We girls, we have a handbook.
- Miss Morgan.
Um... Well, I need to go fix the ball,
and you need to fix what you broke too.
But will you please sing first?
Please.
And don't forget, second chances,
they don't expire until midnight.
Okay?
Thanks.
You rock.
- Ha-ha.
- I'm a big fan.
Thank you.
Goodbye, 2011!
New Year's wave!
Hi. I am Sam Ahern, Jr.
I won't give a long speech.
Socrates gave long speeches
and his friends killed him.
In the past, my father would
always kick things off...
...and then turn it over
to the vice presidents...
...but as you know,
Dad's not with us any more.
I think that anybody that knew him
knows that he was a great man.
And we're thinking
about you tonight, Pops.
He always ended with a quote.
He would say, "What would you do today
if you knew you would not fail?"
And then he'd say,
"Now go out and do it."
You know where he got that from?
My mother, Rose Ahern.
All right, let me finish with this.
As we move forward into this new year...
...let's try to remember that
sometimes it's okay...
...to listen to your heart.
I know it's risky.
Take that leap of faith.
Happy New Year, everybody.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
All right, let's do this.
Ladies and gentlemen, Jensen!
Come here! Why don't you have one on?
Come on!
I can't turn you loose now
If I do I'm gonna lose my life
I'm never turning you loose now
If I do I'm gonna lose my mind
I can't turn you loose to nobody
'Cause I love you baby
Yes, I do now
Hip-shaking mama, I told ya
Oh, honey, I'm in love with you now
It's okay. They got it.
I wanna give you everything
That you want
Gotta, gotta, gotta
Keep on lovin', baby
Never gonna turn you loose
I gotta keep on
Huh!
After.
Okay, almost. One more test.
One more test, my darling. Okay.
I get this wire here.
Uh...
I got it!
I put new one inside! Okay, baby!
- Mwah!
- Does it work?
Flip switch!
I'm flipping. I'm flipping up.
It's working.
It's going up. It's going up!
Hang on, Kominsky!
Tell Miss Morgan it's working.
He's got it!
Wait, wait! Get me down first!
First, down!
Coming down! Flipping down!
Way to go, buddy!
Mr. Kominsky, tell us, how does it feel?
Well, it feels okay.
Everyone talking at me.
Wade said the mayor called.
- He wants you to come down there.
- Now?
He thought what you said
a lot of us needed to hear.
Tell Mayor Bloomberg I'd love to.
But I have another pressing matter
that needs attending.
- Mr. Kominsky?
- Yes.
As a reward for 37 years of service...
...before being temporarily
relieved of your duties...
...I officially hereby leave you in charge.
What took so long?
Thank you.
Watch him like a hawk.
You got it. Let me find Nolan
to give you a lift, though.
Officer Nolan's right here.
Hi.
Hi, Tanya.
Go see your daddy.
Hey, baby.
Hi, Daddy.
My little rugrats.
Heard you need a lift.
No. In a car.
Yeah, we have cars too.
Happy New Year, Brendan.
Happy New Year, Claire.
Ah... Alyssa, thank you.
Your favorite, Disaronno and cranberry.
Um... I'm off at 1.
- I will keep that in mind.
- Okay.
Hey, Sam.
- Wendy! How are you?
- Great.
- You look fantastic.
- Thanks.
Sam?
- Patty.
- I'd love to be the woman behind you.
And I'd love to be in front.
Oh. I'm a Sam-wich.
- How's everything? Okay?
- It was wonderful.
- It was delicious.
- Thank you.
I have to say that he was
absolutely right.
The food is sublime.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
That's great to hear.
Who was right?
Jensen. He told us that we had to hire you
or he wouldn't sing tonight.
Ah.
I'm gonna recommend you to everyone
I know, and, honey, I know a lot of people.
Thank you.
I'll give you my new condo number
and my new cell.
You ran out on us last New Year's.
Do you remember that?
Here you go.
Fun.
You know what? I'm sorry.
I can't do it. I gotta go.
I'm sorry.
Make a hole, people!
Stan.
It's just me, Aimee.
Please go.
I don't want you to see it happen.
No, I'm not gonna leave you alone.
He's not alone.
Hi, Daddy.
Hey. Kiddo.
Hey, kid.
Did we miss it?
Ball hasn't dropped yet.
You're really here.
Yeah.
Well, my shift is up.
- Have a happy New Year, Aimee.
- Thank you.
- How about some holiday cake?
- Nope. Don't need it.
Dessert is now being served.
Chocolate truffles.
This is working!
- I'm gonna grab some more parachutes.
Okay. We'll keep throwing.
Throw it at the pretty ones!
I really would like to speak with you
about Miss Pearlman.
She's not doing too well today.
She has a high fever, but he didn't
really leave any more orders.
So we really would like you to come in
and take a look at her.
Thank you, bye.
- So, what do you think?
- Wow.
Somebody's gonna have
a happy New Year.
I sure hope so.
Ha-ha.
- Aimee, Aimee!
Come here. Quick, quick.
- Mr. Harris isn't in his bed.
- I know.
- So should I look for him?
- No. It's okay.
You look hot.
I can do this.
Hang in there, babydoll.
We made it on time.
- It's our thing.
- Yeah.
You want me to put you
on my shoulders?
Wowee-wow.
Where in the world is
the rest of that dress?
New Year's is all about the dress.
You said that we could change
before dessert.
There's nothing wrong
in show a little something.
Trust me, but there's nothing little
about those.
- What, did one fell off?
- No, no. They didn't fall off.
They are still there.
You look great. Perfect, in fact.
You mind taking these
parachutes upstairs?
- Okay.
- Thank you.
You're going out there
to celebrate with us?
No. I'll just hang here.
No, it's fine. I'm good.
Okay, I take the parachutes.
Thank you.
Dr. Steam, to the Ira Keenan lounge.
Hi.
What do you think?
Oh, I love it, I love it.
You look so beautiful
I think I need to be there.
Ha-ha. I think I wish you were.
Hi, baby.
How've you been?
I'm okay.
The guys are all watching
Times Square on TV right now.
I tell them I'm better off.
I'm watching you.
I miss you so much.
I miss you too, baby
I do.
But you know what?
This is gonna be a great new year...
...because you're coming home
really soon.
I hope so
You are.
Yeah. Happy New Year.
Happy New Year.
Kitchen still open?
Mm-hm.
Yep.
For dessert it is.
- Ha-ha.
- We got Jell-O. We got cupcakes, truffles.
Mm.
So you talked Mrs. Ahern
into hiring me tonight, huh?
Well, I knew you had a lot of other offers
and I wanted you to take this one.
I really wanted to talk to you.
Well, I'm glad you did.
I'm glad we had a chance to talk.
I'm canceling the tour.
Why?
Because of you.
I'm never gonna leave you again. Ever.
The best decision I made
was asking you to marry me...
...and the worst decision I made
was sprinting.
I plan to make it up to you
as long as it takes.
Well...
...you do realize that it could be an awfully
long time before I choose to forgive you.
I mean, we could be old and gray
before I choose to forgive you.
I'll Wait.
It could be years of make-up sex
before I choose to forgive you.
I'll suffer.
It's almost midnight.
You wanna go to a party?
Let's do it! Please welcome
Mayor Bloomberg, ladies and gentlemen!
Nice to see you, sir.
- Happy New Year.
- Thank you. Shall we?
I think it's time. Let's drop the ball.
What do you say?
Here we go!
All right, New York City! Are you ready?!
One minute to go.
Let's start the countdown
when we hit 10.
And here comes the ball.
Uh-huh.
There it goes.
Dad, aren't you gonna be cold?
No, no. There's nothing
like New York air.
Look, there it goes.
I made so many mistakes.
You weren't one of them.
Okay, folks, let's start the countdown.
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Happy New Year!
Wait.
If you're here, who's at Times Square?
Should auld acquaintance be forgot
And never brought to mind?
And auld lang syne?
And surely you will buy your cup
And surely I'll buy mine
And we'll take a cup of kindness yet
- You seen Hailey anywhere?
- I haven't.
I was looking for her and I haven't... Mm.
For auld lang syne
We two have run about the slopes
And picked the daisies fine
But we've wandered many a weary foot
Since auld lang syne
For auld lang syne, my dear
For auld lang syne
We'll take a cup of kindness yet
They're calling me now. We have to go.
But I love you so much.
I think about you all the time.
I love you.
I love you so much.
We two have paddled in the stream
From morning sun till night
But the seas between us broad have roared
From auld lang syne
For auld lang syne
What the hell are you doing?
I'm twice your age!
Final resolution.
Midnight kiss on New Year's Eve.
Boom! Check it off.
We'll take a cup of kindness yet
For auld lang syne
Start spreading the news
I'm leaving today
- I'm fine, Mom.
- You're sure?
I'm sure.
You have no idea how worried I was.
I know, I know. I'm sorry.
Hailey.
- Hi, Piper.
- Where have you been?
- You totally freaked us all out.
We got passes to the after party
at the Hard Rock.
And Piper's mom, who's been following
us all night, is gonna take us all home.
Can I go, Mom? Please, please, please.
- Go. Go. Have fun.
- Really?
- Yes. Have fun. Yes, really.
- For real? Thank you.
- Do you wanna come with us?
- No.
- I'll pass. I'm good.
- Are you sure?
You should go to your party.
I love you, Mom. Really.
I love you too.
But you're still grounded.
Yeah, I figured.
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
Happy New Year, bro. Take care.
All right. Talk to you later, man.
Text me when you get home
that you got home all right.
Bye! Happy New Year!
- Hey, Kim, you came for the party.
- Oh, no, I'm just picking something up.
Hey. You made it.
Whatever. You know,
I saw you kissing Lily Bowman.
Busted.
Can we talk somewhere else?
Come here.
Look, I'm...
Hello.
I'm telling you the truth. She grabbed me
and she totally stole it from me.
Oh, she stole it. Oh, okay, yeah.
That makes just perfect sense.
Well, look, I was just watching
the ball drop and then...
Whoa.
Aw...
Who is that?!
Would you like to see what we do
on New Year's Eve?
Welcome to the world.
- Hi.
- Hey.
So you had your baby.
Congratulations.
- Boy or a girl?
- A boy.
A boy.
- You?
- Girl. Third one.
Exactly at 12:04.
And yours was when?
12:05.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Thank you. Thanks so much.
12:05 it is, then.
- Hey. Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year.
It's a very good job.
They asked us back for next year.
You showed up.
You look beautiful.
Well, I had a year to get ready.
- Sometimes it feels like there are so
Earthquakes, floods, reality shows.
But it's important to remember
the things that we can...
...like forgiveness, second chances,
fresh starts.
Because the one thing that turns the world
from a lonely place to a beautiful place...
...is love.
Love in any of its forms.
Love gives us hope.
Hope for the new year.
Hope...
...and a great party.
Don't just dump them!
It should be magical!
Take one.
I've been plotting that slap for years.
How I would just walk up to you
out of the blue... Shit.
I wouldn't want you to be my doctor.
You think we should...
You think we should move him
to hospice?
- Why did you do that to me?
- It's okay, Nurse Aimee.
- Good one.
- Yeah, good one.
Cut, cut, cut.
I... up. I didn't tell her
in the middle of her sentence.
Go to mark.
Oh, hey. Hold the elevator.
Baby, things were just heating up!
Oh. Mrs. Baxter.
I mean, Mrs....
What's your name? Ms. Withers.
It's midnight. We have to do something
tonight. Get over yourself. Shi... Uh-uh.
Ooh. Sorry, you're a little late.
He was in this morning.
He didn't leave orders, and...
And I may not allow him
in my unit any more.
Something coming.
Oh, something coming.
Oh.
Oh, what do we have here?
- I think we have twins.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, you are a goddess.
That is a wrap!