(♪ M.I.A. "BAD GIRLS")
- (SONG CONTINUING OVER STEREO)
- GIRL: Oh, Father, turn it up.
Please, Mr. Dragomir,
I love this song.
This song is sick... the traditional
"vomit" definition of the word.
Shut up, Andre. Me and
Rose want to hear it.
"Rose and I," Lissa, "Rose and I."
- I think the tune is rather catchy.
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
(GASPS, SIGHS)
- (MUFFLED CRYING)
- Lissa?
- (CRYING)
- Lissa. Hey, Lissa, wake up.
- You're having a bad dream.
- (SIGHS) It wasn't a dream.
I know. The accident.
Sorry. Not again.
You know, ever since that night,
I still can't get used to it.
You being in my head,
it's so weird.
You should know by now, with us,
"weird" doesn't begin to cover it.
Why can't you be like
a normal teenage girl
and dream about hot,
naked guys on unicorns?
Does it have to be unicorns?
Of course not. It could be Jet
Skis, mechanical bulls or...
Why do you have a scary poster
of an American ex-president?
Well, you told me I needed to
blend more into Oregano society.
We're in Oregon. You know
you're completely hopeless
as a human being, right?
I'm still adjusting, Rose.
It's been less than a year since
we ran away from the academy,
two years since the crash.
Don't you ever stop to think about
everything that we've gone through?
Stopping is for losers. I only
think about keeping us moving
and keeping you safe.
Does anyone even remember us?
You really think the academy's
still trying to hunt us down?
Absolutely. I think we may
have to get plastic surgery.
No, don't, please.
- Yes? No?
- (LAUGHING) No.
- Just like this? You like it?
- Rose, no.
- Whoa. When was the last time you...?
- I'm not hungry.
Is exactly what you say
every time you're hungry.
Come to the kitchen.
I'll make your favorite.
Are you... are you sure about this?
Bon appétit.
- Thanks.
- What are friends for?
- (CAT MEOWS)
- You jealous, Oscar?
What are you looking at?
Do I still have anything on my...?
Lissa, smile. They're watching.
Not a drill.
- What's out there? Not Strigoi?
- No, not Strigoi, thank God. Guardians.
Keep close, just like we practiced.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(WHISPERS) Lissa, go.
- (MOTOR REVVING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALARM CHIRPS)
- Did you have to hurt them?
- Did I have to hurt them?
You're welcome.
Get out the map, Gandhi.
We'll head north into Canada.
- (OSCAR MEOWS)
- Did you really bring that fur ball?
I couldn't just abandon him.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Hells, yes.
Rose.
Princess Vasilisa Dragomir.
My name is Dimitri Belikov.
I've come to take you back
to St. Vladimir's Academy.
Listen, comrade, to get to her,
you're gonna have to go through me.
ROSE: Like I said, "weird"
doesn't begin to cover it.
My best friend Lissa
Dragomir is a royal member
of a magical, ancient
race: the Moroi.
The Moroi don't wear black capes,
turn into bats or sleep in coffins.
Daylight annoys yet doesn't kill them,
and they don't sparkle, either.
But, yes, like most creatures with
fangs, the Moroi live off blood.
But they don't live forever,
that's why they need us.
(GASPS)
My name is Rose Hathaway and like
these other guys, I'm a Dhampir.
We're the protectors,
the guardians.
Only half Moroi, I can eat a bacon
cheeseburger or whatever else I want.
Dhampir lives are dedicated
to protecting the Moroi.
We live by one simple
expression: they come first.
Only nothing's ever simple.
Handcuffs? There's got to be a
compliment in there somewhere.
So you're taking us
back to the academy.
Tell me, how bad is it gonna be?
Nothing?
You know, I kept the
princess safe and hidden
for an entire year
before you got lucky.
- Congratulations.
- It speaks.
Wow, that's a lot of molnija
marks you got there.
You've killed six Strigoi?
We were afraid that we'd run
into one of them back there.
If you had run into a Strigoi, we
wouldn't be having this conversation.
This is your idea
of a conversation?
(LAUGHS) Exactly.
(ROSE AND LISSA LAUGHING)
DIMITRI:
We are here. Open the gate.
Anyone there?
(RADIO CRACKLING)
Where is everyone?
- (LISSA SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTING)
(SNARLS, SCREAMS)
- Let's go!
- Lissa!
Move, move!
(GRUNTING AND SNARLING)
Stay in the car.
- (SNARLS)
- (MAN SCREAMS)
- (GRUNTING AND SNARLING)
- (MAN SCREAMING)
No!
(MAN SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
DIMITRI:
I've got this one. Stay here.
What's going on out there?
Stay here.
(RUSTLING)
(SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
- (GASPS)
- (SNARLS)
(GRUNTING)
- (BONES CRACK)
- (GROANS)
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
DIMITRI: Spiridon.
Welcome back, Dimitri.
ROSE: And then there's group number
three: the bad vampires, the Strigoi.
Evil bloodsuckers that
only come out at night
and can only be killed
by a silver stake.
It takes five of our best
to kill one of their worst.
If you're lucky,
they'll just rip you apart,
but they can also turn
you into one of them.
Strigoi were the true
monsters of our nightmares.
For all the stories, the warnings,
and the training films,
I had never seen one up close.
- (HISSES)
- (GASPS)
I told you to stay in the car.
We're clear.
ROSE: And there it was.
Goodbye, Facebook.
Goodbye, iPhone 5.
Hello, St. Vladimir's.
It is not just another school.
It's another universe.
Moroi and Dhampir students
come from all over the world
to study history, science, math,
and all the other boring stuff,
but around fourth period,
we Dhampir go off and learn fun
new ways to maim and kill,
while, for the Moroi,
it's magic time.
Water, earth, fire, air.
You see, it's not just their diet
that makes the Moroi special,
and some are more
special than others.
Our secret society has
its own government
that alternates leaders
from 12 royal families.
That's Queen Tatiana up top,
but my girl Lissa is in the mix.
You can see why the princess leaving
the academy was such a scandal,
and me helping her was worse.
Damn, back to Vampire Academy.
Please don't say Vampire Academy.
You know how I feel about the "V" word.
Sorry.
It's not like the drinking of blood
is your main source of sustenance.
No, wait, that's
exactly what it is.
- (LAUGHS)
- (SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
They just had to bring us back
in the middle of the night.
So not cool... 1:00 a.m.,
end of fifth period.
Ew, it looks like Aaron's
tried to replace you
with a little keychain version.
God, I hate high school.
Princess. Headmistress
Kirova is ready for you.
Come on.
It's all so unprecedented. I'm at a
loss coming up with proper punishment.
As Lissa's guardian...
You're not an official
guardian, Hathaway.
You are a novice.
You put Vasilisa at the
mercy of the Strigoi,
who would love to destroy,
or even worse, transform...
It was my idea to leave.
Rose only did what...
KIROVA: A trained guardian knows...
- (DOOR OPENS)
- MAN: Ellen, please.
- Victor.
- Lissa.
VICTOR: Ah.
ROSE:
Prince Dashkov, you look so...
Yes. My Sandovsky's
syndrome has gotten worse.
Oh, Victor, we never
meant to worry you.
Headmistress,
these girls have been
through so much.
As provost of this school
and Lissa's father's oldest friend,
I beg you, look into your heart.
Vasilisa, I have the
utmost sympathy
for the loss of your parents
and your brother, Andre.
But why did you flee a
heavily guarded compound
of Moroi students from
all over the world?
It's not easy to explain.
Lissa felt more in danger here
in your secure environment
than on the outside as
an anonymous teenager.
Fascinating. This is where
you give me specifics.
Where's Ms. Karp?
She should be here.
She can maybe shed some
light onto the situation.
Ms. Karp is no longer
part of this institution.
I...
This is where you give me specifics.
What do you mean?
It's not important!
Vasilisa Dragomir is from one
of the 12 royal families.
She's the last of
the Dragomir line.
With my condition taking the
Dashkov family out of contention,
Lissa is a possible
successor to the throne.
But you, Hathaway, a Dhampir
girl cut off from the community,
out on civilian streets without a
dime or a Social Security number?
"Blood whore" is such an ugly term,
but I'm sure Moroi men on
business trips would pay a lot
for the especially sweet taste.
Headmistress Kirova.
- They have the bond.
- That's... that's impossible.
In my brief observation period,
Rose could tell what Lissa
was thinking or feeling,
sometimes without being
in the same place.
What a rare and wonderful gift.
This doesn't take away from the fact
that Rose Hathaway is wild, dangerous...
- insubordinate, vulgar.
- Right here, folks. Right here.
But the number of female Dhampir
guardians has gone down
way too much to risk losing
one with such potential.
Ellen, what this impressive new
guardian says seems reasonable.
We're so sorry, Headmistress.
After the crash, I lacked a strong
parental figure to confide in.
I'm afraid Rose and I got
in way over our heads.
Two crazy kids.
Hathaway can stay, but no
extracurricular activities,
no parties, no socializing,
nothing resembling fun.
Take the princess to her royal quarters
and find a broom closet for...
Oh, Rose, I almost forgot.
A telegram.
From Mom.
ROSE: Kirova flipping out and Lissa
using compulsion to save my ass,
just another night
at St. Vladimir's.
Wow. This place definitely
brought back memories.
Come on, over here.
LISSA: Before the accident,
my father used to say
that for a Moroi not declaring a magic
is like not going through puberty.
Yeah, and he also used to
say practice during the day
while the world,
your world, is sleeping.
Let's make some magic.
Perfect.
Fire and water.
That's my Moroi.
- Rose...
- Don't leave me hanging.
Rose, you know how I
feel about high-fives.
Ladies. It's after 11:00 a.m., girls.
You should be in bed.
The sun has cleared the trees,
and it won't be kind, Your Highness.
I never got a chance to express
my condolences at the funeral.
But I am so heartened
by the extraordinary
recovery you've both made.
(LAUGHS)
And don't worry, Princess.
I never officially
declared a magic, either.
And look how I turned out.
Ms. Karp's so different
from the other instructors.
It's really refreshing.
The thing that I like the most about her
is she's not strange or creepy at all.
(CROW CAWING)
(GASPS)
- It's hurt.
- It's more than hurt. It's done.
Leave it. Come on, let...
(CAWING)
That was unique.
Lissa.
Lissa?
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GASPS, COUGHS)
(LAUGHTER)
Hey, Liss.
- It's good to see you.
- Aaron.
Guessing your new girlfriend
practices water magic. Classy.
Yeah. Hey, I'm sorry.
Mia gets jealous, but
deep down, she's sweet.
Back off, bitch. He's mine now.
Very deep down, apparently.
How does it feel to leave at the
top and come back at the bottom?
Don't like what I'm saying?
What are you gonna do about it?
Thanks for asking.
I'm gonna go to a quiet place
and be very depressed
that this is my new life.
(GRUNTING)
MAN OVER SPEAKER: All Dhampir novices
transfer to the next training station.
Everyone transfer to their
next training station.
BOY: Dimitri is a God.
I hear he tracked
them down to Oregon,
and when Rose tried to put up
a fight, he handed her her ass.
And what was left of that ass got
chewed up by Headmistress Kirova.
Surely, you have something more
interesting to discuss than my ass.
- Your boobies?
- Quit while you're alive, Mason.
What up, baby?
BOTH: Ooh.
Forgot the secret handshake.
That hurts.
You know, I'm gonna make you
pay for your booby comment.
Old Rose maybe, but you've
missed a year of training.
Yeah, you needed that year to catch
up with what I was born with.
Prepare to...
Ow! (GROANS)
Sorry, Rose. Don't hate me.
I'd hate you more if you held back.
They have these things
in the outside world...
Pinkberry and mini taquitos,
Toaster Strudel... (SIGHS)
Oh, no. Not this again.
(PANTING)
(RAPID FOOTSTEPS)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (GASPS)
Don't worry. I don't bite.
Well... only literally.
What are you doing here?
This is where I come to get away.
Hey, this was my... special place
before it was your special place.
What do you have to get
away from, Princess?
What do you know about pain?
Break a nail off in your tiara?
- Excuse me, after a car crash...
- You got off easy.
How dare you! Do you have any idea
what it's like to lose your family?
(SOFTLY) Oh. Sorry.
You know you're talking to
Christian Ozera, right?
Parents transformed
themselves into Strigoi...
When your folks died,
there was a pretty funeral,
and everybody cried.
When my mother and father were
hunted down, everybody cheered.
I hate what they chose to become...
but they were still my parents.
A Strigoi can't enter holy ground.
Is that why you come to the church?
To prove to everyone
you haven't turned?
Get away from that freak.
(FRUSTRATED GRUNT)
Maybe I just like the way the
moonlight hits this spot.
It's as if you're
on another planet.
What was it like...
outside the academy?
It was kind of scary, just
the two of us out there,
but... it was also kind of great.
No one knew who I was.
It does sound kind of great.
But what did you do for blood?
I mean, it's not like you
can pick it up at 7-Eleven.
Or so I've read.
Don't you say anything, girl.
People will get the wrong idea.
You and Rose, all alone on the road.
I have my theories.
Promise me you won't tell
your friends these theories.
I promise you I have
no friends to tell.
ROSE:
Stop staring at each other all...
- ...gooey like. (GASPS)
- Hathaway!
Look alive!
Comrade Belikov.
They ran me ragged. What do
you say we go easy today?
- Perhaps discuss a bit of theory.
- Of course, Rose. I understand.
(ROSE GRUNTS)
How do you say
"what a dick" in Russian?
Did you even go to a gym out there?
I took a couple of
spinning classes.
Do you really think beating me up is
gonna help me face a live Strigoi?
After your performance last night,
if you see a Strigoi,
I recommend running.
Now, give me ten sets of lines.
You know, this country has a concept
called "positive reinforcement."
Rose, your bond is special.
You're an ideal choice to guard
Vasilisa when you both graduate.
But if you want to be with her,
you need to be ready for anything.
(ROSE YELLS)
- Ow!
- Wow.
You look how I feel.
I look how I feel.
How's that "under the radar"
plan working out, Highness?
Not so much.
If you need a shoulder to cry on,
use mine, not Christian Ozera's.
- Who told you?
- I was sort of... you know, there.
Oh, not again. That's so gross.
I know, and it was, like,
the longest one yet.
- You seriously can't turn it off?
- I don't know.
Have you ever seen me
go to the bathroom?
No, but thank you for giving me
something to look forward to.
- Oh, shut up. Oh!
- (ALARM VIBRATES)
No wonder I'm so cranky.
I'm starving.
ROSE: And now, for the obligatory
cafeteria scene, sort of.
Ever wonder what happened
to that friend of yours,
obsessed with vampire
books and shows?
It's called the human
feeder program.
Human civilians systematically
giving their blood.
I forgot how much
I did not miss this.
LISSA: Hey, no feeder is brought
here against their will.
They can leave any time
that they want to.
Yeah, it's just a
one-year service limit,
and their memories are officially
compulsed upon departure.
That's completely normal.
LISSA: Don't feel too
sorry for the feeders.
If you recall, the bitee does get
something out of the process.
- (GASPS) Oh, there's Norrine. Here.
- Hey! Look at you!
- How are you?
- Yeah, good.
- (YOWLING)
- Here.
(SIGHS) OK.
Rose! Come and keep a
decrepit man company.
Decrepit? You're just saying that so I
won't kick your ass in five-card draw.
Tell me, my darling,
while you were gone,
did Lissa get any
closer to declaring?
There's not a lot of places to
practice magic in Portland.
Oh, true, true.
On the subject of non-declarers,
I want to know why, when I brought
up Ms. Karp's name yesterday,
you all acted like I put a
porcupine in a hot tub.
Karp has always been a few
corpuscles shy of a full artery.
She didn't have a Dhampir
to look after her.
I know you have your
special bond with Lissa,
but it makes your escape
that much more alarming.
I'm on your side, Rose,
but we live in a world where
the bogeymen are real.
I know. I'm still a
little freaked-out.
I was there last night when
that Strigoi attacked,
and I just... I totally choked.
Don't be so down on yourself, Rose.
- Why are you...
- (CLATTERING)
I know you have your life
mission to protect Lissa,
but would you now and again
look out for my Natalie?
ROSE: Mm...
She's a goofball,
but I do cherish her.
Yes. Well, she worships her father.
She would do anything for you.
I must go to her.
- Hey.
- (OSCAR MEOWS)
(SIGHS) Hi.
- Do I have anything...
- (GROANS)
Just fat-lady feeder breath. Here.
So, do you even know your feeders?
Norrine's recently divorced, and
she's catching up on some me-time.
She writes Twilight fan-fiction.
- Have you read any of it?
- Oh, God, no.
Rose, Princess Vasilisa.
I mean, Lissa.
You said I could call you
Lissa, but if I can't anymore,
- that's totally fine.
- Hello, Natalie.
By the soul of St. Vlad's,
so much has happened.
Nothing bigger than your escape,
of course. Why did you escape?
Did you hear Sheila Flight and
Bruce Bugsburger broke up?
Apparently, Bruce still has his baby
fangs, and it freaks Sheila out.
And you know about
Tess and Jackson?
Each was afraid that they're
gonna be the ones to get dumped,
so they started this really weird
rumor. I can't really remember...
Natalie? Do you take
gossip requests?
Mia Rinaldi over there, is she new?
Well, she's been around,
but new haircut, new fangs,
and now she's hanging out
with all the royals.
Rose Hathaway, what
are you doing here?
Surely you would not deprive a
girl of her religious needs?
Just get inside.
The debate team, and
I don't really know if I...
Speaking of extracurricular activities
that I miss, is that Jesse?
The hot get hotter.
Yeah, Jesse's still the academy's
number one wet dreamboat.
(SCOFFS)
He has a terrible personality.
Jesse has a personality?
I didn't know.
Don't judge a book by its content.
You know this is a church, right?
Gosh, if only there was a way
that we could set up a double
date with Ray over there.
You can't tell me that there's no
inbreeding amongst you royals.
Exhibit Ray.
Ray just doesn't know how
to express his feelings.
You know, when a boy throws
sand in a girl's face,
it really means that...
Never mind.
Yeah.
- Your friend's a tool.
- Don't change the subject.
You, me... you and me.
Yeah, but don't you
have a girlfriend?
- Probably.
- Oh, you are bad.
What's so bad about bad?
(CHURCH BELLS TOLLING)
(CHUCKLES)
You do understand, Rose,
that even the walls of a church
can't protect a true sinner
from a good lightning bolt?
Save a seat for me in the
Dhampir section, you dork.
Mason likes you so much.
Why can't you go outwith a
nice, funny guy like him?
I know. If only I could put
Mason into Jesse's body.
God can be cruel.
Yes. That's true.
Come on. Let's go.
MAN:
Following God's path is never easy.
Even St. Vladimir had
difficulty controlling
and understanding his powers.
But he was bound to a
loving Dhampir guardian
who always knew what was
in his heart and mind.
Shadow-kissed Anna.
Shadow-kissed Rose,
you're bound to Lissa, and
it's up to you to help her.
(EXPLOSION)
(CONGREGATION GASPING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHTER)
What's so funny?
Did you write that?
Down, Dhampir,
you saw me in church.
Listen, Gap Kids, if I find out
that you had anything to do
with that, I will rip your...
You'll what? You're on lockdown.
You breathe the wrong way
and you're out on the pavement
doing amateur blood whore porn.
Listen up, that's enough
excitement for a Sunday night.
Everyone back to your dorms
until further notice.
Royal rec room, high noon.
I've changed my mind.
I'm feeling bad.
Good.
(♪ GOLDFRAPP "THEA")
(SIGHS) We Moroi may not burst
into flames like Strigoi,
but daylight still stings.
Poor thing. (CHUCKLES)
Did you have jobs out in the world?
What about an iPhone?
- What's a hashtag?
- Please, stop talking.
Whoa, horsey, what do
you think you're doing?
Come on, Rose. A bite while
you're going at it is the best.
Stop it!
Oh... I know that look.
You've done it before.
I would never let a guy
degrade me like that.
Not a guy, of course. Lissa.
We've all been
wondering how she fed.
Once you've had fang,
Rose, you never go...
Daytime fraternization. Forbidden.
I get it. Chill, chill.
Again, Jesse? Back to your room!
What? (GASPS)
(CREAKING)
Lissa, what are you doing?
(GASPS)
- (LISSA SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
- Rose?
- Lissa's in trouble.
(CRYING)
(STAMMERS)
I heard... I heard a noise.
(WHISPERING) Lissa...
There's so much blood.
It's starting again, isn't it?
I tried, Rose, I tried
to bring it back,
but... it was too late.
- Get over here and comfort her, jerk.
- (MEOWS)
It's gonna be OK.
- What the hell is Kirova doing?
- She's giving Vasilisa a sedative,
and we are increasing
her guardian detail.
Our security system is geared
to keeping Strigoi out,
not dealing with teenage
bullying within.
Bullying? You really think
that's all this is?
- Rose...
- Sorry.
Thank you for not saying
anything to Kirova about...
it was foolish of me to assume you'd
be above such 17-year-old silliness.
Hmm. Hmm...
(INHALING)
The sunlight, it's nice.
I miss it.
Stupid vampire timetable.
The little sacrifices we make.
And the big ones.
My 17-year-old silliness,
that was the past.
That was an hour ago.
Are you trying to tell me you're
suddenly mature and responsible?
I'm trying to tell you that
I want to be, I have to be.
Teach me something
more than doing laps.
I know enough about running away.
And next time we meet,
teach me how to fight.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Pipe down. Let's pick
up where we left off.
After the tribunals
in Romania... Mia!
You're usually a lot better
at passing on notes.
- Having an off-day?
- Oh, no, Mr. Meisner,
please don't read this note
out loud, I beg of you.
"I'll bet that drama queen..."
"I mean, drama princess,
killed that fox herself"
"to distract the school
from her real secret."
Don't go on.
Mr. Meisner, you're being used as a tool
to broadcast Mia's vile propaganda.
Are you calling me a tool?
- If she's not, I will.
- What was that, Hathaway?
Now I'm curious.
"So, it turns out the reason"
"that Lissa survived so
long on the outside"
"is she used Rose as a
personal feed bag."
- (STUDENTS MURMURING)
- Settle down!
Dhampir-Moroi mastication is
a very serious allegation.
I'm gonna pretend
I never read this.
Everyone turn to page
three of your handout.
RAY: But, Mr. Meisner,
you left out the best part.
About me and my boy, Jesse,
and that Dhamp tramp last night.
- What?
- Truth hurts, blood whore.
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
(SHRIEKING, GASPING)
Christian, cut it out!
Kindly report to Headmistress
Kirova's office, Mr. Ozera.
- Down the hall, turn left.
- Like I need directions.
- (SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
- Lissa, Lissa, wait up.
Not here, not in front of everyone.
What was that back there?
Fire magic in class?
- Uh-oh. Lovers' quarrel.
- Rose, I bleed for you.
No, it's Rose who
does the bleeding.
(GRUNTING)
You can't beat up everyone
we have a problem with!
- Well, I can try.
- What is going on?
I told you, Jesse and I barely even
made out, and Ray wasn't even there,
so I don't even know
what he's talking about.
OK, yes. Teenage boys are
weak and sweaty piglets.
It is our covenant...
I'm talking about you and me.
How did they find out
about the feeding?
You know, when Jesse's fangs
came poking out, did you...
No, not even.
But... he did kind of suspect.
Lissa, let me explain, please!
Let me talk...
Is it true?
You're gonna have to be
more specific, Mason.
Jesse and Ray, and not just
hooking up, fanging up.
- They claim they fed while...
- Absolutely not...
Well, actually, Jesse and I
did make out a little, but...
- Where there's smoke, there's fire.
- Leave fire out of this.
You girls throw yourselves
at any douche bag
who happens to be Moroi and royal.
Whoa, Duckie. I do not have time to
deal with your feelings right now.
- OK.
- (STAMMERING)
Oh, God, come on, Lissa-vision.
Where are you when I need you?
You should thank me for
changing the news cycle.
It took something epic to take
animal death and blood whoring
off the Vampire Academy front page.
Please don't say "Vampire Academy."
I find the term to be quite...
You set someone on fire!
Come on. Did you see
any burn marks on him?
Now whoever killed that fox is
going to feel the real heat.
Is this your idea of chivalry?
You did not just
flip your hair back.
That's your move.
She's flirting, folks.
If we used our magic as a weapon,
instead of just for warm and
fuzzy classroom exercises,
the Strigoi wouldn't
be picking us off.
- Yes, but the rules forbid...
- The rules?
Lissa, I've seen the way you tilt
your head from time to time.
I'm very sure I don't know
what you're talking about.
Hey, compulsion must have been
a necessity in the outside world.
You can't know all my secrets. Yet.
- (FANFARE PLAYING)
- Queen Tatiana?
(APPLAUSE)
I hope I did not take you
too much by surprise,
but sometimes your queen awakens
with a need to look upon her lovelies.
Where's Vasilisa?
Vasilisa Dragomir?
Please come up and let
me see the princess.
Not a day goes by
where we don't lament
the loss of your parents
and your brother.
The Dragomir name represents
the finest of Moroi qualities.
While you, Vasilisa Dragomir,
the last of the Dragomir line...
if you are our future,
I am less than impressed.
The power that comes from royal
blood must be used responsibly.
While you... you give us
dead animals, blood games,
escapes to Oregon. Shameful!
- Queen Tatiana, I can explain.
- Shh, shh, shh.
Not now, dear.
However, I have every confidence
that our dear Vasilisa
will turn things around.
Now, let us adjourn
to the banquet hall.
NATALIE: My father would never
have done something like that.
After all that Lissa has been through,
to be shamed by our queen bee?
Don't you mean queen bee-etch?
You don't talk to Lissa like that.
So much for round-the-clock
guardians.
Lissa?
Oh, my God.
- NATALIE: By the soul of St. Vladimir.
- Who would do something like this? Why?
Go to the wall, Nat. Talk to me.
- What?
- (GRUNTS)
Yeah, OK.
(WHISPERING) Oh, God.
- It's fresh, and it's Moroi.
- OK, can you tell me if it's royal?
- (SCOFFS) Don't be absurd.
- Said the girl licking the wall.
I can tell you it's more
than one person's blood.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
- They misspelled "beware."
Lissa, I can clean it up.
I'm sorry.
Leave it. The misspelling shows it was
just a bunch of stupid teenagers.
OK, you know what, I'm gonna
go start packing. I'm really...
No, Rose. We can't just keep running
away, at least until we know
what we're running away from.
Ooh! A mystery, how exciting.
We can be like three
Nancy Drews trying...
I hate mysteries. I would prefer a
good Strigoi attack at this point
because at least I'd know what
those homicidal bloodsuckers want.
No more. I am taking our
dear beloved queen's advice,
and I'm turning things around.
Jesse and Ray are pawns.
Mia is the mastermind.
Yeah, but we didn't even
really know Mini-Mia
when we were compelled to
leave for the first time.
Ms. Karp is the one that
we should be focused on.
Do what you have to do, Dhampir. I am
done trying to crawl under the radar.
It's not possible, and...
it's not effective.
(OSCAR MEOWS)
Besides, I have a way of getting
people to see my side of the story.
Don't worry, Natalie
knows of my skills.
It was too exhausting
keeping it from her.
Are you going to use
compulsion on Mia?
Where's the fun in that?
I'm going to use compulsion
on everyone but Mia.
But compulsion on
such a large scale...
Magic should be used for something more
than warm and fuzzy classroom exercises.
Oh, God, and now you're
quoting Christian?
- What?
- Yeah, I was there.
And the poison that that freak
is pumping into your brain
makes me want to vomit.
Lissa, I'm the reckless, and
you're the cautious, remember?
You've already taken too
many hits for me, Rose.
Look, it's your turn
to have a little cry,
and it's my turn to
kick a little ass.
Whoa!
You do not jump out at
a guardian like that.
I think you mean novice.
Just wanted to know
if Lissa was all right.
Queen Tatiana had no right
to bring up family.
- I should go and talk to Lissa.
- Oh, don't worry about it.
But I do. Lissa and I have a bond.
A bond?
Listen, Chris,
just stay away from her.
She's had her little flirtation
with the dark side, and she's done.
Lissa used to like Hot Topic,
too, and then she turned 12.
I was only concerned.
There's a fine line between
concerned and stalker.
Seriously, Christian, go away.
It's what Lissa wants.
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
OK.
I thought we'd practice out
here, away from there.
Dimitri, I know you must
have heard some rumors.
All that high-school der'mo
stays back there, not here.
This is life and death.
The silver. Don't be afraid of it.
Besides the sun, this stake is your
only friend against the Strigoi.
But you must subdue the monster
and bring yourself to kill.
Yeah, killing Strigoi is
what it's all about, right?
Most Strigoi were once Moroi.
Some turn themselves Strigoi by
killing during the feeding process.
But many are turned by force.
If you are going to thrust, thrust.
My point is you might have known
one personally, as a friend.
Can you kill someone
you used to know?
I... If it was them
or me or Lissa...
You hesitate, and that
hesitation could kill you.
You have to keep telling yourself that
they aren't the same people you knew.
Good. Very good.
I don't mean to belittle
what you are going through.
The queen crossed a line.
But the Dhampir must always bow down.
I get it. The Moroi come first.
Not always. My father was a Moroi.
He visited Russia once a year.
He liked to hit my mother.
When I was old enough,
I liked to hit him.
He stopped visiting.
- How old is old enough?
- Ten.
(CHUCKLES)
The only parent I've ever
really had is the academy.
Your mother is one
of the most feared
and respected Dhampir
guardians in the world.
I see you finally
read her telegram.
You want to know what it said?
"Glad you're alive. What you
did was inexcusable. Mom."
Aw.
What do you know of
your Moroi father?
That he must have had dark
eyes and amazing hair.
When I start killing
Strigoi left and right,
I'm gonna have to cut
it all off, won't I?
Sorry. That sounded really girly.
You can wear it up.
Doesn't a Dhampir need to keep
their molnija marks exposed?
Don't ever cut your hair.
Wear it up.
You have to admire our queen.
Her elegance, her dignity, her
ability to recognize trash.
And my good mood is over.
You know, "beware" isn't
spelled with an "H" in it.
- Hey.
- Where's Lissa?
I haven't seen her, but guess what?
I heard that Mia and
Aaron are going
on that field trip to
the hemoglobin factory.
I figured it gives us a
chance to raid their rooms...
- Pretend to be talking to me.
- But I am talking to you.
It's nasty. If you
guys were doing it,
I'm not surprised Rose got
addicted and necked with Jesse.
She didn't do it with Jesse.
And it's not like we fornicated.
We just didn't have any feeders.
It's no big deal, Camilla.
Yeah, it's no big deal.
I mean, Jesse's a liar.
What are you guys doing tonight?
Shannon and I are going to her
room to study for Meisner's test.
Invite me.
Lissa, you want to
study with us tonight?
LISSA: Sure.
Oh, look. It's the
queen's court jester.
You can't talk to me like that.
The queen treats me like a daughter,
so you should be envious.
You're buds with Mia. What
secrets are you keeping?
- I like to wear my mommy's knick...
- Not about you.
Secrets about Mia.
- LISSA: Busted.
- Ow.
Did you witness how amazing I was?
I felt it. Using the power has an
effect, a cost, on both of us.
Look at you, you're shaking.
I'm shaking.
Three cups of coffee shaking.
More like 18 cups,
dark roast, no room.
- I got it, the computer.
- What?
I told you.
Mia's on a field trip...
Hey, you. I'm sorry I haven't
been to church in a while, but...
It's OK. You don't have
to pretend anymore.
You've had your little
flirtation with the dark side.
- Check that box and move on.
- What are you talking about?
But, hey, nice hypocrisy
on the magic use.
- (POP MUSIC PLAYING)
- LISSA: So what? A stolen laptop.
Kirova strangled Internet
access years ago.
Yeah, St. Vlad's operates
on a closed network,
but there is more to a
person than status updates.
There's photos, receipts,
inter-academy e-mails.
(GROANS)
You're making my brain bleed.
But you were sure right
about cuckoo Christian.
What a whack job.
Are you seriously going to
that study group with Camilla?
You know, you don't have to
use compulsion to be popular.
You may not recall, but you can
be quite charming on your own.
Who has the time? Natalie,
return that computer.
Later, losers.
(GROANS) Gosh.
I wish Lissa could compulse
Ray into being nicer.
And taking my virginity.
No one has ever
really seen me naked.
- Moroi, Dhampir, human, mineral.
- Uh-huh.
I once turned a plant around because
I was too shy to change in front of it.
You know I can't
un-hear this, right?
- Sorry. Yeah, I...
- It's OK.
Though I'm not much better.
I'm crushing on my mentor, Dimitri,
who's, like, old enough to be my...
Not my father... like an uncle.
Like a disturbingly sexy uncle.
Andre?
What the hell is this?
NATALIE: Goodness gracious.
Andre, Andre?
That's Lissa's brother, isn't it?
ROSE: Andre could have, like, any
girl he wanted, and he usually did.
Most of the girls knew the drill.
It was down low, no commitments and...
This is the face of a girl
who did not know the drill.
NATALIE: Holy moly.
Mia's not just angry at Lissa.
She despises the whole Dragomir line.
Right, which makes her someone willing
to take things to a whole other level.
OK, all right. Take this
back to Mia's room.
- Yeah?
- OK.
See ya.
- (SIGHS)
- (OSCAR MEOWS)
Hey. To what do I owe this honor?
Can we talk, Oscar?
ROSE: I'm worried about Lissa.
I love that our princess is learning
that the best defense is a good offense,
and believe me, I am all for putting
mad munchkin Mia in her place,
but this Operation Brainwash is turning
Lissa into something she's not.
She can't see that. I can.
It's like I feel Lissa's
feelings more than she does.
I need to put on my game face.
Can't wait around for my
next psychedelic flashback.
The stakes are too high.
- (GRUNTING)
- Get it?
Dhampir? Fight with stakes?
Best defense, good offense.
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
I knew you'd improve.
No fair learning from a god.
I heard you were good at
taking on two guys at once.
(GROANS, COUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Rose, uh, about Jesse and Ray...
- Mason...
- No, not that.
In the locker room, it was weird.
They had these bandages
on their wrists.
I don't know if it means anything.
ROSE: Covered wrists?
- Is that some new Moroi thing?
- Check out Mia.
(CHUCKLES)
- She's getting away.
- Let her.
Kirova's the one I
should be tracking.
I need to break into
Kirova's office today
when the fang gang is asleep, OK?
There's a file in there that
could be the key to my past,
my present and my future.
That's it?
Sounds cool.
(GRUNTING)
Forty-five minutes of silence.
It has to be a Rose
Hathaway record.
OK.
What do you know about Ms. Karp?
Karp? She retired
before I even arrived.
Kirova, Victor, you.
I ask about Karp, and it's no eye
contact and a subject change.
Enough. Your training of
late has been quite...
- ...fine.
- Fine? That's it?
What do you want me to say?
That you are a
remarkable quick study?
That you bring originality
to classic moves?
Yeah, I want you to
say all those things.
Good night, Rose.
(ROSE SHOUTING)
What did I do wrong? I had you.
(LAUGHS) The battle cry
was your first mistake.
I like your laugh.
Singular, not plural.
It's the first time I've heard it.
So even if I wouldn't have screamed,
you still would have stopped me, right?
Probably, but nice initiative.
Keep trying those surprise attacks.
It's good training for both of us.
So, uh... you have any other
moves you want to show me?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CLATTERING)
(SIGHS)
I give it and they take it, but when it
comes back, it's not the same, is it?
I give it and they take it,
but when it comes back,
it's not the same, is it?
They're coming to get me.
But they want something
that I can't give them.
Those of us who never declared, those of
us who have powers that have no name,
there's only so much we can do,
only so much we can handle.
I should have gone with Vasilisa.
I should have.
I'm so alone.
The clarity of the
darkness beckons.
I just want it to go
away, the shaking,
the scratching,
nightmares, all go away.
Lissa. The king and queen of
the school together again,
- the way it should be.
- CHRISTIAN: Lissa!
It's you and I who are
destined to be together.
Let me handle this.
Look at what you made me do to
myself, just like my damn parents.
(SNARLS)
(GASPS) Lissa!
- (STUDENTS SCREAMING)
- (GLASS BREAKING)
I have a new family now.
Strigoi brothers and
sisters, attack!
- (SNARLING)
- (STUDENTS SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
- Rose, what's happening?
- Stay close, right behind me,
just like we practiced.
(GRUNTING)
OK. It's not looking great,
but we will get through this,
Lissa, we always do.
Dimitri?
Oh, Rose, you worry too much.
Lissa, no.
What are friends for?
(WHIMPERING) No.
No!
Rose, are you there?
Did you feel that one?
What a weird dream.
Yeah. Yeah, Liss, weird dream.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
Don't you dare feel sorry for me.
Feel sorry for her,
for the princess.
(ROSE WHISPERING) I lied.
Lissa doesn't think that
you're a creepy stalker.
She actually likes you.
Then why did you...?
Because I think that
you're a creepy stalker,
and I actually don't
like you, but...
I like the way that Lissa
feels when she's around you.
So what?
Look at her. She's back on top.
She's not happy. She's not
herself, not as she wants to be.
Trust me, I know, Christian.
- I can f...
- (ORGAN PLAYING)
Shadow-kissed Anna
did all she could,
but on some days, Satan's darkness
seeped into St. Vladimir,
weakening his health and mind.
See, Christian, I don't
want that to be Lissa.
You are the phantom here. You must know
where they keep the books and scrolls
and whatnot, and I need to
figure out what her abilities...
You sabotaged the first good thing
to happen to me in a long time,
and now you want me to help you?
Ugh. God.
Princess party in
the royal rec room.
- (DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CHEERING)
There's my blood bitch.
What took you so long?
- (MOCK GROWLING)
- (LAUGHING)
It's great that you
can joke about it.
Lissa, listen. A lot has happened.
We have to sit down and
have a real conversation.
Stop being so serious, Rose.
It's a party.
- Hey, Natalie.
- Hi.
(SIGHING)
Awesome party, huh?
Check this.
(ALL GASPING)
Can you say "keg magic"?
Wow, Lissa, you can
really do it all.
Well, of course I can.
I'm the princess.
But doing it all is wrong, right?
Fire, air, fire, air, fire,
air, fire, air,
- fire...
- AARON: Hey.
Aaron. (CHUCKLES)
Rose! Where are you going?
You weren't just going to
bail without saying goodbye.
I need to go home
and sleep you off.
Oh, is the bond making
you as buzzed as I am?
God, you are burning
us both out on magic.
Stop worrying. It's working.
Weeks have gone by,
and Mia is toast.
No threats, no notes, no foxes.
You're just bummed that I, not
you, have neutralized the threat.
You neutralized a threat,
not "the" threat.
And Aaron, seriously,
you really want to show up to
the Equinox Dance with that?
He's... cute.
And incredibly boring.
You think everyone's boring.
Christian's not.
No, you were right about him.
(STAMMERS)
I knew "little flirtation with the dark
side" sounded like one of your lines.
- Sorry.
- You know what? You can have Christian.
You're both savages.
Lissa, what I've been
trying to tell you
is that you're making
this about high school,
and it's about something more.
(CLATTERING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GASPS)
Natalie... Are you nuts?
What are you thinking?
Trust me, you do not want to have
to get a nose job in Montana!
Sorry. I'm sorry. It's...
When you both left the
party, I had no one to...
Everyone kept staring
at me, so I left,
and on my way back to the
dorms, I swear, someone...
more like something,
started to follow me.
I just... I don't know. I'm
probably just being paranoid.
- (DISTANT HOWLING)
- (GASPS)
That's not paranoia.
- That's a psi-hound.
- Rose thinks everything is a psi-hound.
What's a psi-hound?
- (GROWLING)
- (NATALIE YELPS)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(DISTANT HOWLING)
- What's my backpack doing over there?
- Lissa, no.
Lissa!
(LISSA GASPS) Oscar! Oh, my God.
(GASPS)
Oscar.
- Lissa, just...
- No, Rose!
(SIGHS)
(THUD)
Shadow-kissed Rose,
you're bound to Lissa,
and it's up to you to help her.
Don't you understand?
The more that Lissa uses her
powers, the worse it'll get.
The more dangerous it will be.
They came for me.
They'll come for her.
What are you talking about?
Is it the Strigoi?
(LAUGHS)
This isn't about Strigoi.
Not everything to be feared roams
outside the gates of St. Vladimir's.
- I don't understand.
- Oh, you couldn't understand it.
You don't have to understand.
Look at me.
No, please, Ms. Karp,
not compulsion, please.
- I beg of you, please!
- I'm not taking your memories away.
Just hiding them for a bit.
(ECHOING) Lissa's life is in peril.
You only need to know you have to
get her away from the academy.
Forget everything I've said
until it's time not to forget.
(AIR BRAKES HISSING)
ROSE: I guess you could say
that it was half-repression
and half-compulsion,
and when you asked me
why we left the academy
in the first place,
a part of me couldn't remember.
I just knew that we had to get out.
Outrageous.
What Headmistress
Kirova means to say
is that it was brave of you
to come forward, Rose.
Well, I'm doing it for Lissa.
She needs help.
But is it really true she
can bring the dead to life?
Dead's dead... but from
the brink of death.
Not since St. Vladimir, and he
never declared a magic, either.
But there is no actual proof
to anything you're saying.
We found no cameras,
and the compulsion alone
can only be done in specific
environments by trained professionals.
Well, Lissa had no problem doing it
to you, right in your own office.
Surely, you had to wonder why you
didn't just throw me out of school.
It's outrageous.
Enough, please.
Ms. Sonya Karp. I want to
see the Day Six footage.
I've had a rough night.
Don't make me crawl through
a ventilator shaft
and lower myself down into the
security center on a wire.
Headmistress, we have no right to keep
Rose in the dark for as long as we have.
All right. All right.
Take her downstairs.
Show her everything.
Show us Karp Day Six,
please. Thank you.
(COMPUTER KEYS TAPPING)
(COMPUTER CHIMES)
I knew this is what
you were looking for.
Couple months after you left,
Ms. Karp had a complete breakdown.
And did the doctors
find a way to help her?
She found a way to help herself.
Karp was not like the others.
She didn't become Strigoi for
the power or the immortality.
She just... wanted
the pain to go away.
Nobody likes to talk about it,
but the most effective way
for the undeclared to take
away their special anxiety
is for them to take a
life and become Strigoi.
Strigoi have an inner clarity.
No feelings. No worries.
- No weakness.
- (GASPS)
DIMITRI: She got away.
We don't know where she is now.
(GASPS)
Roza? Roza, calm down.
- I'll protect you.
- (LAUGHS) Roza?
It's not Karp. It's Lissa.
She's upstairs, and she's...
she's pissed.
LISSA: Cuts on my arm?
Is that what she said?
And without the use
of a blade, no less.
I know I've been having
trouble declaring a magic,
but that seems a pretty
pointless skill.
Allow me to put your mind at ease.
Rose is a dear friend, but she
has a talent for tall tales.
Kirova's letting herself be compulsed
even after I gave the compulsion speech!
It's classic!
Ever since the accident,
it's like my life has
been on autopilot.
I guess in Ms. Karp's own
spooky way, she was trying
to help me figure it all out,
but who do I have now?
There is another person
who can help you.
He is on our flags,
posters, uniforms
and the statue in the
middle of the school.
St. Vladimir?
OK. I'm on it.
So, is this where the
outcast losers hang out?
- How did you know...?
- Books on St. Vladimir. Now.
Before, I was asking.
This is me telling.
- God, you're annoying.
- I'm right that this could help Lissa.
Yeah. That's what's
so annoying. Come on.
God, what's a girl got to
do to get a definition
- of "shadow-kissed" up in this...
- Check this out.
"Vladimir had mastered
a very rare magic,
and this magic had a name: Spirit."
All this time, Lissa's
been beating herself up
about not being able
to declare a magic.
Oh, my God, if she only knew.
This makes Lissa more special
and valuable than
I ever even imagined.
I guess I should be happy that the bad
guys aren't trying to kill Lissa,
but it kind of just makes things
more sick and disgusting.
What do they want from Lissa?
What is the point of killing her
cat and setting up cameras?
- Who could be that cruel?
- Headmistress Kirova could be.
And Mia likes to film her pranks.
- That...
- I know.
Both a little on the nose, but...
No, maybe they're so obvious
that they're not obvious.
I did see Kirova with
Mia the other night.
OK, my conspiracy theory of choice
is that someone might be
trying to drive Lissa mad,
to take her out of
throne contention.
I mean, we all know Queen
Tatiana has her issues.
All three witches could
be working together.
I like the way your mind works.
Just hold that thought.
"At times, after the expense of
power and in times of trauma,
Vladimir's agony would manifest
directly onto his skin."
So this proves that
Lissa's not a freak.
Sort of. I mean, it shows that
she could be rehabilitated.
Wait. Lissa does something
like that to herself?
- Cuts and scars and...
- Yes.
Christian, she really could have used
your support these past few weeks.
You agreed Lissa
hasn't been herself.
It's her fault we're not together.
God, the female, especially one
who lives off of blood and magic,
is going to have her mood swings.
It is never the girl's fault,
even when it is the girl's fault.
No one ever explained that to you?
You know, if you weren't so psychotic,
you'd be fun to hang outwith.
Same to you, creep.
Thank you.
- OK, bye.
- (CHRISTIAN LAUGHS)
- OK.
- See ya.
What were you doing with Rose?
You were fornicating, weren't you?
Fornicat... We were reading.
We discovered a magic
called Spirit. You have it.
Ms. Karp had it,
and so did St. Vladimir.
- He used to cut himself, too.
- Rose told you that?
- I'm gonna kill her.
- Look, stop it, Lissa.
We're trying to help you.
I know now if you don't
have any family,
you need as many friends
as you possibly...
I don't need friends or
family or pets or...
(SCREAMS)
I hate you!
(LISSA CRYING)
You liar.
- Lissa, listen...
- Don't "Lissa, listen" me.
- You've ruined my life.
- Oh, bite me.
- You wish, blood whore.
- Wow.
OK, Lissa, I need
you to understand.
We can learn how St.
Vladimir used Spirit...
- Did you kill my cat?
- Hey,
Oscar and I's relationship
was on the mend.
Lissa, this is important.
Ms. Karp turned herself Strigoi.
She didn't do it to become evil.
She did it to take away from
the scratching and
the shaking. I mean...
which future do you want, a sick
and soulless one like Karp's
or an epic one like Vladimir's?
Stop talking to me about
the past and the future,
because I only care
about the present.
You know, if you have to choose one,
pick the one that's happening right now.
I am Princess Vasilisa Dragomir.
I'm the last of the Dragomir line.
If they see I'm weak,
they'll attack.
This isn't about a "they" anymore.
This is about you! This is...
- (SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
You're awake, finally.
The princess has been going
through feeders all morning.
How are you?
I don't know. You tell me.
I'm afraid to even look.
I can move it,
that's a good sign, right?
Rose, I don't know how
to say this, but...
you are not injured.
That's easy for you
to say, comrade.
I heard the crack.
I saw the bone...
Sorry to interrupt.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Here.
- Thanks.
So, I saw Aaron go by.
- I kicked him to the curb.
- Mmm.
When I saw your leg, I got
everything out of my system.
- Everything.
- Thanks for that, by the way.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- Ugh.
I'm so glad you're both alive and
not at each other's throats.
This whole matter of Spirit
has taken us by surprise.
Until the advisers
arrive from Romania,
we'll be sequestering
you both into a bunker,
away from any excitement.
No classes, and obviously
you will not be attending
- the Equinox Dance tonight.
- Oh, nonsense.
Please, you have to come.
I'm gonna go with the headmistress
on this one, Prince Dashkov.
Besides, we're all forgetting
the most important thing.
- We have nothing to wear.
- There the gods have smiled upon us.
Today is an overcast day,
and I have engineered a
little shopping expedition.
Please? You know how
much I need your help.
And plus, when has shopping
ever not cheered you up, Lissa?
Where is Rose?
(ROSE SHOUTS, GRUNTS)
(DIMITRI AND ROSE CHUCKLE)
(GROANS) OK.
What was that about?
It's just a little something Dimitri and
I do to keep each other on our toes.
Wow, that was weak. How long
have you been in crush with him?
I am... very sure that I don't
know what you're talking about.
- (ENGINE STARTS)
- (POP MUSIC PLAYING)
- So, do I get a silver stake?
- That would be a... no.
But remember, today you are
not just Lissa's friend.
Spiridon.
Ain't likely any Strigoi
is gonna make a play
in a public place
in broad daylight,
but if Dimitri ain't
giving you a stake, missy,
you should have one
of these bad boys.
'Causes a blinding flash of
UV light. Buy you some time.
Well, at least someone
thinks I'm worth a weapon.
So, my superpower turned out
to also be my Kryptonite.
Wow, Your Highness with the
pop culture reference.
You know, I...
I confused power with popularity.
(LOUD SHRIEKING)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
Ever wonder what it'd be
like to be like that?
It's not our destiny.
Destiny? I hate that word.
You know, "royal responsibility,"
"the Moroi come first,"
it's all so twisted.
It's not twisted. I'm your Dhampir
and you're my Moroi. Done.
Some days we're kooky teenagers,
and other days I'm risking
my neck to protect you
from an ancient race of
predatory vampires...
or whoever else, and that's life.
At least until they come up
with a better word for it.
Somebody looks tense. Free massage?
(GROANING)
I'm really sorry. I'm so sorry, OK?
Run.
Ms. Karp, I understand all that,
but Mia and my brother...
don't think so.
Andre was generous and
funny and amazing,
but... he could kind
of be a player.
Lissa, don't look like you don't
know what I'm talking about,
'cause I can feel you, OK?
You know, I hate having a
best friend I can't lie to.
Do you really think
Mini-Mia's behind everything?
No, not exactly.
But I think we'll find out tonight.
Tomorrow you're getting sequestered
away by Spirit advisers,
so the dance is the last chance
for anybody to try to get to you.
Look, if you could put a pin in all
that, we have more vital matters.
Finding you a dress.
(SINGSONGY)
I can go into my trust fund.
I could not possibly accept that.
That's your dress. That's the
dress you were born to wear.
Lissa, we have more important
things to do than sh...
That is my dress.
Thank you, sir, and if you
could just sign here?
And that is your necklace.
ROSE: That is my necklace.
That's not your necklace.
So not my necklace.
Did you take my lip gloss?
Corpse Number Five? Like I'd
wear your pale-ass lip gloss.
No way.
Natalie, you look gorgeous.
Rose... this is for you,
from my father.
That's my necklace.
Daddy saw you looking at it. Here.
- How does it look?
- Beautiful.
(METAL MUSIC PLAYS ON COMPUTER)
All right, ladies.
I don't know what's
gonna happen tonight.
At this point, I can't remember
who loves us and who hates us...
but I do know that we are
going to own this dance.
Let's make tonight our bitch.
(♪ BEAR IN HEAVEN "SINFUL NATURE")
(HISSING)
Not much of a reaction
from your boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend, but...
grading on the Dimitri curve,
a huge reaction...
mammoth, gargantuan.
Come here.
Genuinely un-small.
Christian Ozera.
At a school dance.
After this week, I thought I'd
lost the ability to be surprised.
I'm sorry about that
kiss the other day.
What about the one right now?
(♪ KATY PERRY "SPIRITUAL")
- Rose.
- Hey, what's up?
- (SIGHING) OK.
- Rose, you look...
No, you don't get to stare at her.
I took it upon myself to talk to
these royal pains in the butt.
ROSE: Hmm.
Don't you have something to say?
- We're sorry.
- Hmm.
We didn't do anything to
you that we said we did.
You're telling something that never
happened actually never happened?
Thanks.
Mia let us have sex with
her if we obeyed her.
I tagged the note at the church
and air-blasted the memorial.
What did you think of
the scary screen saver?
We actually put a lot
of work into that.
And the bloody one just happened.
We thought it'd be fun to all
hook up in the princess's room,
and things got out
of hand, literally.
It's called blood splash.
It's a new Moroi fad,
where when things get hot and sticky,
you fang open your wrist and spray.
Ew! Stop. I nap on that couch.
OK, what about the cat?
We thought it was a fox.
Hurting animals...
that's disgusting.
Said the creepy blood splasher.
Please, Rose, don't kick my ass.
ROSE: Go dance with Natalie.
Go, now.
(SIGHS)
Oh, Jesse.
- Who's the man?
- You are so the man.
Break the case wide open and
I still only get the cheek.
Ouch.
Ever feel like you're
being watched?
Can we pretend the past
month never happened?
Why were you in the hospital?
Pregnant?
- I guess not.
- Herpes?
Maybe your baby has herpes.
I don't care if it's true. I'll tell...
- Go away, Mia.
- Why are you Dragomirs such drags?
First Andre, then you steal Aaron
from me and don't even keep him.
- I don't need this.
- I vow to take down the entire...
I'll fire-magic you into ash.
I'll just water-magic
myself before you can...
Gosh, you two are a riot.
Allow me, Mr. Ozera.
Rose, I hear you and the
princess are friends again.
Too bad... could have
made a great team.
Oh, nice wrist corsage, Splashy.
Your sex slaves told me
everything, and poor Aaron
had no idea what a
sociopath you really are.
- I'll bet you did off Lissa's cat.
- Oscar? I gave him treats.
I would never hurt a kitty.
Oh, my God, you poor little...
All this time, me thinking
that you're a villain
when you're really just...
you're just an insecure little girl
in desperate need of attention.
- (SHRIEKS)
- (CROWD GASPS)
Everyone saw that I tried to
take the high road there.
- CHRISTIAN: Rose.
- Sort of.
If Mia didn't do it, that means there's
a bigger threat still out there.
- Hathaway, you're out of here.
- Lissa's run off. I didn't see where.
Oh, God, if only there was a secret place
that she went to when she was sad.
- Right.
- Genius.
(GROANS)
OK, OK.
OK.
(SIGHS, WHISPERS)
Please, please, please, please.
- LISSA: Christian.
- We need to get you somewhere safe.
- Just a little longer in the moonlight.
- No, no.
Our moonlight.
OK, now we need to go.
- (CHRISTIAN GRUNTS)
- (LISSA SCREAMS)
Lissa.
Headmistress Kirova,
we need to get Dimitri.
- The princess is in trouble.
- She's not the only one.
- You don't understand.
- I do understand, Rose.
I understand more
than you'll ever...
(GASPS)
I could have been a model.
A man in Milan gave me
his card when I was 16.
(KNOCKING)
Dimitri? Dimitri, open up.
Dimitri, something has happened.
Rose, what's wrong?
What's right?
Sweet sassy molassey.
What do you want, Rose?
Some of that.
This is insane.
What are we doing?
Everything.
I love your dress.
Let's burn it.
(ROSE GASPS)
Love charms... hypnotic,
dangerous, put over jewelry...
Forget about it. Lissa's been
kidnapped. We have to hurry.
Report from the gate.
Nothing's come in or out.
They're still on academy ground...
Have you cleared this with Kirova?
Better to beg forgiveness
than ask permission.
Yeah, and I put a
sedative in her ass.
Let me concentrate.
You've got to be kidding me.
- DIMITRI: What is it?
- Nothing. Hold on. OK.
SPIRIDON: He's coming in.
Check the blindfold.
No compulsion tonight.
I can't make out anything
through the blindfold,
but I know that voice.
It's... that guardian.
- Oh, no.
- DIMITRI: "Oh, no," what?
"Oh, no," who. The bad
guy's Victor Dashkov.
Welcome, Vasilisa.
How was the dance?
It's officially tomorrow,
and, as promised,
we have much to talk about.
Forgive me if I don't
make eye contact.
- I've seen you in action.
- Why are you doing this?
My dear, the simple truth is,
I need you to heal me.
Testing you with the
animals was misguided,
but earth-magicking the cement
and shattering Rose's ankle
was supremely clarifying.
You're forgetting something.
My bond with Rose is
practically a psychic GPS.
Ah, yes, but the necklace
gift that I gave to Rose
is bathed in a very
expensive love charm,
and she is a little too preoccupied
to be of much use to you.
That's what you think, mother...
Victor wants her to heal him.
You were my family's
most cherished friend.
Why didn't you just ask me?
How touching...
genuinely, my darling,
but a chronic disease
like my Sandovsky's needs
continual healings, and then
there is the other matter.
The physical toll on me.
Yes, Spirit users take their
power from their own essence.
To heal another requires
giving part of oneself,
and it can destroy one over time.
You want me to give
up my life for yours.
Basically. But, you see, my dear,
I am much more important than you,
and the Moroi need a strong
leader, but my disease means
that I cannot occupy my
rightful place upon the throne.
But you shouldn't bother
your pretty little head
about all this royal intrigue.
Guess what, Victor.
The spirit in this pretty little
head isn't going to heal you.
- You can't make me.
- (GROANS) Bring in Kenneth.
Do you know somebody named Kenneth?
Your compulsion won't
work on Kenneth.
He's blind, but he's one of the
Moroi's most ingenious air users.
- Shall we begin? Heal me.
- Go to hell.
You're up, Kenneth.
(GASPS)
- (BLOWING)
- (GASPS, SCREAMS)
- Rose?
ROSE:
Don't stop. They're torturing her.
Heal me.
- (INHALING)
- (LISSA GASPS)
(GASPS)
Now he's...
(CHOKING)
(GASPS)
Ah, Lissa.
Heal me.
(CANE CLATTERS)
My...
this really worked out.
Take the girl upstairs
till departure.
Rose, stay here. It's too dangerous,
you'll just get in the way.
- But...
- Do I really need to remind you
the last time I said
"stay in the car"
and was disobeyed?
No, I totally understand.
Good luck.
- You're not really staying, are you?
- What do you think?
But what did Dimitri mean by
"last time I said 'stay in the car" '?
He was talking about another
girl from another time.
She was a novice.
I'm a guardian.
Let's roll, fire magic.
I need a seeing-eye dog.
(GRUNTING)
Take my arm.
The princess is upstairs.
(GRUNTING)
No, no, not this way.
- Rose.
- Keep going.
- It's right up there.
- Rose!
What?!
- (YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
(THUD)
(BUZZING)
(GRUNTING)
Spiridon, send for the girl.
We're ready now.
I believe you can fly.
(GRUNTING)
Feel free to chime in at any
time with some fire magic.
Maybe a ring of flame
around the knob?
I've never really worked outside
a classroom setting before.
Forget it, she's gone.
Stop trying to save yourself, Liss.
Stupid one-way bond.
(GASPS)
(SNARLING)
- (LOUD GROWL)
- (GASPS)
(HOWLS)
Psi-bounds.
(BOTH GROWLING)
Expensive to breed,
difficult to train,
but there is no denying the
brilliance of the psi-hounds.
They will stalk the
princess, maneuver her,
but they won't attack
unless I say the word.
(SNARLING)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
(BANGING AND GRUNTING)
I presume you can deal with that?
They say Dimitri is a god.
Well, I'm an atheist...
an atheist with a big gun.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(SNARLS)
(GRUNTING)
That's it? Seriously?
(GRUNTS)
I've waited for this moment.
Do you know what it's like to always be
referred to as the second best guardian?
No.
(SPIRIDON SCREAMS)
Are you OK?
- Did you see what Victor did?
- I know. What an asshole.
I hate to interrupt, but unless
either of you can fly a chopper,
- maybe we should get going.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (LISSA SCREAMS)
- Lissa, get back.
Rose, be a dear and step
away from the princess.
I don't want to accidentally
shoot her when I'm shooting you.
You heard him, he won't shoot me.
- I am your guardian.
- No, Rose, you can't do this.
ROSE:
Lissa, don't you dare fight. Lissa.
- You're worse than a Strigoi.
- Christian!
Do you know what I like
most about the psi-hounds?
They're wonderful at tracking.
They're even better at killing.
- Attack!
- (SNARLS)
(BARKS)
No.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(PSI-HOUNDS YELPING)
Now, that's some
freaking fire magic.
Rose, I need to save
him, but I can't.
Victor took everything,
all my energy.
Power up, Princess.
(SIGHING)
- (THUD)
- (SIGHS)
(GASPS)
KIROVA: This has been a night that
St. Vladimir's will never forget.
We have extra guardians manning the
academy perimeter. Nothing can get in.
Victor Dashkov will be confined
to a holding cell downstairs
until he can be transferred to the
Royal Court Prison to await trial.
How's Natalie? She worshipped her
father. She must be devastated.
The other members of the Dashkov
family are removing her from school.
For the best.
Uh-oh, Rose. This came for you.
Oh, great.
KIROVA:
Uh, Dimitri, one last thing...
The time gap after Rose so
dramatically burst out of my office...
DIMITRI: It should all be
explained in the other file.
A Nobu charm was put on a
necklace Rose had been wearing.
The spell caused Rose to attack
me and me to attack her.
I disengaged the necklace before
critical... violence could occur.
Mmm.
Hey, we should probably talk
about what happened earlier.
I just want you to know I
would never use the words
"sweet sassy molassey"
unless under the influence.
It is not a matter of
amusement or discussion.
- It was horrific.
- Horrific...
isn't really the first
adjective that comes to mind.
Don't make light of this.
It's one thing if I were
36 and you were 28,
or me 28 and you 20.
That's a lot of math for
someone who's not interested.
Your life is about
homework, dances, parties.
How can you say that
after what happened?
It's what it should be about.
I'm not interested
in you in that way.
- OK.
- It was...
- ...just a spell.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Let it go.
- Got it.
- Rose?
- Yeah?
You're still here?
I'm not sure how I feel about this,
but Victor has requested
a moment of your time.
Yeah, no, that's not gonna happen.
He said something about you
being "shadow-kissed"?
She's not going. That's final.
Don't tell me what to do.
ROSE: You look good, Vic.
Which is ironic, considering it
means more time rotting in jail.
Don't take this the
wrong way, Rose, but...
I probably should have killed you.
There's a compliment
in there somewhere.
I spent a lot of
money on that charm.
It didn't quite work
out the way I wanted.
Mmm. It worked out well enough.
Caused a man with no interest in
me to burn off my dress, so...
You're so tough, so one-of-a-kind.
But you're still a girl.
All this has happened,
and what you want to know is,
"Does Dimitri really like me?"
It's a powerful charm, Rose,
but it's not that powerful.
There has to be a degree of affection
and attraction already in place.
Happy?
- Shadow-kissed?
- Ah, yes. I owe you that.
You see, I didn't begin
to track Vasilisa
with some silly old raven.
My eye was on her long before.
I've seen the accident report.
And there's absolutely no way that
either of you should have survived.
The accident was what woke
her spirit in the first place.
The fear of seeing you
dead made it burst out,
allowing her to heal,
made you form your bond.
Rose...
you've been kissed by shadows.
You've crossed over into death,
into the other side, and returned.
Don't you think that leaves a
mark on the soul... somewhere?
That's why you're not afraid
to show your feelings, Rose,
your passion, your anger.
That's what makes
you remarkable. Yes.
But it's ironic... considering.
Considering what?
(CHOKES)
(CHOKING)
Considering I'll have to kill you.
Natalie. You made your own
daughter turn Strigoi?
And how do you think I can
circumvent the outside security?
I'd do anything for my daddy.
(ROSE GRUNTING)
All that training, and yet,
I'm going to obliterate you.
VICTOR: You see, Natalie was not
the innocent you thought she was.
In fact, she was the one who
provided me with the intel
regarding you,
Dimitri and Vasilisa.
The cat was my idea.
Daddy wanted to do another fox.
(MOCK GASP) Father, look.
Rose does choke before Strigoi.
(GROANING) I don't understand.
To become a Strigoi,
don't you have to...
Yes. I chose Ray to be my first.
Killing him was a lot more fun
than losing my virginity
to him would've been.
And with a lot more blood.
- (HISSING)
- Too soon?
(GRUNTING)
- (HISSES)
- (GRUNTING)
(SPITS) Hey, Victor?
Aren't you afraid your
new Strigoi daughter
won't be able to resist
your Moroi veins?
Don't be ludicrous.
I'm gonna wait outside, Natalie.
Finish her off.
You don't know what high school
is like for a loser like me.
I was so scared all the time...
so weak, so sad, so lame.
Now my eyesight is perfect,
my skin is clear,
and so is my mind.
I may be dead, but I have
never felt so alive.
How awesome for you. Say cheese.
- (SCREAMING)
- (GRUNTS)
(WEAKLY) Rose?
Oh.
(GRUNTS)
(BEEPS)
(DOOR HISSING)
(CRUMBLING)
Maybe I won't kill you.
Maybe I'll make you just like me.
That way, we can be
friends forever and ever.
BFF! (HISSES)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GROWLING)
(CHOKING)
Who's choking now?
Roza, Roza.
Oh, my Roza.
Lissa, you're gonna
want to see this.
I don't believe my eyes. You got him
wearing a color other than black.
LISSA: Baby steps.
Oh, Rose, wait.
There's so much to read here.
Apparently, Vladimir and Anna
almost drowned in this flood,
but he saved them from certain
death, and listen to this.
"It took many years for Vladimir to
master the power of his Spirit."
"Despite his sufferings
and delusions,"
"he never contemplated
the way of the Strigoi,"
"because he always
had the strength"
"of his shadow-kissed guardian,
Anna, to see him through."
Similarities. Weird.
Well, Christian, for us, weird...
Doesn't begin to cover it.
(SIGHS) Do I have to?
It's time.
(LAUGHTER)
- (FANFARE PLAYING)
- God, not her. Not now.
And once again, this grotesque
maelstrom of indecency
seems centered on one
royal individual.
- Where's Vasilisa Drag...
- Thank you, Your Majesty,
for allowing me to clear the air.
I finally declared a magic,
and it's called Spirit.
It may take years to
get a handle on it,
but I have a bunch of wise
men in robes to help me out.
And yes, that was not a mirage
you saw on the dance floor.
My boyfriend is Christian Ozera,
and his parents were Strigoi.
Get over it. He has.
I'm not quite sure
what you think...
- Shh! Not now, dear.
- (CROWD MURMURS)
Blood. Blood is what
connects us all.
Blood is sustenance.
Blood is family.
Blood is pain, and blood is death,
be it the fang of the Strigoi
or a drunk driver on the
wrong side of the road.
(CRYING) Blood is many things,
and sometimes it gets
so crazy and confusing
that you need a best friend
to tell you, "it's OK."
"It's all life, at least until they come
up with a better word for it."
Unfortunately, you can't
all have a Rose Hathaway.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm very lucky that she's mine,
but if you don't have a soul mate,
by Vlad, the least you deserve
is kindness and dignity and something
more original than gossip,
snobbiness, slut-shaming
and bullying.
Let's prove that Moroi
blood is worth protecting.
What do you say, everyone?
No more bad blood.
(APPLAUSE)
(APPLAUSE CONTINUES)
ROSE: So, that's Natalie, huh?
Looks... fresh.
I'm sorry.
I had to.
- I hesitated.
- Rose...
you're so brave and
strong and bold.
Sadly, you'll have many other
opportunities to kill Strigoi.
You lied about your
feelings for me.
Yes. I did.
Why would you do that?
It's more than my age and
my position at the academy.
Our allegiance is to the Moroi.
If I let myself love,
I wouldn't throw myself
in front of the princess.
I would throw myself
in front of you.
It's funny.
Your reasons for not
loving me just...
make me love you more.
I want you to kiss me without a
magic charm forcing you to do it.
That's not a great idea.
Please.
Everyone's at the banquet. Just...
one last kiss.
Yes! Yes, yes!
Yes! Are you not entertained?!
(ROSE GIGGLES)
ROSE: My name is Rose Hathaway,
and I'm not your
normal teenage girl,
but I guess, is there
really such a thing?
Every life has rules, traditions,
friends and enemies,
sheer terror and incredible joy,
- but I've learned...
- (CAWS)
Whoa! Watch where you're
going there, bird.
Are you kidding me?
- It's you, isn't it?
- (CAWS)
- Come...
my shadow-kissed soul mate.
(CAWING)
Well, same to you, buddy!
(CAWING CONTINUES)
Now!
Soon.
(STRIGOI CHATTERING AND HISSING)
(SCREECHING)