Out of my way!
Ok, here they are.
Philippe, wake up now, I bet
you 100 € that I'll lose them.
Philippe? Deal.
Let's do this!
You're in a good form tonight.
Shit!
You lost them alright.
Out of the car!
Hands on the hood!
- I'll double it.
- 200 € that they'll escort us.
You'll lose again.
-200 € on the escort!
- Come on! Show me your hands!
Your hands goddammit!
- Wait. I'm gonna explain.
- Shut up. Hands on the hood.
- Wait.
- Get out of the car. Now!
Take it easy!
He can't get out.
He can't even open the door.
Look at the Handicap Sticker!
The wheel chair in the trunk.
The guy's paralysed. Go check!
Get off me.
- He's telling the truth.
- SO!
What did you think?
You think I'm doing 180
For the fun of it?
I was going to the hospital.
I work for him. He's having a stroke!
The more we wait,
the worse it gets.
He can't move, he can't do anything.
That's why I'm here.
I think we have a problem here.
Come see this.
- What the fuck do we do now?
- That's right, think about it. Take your time.
Meanwhile call his 15 year-old daughter
tell her her father's dead because of you!
If he's not taken care of
in 5 minutes, it's over. He's dead.
But take your time.
Think. Think fast. He's dying!
Alright,
don't lose any more time. Go.
- Where are you going?
- Emergency.
We'll escort you, it's safer.
We're escorting them! Let's go!
They're gone. They're leaving.
Good.
This is so gross!
Eww! I can't handle this...
How do you produce this goo ?
OK, for now, just worry about
getting your license.
For now let's escort you,
"it's safer".
A 200 € escort.
No way! I never bet you that much.
Let's set the mood to celebrate.
"We're gonna escort
you, it's safer."
OK, OK. I helped you out of this.
An escort... A "safer" escort!
...
[Earth Wind and Fire"SEPTEMBER"]
Here he comes.
We called ahead.
A stretcher is coming.
- Alright?
- Yeah, it's fine.
- Good luck.
- Whatever.
Now what?
Now you let me decide.
THE INTOUCHABLES
Inspired by a true story.
Do you have references?
Well yes. I have my CAFAD.
A Certificate of Aptitude
for the Care of Disabled persons.
From the Bayer Institute
in the Landes country in 2001
I have a high school
"Proximity Services" diploma
and a bachelor's in "Social
and Family Economics"
I don't... like... I mean...
I've been studying more than working.
What is your main motivation?
Money. Duh!
Humanity.
I'm all about Humanity.
Good for you.
To help others, I think.
Alright ? ... Good answer ?
I like the neighbourhood.
I always loved "persons of diminished
function". Since I was little.
To promote the autonomy
of the disabled, I'd say.
Their social integration.
Sports, too.
Gotta move, you know.
For the social life, I mean.
These people can't
do anything...
I had my first
professional experience...
It was Mme Dupont Moretti.
A really old, old lady...
really old...
I attended her...
until the end, daily.
In Geriatrics we had good times too.
We had "King's cake", er...
I'm also an expert
in administrative stuff...
Financial aid. Welfare housing
I don't know if...
if you need that.
Check it out, Magalie,
but I don't think so.
- Yvan Laprade?
- Yes.
Stop, alright? It's been 2 hours.
My turn now.
Hello.
I'd like to have
a paper signed.
Please take a seat.
Do you have references?
References? Yes I have.
And...?
We're listening.
"Kool & the Gang",
"Earth, Wind & Fire".
Those are good
references, aren't they?
I don't know them. Take a seat.
If you don't know them, you don't
know anything about music.
I don't think
I'm musically uncultured.
- Even if I don't know your
"Sool and" whatever...
- No.
No, "Kool & the Gang".
What about you?
You know Chopin, Schubert, Berlioz?
You're asking
if "I" know Berlioz?
I'd be surprised
if "YOU" knew Berlioz.
Even so, I'm an expert.
Really?
Who do you know there?
- Which building?
- What do you mean which building?
But, man...
Berlioz, before being a neighborhood,
was a famous composer,
writer, critic of
the 19th century.
It's a joke. I know who Berlioz is.
I see humour is like music for you.
You know nothing about it.
Tell us about your paper.
I need a signature...
To prove I came to the interview.
That says, despite my skills, qualities,
or whatever usual bullshit you use...
you're still not interested.
I need 3 refusals to get
Unemployment money again.
I understand, Unemployment benefits.
- You don't have any other motivation in life?
- Oh, sure I do.
There's one right here.
That's really motivating.
Alright, so, what now?
Sign? Not sign?
I'm sorry I can't
sign on the spot.
Why is that?
Why?
Oh, that's annoying.
It's just... I have a deadline,
and since I'm pretty late...
It's "a bit annoying", indeed.
Can't Miss "Motivation"
sign for you?
No, Magalie doesn't have proxy.
It's a shame.
She could have slipped
in her cel-number(06).
Alright, come back tomorrow.
9: am. Your paper will be signed.
I surely don't want to deprive
you of your Unemployment check.
- Sorry, I can't see you out.
- It's all good.
Don't get up...
I mean stay seated.
Be back tomorrow.
- Mina?
- Yeah?
- Is she here?
- No. She'll be home late.
No, no! Hey!
Turn off the tap.
I got no more water.
Turn it off!
And get out.
- I'm showering, why are you here?
- Leave me alone.
- Out!
Take them out. Come on.
Bintou, I'm not joking.
Mina!
Mina. Get your fat belly out!
Let it go!
Give me a towel.
Why are you still here...
Get out, all of you!
Bintou, come one.
Hey! Bintou!
What do you think you're doing?
Sit down.
What do you want?
Coke or this?
I want Coca-Cola.
- Where did you come from?
- From school.
Can you wipe the trash?
Where are you going now?
Horseback riding.
Be a smart ass !
It's for you.
Where have you been?
- On vacation.
- On vacation?
You think people don't
talk around here?...
...that I'm an idiot?
6 months, we don't see you!
Not one phone call. Nothing!
And you show up, like nothing
happened, giving me a Kinder egg?
You think I can pay the rent
with your scams?
The groceries?
...
This isn't a hotel!
Look at me when I'm
talking to you !
Imbecil!
- I just can't talk to you.
- You want to talk?
OK.
I'm listening.
You know Driss...
I prayed a lot for you.
But, may god forgive me...
I have other children.
I still have hope for them.
I don't want to see you
hang around here any more.
Pack your bags.
And get the
hell outta here.
Got it?
Get out.
Get out!
...and he's gone!
Good one, hey?
Ok, I'm off.
What, that wasn't funny?!
Yes?
- I'm here for my paper.
- Yes, I'm expecting you.
- For the... Unempl...
- Come in.
Can you tell Philippe
the young man is here?
Of course.
- So?
- The beets aren't ready.
- But the radishes are good.
- Fine.
- Hello.
Shall we go?
Just so you know,
he had a rough night.
(Just like you, apparently.)
The day starts
without fail at 7:AM
...with the nurse.
He needs 2 to 3 hours
of care every morning.
You should know, most people
give up after a week.
They just "parade" through here.
Well...
I like the decorations
the music, and all that...
but I don't think I'll buy it.
And I didn't plan my day around...
Listen, I was asked to give you a tour,
I also have other fish to fry.
Anyway we're almost done.
You can communicate
with a BabyPhone.
It's like a Walkie-Talkie.
You hear him, he hears you.
Under the contract,
you have a separate room.
There - the toilet.
And there - a bathroom.
Private.
Yoohoo!
It's here.
He's waiting for you.
One minute...
So I signed your paper.
It's in an envelope,
on the little table.
By the way, how do like
being on assistance?
What?
Living on the backs of others,
doesn't bother your conscience?
It's alright, thanks.
How about you?
Do you think you'd
be able to work?
I mean with duties,
a schedule...
Responsibilities.
I was wrong.
You do have a sense of humour.
So much so, that I'm willing
to try you out for a month.
Do you want a day
to think about it?
I don't think
you'll last two weeks.
What?
Not one bone not one muscle
must be overlooked.
Everything must move.
We want to keep the skin
and the joints in shape.
You need to be meticulous.
Rigorous.
Ok? Understand?
Hey, wake up!
Sleep at night!
- I'm not sleeping.
- Come help me!
We're going to put
Philippe in his chair.
Then off to the shower.
OK, here!
Try it yourself. Show me.
Don't be afraid. Go ahead.
I'm not afraid.
- There. That alright?
- Wait!
Never leave him until
he's strapped in.
It's one of my vices.
No one told me.
I'm in training!
No need for kid gloves!
Rub, for god's sake!
It doesn't foam!
It's a weird shampoo.
- How are you getting on?
- I'm washing his hair...
but it doesn't foam.
How's that?
What the hell...
are you kidding me?
You put the foot-ointment in his hair.
Wait, wait...
Please tell me you can read!
You're a clever one, aren't you?
They look the same. There should be
one for the whole body.
But there are 20.
Ok, get a move on.
I won't be here 2 hours.
- So I'm using this one?
- The one marked "shampoo".
- Are you gonna be ok?
- Of course, he'll be ok.
My feet have never
been so well "permed".
Go have your lunch, Marcelle.
Everything is fine.
Where's the matching skirt?
Those are compression stockings.
If I don't wear them, my blood won't flow
and I'll pass out.
I'm not putting stocking on you.
We have a problem here.
Since I won't do it,
we'll have to see if...
Marcelle!...
If Marcelle can come back...
and do it herself.
Since she's a girl and all,
she knows how.
I don't know why we're debating.
I'm not gonna do it.
Even for your sake ...
you might as well pass out.
You just say no, put your foot down.
Marcelle, I'm not going to do it!
You know, my stockings and your cute
little earring - they go well together.
Cut the wise cracks!
Looks like you've done it
all your life.
Ever thought about...
a vocational course in beauty care?
There. It's done.
What are the gloves for?
Er... we'll wait
a while for those.
You're not quite ready.
No. He's not quite ready.
Why "not ready"?
For what Marcelle?
- What's that for?
- We'll explain later.
Marcelle, we have to talk...
Excuse me but there's
a problem with my training.
There's nothing to "learn".
I don't do that.
I don't clean out strangers' butts.
I don't even clean out
friends' butts.
I don't clean out butts in general.
Question of principle.
Can we talk about it later?
After my lunch, for example?
No, no.
Actually, no need to talk later.
Let's stop it here.
It's weird,
but I don't like these discussions.
I said nothing about the stockings.
It cost me, but I did it.
I took a step towards you,
you meet me half way.
- Stop with the butt-cleaning.
- I think I get it.
It's not right. I'm done.
- Bon appetit.
- Thank you.
- Pretty, huh?
- I love it.
Not bothering you, am I?
Think you're in a theatre or what?
- I'm eating here.
- Hi.
- You know where I can get a beer?
- Try in your hair.
We had two 6-packs,
did you take them?
Don't know. Don't give a damn.
So take your feather
duster for a walk.
Come on, let's split.
It's the new guy
works for my father.
The "guy" has a name !
Damn.
- What?
- Sorry.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I'm massaging.
This is nuts !
Finished playing?
You don't feel
anything at all there!
What the hell...
- What are you doing?
- Experiments.
He doesn't give a damn,
he feels nothing. Look!
Stop it, you'll scald him.
Lawyer.
No, it's personal.
I'll read it later.
Personal file?
Ok.
Trash.
She's got something, though !
Could't we make a hooker file?
- Bon appetit.
- Thanks.
Please.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Shit, I keep forgetting !
Fuck, sorry !
That's good !
Driss?
Can you come?
Can you hear me, Driss?
Can you please come?
Driss.
What?
It's almost 9.
Philippe is waiting.
It's 9 already? I lost track of time.
My bath took forever to foam.
- This room's a pig sty.
- Make me a coffee, I'm coming.
The babyphone...
should always be with you.
With Nutella! Not jams made of
fruits nobody's heard of.
I'm not going in that !
Even for you!
I'm not gonna load you
in the back like a horse !
What's this one?
This is much less suitable.
- Meaning?
- I have to be pragmatic.
Pragmatic?
Oh damn!
Son of a...
Oh, that feels good !
- It does.
- So good !
She's got nerve !
Let's go.
The neighbour's parked there again.
No way to persuade him it's not his spot.
But that might change.
- Hi, how are ya?
- What?
Am I bothering you?
Wanna cup of coffee?
- Can I see that?
- What the...
Come here !
Come read this. Read! Read!
"No Parking."
- Louder! I can't hear you.
- "No Parking"!
- Good method !
- Read it all !
- "Reserved spot".
Imprint, imprint, imprint that
in your brain, and beat it !
Piss off !
We open on tuesday.
Monday night it'll be sold.
Shall we go?
You've been stuck here for an hour.
You gotta change the channel !
There's a lot of serenity
in this canvas.
And a certain violence.
I find it moving too.
Red stains on a white
ground are moving ?!
How much for this thing?
I think it's 30,000 €.
I can check if you want.
Yeah, better check.
It seems excessive, price-wise.
30,000 € for this piece of crap!
- Impossible !
- Oh, it's possible !
This dude has nosebleed on a white
board, and he wants 30000 € ?!
Driss, why do you think
people are interested in art?
- I dunno, it's a business.
- No.
Because it's the only trace
left of our time on earth.
That's crap. For 50 € in a
hardware
store, I can leave my trace too.
I can even add blue
free of charge if you want.
Stop talking nonsense.
Give me a chocolate.
No.
No feet, No sweets.
It's a joke!
Hey, I'm kidding.
- Oh it's a joke!
- Well yeah!
- A joke...
- A good one, right?
Really funny.
A schoolyard classic.
No feet, No sweets.
Give me one.
- That's wicked!!
- Cool it.
Oh come on!
No legs, Philippe.
I'll tell the tight-ass chick.
Too bad there's no audience.
Sorry, I made a mistake
on the price.
- Oh, alright !
- Yes.
It's 41.500 €.
I'll take it.
Wha...?
Hi, Philippe.
How are you doing?
You summoned me, I'm here.
I'm listening.
What's so important?
I didn't 'summon' you...
Can you guess why I'm here? No?
Who is this guy?
Everyone around you is worried.
Yvonne told me he's
reckless ... violent.
He hit a neighbour.
Philippe, I don't need to
explain to you to be careful.
You can't let just anybody
in your home.
Especially given
your condition...
First of all...
I'm not certain you know
who you're dealing with.
Go on...
I know people
in the Ministry of Justice.
He's not a mass murderer, (Mesrine)
but he has a full rap sheet.
He's just did 6 months
for a jewelry heist.
If at least he was qualified...
but I hear he sucks.
Be careful. Guys from
the suburbs have no pity.
That's it, exactly.
That's what I want. No pity.
He often hands me the phone.
You know why? He forgets.
So it's true. He has no
special compassion for me.
He's big, has strong arms
and legs,
a brain that works, healthy.
So for the rest, given my
'condition' as you say...
Where he's from, what he's done.
I don't give a damn.
As you wish.
That's all you wanted to say?
Hey, Magalie.
- Do you have a minute?
- No, not really.
Not for long,
just to show you something.
- What is it?
- Don't freak out, come see.
- One minute, that's it.
- Deal.
- So?
- So I have a bathtub.
See.
- Really fascinating...
- Yeah.
- So what?
- So...
we could take a bath.
It's big. There's room.
I have bath salts, bubbles...
OK.
Why not, after all?
Yeah, why not?
Go ahead.
- Start undressing.
- You wanna be naughty.
I like that.
I'll take off my clothes.
No problem.
What?
Hey where are you going?
You said yes!
Even without soap,
just a rince.
What...?!
When the mail comes,
I'm always a bit tense...
As Apollinaire said...
Colon, open quotes...
'Without news from you I feel hopeless ...
Wait.
I'm lost, you're going too fast.
I'm still at "As Apollinaire said"
Colon, open quotes,
"Without news of you I feel hopeless"
Don't you get it ?
This is an intimate moment !
- Nope, I don't get it.
- Give it back.
I'll quit it if you explain.
There's nothing to explain.
He's doing his correspondence.
Correspondence?
- With whom?
- Mostly women.
No kidding ! Who ?
With one in particular.
Eleonore.
Who is this Eleonore?
I've never seen her.
How come?
That's the basis of
an epistolary relationship.
Means they write to each other?..
Correspond solely by mail?...
Fine, I got it.
Are those the blue envelopes?
He's a player !
He 'epistols' like a pistolero.
What about you?
No special little friend?
Not even Albert, the gardener?
- Not at all.
- I noticed it !
He has that look just for you.
Am I right, or am I not?
- Stop it ! This is ridiculous!
- Did he plant it in you ?
- What ?
- His little cucumber?
What?
- Am I dreaming this ?...
- Albert, Albert...
- Soon.
- No !
Soon, trust me.
Fuck.
Hello...
You alright?
You want the music?
Stay calm.
Calm down, Philippe.
Philippe. Oh, Philippe.
Try to relax.
Breathe slowly.
Are you with me?
You'll be alright.
I need air.
Air!
Feels good to breathe !
- What time is it?
- Dunno, must be 4.
Been a while since I saw Paris
at this time of the morning.
What happened?
It's beyond medication.
Doctors call them "phantom pains".
I call it "being a frozen steak
in a burning pan".
I feel nothing, yet I'm in pain.
Hard to believe there's
nothing to relieve it.
There goes what could relieve me.
We're all sick over that...
I might even be sicker than you.
By the way, I meant to ask you...
about with women...
Can you...? what happens with...?
One adapts.
But concretely...
Can you do it or not?
Concretely, I don't know if you're aware,
I feel nothing between my neck and toes.
So you can't.
It's complicated.
I can, but...
I can't always decide when.
One finds one's pleasure elsewhere.
Really?
You can't imagine.
I sure can't. What for instance?
For instance, the ears.
What about the ears?
It's a particularly, erogenous zone.
Very sensitive.
So your thing is
to get your ears licked?
I'd never have imagined !
Philippe.
- Have a hit. It'll do you good.
- What's this bullshit.
Go ahead and see.
Puff.
Come on, puff.
Alright, let's share.
More.
- A bit more.
- Enough for tonight.
That thing about the ears intrigues me.
It really turns you on?
So if you have red ears,
it means you're excited?
That's right.
Sometimes I even wake
up with stiff lobes.
Both of them?
I met Alice, my wife, when we were
studying Poli-sci. We were 20.
She was tall and elegant.
Smiling eyes.
I saw pictures at your place.
The blonde one, right?
She's not bad.
We had an incredible
time together.
I wish you the same.
Damn, I loved her so much!
Then she got pregnant
once, twice...
Five miscarriages in a row.
The doctors diagnosed her
with an incurable disease.
We decided to adopt.
Sir.
Please.
Please!
Yes.
I want...
I'll have a tarte tatin.(upside-down tart)
But cooked through. Because there was
a problem with the chocolate pastry.
It was raw, it oozed...
flowing everywhere. Weird !
That's the whole point
of 'mi-cuit' (half-baked)
- That's why ?
- Yes.
I still want a tarte tatin.
I always liked competition.
Extreme sports, speed...
Going faster, higher...
With paragliding I had it all.
I could go high,
see things from above, and breathe.
I was raised with the idea
that one pissed on the whole world.
I'd like to drink something.
My mouth's a bit dry.
It's one side effect of the joint
- What are the others?
- It makes you hungry...
And chatty.
In paragliding,
bad weather can be unforgiving.
But you went, in spite of it.
Maybe to to share Alice's pain,
because I knew she wouldn't make it.
Result:
neck cervicals 3 and 4 broken.
And just my head to get high with.
When the pain leaves me,
I still have my mind.
My true handicap is not
being in a wheel chair.
It's being without her.
What do the doctors tell you?
With the scientific progress,
I can keep on until I'm 70.
With massage and medication.
It's expensive...
still, I'm a rich quadraplegic.
If it was me,
I'd do myself in.
That too is difficult for a quadraplegic.
Yeah, that's right !
Damn, that's tough !
What's the date today?
I don't know, the
8th or the 9th...
So it's official!
- What?
- You won the bet.
Your trial period is over.
- So I'm hired?
- Of course you're hired.
- Can I rely on you?
- Yeah.
Good.
Start by giving me back
the 'Fabergé' egg.
It's a gift from Alice.
She got me one a year. I have 25.
One each year we were together.
I'm really attached to them.
No. I don't know, what you...
It wasn't me.
What is it you lost...?
Nina.
- What are you doing here?
- Hurry up, get in.
Put your seatbelt on.
How are you?
How is school?
Why don't you answer my text messages?
I was busy.
So tell me, who was on the phone?
A detective, he wanted to talk to mom.
I faked her voice and told him
we'd be over to see him.
Did you find my egg?
Did you find the egg or not?
I don't care about your stone egg !
And I didn't find it.
What did you tell them?
Nothing.
What would I tell them?
They caught me with only 30 grams.
You know: Police Custody, then bye bye.
Shall we get a Greek kebab?
- I'm not getting in.
- Cool it.
- Let me go!
- Shut up. Who's taking you home?
- Who's taking you home?
- Piss off !
- None of your business.
- Get lost!
"Her polished eyes are carved
in delicate minerals,
"And in this strange and
symbolic nature...
"And in this strange
"and symbolic
- "nature...
- Damn, that's boring !
"Where the pure angel merges
with the antic Sphinx."
I never know if 'Sphinx'
takes a 'i' or a 'y'?
All this gives me a headache.
It's an "i". And singular.
What's all this crap for ?
A sphynx, daisies, angels...
Would you care for a
guy who talks like this?
Of course, there is
a more basic approach.
"merges with the antic Sphinx"
What, next?
What does Eleonore look like?
I don't know, It's not important.
It's intellectual. Emotional.
I don't focus on the physical
but on a relation of the spirit.
Fine, the spirit...
But if she's a skank.
It's a relation with
the spirit of a skank.
Very elegant !
Really !
What can I say...
Bravo.
How long has it been going on?
This guy's such a pain!
Six months.
Six months?
And you've never seen her?
She might be ugly, fat...
or even handicapped !
After the poem add:
'by the way, how's your weight?
Write it.
Thanks a lot, Driss
for your pertinent advice.
Let's get back to it.
Where was I?
I think a sphynx was eating daisies,
in seventh heaven, doing weird stuff.
Alright...
'strange and symbolic nature'
And in this strange and
symbolic nature...
You gotta call her.
- Where the pure angel merges
with the antic sphynx...
You gotta call her.
I'm telling you.
I can get a lot more across
in writing. Alright !
Unbelievable !
Fine, but I'm gonna find her number.
This is stressing me !
Hey!
She's from Dunkerque.
That's not good.
Put down the envelope.
Never seen a 'Miss France' from Dunkerque.
Usually they're dogs over there.
Put that down immediately.
She added her number. Handwritten!
It's a sign. She wants you to call !
Leave it, please !
She handwrote her phone number.
What do you think it means?
"Call Me".
"I want to lick your ears".
- Yes, Philippe.
- You're not calling her ?!
She doesn't care about poetry.
Six months of poetry...
The guy's nuts !
- I won't talk to her.
- I'm gonna check if she has a weird accent.
Dunkerquers are hicks.
Put down the phone!
"Ah wants me some Philippe"
She's gonna get some.
Hello.
Nice voice, for starters.
Hello...
- No.
- Hello...
- Improvise, talk about daisies and shit...
- Eleonore?
- It's Philippe.
Well I...
I'm calling you because I really
wanted to hear your voice.
And your merest 'Hello'
overbrims me.
Hold on. I'm gonna get her.
Cut the fancy talk.
- Hello.
- Eleonore. It's Philippe.
Philippe?
I was writing you a letter, and
suddenly I thought, why not call her?
Don't forget to ask
about the weight.
- Pardon me?
- No. Nothing.
"I'm in mourning,
"I cry,
"I'm afraid. A little coolness, Lord,...
Yes, that's it! "Vierge folle".
You're unstoppable !
- Great that you love Rimbaud !
- Pardon.
- I was first in line.
- Eleonore.
I'm glad.
Yes, I am.
- Chatterbox! No stopping you now.
- I'm sending you kisses.
Everybody kisses,
Everybody licks ears.
Good. Well... ?
There's good news
and not so good news.
- What about the good ?
- 116 lbs.
- 116 lbs? That's good !.
Unless she's three feet tall.
The not so good news...
she wants a picture.
- So?
- Oh, funny guy !
Good evening, gentlemen.
Your tickets?
- Good evening.
- Just there.
- Very good.
- Have a good evening.
- Good evening to you.
- If you want us, we'll be here.
We won't move.
Especially him.
Wait...
What do you think women want?
I don't know.
Beauty, charm, elegance.
My ass!
They want dough. Security.
Ask this dude.
And you make a good case for it.
I might be naive, but I still hope I have
something more than my bank account..
She spent 6 months reading
your goddamn poems. And she digs it.
She's peculiar, for sure.
I'm sure she doesn't care
about the wheelchair.
That's true.
And in the north, guys beat their women
on account of the drinking.
No risk of that with you.
You bastard.
Pragmatic, no ?
Dunno if... Yeah.
The photo is a good test.
If she sends hers back
it means she'll go further.
You can send your picture with
the chair, but don't overdo it.
No need to send a
Telethon-type picture...
Drool and all...
Nasty looking !
Alright, alright.
What's his problem ?
Nuts falling off ?
I kill myse...
He's a tree.
A singing tree.
It's in german !
What? Shushing me!
It's in german anyway.
As if it wasn't enough.
You're all nuts.
Oh what torture !
- How long does it last?
- Four hours.
Oh fuck !
You were quite a hunk
back in the day !
Which one?
This one.
Or this one... It's good.
Wheelchair's not too obvious...
Still, you can see the problem,
and physically you look good.
- Are we doing this?
- I don't know.
Didn't you have a
blast on the phone?
I did.
Is that all?
- I had a major blast.
- So?
So put the goddamn picture
in an envelope.
That's what I wanna hear !
We're off !
Got a smoke ?
Never learned to knock?
You're painting?
- Yes, get out!
- You're kidding me.
Painting !
And you learned to read too !
What do you want? Get out !
Or what? You'll beat me?
Is that how you treat women in your country?
Are you stoned ?
Fuck off!
- I'll leave when I want.
- Right! Leave !
- See, I'm deciding to leave now.
- Leave!
God damn it.
Replace this picture
with the other one.
Please post it personally,
and be discreet.
As you wish.
Now throw the other
picture in the trash.
I'm losing it.
I'm shitting bricks !
- What's the problem?
- Your daughter.
- I was painting...
- You were painting ?!
Yes, whatever.
I wanted to tell you...
Set her straight
otherwise I'll smack her.
- Oh, calm down.
- No, I'm not calming anything!
You agree that
I'm your arms and legs?
Yes, alright.
I wanna be your hands too,
so I can give her a good one.
Since you can't really do much
except run her over with your chair.
Driss, don't you think
you're exaggerating? Yvonne ?
Yvonne...
Well...
She might need a
slight adjusting.
Slight ?!
She's 16, dresses and paints
her face outrageously.
French kisses her dust-mop-headed
boyfriend all over the house.
But that's none of my business.
It's her education.
What bothers me is how
she looks down her nose at everyone.
How she talks to you. To me!
What about respect?
We're not dogs !
Pardon me if
I straighten her out right now.
Alright, I get it.
Let me talk to her.
Then talk to her, fast.
I'm gonna do my stuff...
He's painting?
What is he painting?
I don't know.
Get up, Philippe.
Fits you like a charm.
Right.
You must respect people who work for me.
It's unacceptable. Is that clear?
No. Get tough on her.
And I don't want to see
your dust-mop under my roof.
- Alright! Leave me alone!
- No it's not alright !
Do I need to run you over with
my wheelchair to make you obey?
That's it. We're getting there.
- You did that?
- Yeah.
I love it.
I'm not saying I would
hang it at my place...
but it's...
How much do you think
we'll get from it?
We'll see.
We'll see more... or less?
It's...
- What the hell?
- What?
- What ?! It was no tongue !
- You're sick !
Can you boost it a bit?
I can't run in these conditions.
- I'm flooring it.
- It's like a tricycle.
Will 12 km/h suit him?
It can do 12 km/h.
Is it the maximum?
Can't we get more?
- It's the maximum.
- Alright then.
Oh yeah...
No, no.
Stick to the ears.
There.
- Bye.
Hi Yvonne.
No he can't hear. He's too far.
He can't hear, Yvonne.
Ok.
We'll be home at 8:30.
OK, we're leaving. Good bye Yvonne.
- What's up with her?
Still freaking out?
- Yeah.
It's your surprise
birthday again.
It's half an hour earlier.
Every year she gets all worked up.
She invites all my family,
and it's always exactly the same.
They mostly come to
see if I'm still alive.
Smells contrived.
I pretend to be surprised.
Everyone makes an effort.
But in the end we're
just all fed up.
Pardon.
Excuse me.
Would you mind moving over?
It's my seat.
I would mind indeed.
- Yes,yes, yes. Thank you.
Shift over. Shift, shift shift.
There.
Very nice of you.
The suit makes you
look like another man.
It looks really good.
You look like Barack Obama.
Really?
She has the hots for me, obviously.
Barack Obama. How classy is that!
It's like someone called you...
Raffarin.
(Pr. Minister 1995–97)
Or Georges Marchais.
(head of Communist Party 1972-94)
What are you up to?
You'll miss the concert.
Leave me alone.
- Having your period ?
- Piss off !
- What is it?
Elisa.
- Leave me alone.
- What did you take?
What have you done?
- Where did you find this?
- In Yvonne's purse.
Imodium?
What did you intend to do?
Kill yourself?
- You just won't shit
for 3 months.
- Leave me alone!
Wait... you took Ibuprofen too?
You're gonna die!
It's serious!
What should we do?
Call emergency?
What got into you?
It's Bastien.
- What about Bastien?
- He dumped me.
He doesn't care about me.
He called me a slut.
That's not right !
if I died it would suit everybody.
Stop talking bullshit.
Let's go downstairs.
You go see him.
Talk to him.
- To who?
- Bastien. I'll pay you.
What do you mean, pay me?
Are you sick in the head?
I don't give a rat's ass
about this kid stuff !
- Please.
- Talk to Bastien?!
Pay me?!
Who do you think
you're talking to?
Driss, please !
How much you got?
You bastard.
It has a style...
a particular touch.
But I mean... 11000 € for an
unknown artist seems like a lot.
Hmm...
On the other hand, if I don't buy it,
in a year it'll be worth triple.
And you'll say "I told you so".
Huh ?
Hmm !
- Did you say he's showing in London?
- And Berlin.
Berlin?
Well that's...
I don't know...
Hefty sum, 11000 € !
Give me something to go on.
She has someone, is that it?
Yes. Fred.
What about Fred?
They've been together
for two years.
One day it's 'on' the next
it's 'off'... a lot of tension.
Right now it's not
going too well.
- Maybe because of me.
- Mm hm !
- Did she mention me?
- No.
Of course, she did.
A little bit.
I knew it!
She's got the hots for me.
Are you pulling my leg?
- No.
- Go on, laugh !
One day Magalie
will come to my bed.
Hope springs eternal.
Easy on the appetisers,
with your gastric problems.
I'm no doctor, but if you
take Imodium, something's wrong.
Pardon me. Please...
Can I ask you a favour?
A little piece for me?
No, Philippe! We were fine !
Yes.
The Fours Seasons, Vivaldi.
L'estate (Summer)
You'll see, you'll like it.
So Driss? Don't tell me
that does nothing to you.
Nope. Nothing.
Not at all.
If you can't dance to it,
it's not music.
Let's try something else.
Yeah. I know this one.
It's a commercial!
For coffee, no?
Oyez, oyez! By royal decree !
I must hasten to the
Castle of Assholes.
And there deliver the minstrels.
Let's go !
Yes, I'm a good knight and true.
That's creepy...
It's about guys with no clothes
They're running in the fields,
but they're naked.
And giggling...
Alright, enough.
Bach was badass...
must a' been a chick magnet
with his music.
The Barry White of his time.
Oh I know this one.
Everyone knows it.
Of course.
"You have reached the Paris
unemployment agency."
"All our lines are busy."
"Estimated waiting
time is, two years."
Tom and Jerry, isn't it ?
Tom and Jerry...
What a jerk !
Help !
Help ! It's a masterpiece...
My turn, now. We listened to
your classics, let's listen to mine.
Earth, Wind & Fire. We talked about them.
Listen it's a smash !
It's something else.
That's something else for sure.
Am I right? ... Don't call
'cause I ain't answering.
Driss.
- Driss.
- I can't hear you !
Come on, it's his birthday,
dance !
Come on. For Philippe.
That's it, Yvonne.
Great, Albert.
Hup !
So...
With all that I didn't
give you my present,
it arrived this morning.
I didn't want to ruin the party,
in case she was ugly or ...
You never know.
At least she answered.
Well... Good night!
Alright, I'll open it,
It'd take you too long.
So?
She's not a dog.
Not at all.
Oh damn...!
The only girl in Dunkerque
with all her teeth !
There's a note with it.
'Passing through Paris next week.
I'm waiting for your call.' 'Dot dot dot.'
You know what it means "3 dots"?
What does it mean?
- Is that good ?
- Of course it's good, she wants you.
1 dot, 2 dots, 3 dots:
she wants to snag you - end of story.
- I'm gonna get snagged.
Feels good, doesn't it?
- I'll never get to sleep.
- But you will.
I'll put it here.
She's watching you sleep.
There.
Good night, Philippe.
Sweet dreams.
Shall we try the hat again?
- Not bad.
- No.
No, not the hat.
Looks like a chimney-sweep.
He can't be too conservative.
- What did I just say?
- Ok, so it's too classic.
- Let's forget the hats.
Classic or Grand Style?
There's something.
It works.
- What about some fishing?
- Jerk.
- Let's ride to Dunkerque
- Come on.
Yvonne will take me there.
I'll go alone.
- Really?
- It's ok.
Yes. I'll manage.
Alright.
I think I'm freaking
out a little.
Doesn't show at all.
4ac minus B².
B² ?!
I got 20, not B squ...
Hey.
Dave ? Take a hike.
- So Bastien, remember me?
- Yeah.
- Oh yeah?
- What is it?
It's not right what you said to Elisa.
Not very nice.
- I didn't say anything.
- Shut up !
Now you'll act like a
man and apologise.
- I'm sorry, man.
- Hands off me.
- Not to me, to her!
- Ok, to her.
And you'll bring her
croissants every morning.
- Plain or with butter?
- What?
- Whatever. I don't care.
Do as you want, but do it right.
- You be nice.
- Yes. I'll be very nice.
Now beat it. Move!
And comb your hair.
Wear a barrette.
What time is it?
4:45
Should I lose the hat?
Yeah. That's better.
What time is it?
46 - 47.
It doesn't change that fast.
I'd like a whisky.
Yeah.
Sir !
Another.
You're going on a date
I don't know if...
A double !
Sir, a double whisky please.
- Hello.
- Hello, Driss.
What are you doing?
Am I disturbing you?
I'm working out. So ?...
Feel like getting away?
No questions?
No. No questions.
- You wanna split?
- Yes.
Where to ?
To breathe a little.
Breathe a little?
I'll have a shower then come.
OK, let's go. Take the hat.
- But it's barely 6.
- We're going !
- Good evening.
Give him so champagne too.
It'll de-stress him.
- I'm not stressed.
- Really? - No.
It's only us?
No other people coming ?
It's just us ?
I'm not reassured.
Why?
I don't know.
Tell me you're not
the unluckiest person !
The accident...
The wheelchair... Your wife.
You got a Kennedy thing going on.
- Miss.
- Yes?
Can you give him the package, please?
Thank you.
Why?
What's that?
That's your worth in the art market.
I got 11000 € for your painting.
Keep at it, you have
a hell of a talent.
- Yup.
A very good deal.
I felt it... It was cool ... Like an instinct.
With the music and all...
A really nice mix...
Then, a sort of revelation
lit up...
Don't overdo it.
11000 €, though,
It's incredible... Aah !
What was that?
Nothing, just a hole in the cabin.
We probably won't make it.
Philippe,
tell me if there's a problem.
It was nice knowing you.
Philippe, I don't like these gags.
No, really, you're used to drama.
I'm not.
You gotta be totally
insane to do that.
A bit, yeah.
I gotta tell you, Philippe.
- You're seriously insane.
- Really? I didn't know that.
- Now you rig up Driss.
- Sure.
In your dreams !
I don't want any part of this.
I'll be waiting over there.
Taking pictures.
'Rig up Driss' !
How are you gonna take pictures?
Laugh it up.
I'm not doing this.
- No way !
- Wait.
- Take it off.
- Wait, wait.
I don't have to do this.
Wait, I don't wanna !
Hey, my shoe !
What's wrong?
My shoe !
Motherfucker !
We're climbing higher?
What's going on?
Oh my god !
Hey, Driss!
Relax, for god's sake.
I'm relaxed.
Let's get down now.
I've seen it, it's cool.
I'm done. Aaahh!!
Oh daaaamn !!
What is happening now?
Come on, Driss.
Listen to this.
Where can you find
a quadraplegic?
I don't know.
Just where you left him.
Good one, hey?
You're a bastard !
Driss, someone's here for you.
Why the fuck are you here?
You're hiding out in all this?
- How'd you get the address?
This letter from the
unemployment agency has the address.
- And what's that?
- Nothing. Let it go.
- What did you do?
- I fell from my scooter.
- From your scooter?
- Yeah.
Bullshit! Get up.
Scooter !... This way.
Damn !
You sleep here?
- Tell me what happened.
- Nothing.
- Tell me.
- Not your problem.
Just a little swelling.
How is it not my problem?
You come to hide out here
but it's not my problem?
We were only four and they screwed us.
But don't worry, we'll get 'em.
You're not gonna 'get' anyone
Does mom know?
No, what for?
- Don't worry, I'll handle it.
- You'll handle nothing !
- You're getting on my nerves.
- Alright.
Now don't touch anything
and wait here, got it?
- Can I lie down?
- You touch nothing!
Alright, I got it.
Moron...
It's alright, he's with me.
Mina, stop crying .
He's not wounded,
it's just a scratch.
It's nothing!
Don't talk nonsense, Mina.
Nobody's gonna kill anybody.
It's only threats. Only words.
I can't take care of him.
I'm working.
No, don't tell her.
Go in your room and cry if you want,
but don't tell her anything.
Time for bed, huh?
I'm gonna stay up for a bit.
Sit down.
Sit down here.
What does that woman do for you?
- Dunno, she looks hot.
- Besides that.
Shall we go upstairs now...
I have a thing to ...
I imagine she gets up...
turns around...
and I finally discover her face.
The kid resembles you.
- Adama?
- That's right.
I saw him earlier.
I think if I had crossed
him in the street,
I could have told he
was your brother.
That's funny.
Why?
Because he's not my brother.
Really?
It's complicated.
Is he your brother or not?
Fine, I get it.
Alright, let's go.
My parents...
...are'nt really my parents.
They're my uncle and my aunt.
They came to get me in
Senegal when I was 8.
They couldn't have kids, so they went
to see a brother who had a load of them.
They took the eldest.
Me.
Actually, I'm called Bakary.
That's my real name.
There were already a few Bakarys in the
neighbourhood so they called me Idriss.
Somehow it turned into Driss.
Then what?
Then out of nowhere my mother...
I mean my aunt...
she got pregnant twice.
Then my uncle died.
And then there were other
guys, other kids.
I told you it's complicated.
About Adama. Don't you think
he needs a light admonition?
He came to look for you, didn't he?
Driss.
I think we'll end it here.
You're not going to push
a wheelchair your whole life.
You worked hard,
you've earned your unemployment check.
Alright.
Let's go.
Come on.
Yeah.
Vassary Bakary. Bakary Vassary.
It's beautiful.
Very poetic.
It has an alliteration.
- Do you know what an alliteration is?
- No.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Bastien. Thank you.
Tomorrow we're having a brunch.
Could you bring something more...
Of course.
- Goodbye Yvonne.
- You didn't forget my puff pastry?
No.
- Good, thanks.
- Say hello to Elisa.
See you tomorrow.
Bastien, buddy, what's up? It's me !
So it's true.
- You're leaving.
- Yeah.
Don't worry, I have your number.
I'll call you. We'll stay in touch.
- It's gonna be tough on you.
You have to be strong.
- It's a shame.
You know I'm getting your room?
There's a water leak in mine.
I might stay, after all.
We could cuddle up
in the bed together.
It would be a bit cramped.
I'm not alone.
Here, ...
- may I introduce Frederique.
- Hello.
Hi.
Alright...
- What?
- I get it. It's your...
So that's why...
Yes.
Well.
No good bye kiss, then.
I have nothing against
a threesome.
Well... I'm raring to go.
Not now though, I have to leave.
But I can come back, if you want
- I've got stuff,
but I'll be back.
- I'm joking.
Alright...
See you, dudes.
Mr Michel Saloudy.
Keep it always on channel 2.
Are you mad at me about Magalie?
No. Well played.
Nice one, but...
it seemed weird how she could resist me.
It never happened before.
Kiss?
Yes. Sure.
Yvonne.
You leg puller, you!
Later.
Yvonne.
Wait.
We won't need that any more.
Bye.
Watch your foot.
Let's go.
Wait.
What's your bank?
Ok.
Excuse me.
Could you please move your car?
You can't park here.
It's marked over there.
- I'm moving.
- Thanks.
I'll call you back.
Why bust his balls?
We're not even driving.
A question of principle.
Go on, ahead.
Wait for me over there.
What are you doing?
I'm coming.
I can cancel my date you know.
Of course not.
Why would you do that?
Go, have a good time.
Everything's fine.
OK, Yvonne? I'm ready.
Good. I'm coming.
Well, everything's ready.
You just have to serve.
Call me if anything's wrong.
- Call me, ok?
- Yeah.
So if you're ready,
I'll serve your meal.
Take that lab-coat off.
Feels like I'm in an asylum.
- Alright.
- Do you have a cigarette?
No. I don't smoke. Not any more.
I gave it up recently and I think...
for you it's not advisable.
Even if you're not
exercising or something...
it's better for your
lungs, your breath.
You're not going to eat.
Heyyy !!
Come on. Be careful.
I'm sorry.
- Good morning, sir.
- WHAAAT !!
It's the person you asked for...
the cranial massage...Mr Jacquet.
Good morning.
Get out!
Leave me alone.
Leave!
- Is it my fault?
- No, non.
He got up on the wrong
side of the bed.
"Got up on"... Idiot.
Moron.
Driss Vassary?
- Yes.
- It's your turn.
I see you've had your
license for a month.
Yes, but I've been
driving for longer.
I mean I drove on private roads, alley-ways.
Parking lots...
I'm a good driver.
I read your file.
In your personal evaluation you
only wrote one word: pragmatic.
Yes.
It is important.
There's another important aspect
to our company, that you forgot to mention.
Did I?
Could you just take the time
to read the poster line.
- That's, Alexandrine rhyme.
Pardon?
Could-you-just-take-the-time
To-read-the-pos-ter-line
12 feet.
- It wasn't deliberate.
- Your slogan: "Just in time".
Oh that's why you got
Dali's "Melting Clocks".
A little artistic touch.
Maybe, yeah.
- You like painting?
- Oh, yes.
- I like Goya.
- It's not bad.
After Pandi-Panda
he didn't do much.
Yes.
I'm coming.
Right way.
- Are you ok?
- Yes.
Piss off !
Do you need water? A compress?
Get out.
- I mean I can...
- Get out !
There.
- Thanks, Bruno.
- You're welcome.
- Have a nice week-end.
- You too. See you monday.
- What's going on?
- He's not in great shape.
- Where is he now?
- He was in the garden earlier.
Ok.
So...
What's going on?
What's with the beard?
Serpico ?
Jean Jaurès ? Careful, they'll
name a Metro Station after you.
Victor Hugo.
You gotta shave that.
You let yourself go.
It's about time I came back.
See ya.
Now what?
Just leave it to me.
Nice, huh?
One quick slice
would fix me right up.
You're feeling better !
That's nice !
I really put my heart into it.
Open your eyes.
Oh my god.
It's atrocious.
- No! It looks good.
No.
Look...
leather jacket... sleeveless.
Gold neck-chain
Village People-cap.
Oh, I know! José Bové!
...
(enviro-anti-globalist politician)
You look exactly like him.
Really creepy.
An orthodox priest or something.
- A pope.
- Exactly, a pope.
Come on.
He's crazy.
What are you up to?
- I'm expecting the worst.
- No you'll see.
I look like my grandfather.
Really?
Oh Philippe, you dont know what your
moustache does to me I'm so turned on.
- Ok, I'll shave it all.
- Thank you.
Very well.
No. Please. No.
No.
Nein!
- Nein is what you mean.
- I'm not ok with that.
Philippe, angry ? Big angry !
So I'm your plaything now.
You're fit to be tied !
You'll end up in an asylum.
Don't you feel like
invading a few countries?
Ok, what we need here is...
one more rasor stroke.
This makes you laugh?
I'm thinking about
quadra-Nazis.
A bit odd for them
to do the Nazi salute.
Ok, fine, you had fun.
Take it off !
Heil.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
Vassary.
I have a reservation at 1.
- Yes. Vassary, # 8.
- Follow me.
- Over here.
- Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
So, Philippe.
I'm not staying for lunch.
- Why?
- I'm not leaving you alone.
Just so happens you have a date.
A date?
How's that?
Don't panic. It'll be fine.
What the...
Only this time you can't take off.
By the way...
It took some time, but I found it.
Give her a big hug for me.
Driss.
What's going on?
Hello, Philippe.
Philippe Pozzo Di Borgo now lives in Morocco.
He's married again, and has two daughters.
Abdel Sellou now owns a company.
He's married and has three children.
Philippe and Abdel
remained close friends.