What should I do with this,
Your Excellency?
Yes.
I picked it out for Daria
Alexandrovna and the children.
Bonjour, Lili.
Bonjour.
Bonjour, Grisha.
Vasya.
Who is coming to see
Grand-maman?
Me! Me! Me!
Come along,
my little ducklings.
Be good today. I'm off.
Read the chapter carefully.
I'll come back
to test you on it.
Read it twice.
Au revoir.
Oh, Stiva.
Aunt Dolly found a note
from the governess.
Well?
Stiva wants me to come to Moscow
to persuade Dolly to forgive him.
I'm to be deprived of my wife so
that adultery may be forgiven?
I can't excuse him just
because he's your brother.
Oh, it's for
Dolly's sake, too.
Four committees today.
I have the world
waiting for me.
There's never time to
look at your exercises.
Serozha is doing very well,
Your Excellency.
Who put this shirt on you?
Well, never mind.
I'll come and hear you read.
Tomorrow, perhaps.
Thank you, Lukich.
Perhaps tomorrow.
No. No, no, not tomorrow.
Thank you,
Your Excellency.
Come along.
Alexei, do you think nine years
of marriage and children
should count for nothing
against an infatuation?
No. Very well.
But sin has a price,
you may be sure of that.
But why?
Because that's
where Aunt Dolly lives.
- But why?
- I told you, Serozha.
She's not well.
I must go to see her.
But why, Mama?
Don't make Mama cry.
I'll be back before you know,
and bring you a present.
I don't want a present.
I want you to stay.
Oh, my little Kotik.
What present?
That's better.
It's the first time
I've left my little boy.
So, you're leaving your son
and I'm returning to mine.
I'm Countess Vronskaya.
I've been in St. Petersburg for the
christening of a granddaughter.
My eldest son married
Princess Chirkov.
You're a charming creature.
Why don't I know you?
I've never been
in Moscow society, really.
But you know my name.
- I've heard you mentioned.
- Talked about, you mean?
Ah, love.
- Was it love?
- Always.
My sons are ashamed of me.
But I'd rather end up wishing I
hadn't than end up wishing I had.
Wouldn't you?
I don't know.
Some man came without an
appointment, Your Excellency.
Waiting outside.
Levin!
Where did you disappear?
I'm very anxious to see you.
I need your advice.
Well, come into
my room, then.
This is my oldest friend,
Konstantin Dmitrievich Levin.
Someone send word
I'll be a few minutes late.
That's my office, up there.
Oh, I've been hard at it.
Sit down.
Hard at what, exactly?
Well, we're overwhelmed
with work.
Paperwork.
Paperwork is the soul of Russia.
Farming is only the stomach.
Now, when am I going to
come and shoot some snipe?
Look at you, in Western clothes you
told me you'd never wear again.
Something's up.
Yes, I'm in love.
I've come back to propose.
Have you guessed who she is?
I... I have a suspicion.
Why didn't you propose when you were here?
I decided it was impossible.
Kitty is of the heavens, an angel.
And I am of the earth.
But then, I thought and thought, and
there's no life for me without her
- Do I have a chance?
- Of course you do.
The Shcherbatskys are giving
a soiree this evening.
Get there early,
before the crowd.
- And if I may suggest...
- Anything, what?
- New boots.
- Right. Anything else?
We'd better have
dinner together.
Come on.
We'll meet later at l'Angleterre.
Or do you prefer
the Hermitage?
Let's say, 5:30
at l'Angleterre.
I owe them more
than the Hermitage,
so it wouldn't be fair
to withdraw my custom.
Uh, so, new boots,
coat, and a proper hat.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Do you...
Excuse me.
It's so unfair.
You marry for love.
You're a good husband.
Children arrive,
years depart.
And all of a sudden,
your wife grows old and tired.
And her hair is thin.
And her body...
And you yourself,
you still have your vigor!
And then you find yourself a martyr
to distraction by so many women.
Forgive me, but I find
that incomprehensible.
As though, I should leave this restaurant
and steal a roll from a baker's shop.
Well, you know,
a freshly baked roll.
I'm talking about love, and you're
talking about your appetite.
Easily confused.
Now, do you know, um, Count Vronsky?
Who? No. Why?
He's your rival. He turned up
from Petersburg after you left.
Who is he?
Oh, you don't need to worry about him.
He's... He's just...
He's a rich,
good-looking cavalry officer
who has nothing better to do
than make love to pretty women.
Is that cabbage soup?
Potage aux choux a la russe,
as the gentleman ordered.
It's what I wanted.
Understand that, for me, tonight
is a question of life and death.
Kostya...
Kostya, Kitty would be
mad to refuse you.
And Dolly's on
your side, you know?
She says her sister Kitty was always
meant to be your wife, and will be.
Dolly said that?
I've always thought
your Dolly was a gem.
She is.
I loved her to distraction.
Konstantin!
I'm too early.
I'll come back.
No. Come up.
Look at me.
I'm receiving for Papa and
Maman, who are late to dress.
It's my first reception.
Princess Ekaterina.
Delighted. Delighted.
I'm so pleased you were able to be
with us, Konstantin Dmitrievich.
Kitty, you look...
- You look...
- Stiva told us you were back.
How long are you staying?
I don't know.
It depends on you.
On me?
What I mean to say is I...
I only came with one purpose.
I want to...
Will you be my wife?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Wrong moment.
It's the wrong moment.
But will you?
I can't.
I'm sorry.
Yes.
It was impossible.
I'm sorry.
Are you the brother
of Nikolai Levin?
Yes.
He's in Moscow.
He's staying at the Unicorn in Khitrovka.
How do you know?
It's the sort of thing I know.
Count Vronsky?
Yes?
Princess Kitty.
It's been so long, and yet,
it seems like yesterday.
It was yesterday.
Excuse me.
No.
Sorry.
It's Kostya.
Good God! Look at him.
You look like a capitalist.
What do you want?
Nothing.
I came to see you.
Good evening, miss...
Madam.
Don't talk to her like that.
You sound like a magistrate.
More vodka for my brother!
Quick about it.
I don't want anything.
I'm all right.
Who told you
where to find me?
A colonel in the Third Department.
They're watching you.
Good.
They must think
I'm dangerous.
What have you got
to smile about?
Nothing.
That's right.
The day is coming.
I have given up my birthright for it.
You're on the wrong side
of history.
Not because privilege
is immoral.
But because it's irrational.
He's sick!
Let go, if you know
what's good for you.
I took Marya Nikolaevna
from a brothel.
But I consider her my wife.
If her presence offends,
you're free to leave.
Are you married?
No.
Why not?
Are you waiting to fall in love?
- No.
- Good.
Romantic love will be the last
illusion of the old order.
You should marry
one of your peasants.
Yes. I damn well should.
The brotherhood of man!
Nikolai, you need to
see a doctor.
Then come and stay with me at Pokrovskoe
till you get your health back.
With my wife?
If you
Or...
Or go abroad to a spa.
I'll send more
if that's what you want.
Hello, what's this?
Austrian royalty on their honeymoon.
I've got them for four days.
The private carriage will
stop opposite the stand.
Bad luck.
What do they like, art?
Food.
Here's the train.
Oh.
I'll come back.
Stiva!
Anna!
- You don't look ashamed!
- Oh, I am, I really am.
Yes, of course.
Oblonsky's sister, Karenina.
Charmante, don't you think?
There, Countess.
You have found your son,
and I have found my brother.
Madam Karenina
has a son, too.
It's the first time they've been
apart, so she frets about him.
Excuse me for not
recognizing you before.
- Au revoir, Countess.
- Au revoir, my dear.
Let me kiss that pretty face.
Keep your people inside until
this has been cleared up.
The sole supporter
of a large family, they say.
Well, can't anything
be done for them?
Wait for me, Maman.
Stand back.
Move aside. Stand back.
I have you to
thank for that.
Oh!
Oh, what a good fellow!
What a good fellow.
Have you known
Count Vronsky long?
Did you like him?
He's in love with Kitty.
Oh.
But we should be discussing
you and Dolly.
What have you got
to say for yourself?
I've said it all.
On my knees, in tears.
Now I need you to say it.
I'm going to the office, so
you'll have Dolly to yourself.
Don't be late home.
Oh, dear.
Kitty's coming by
to see you.
She's all grown up
and a bit frightened of you.
The belle of
St. Petersburg society.
Is that who I am?
Dolly.
Stiva has told me.
Oh, Dolly, I'm sorry.
From the bottom of my heart.
I don't know what to do.
I know. I know.
I can't bear to be with him.
And he doesn't care.
He's got what he wants.
What he wants is you.
He loves you, Dolly.
You and the children
are everything to him.
Are we?
And there is room
for a governess?
That was shameful, disgraceful,
but it was not love.
It was the animal in man
not the soul.
Stiva's remorse is
from the soul.
Well, what about me?
Does his remorse
make it easier for me?
I know you are suffering.
But, Dolly, you must tell me.
Is there enough love left in your heart?
Enough to forgive him?
Well, when I think of them
together, I can't forgive him.
No.
My poor lamb.
So you would rather accept your fate?
My fate?
But I haven't done anything!
It's him who...
Do you love him, Dolly?
You love him,
and he loves you.
But you can't forgive.
So, your lives must continue like this
forever, with both of you wretched.
Oh, that's pretty.
Is that a wedding dress?
Yes.
Look for
the "G" for "Grisha."
- Here.
- Ok.
Can you do your whole name?
Doesn't that look
like a princess? No?
I'm home!
Home, home, home!
Now, where are
my little ducklings?
Papa! Papa!
Papa!
Will you stay for
the Bobrishchevs' ball, Anna?
Oh. I always feel
dull at a ball.
Stiva, tell Anna
she must come to the ball.
Well, of course she must.
And God go with you.
You can introduce me
to your new governess.
But she's old!
She's a hundred!
I know why
you want me to come.
You want everyone
to be there
because you're quite sure
it's going to be your night.
How did you know?
I know everything.
Oh, to be your age again.
Surrounded by that...
That blue mist.
I was 18, too,
when I got married.
Is the prince at home?
He's just
gone up, I believe.
Is nobody receiving?
- I can enquire, sir.
- I don't think so.
- The princess retired early.
- Is there a message?
No. Thank you.
We thought you would
come back married.
Did you?
But you only came back
with a hat.
A black silk hat.
What kind of animal can you
make a hat like that from?
It's not natural.
Next time, perhaps.
There'll be no next time.
Kitty.
May I have a waltz?
You may, Boris.
I'll save you the third, just
because it's your first ball.
You're my first conquest!
Where do you want
to be taken?
There.
How are you, Stiva?
Thanks to Anna, lam a happy man.
Would you like to dance?
No. Ask Anna.
No, I don't...
- Come on, then.
- Oh! Look out!
This vile, idiotic
matchmaking of yours.
For goodness' sake,
what have I done?
Is anything the matter?
No.
You look as lovely as ever,
Princess Kitty.
Don't ask me, Maman.
Kitty, it's us next.
Princess, I have the honor
to claim my dance.
He'll dance the mazurka
with Kitty. You'll see.
lam! I really am!
Dance with me.
I'm not used to being
spoken to like that
by a man I met once
at a railway station.
I dare say, but if I'm
not to dance with you,
then I'm getting out of
this operetta and going home.
Then, for Kitty's sake.
That's my sister.
Next stop is Bologoyel
Bologoye, next stop.
Can I be of service to you?
Why are you leaving Moscow?
What else can I do?
I have to be where you are.
Stop, that's enough.
Go back to Kitty.
No.
This is wrong.
It makes no difference.
You have no right.
You must forget me.
If you're a good man,
you'll forget everything.
And you? Will you forget?
Yes.
Is Serozha all right?
Oh, is that all I get?
Yes, he's quite well.
Were you a success?
L?
Oh, Dolly and Stiva.
Yes, I think so.
- I'll announce myself.
- Very good, sir.
Vronsky.
The master himself.
Baroness, coffee from the new
coffee pot for Count Vronsky.
I'll be off home
if I'm in the way.
You're at home
where you are, Baroness.
Oh! Oh, Pierre, you never say
such pretty things to me.
We were just
discussing my husband.
He won't divorce me, you see,
and do you know why?
No. Because he likes eating
off my family silver.
I want to bring an action.
Just because I'm supposed
to be unfaithful,
I don't see why I have to
eat off Pierre's crockery.
Look at it!
It's my crockery.
Oh!
How was Moscow?
Provincial.
Thank you for my presents.
I'm writing to Dolly
and to Kitty.
You are good.
Time for bed.
What are they saying in Moscow
about the new statute?
What new statute?
The new statute
I carried in Council.
No one mentioned it.
Really?
Oh.
Here, it caused
quite a sensation.
Princess Betsy.
Cousin.
I didn't know
you were an art lover.
I'm prepared to be one.
Countess Lydia tells me
you haven't been to one of her
evenings since you returned.
The last one was to
meet a missionary.
The one before that
was for a lecture on the union
of the Greek and Roman Churches.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I know you're fond of her.
Come on, or we'll be late.
Here's the thing, Vronsky.
A posting's come up, and there's
a promotion in it for you.
Thank you, sir.
In the garrison in Tashkent.
Tashkent? But...
I would like to stay in Peter,
sir, if you don't mind.
Well, I don't mind.
But your mother...
It's her idea.
Your husband is a saint,
and we must all cherish him
for Russia's sake.
You didn't come
to my dinner.
I had to see my
Commanding Officer.
Well, "she"
didn't come either.
I do hope you can
come on afterwards.
Father Kristof's report on the Chinese
mission will be with lantern slides.
I'm expected
at the Tverskoys'.
No doubt.
But I'm sure that Princess
Betsy can wait for you.
Yes, in fact, I don't think
I will go to Betsy's.
You're caught.
I'm afraid I'm becoming
quite ridiculous.
Now, there's
a phenomenon.
Look, Anna's shadow
has arrived before Anna.
I'm Anna's friend.
But all this making up
one's mind to it in public
is not polite to a distinguished
man like Karenin.
In my opinion, Karenin is a fool
and Anna is the best of us.
And we all love you for your
contrary opinions, Princess.
Alexei, you look desperate.
It's not attractive.
I'm losing hope.
Hope of what?
Persuading a virtuous woman
to break her marriage vows?
No, you're right.
She won't come.
He's gone.
But you're just in time
for the surprise.
Turn around!
May I have the honor
of bringing you an ice?
Ices are being served.
I would prefer
to try a cigarette.
Courage.
I'll try another one
sometime.
When?
Where?
Just as I was thinking your manners
had improved since Moscow.
You behaved badly.
Very badly.
And who was
responsible for that?
Give me a cup of tea.
How nice!
Alexei Alexandrovich
has arrived.
I'm not sure my nerves can stand
another Alexei at this moment.
Were you glad
to see me or not?
So the Schuzburgs
asked us to dinner.
The sauce was said to have cost a
thousand rubles, and it was ghastly.
I gave them a sauce that cost
85 kopeks and it was a triumph
This must stop.
You make me feel as if I
were guilty of something.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to go to Moscow
and beg Kitty to forgive you.
No, that's not
what you want.
Moscow?
I can do better than that.
Tonight I refused a posting
to Tashkent.
I can change my mind,
and you'll never see me again.
If you have any thought for me,
you will give me back my peace.
I have no peace to give.
There can be no peace for us.
Only misery
or the greatest happiness.
Your husband is impossible.
His opinions are all wrong,
but he talks so brilliantly,
he wins every argument.
What?
I called to take you home.
No, I'm staying.
Send the carriage
back for me.
Of course.
Do you want me
to go to Tashkent?
So I'll go to Tashkent.
No!
I don't want you to go.
I stayed up
to talk to you.
What about?
It's late.
Where's Annushka?
I sent her off.
Well.
If you want to talk,
but we should go to bed.
I must warn you
about something.
Warn me?
Oh, it's really
rather late.
I wish to warn you that
you may, inadvertently
by indiscretion
and carelessness,
give the world occasion
to talk about you.
I am not a committee.
Please say
what you want to tell me.
You and Count Vronsky
attracted attention tonight.
You don't like it
when I don't talk to people,
and you don't like it
when I do.
I didn't notice
anything myself,
but I saw
everyone else noticed.
I consider jealousy to be insulting
to you and degrading to me.
I have no right
to inquire into your feelings.
They concern
only your conscience.
But it's my duty to remind you
that we are bound together by God,
and this bond can only be
broken by a crime against God.
I have nothing
to say to you.
And you have a son.
And I'm tired.
If I am wrong,
I ask your pardon.
I don't know
what you're talking about,
and it's really
too late for this.
Excuse me, please.
Too late.
Oh, God! Oh, forgive me!
It's the end of everything.
I've got nothing left now
except you, remember that.
How could I not remember?
You're my happiness.
Happiness?
You murdered my happiness.
Murderer.
Go on.
Yes.
Go on. Murderer.
Murderer.
Look out,
here they come.
Oh, bad luck.
Potage aux choux a la russe!
Agafia, if you
opened up in Moscow,
the l'Angleterre
would go out of business.
It's true.
- Do you want news of Moscow?
- Babylon? No.
Oh, you're right,
what do you care?
You love the country,
you've got it.
You love agriculturing, and,
Lord knows, you've got that.
You love shooting,
you've got that.
- You've got everything you want.
- Ha!
All right, go on, then.
Have you stopped
stealing bread rolls?
Ballet girl, Oriental type.
How can I help it?
How is...
How are the Shcherbatskys?
You mean Kitty.
- Is she engaged now?
- No.
Vronsky went back
to St. Petersburg.
Huh.
Kitty will be seeing Dolly
at Ergoshovo in the summer.
You could...
Oh, yes, as if I had
time in the summer.
And I've got extra land at Kashin
this year for the haymaking.
Kashin? That's on the
Ergoshovo road, isn't it?
Couldn't you see Kitty
when she's there?
Especially, not then.
I humiliated myself once.
Oh, damn you, Kostya.
You love Kitty.
You love Kitty
and you can't forgive her
because, first, you funked it,
and then you bungled it.
And then you ran away
from an 18-year-old girl
who was made
a fool of by a uniform.
It's not you I feel
sorry for, it's Kitty.
Her heart told her no.
Did you come to shoot snipe
or criticize me?
Well, don't hold him
like a parcel.
Oh! It's Aunt Kitty,
darling.
Doesn't he make you ashamed
of dwelling on your troubles?
I have no troubles.
That man wasn't worth
the tears, believe me.
I don't care about him.
I don't even think about him, or her.
Except to hate her.
Then we'll never
speak of it again.
There are better men
waiting for you.
Stiva says...
Kitty, my lamb,
did Konstantin...
What has Levin
got to do with it?
Anyway,
I'll never get married.
The whole business of it
has become disgusting to me.
And look what it's done for you.
Why do they call it love?
Because it's love.
I want you to,
I don't care about it.
You should care.
Anyway, someone
might be watching.
But I'm damned, anyway.
I'm not. I'm blessed.
- You love me.
- Yes.
-  Only me.
- No.
- Apart from Frou-Frou?
- Yes.
But me more
than your horse?
Yes.
Are you happy?
And you love me?
Yes.
How much?
This much.
This much?
Yes.
- This much?
- Yes.
And this much?
Yes.
This much?
And this much?
So, this is love.
This.
Countess.
I thought you would be
at Peterhof now.
I've come from there.
I'm distressed that you haven't
taken your usual house this year.
Anna wanted a change.
Nearer to Princess Betsy
at Tsarskoe Selo.
The guards are in summer camp
at Tsarskoe.
Alexei Alexandrovich,
forgive me, but...
You are too tolerant.
Your wife is...
Oh! Is this about my wife?
My wife is beyond reproach.
She is, after all, my wife.
Alyosha! Alyosha!
A message from Maman.
Her friend Princess Sorokina
has a house here
and a virgin daughter.
Well, that's not
part of the message,
but they'll all be
at the races
and you're expected
to supper afterwards.
Gentlemen! Gentlemen!
I give you the regiment!
The regiment!
I heard you turned down
a promotion.
That was Maman interfering.
Yes.
And now she's come up
with a princess for you.
Alexei, we're brothers,
so don't take offense.
Getting married
puts the pack on your back.
It leaves your hands free
for climbing the ladder.
Getting serious
about a married woman
is like carrying
your pack in your arms.
So, they talk about me.
I'm leaving, Sasha.
An assignation?
Come on, I'll introduce you.
Beautiful.
A man would
come to no harm.
Do you think
you'll win tomorrow?
Makhotin's
Gladiator is favorite.
Sixteen hands.
Frou-Frou looks dainty
beside him.
But she's got heart.
Haven't you, my darling?
Anna.
Alexei!
What is it?
I couldn't bear not to
see you before the race.
What were you
thinking about?
Tell me.
I'm pregnant.
Oh, my love.
Well, love was
never a game to us.
Here's an end
to living in corners,
existing day to day on lies.
Yes.
Now we can be together.
How can we, Alexei?
Tell Karenin everything.
Do you think my husband
will make you a present of me?
Leave him.
Leave him
and be your mistress?
Yes, run away.
I would never
see my son again.
The laws are made by
husbands and fathers.
What, then?
I'll never forgive myself
for your unhappiness.
Unhappiness?
I'm like a starving beggar
who's been given food.
I, unhappy?
No.
This is my happiness.
Serozha!
Serozha,
I'm coming to get you!
Where are you?
Serozha!
How are you, young man?
Your tutor doesn't seem
to be in evidence.
Yah!
Alexei.
You got away at last.
Can you stay?
Why?
Go and find Vasily Lukich.
I have to change.
Princess Betsy
is sending her trap for me.
Would you like to come?
She's taking me to watch the race.
Races, surely.
No, I'll come on later.
Then I must get back to town.
Yes!
Princess! Princess!
A bet!
Who do you fancy in the next?
Kusolev.
I'm on Vronsky.
Pair of gloves?
Done.
Alexander Vronsky.
You are an
exquisite creature.
You really ought to be
the spoils of victory today.
Yah! Yah!
Go, Frou-Frou! Go!
Go!
Alexei!
I'm here.
Oh
Get up!
Her back is broken.
You know...
They say the Emperor
disapproves of the races.
The danger of injury.
But I...
What?
I'm saying I think there's a value
in manly sport, for the military.
I don't understand.
In my opinion, it's not the sport itself.
It's the spectacle.
It's making
a cruel spectacle out of...
What are you talking about?
- I have to tell you...
- Yes.
I have to tell you,
you behaved improperly today.
How is that?
By making plain your feeling
when one of the riders fell.
Your conduct was improper.
It must not occur again.
I have said it before.
You will say my concern
is unnecessary and ridiculous.
You are my wife.
I'm wrong to think that.
Yes?
Perhaps I was mistaken...
No.
You were not mistaken.
I love him.
I am his mistress.
Do what you like to me.
Wait. Please, move away.
I will not have a scandal.
Therefore, you will not see this man again.
You will behave in a way that
nothing is known against you
by society or by the servants.
In return, you will keep the
privileges of a wife, and the duties.
Tomorrow you will return home.
That is all.
Are you hurt?
What's happened?
I told him
I'm your mistress.
He thinks I can give you
up and go on living.
No. You cannot.
Time for bed?
It was pleasant to hear you being
congratulated on your husband.
Not that I care
for decorations, but...
Alexei, I can't. I'm sorry.
Oh.
But I'm his wife, now.
I'm having his child.
Tell me what I did
to deserve this.
Halt!
How many mowers
is it, Theodore?
Forty-two, Master.
In your father's time, it was
work for two days for 30 men.
Though he never
picked up a scythe himself.
The men don't
like me for it.
They like
what they're used to.
It settles me.
How is that, Master?
When I'm mowing, I don't
ask myself why I'm here.
You're here to be
Master Konstantin Dmitrievich.
As it's always been,
by the grace of God.
My father owned you,
Theodore.
Owned you like chattels
to be bought and sold.
Was that
by the grace of God?
It was.
That's my youngest
you were looking at, there.
His young life is perilous now since the
freedom came and work must be found.
They look happier
than I've ever been.
Is it living simply
that I'm looking for?
I'm expected.
No.
I will not live like this.
This waiting
for hour after hour,
not knowing
when I'll ever see you again.
Sorry.
It's my demon.
I can't help it.
You wrote that you were ill.
Don't worry,
it won't be for long.
- Stop.
- No, it's true.
I was told it in a dream.
There.
It was only a bad dream.
Yes, and I'm only going
to die having your baby.
That's all nonsense.
Tell me it is.
You love me, only me.
Your note said
your husband would be out.
He was late.
It serves him right.
And you...
Why do you call him
my husband?
He isn't my husband,
he's a clock.
But it was awkward. My honor.
You made an agreement.
Do you think of your honor when you're
sharing whores with your Colonel?
Your demon again?
I'll be glad to die
before you start to hate me.
Anna.
Put your hand there.
You can feel him move.
I respectfully ask
Minister Karenin
whether his proposals for the regulation
of these colorful gypsy tribes
of these scholarly,
God-fearing Jews, and of...
But I'm afraid I've lost
the Minister's attention.
Who is here?
Only Madame,
Your Excellency.
I wanted to see him because...
I do not wish to know why a
woman wants to see her lover.
What are you doing?
I want his letters!
lam going to Moscow tomorrow,
and then the provinces
with a commission to investigate
conditions among the Jews and gypsies,
whose conditions
I infinitely prefer to my own.
I will not return to this house until
divorce has driven you into the street.
Meanwhile, my son will be sent
to live with my eldest sister.
No, Alexei, please.
Please, leave me Serozha!
Do you think
I would let you have my son?
You are depraved.
A woman without honor.
I thank God the curse of
love is lifted from me.
I need your advice.
- Come on, come on!
- Yes, yes.
Right, after you,
after you.
- Are we late?
- Of course, you're late.
I'm Countess Nordston.
We nearly met at the
Shcherbatskys' last winter.
Come into the fold.
Come on.
You've been waiting for me.
Forgive me.
Kitty is here.
Konstantin, what a long time
since we saw each other.
Since you saw me, but I
saw you not so long ago.
When?
You were driving
to Ergoshovo.
I was at Kashin
for the haymaking.
Oh, but why didn't you
I'm so glad to see you.
You're just the same.
I hope not.
I was young and silly
in those days.
Months and months ago.
And you haven't changed.
No. I haven't.
Permit me to announce,
um, soup Marie-Louise carp
with asparagus
and roast beef.
I went to the market
in person.
An extra place.
I've come to tell you our
connection must be severed.
I'm going to
divorce your sister.
Divorce?
Oh, dear me, what are you
talking about?
Well, don't be in a hurry.
Stay to dinner.
And later, you can talk
it over with Dolly.
Prince Oblonsky, everything
is over between our families.
Alexei, divorce is one thing.
Dinner is quite another.
You Petersburgers
think yourselves so de bon ton
compared with dull,
old-fashioned Moscow.
But we know
how to do things.
Only the other day,
I hear Vasya Pryachnikov fought a
duel with Kvitsky and killed him.
Well, what...
What was the challenge about?
Pryachnikov's wife,
naturally.
It was a matter
of honor, defending a woman's honor.
Sounds like barbarism to me.
What if the lover had killed the husband?
Would that have preserved
the wife's honor, too?
Still, not many of us can say
our lover died for love.
Love?
"Thou shall not covet
thy neighbor's wife."
Would you die for love,
Konstantin Dmitrievich?
I would. But not for
my neighbor's wife.
An impure love
is not love to me.
To admire another man's wife
is a pleasant thing,
but sensual desire indulged
for its own sake is greed,
a kind of gluttony,
and a misuse of something
sacred, which is given to us
so that we may choose the one person
with whom to fulfill our humanness.
Otherwise,
we might as well be cattle.
Ah! An idealist!
But she will be
nobody's wife.
She'll be ruined.
I tried to save her.
She chose ruin.
Alexei Alexandrovich.
Look at me.
You will have no peace of mind
until you forgive her.
It was Anna
who taught me that.
I do not wish to forgive.
I'm not a cruel man.
I've never hated anyone.
But I hate her
with all my soul
for all the wrong
she has done me.
Now, it is your turn
to play us something, Countess.
I thought you'd never ask.
Very good.
Since we last met,
there is something I have
often wanted to ask you.
What is that?
This.
Do...
Not...
Did.
Did not.
The last word is "never."
I know what it says.
Then.
But now?
Can you forgive
and forget?
I never stopped.
Why doesn't he come?
He is kind.
He will forgive me.
Her fever is higher.
I want Alexei.
Why doesn't he come?
Give me some water.
No, I mustn't.
It isn't good
for my little girl.
Or let her have a nurse, yes.
Don't bring her here
because Alexei is coming
and it will hurt him
to see her.
He's come, my dear.
Look there.
Her deliverance
is still in God's hands.
You think he won't forgive
me but you don't know him.
No one knows him
except me.
I'm not afraid of him, now.
I'm afraid of death, though.
Oh.
You poor man.
Let him come closer.
Alexei.
Look at my husband.
He's a saint.
Take his hand.
Thank God.
You must leave now.
I promise to send for you
if she asks for you.
I don't know
what happened to me.
I forgive you.
I forgive Anna.
My soul is filled
with joy.
I will remain with her
and look after her forever.
Come now.
Look at you.
You look like what you've become.
A laughingstock.
I fancy you will be asked
to leave the regiment.
I would like you
to go, Maman.
I'll go when I'm ready to go.
A little affair
with a married woman
puts a finishing touch
to a young man's education.
But this morbid,
selfish obsession...
You've publicly
humiliated yourself
and dishonored a man who has
devoted his life to Russia.
So you'd better come back
to Moscow with me.
You're finished here.
And there was her husband,
wearing her best ball gown.
Rouge all over his face.
Ma chre, le scandale!
But I'd better tell you
some regimental news.
Who is here?
Princess Elisabeth Federovna
Tverskaya, Your Excellency.
I don't want to see him.
But surely your husband
wouldn't stop...
I'm so glad
to see you.
You look feverish.
We've been talking too much,
so I'm going.
Princess Betsy
came to tell me...
I don't want to hide
anything from you.
Count Vronsky asked to come to say goodbye.
He's going away.
I've told him
that I can't receive him.
Well, goodbye,
my treasure.
I agree with you.
As he is going away, there's no
need for Count Vronsky to come.
I just said so, so there's
no need to repeat it.
But it is for you
to decide.
Yes, and I decided.
Then I am very glad that...
That we agree, so perhaps we
can stop talking about it.
Of course.
Is there anything I can do for you?
Yes, can you please, please, please
stop cracking your knuckles?
I'm a bad woman.
But I can't breathe.
Your kindness, which I can't
repay, and your forgiveness...
You begged me
for my forgiveness.
But I didn't die, and now
I have to live with it.
Then what? What do you want?
Do you know what you want?
Do you want to see Count Vronsky?
Not to say goodbye.
I can't hear.
You would be lost.
Irretrievably lost.
You would have no position.
And worse, if we divorce,
you would be the guilty party.
That means you cannot
legally remarry.
Your union with Count Vronsky
would be illegitimate,
as would your daughter, who now
has the protection of my name.
And this is what
you want?
It would be a sin
to help you destroy yourself.
You forget something.
Count Vronsky and I
love each other.
And this love sanctifies
a criminal folly?
All I know
is that I sent him away
and it's as if I'd shot
myself through the heart!
I see.
And what of Serozha?
I would die for him,
but I won't live
like this for him.
When he knows of love,
he will forgive me.
Then I must choose
the smaller sin.
Vronsky has robbed me of my cloak
and I will give him my coat.
No, I...
My darling. My darling.
You look so pale.
Oh, my darling.
We'll go south
to the sea air and sunshine.
Is it all right?
Sit down a minute.
I want to see everything.
A moment.
And now I'm doing
kitchenmaid's work
because Nadya's parents won't
let her set foot in the house.
And who can blame them?
It's indecent
It's Konstantin.
Yes, good.
The doctor here is useless.
Get me one from Moscow.
Where did you go?
I asked for you everywhere
when I was getting married.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't leave him.
Yes. My wife...
You can't stay now.
I will nurse him
with Agafia.
The woman will find
somewhere in the village.
You won't see her.
She knows it is impossible
to meet you.
It is a torment to me that I've
brought you under the same roof
as this unfortunate...
As this fallen...
And in your precious,
delicate condition.
Oh, Kostya.
Good. A clean nightshirt
and sheets.
A towel and a clean
pail of warm water.
Wait.
And bring
the perfume bottle,
in the outside pocket
of my handbag.
Twenty-one to Stremov, four to Karenin.
The motion is carried.
Alexei, they're back.
Here, in St. Petersburg.
She has written to me.
To you?
They think I don't have
the right to refuse.
It's the boy's birthday.
My friend,
you would be blowing on the embers of
a fire which must be allowed to die.
Let me write to her.
I'm here to see Serozha.
Madame?
I beg your pardon,
Your Excellency.
No, I've come
to see Serozha.
Serozha.
Maman?
Oh.
My dear little boy.
I knew you would come.
Today is my birthday.
I know.
Are you crying?
No, I won't cry.
Where did you
go, Maman?
I don't know.
Everywhere. The south.
I thought about you
every day.
And I thought
about you every day.
And you must love Papa.
He's better than I am.
No one in the whole world
is better than you.
No.
Where's Anya?
She's still asleep.
Should I take your coat?
Are you feeling
unwell, madam?
I'm not sleeping.
I can send out
for something.
Yes.
Why are you in the dark?
Yashvin is going to call.
You remember him.
Are you going out?
To where?
To whom?
What's the matter?
I didn't know
what happened to you.
But I told you
yesterday. My brother.
Does it take all day
to meet your brother?
Does he need you
more than I do?
What's happened?
Well, Alexander agreed
to everything.
Mother's house in Moscow
will go to him,
and the country estate
will be our new home.
As soon as the divorce.
Karenin hasn't answered
your letter yet?
You're the very first person to
call on me since our return.
I received a note
from Princess Betsy
asking me to call on her
between 6:30 and 8:00.
Or was it 7:00?
But perhaps you'll meet
at the opera tonight.
I would love to be there
if I could get a box.
Madame, your box
is number four.
You'll find me there
with Princess Myagkaya.
Will you come, Vronsky?
Well... I see why Alexei
is so fond of you.
You know you can't
go to the theater.
- Annushka!
- For heaven's sake.
A bath! I'll come in
and choose a dress.
Anna, I implore you.
I'm not ashamed of who I am
or what I've done.
Are you ashamed for me?
Why don't you book
a room at the hotel?
Aren't we together?
Have you changed towards me?
It's because I love you
and care about you.
If that's the case, then I don't
know why you aren't coming with me.
That would make it worse.
You're afraid.
Well, I'm not.
Should we visit,
or stay put?
Stay put.
Minister! Congratulations.
Come in for a moment.
Princess
Sorokina and her daughter.
They're from Moscow, neighbors
of Count Vronsky's mother.
Quite well off. No sons.
She's a widow.
My dear,
I'm a sales catalog.
Alexei.
You'll come up
to see us afterwards?
I'll talk to Varya.
Will you call on Anna?
Oh. Alexei. I'm fond of...
For God's sake!
Anna isn't a criminal.
I'd call on her if she'd
only broken the law.
But she broke the rules.
Who has made the dcor?
Haven't we got a program?
Colonel, would you
be so kind?
Of course.
Please, I would be honored
if you would take mine.
Thank you. How very...
It's a disgrace.
Hush, dean
A common courtesy.
Everyone's looking.
Let them look!
Fetch my cloak.
What are we coming to?
It's an insult to decency.
Take me home.
Hush. I beg you, my dear.
It was only a word or two.
I have a word or two
for some people
one didn't expect
to be rubbing shoulders with.
She has a nerve, flaunting
herself like a slut in society.
Yes, why don't you?
Rescue her and put your
seal on the fiasco.
Alexei
you see why
she must divorce.
Marriage will solve everything.
When will it be?
As far as I'm concerned,
she's my wife.
As you saw, she isn't.
We're going to Moscow, then
to my place in the country.
That sounds
like a good idea.
But, for a day or two,
Anna will be at home.
Then.
I'll say goodbye now.
Well, you had
an excellent night.
Does your mother want you to
marry the widow or the child?
Either one.
Don't joke about it
If you loved me, you would have
looked me in to stop me going!
Yes, it was my fault.
I won't sleep.
I know how
to make you sleep.
Anna, I am very glad
to see you.
Are you well?
How is your little one?
Stiva wanted to invite you and
Count Vronsky to the house,
but it's impossible.
No, I understand.
No. No, you don't.
Kitty and her husband
are with us.
She's in Moscow
to have the baby.
Kitty! Tell her
how pleased I am.
Perhaps I'll wait
a year or two.
Love.
Yes, love.
Don't you disapprove of me
for what I've done?
No. I wish I'd done the same
But no one asked me.
Well, I wouldn't have been
brave enough.
Stiva, you know,
he doesn't change.
Like all men, I suppose.
I had an inspiration.
Why do we have to wait here?
Why can't we wait
in the country?
I don't want to hear any more about
a divorce or think about it.
Good, I'm bored here.
When should we go?
If I bore you here,
I'll bore you in the country.
I didn't say you bore me, Moscow bores me.
When should we go? Tomorrow?
I can't be ready by tomorrow.
- The day after, then.
- If you like.
No, wait, that's Sunday.
I have to see Maman.
That's 20 minutes away
on the train.
You could go
to see her tomorrow.
Or was it that you wanted to spend
Sunday with Princess Sorokina?
Please.
Don't spoil everything.
I can't see Maman tomorrow because she won't
have read the papers she has to sign.
In that case,
let's not bother.
- I'll leave on Sunday or not at all.
- That's absurd.
It's absurd to you because you have
no understanding of my life here.
- Anna.
- No, you've stopped loving me.
You've given up everything for me
and it's turned you against me.
- Why lie about it?
- Stop!
I put off our departure for a day or
two and you tell me I don't love you.
Because I've been living off
your love and there's none left.
So this is over. Finished.
I'm sorry.
I don't mind when we go.
I'll telegraph Maman.
We'll go on Sunday.
I'll do anything you want.
- You should leave me.
- I don't want to. I love you.
Why?
You can't ask "why"
about love.
So, will you be all packed?
I'll be out today
making the arrangements.
Is that your way of telling
me you'll be at your mother's
with that simpering
little princess?
No. I'll be at my lawyer's,
waiting for some documents.
Then I'm having dinner to say
goodbye to old comrades.
I know what that means.
My God, this is unendurable!
I can invite them here,
if you like.
Thank you, but if I'm not fit to dine
in society, I won't eat with the band.
Who was the telegram from?
I didn't show you because Stiva keeps
telegraphing what we already know.
Karenin promises nothing,
but will consider...
I told you I don't care about the
divorce, so why hide the telegram?
Is there anything
you wish to say to me?
So it's the child.
She brought papers
from Maman.
Anna.
No.
Oh, God.
Forgive me.
I'll be buying in feed
before winter's over.
Well, you don't press people
hard, but you live rightly.
For your soul
not your belly
How do we know
what's rightly?
Just by knowing it.
How else?
But I believe in reason.
Reason. Was it reason that
made you choose your wife?
I came looking for you.
I understood something.
What did you understand?
He smiled at me.
He's very advanced
for his age.
What did you understand?
I'm so proud of you.
Night-night.
And you, too.
Good night, my darling boy.
Anya!