Look down, look down
Don't look them in the eye
You're here until you die
No God above
And hell alone below
Look down, look down
There's 20 years to go
I've done no wrong
Sweet Jesus, hear my prayer!
Look down, look down
Sweet Jesus doesn't care
I know she'll wait
I know that she'll be true
Look down, look down
They've all forgotten you
When I get free
You won't see me
Here for dust!
Huh!
Look down, look down
You'll always be a slave
You're standing
in your grave
Retrieve the flag.
Now, Prisoner 24601
Your time is up
And your parole's begun
You know what that means?
Yes. It means I'm free
No. Follow to the letter
Your itinerary
This badge of shame
You'll show it till you die
It warns you're
a dangerous man
I stole a loaf of bread
My sister's child
was close to death
And we were starving
You will starve again
Unless you learn
the meaning of the law
I know the meaning
of those 19 years
A slave of the law!
Five years for what you did
The rest because
you tried to run
Yes, 24601
My name is Jean Valjean!
And I'm Javert!
Do not forget my name
Do not forget me
Look down, look down
You'll always be a slave
You're standing
in your grave
Freedom at last
How strange the taste
Never forget the years,
the waste
Nor forgive them
for what they've done
They are the guilty
Everyone
The day begins
And now let's see
What this new world
Will do for me
Can I help?
A day's work?
Papers.
No work here.
Valjean,
as a dangerous man,
you will be on parole forever.
Failure to report
means immediate arrest.
Be in Pontarlier in 30 days.
Follow him.
Let me
see your papers.
Monsieur?
Papers.
I'll sleep in the stable.
Please, I'm hungry.
Get out.
Hey!
Come in,
sir, for you are weary
And the night is cold
out here
Though our lives
are very humble
What we have
We have to share
There is wine
here to revive you
There is bread
to make you strong
There's a bed to
rest till morning
Rest from pain
And rest from wrong
Bless the food we eat today.
Bless our dear sister
and our honored guest.
Get in there!
Put him down!
Stay there!
Monsignor.
We have your silver.
We caught this man
red-handed.
He had the nerve to
say you gave him this.
That is right
But, my friend,
you left so early
Surely something
slipped your mind
You forgot I gave these also
Would you leave
the best behind?
Messieurs, release him
This man has spoken true
I commend you for your duty
Now God's blessing go with you
But remember this, my brother
See in this some higher plan
You must use
this precious silver
To become an honest man
By the witness of the martyrs
By the passion and the blood
God has raised
you out of darkness
I have saved your soul for
God
What have I done?
Sweet Jesus, what have I done?
Become a thief in the night
Become a dog on the run
Have I fallen so far
And is the hour so late
That nothing remains
but the cry of my hate?
The cries in the dark
that nobody hears
Here where I stand at
the turning of the years
If there's another way to go
I missed it 20 long years ago
My life was a war
that could never be won
They gave me a number
and they murdered Valjean
When they chained me
and left me for dead
Just for stealing
a mouthful of bread
Yet why did I allow this man
To touch my soul
and teach me love?
He treated me like any other
He gave me his trust
He called me brother
My life he claims
for God above
Can such things be?
For I had come
to hate the world
This world that
always hated me!
Take an eye for an eye!
Turn your heart into stone!
This is all I have lived for!
This is all I have known!
One word from him
and I'd be back
Beneath the lash,
upon the rack
Instead he offers me
my freedom!
I feel my shame inside me
like a knife
He told me that I have a soul
How does he know?
What spirit comes
to move my life?
Is there another way to go?
I am reaching but I fall
And the night is closing in
As I stare into the void
To the whirlpool of my sin
I'll escape now
from that world
From the world of Jean Valjean
Jean Valjean is nothing now!
Another story must begin!
At the end of the day
you're another day older
And that's all you can say
for the life of the poor
It's a struggle! It's a war!
And there's nothing
that anyone's giving
One more day standing about
What is it for?
One day less to be living
At the end of the day
you're another day colder
And the shirt on your back
doesn't keep out the chill
And the righteous hurry past
They don 't hear
the little ones crying
And the plague
is coming on fast
Ready to kill
One day nearer to dying!
At the end of the day
there's another day dawning
And the sun in the morning
is waiting to rise
Like the waves
crash on the sand
Like a storm
that'll break any second
There's a hunger in the land
There's a reckoning
still to be reckoned
And there's
gonna be hell to pay
At the end of the day!
At the end of the day
you get nothing for nothing
Sitting flat on your bum
doesn't buy any bread
There are children
back at home
And the children
have got to be fed
And you're lucky
to be in a job
And in a bed
And we're counting
our blessings
Have you seen
how the foreman
is fuming today
With his terrible breath
and his wandering hands?
It's because little Fantine
won 't give him his way
Take a look at his trousers
You'll see where he stands!
And the boss, he never
knows that the foreman
is always on heat
If Fantine doesn't look out,
watch how she goes
She'll be
out on the street
At the end of the day
it's another day over
With enough in your pocket
to last for a week
Pay the landlord, pay the shop
Keep on working as
long as you're able
Keep on working till you drop
Or it's back to
the crumbs off the table
Well,
you've got to pay your way
At the end of the day!
And what have we here,
little innocent sister?
Come on, Fantine,
let's have all the news
"Dear Fantine,
you must send us more money
"Your child needs a doctor
There's no time to lose"
Give that letter to me
It is none of your business
With a husband at home
and a bit on the side
Is there anyone here
who can swear before God
She has nothing to fear?
She has nothing to hide?
Stop making trouble.
I'm not making trouble.
Foreman!
What are you doing?
Come on, stop that!
Monsieur Madeleine is here!
What is
this fighting all about?
Someone tear these two apart!
This is a factory,
not a circus
Now, come on, ladies,
settle down
I am the mayor of this town
I run a business of repute
Deal with this, Foreman.
Be as patient as you can.
Yes,
Monsieur Madeleine.
Now, someone say
how this began.
At the end of the day
she's the one who began it!
There's a kid
that she's hiding
in some little town
There's a man
she has to pay
You can guess how
she picks up the extra
You can bet she's
earning her keep
sleeping around!
And the boss
wouldn 't like it
Yes, it's true there's a child
And the child is my daughter
And her father
abandoned us,
leaving us flat
Now she lives
with an innkeeper
man and his wife
And I pay for the child
What's the matter with that?
At the end of the day
she'll be nothing but trouble
And there's trouble for all
when there's trouble for one
While we're earning
our daily bread
She's the one with
her hands in the butter
You must send the slut away
or we're all going
to end in the gutter
And it's us who'll have to pay
At the end of the day!
I might have known
the bitch could bite
the cat had claws
I might have guessed
your little secret
Ah, yes, the virtuous Fantine
who keeps herself
so pure and clean
You'd be the cause,
I had no doubt
of any trouble hereabout
You play a virgin
in the light
But need no urging
in the night
She's been
laughing at you while
she's having her men!
She'll be nothing
but trouble again and again!
You must sack her today!
Sack the girl today!
Right, my girl
On your way
Monsieur le Mayor!
Please!
Please, monsieur!
I have a child!
Monsieur!
Please! Please.
Welcome, Inspector.
Monsieur le Mayor.
Please
know me as Javert
I'm here at your command
With honor due to each
And justice in our hand
No man's beyond our reach
Let all beware
Welcome, sir
Come guard our laws
I'm sure we're here
In common cause
You've done the city proud
You're praised
by those on high
Your success
has earned a force
The best that Paris
can supply
Your people thrive
The dignity of toil
To stay alive
It seems to me
we may have met
Your face is not a face
I would forget
Monsieur Madeleine!
Pardon.
Monsieur le Mayor!
The weight,
it's crushing him!
Stay still, stay still.
Hold, hold, hold!
Hold that steady.
Hold it steady!
That's it. That's it.
Can this be true?
I don't believe what I see
A man your age
To be as strong as you are
A memory stirs
You make me think of a man
From years ago
A man who broke his parole
He disappeared
Say what you must
Don't leave it there
Forgive me, sir
I would not dare
How much for this?
It's my daughter's.
I'll give you
four francs for that.
Four? It's worth 10!
No.
I smell women
Smell 'em in the air
Think I'll drop my anchor
In that harbor over there
Five?
Lovely lady
I'll love you till I'm broke
Seven months at sea
and now I'm hungry for a poke!
Even stokers
need a little stoke!
Lovely ladies
Waiting for a bite!
Waiting for the customers
Who only come at night
Lovely ladies
Ready for the call
Standing up or lying down
Or any way at all
Bargain prices
up against the wall!
What pretty hair!
What pretty locks
you've got there!
What luck you've got
It's worth a centime,
my dear!
I'll take the lot!
Don't touch me!
Leave me alone!
Let's make a price
I'll give you
all of 10 francs
Just think of that
It pays a debt
What can I do?
Ten francs may
save my poor Cosette
Lovely ladies
Waiting in the dark
Ready for a thick one
Or a quick one in the park
Long time, short time
Any time, my dear!
Costs a little extra
If you want to take all year
Quick and cheap
is underneath the pier
Go and see them.
Come over here
It's 20 francs for a tooth
Come here, my dear
I'll pay you well
for your youth
The pain won't last
You'll still be able to bite
Just the back ones.
I do it fast
I know my business all right
It's worth a go
You'll pay me first
what I am due
You'll get twice
if I take two
Give me the dirt
Who's that bit over there?
A bit of skirt
She's the one sold her hair
She's got a kid
Sends her all that she can
I might have known
There is always some man
Lovely lady,
come along and join us!
Lovely lady!
Come on, dearie,
why all the fuss?
You're no grander
than the rest of us
Life has dropped you
at the bottom of the heap
Join your sisters
Make money in your sleep
That's right, dearie
Show him what you've got
Let him have the lot
Old men, young men
Take 'em as they come!
Harbor rats and alley cats
and every kind of scum
Poor men, rich men,
leaders of the land
See them with
their trousers off
They're never quite as grand!
All it takes is
money in your hand
Lovely ladies
Going for a song
Got a lot of callers
But they never stay for long
Come on, Captain
You can wear your shoes
Don't it make a change
to have a girl
who can't refuse?
Easy money
Lying on a bed
Just as well they never see
The hate that's in your head
Don't they know
they're making love
to one already dead?
There was a time
when men were kind
When their voices were soft
And their words inviting
There was a time
when love was blind
And the world was a song
And the song was exciting
There was a time
Then it all went wrong
I dreamed a dream
in time gone by
When hope was high
And life worth living
I dreamed that
love would never die
I dreamed that God
would be forgiving
Then I was young and unafraid
And dreams were made
and used and wasted
There was no ransom to be paid
No song unsung,
no wine untasted
But the tigers come at night
With their voices
soft as thunder
As they tear your hope apart
As they turn
your dream to shame
He slept a summer by my side
He filled my days
with endless wonder
He took my childhood
in his stride
But he was gone
when autumn came
And still I dream
he'll come to me
That we will live
the years together
But there are dreams
that cannot be
And there are storms
we cannot weather
I had a dream my life would be
So different from
this hell I'm living
So different now
from what it seemed!
Now
Life has killed the dream
I dreamed
Have you anywhere to go?
No? You need to get warm.
What do you have for me?
Here's
our youngest, sir.
I don't want you
You've got some nerve,
you little slut.
You've got some gall.
Ow!
By Christ,
you'll pay for
what you've done
I guarantee
I'll make you suffer
I beg you,
don't report me, sir
I'll do whatever
you may want
Make your excuse to the police
Tell me quickly
what's the story
Who saw what
and why and where?
Let him give
a full description
Let him answer to Javert
Javert, would you believe it?
I was lost here in the dark
When this
prostitute attacked me
You can see she left her mark
She will answer
for her actions
If you make a full report
You may rest assured, monsieur
She will answer to the court
There's a child
who sorely needs me
Please, monsieur,
she's but that high
Holy God, is there no mercy?
If I go to jail she'll die
I have heard
such protestations
every day for 20 years
Let's have
no more explanations
Save your breath,
save your tears
Honest work, just reward
That's the way
to please the Lord
A moment of your time, Javert
I do believe this woman 's tale
Monsieur le Mayor!
You've done your duty,
let her be
She needs a doctor,
not a jail
Monsieur le Mayor!
Can this be?
Where will she end
This child without a friend?
I've seen your face before
Show me some way to help you
How have you come to grief
In such a place as this?
Monsieur,
don't mock me now, I pray
It's hard enough
I've lost my pride
You let your foreman
send me away
Yes, you were there
And turned aside
I never did no wrong
Is it true what I've done...
My daughter's close to dying
... to an innocent soul?
If there's a God above...
Had I only known then
...he'd let me die instead
In His name
my task has just begun
I will take her
to the hospital.
Monsieur le Mayor.
Where is your child?
With an innkeeper
in Montfermeil.
I will send for her
immediately.
I will see it done!
Rest.
From Paris, monsieur.
Monsieur le Mayor,
I have a crime to declare!
I have disgraced
The uniform that I wear
I've done you wrong
Let no forgiveness be shown
I've been as hard
On every rogue I have known
I mistook you for a convict
I have made a false report
Now I learn
they caught the culprit
He's about to face the court
And of course
he now denies it
You'd expect that of a con
But he couldn't run forever
No, not even Jean Valjean
You say this man denies it all
And gives no sign of
understanding or repentance?
You say this man
is going to trial
And that he's
sure to be returned
to serve his sentence?
He will pay, and so must I
Press charges against me, sir
You have only
done your duty
It's a minor sin
at most
All of us have
made misjudgments
You'll return, sir,
to your post
They think that man is me
Without a second glance
This stranger they have found
This man could be my chance
Why should I save his hide?
Why should I right this wrong?
When I have come so far
and struggled for so long?
If I speak, I am condemned
If I stay silent,
I am damned!
I am the master of
hundreds of workers
They all look to me
Can I abandon them?
How would they live
if I am not free?
If I speak, they are condemned
If I stay silent
I am damned
Who am I?
Can I condemn
this man to slavery?
Pretend I do not
feel his agony?
This innocent
who bears my face
Who goes to judgment
in my place
Who am I?
Can I conceal
myself forevermore?
Pretend I'm not
the man I was before?
And must my name until I die
be no more than an alibi?
Must I lie?
How can I ever
face my fellow men?
face myself again?
My soul belongs to God, I know
I made that bargain long ago
He gave me hope
when hope was gone
He gave me
strength to journey on!
Who am I?
I'm Jean Valjean
Monsieur le Mayor!
And so,
Your Honor, you see it's true
This man bears
no more guilt than you!
Who am I?
24601!
Monsieur le Mayor,
you are not well.
You must come with me.
If you don't believe me,
ask Inspector Javert.
You'll find me
at the hospital.
Cosette,
it's turned so cold
it's past your bedtime
You've played the day away
And soon it will be night
Come to me
Cosette, the light is fading
Don't you see
The evening star appearing?
Come to me
And rest against my shoulder
How fast the minutes fly away
and every minute colder
Dear Fantine,
Cosette will be here soon
she will be by your side
Come, Cosette
My child, where did you go?
Be at peace
Be at peace evermore
My Cosette
Shall live in my protection
Take her now
Your child will
want for nothing
Good monsieur,
you come from God in heaven
Tell Cosette I love her
And I'll see her when I wake
Valjean, at last
We see each other plain
"Monsieur le Mayor"
You'll wear a different chain
Before you say
another word, Javert
Before you chain me up
like a slave again
Listen to me!
There is something I must do
This woman leaves
behind a suffering child
There is none but me
who can intercede
In mercy's name,
three days are all I need
Then I'll return,
I pledge my word
Then I'll return
You must think me mad
I've hunted you
across the years
Men like you
can never change
A man such as you!
Believe of me what you will
Men like you
can never change
There is a duty
I'm sworn to do
Men like me
can never change
You know nothing of my life
No, 24601!
All I did was steal some bread
My duty is to the law
You know nothing
of the world
You have no rights
You would sooner
see me dead
Come with me, 24601!
But not before
I see this justice done!
Now the wheel
has turned around
Jean Valjean
means nothing now
Dare you talk to me
of crime
I am warning you, Javert
And the price
you had to pay
I'm the stronger man by far!
Every man is born in sin
There is power in me yet!
Every man
must choose his way
My race is not yet run!
You know nothing of Javert!
I was born inside a jail!
I was born
with scum like you!
I am from the gutter, too!
There is a castle on a cloud
I like to go there in my sleep
Aren't any floors
for me to sweep
Not in my castle on a cloud
There is a lady all in white
Holds me and sings a lullaby
She's nice to see
and she's soft to touch
She says,
"Cosette,
I love you very much"
I know a place
where no one's lost
where no one cries
Crying at all is not allowed
Not in my castle on a cloud
Now look who's here!
The little madam herself
Pretending once again
she's been so awfully good
Better not let me
catch you slacking!
Better not catch my eye!
Ten rotten francs
your mother sends me
What is that going to buy?
Now take that pail
My little mademoiselle
And go and draw
some water from the well
We should never
have taken you in
in the first place
How stupid
the things that we do!
Like mother, like daughter,
the scum of the street
Mama!
Eponine, come, my dear
Eponine, let me see you
You look very well in
that little blue hat
Oh.
There's some little girls
who know how to behave
And they know what to wear
And I'm saying
thank heaven for that!
Still there, Cosette?
Your tears will
do you no good!
I told you, fetch some water
from the well in the wood
Please do not
send me out alone
Not in the darkness on my own
Now shut your face or
I'll forget to be nice!
You heard me ask for something
And I never ask twice
Wakey-wakey, we're opening.
I love you.
I love you so much.
My band of soaks
My den of dissolutes
My dirty jokes
Ugh!
My always pissed as newts
My sons of whores
No, no, no.
Not tonight.
Spend their lives in my inn
Wakey-wakey.
Good boy, good boy,
good boy.
Homing pigeons homing in
They fly through my doors
And they crawl out
on all fours
Daddy, here.
Thank you, darling.
Such a gentleman.
Welcome, monsieur,
sit yourself down
And meet the best
innkeeper in town
As for the rest
All of them crooks
Rooking the guests
And cooking the books
Seldom do you see
Honest men like me
A gent of good intent
who's content to be
Master of the house
Doling out the charm
Ready with a handshake
and an open palm
Tells a saucy tale
Makes a little stir
Customers appreciate
a bon viveur
Glad to do a friend a favor
Doesn 't cost me to be nice
But nothing gets you nothing
Everything has
got a little price
Master of the house
Keeper of the zoo
Ready to relieve them
of a sou or two
Watering the wine
Making up the weight
Picking up their knick-knacks
When they can 't see straight
Everybody loves a landlord
Everybody's bosom friend
I do whatever pleases
Jesus! Won 't I bleed 'em
in the end!
Master of the house!
Quick to catch your eye
Never wants a passerby
to pass him by!
Servant to the poor
Butler to the great
Comforter, philosopher
and lifelong mate
Everybody's boon companion
Everybody's chaperone
But lock up your valises
Jesus! Won't I
skin you to the bone!
Food beyond compare
Food beyond belief
Mix it in a mincer
And pretend it's beef
Kidney of a horse
Liver of a cat
Filling up the sausages
with this and that
Residents are
more than welcome
Bridal suite is occupied
Reasonable charges
Plus some little
extras on the side
Oh, Santa!
Charge 'em for the lice
Extra for the mice
Two percent for
looking in the mirror twice
Hand it over!
Here a little slice,
there a little cut
Three percent for sleeping
with the windows shut
When it comes
to fixing prices
There are a lot
of tricks I knows
How it all increases
All those bits and pieces
Jesus!
It's amazing how it grows
Sorry, love.
I must get
something done about that.
I used to dream
that I would meet a prince
But, God almighty
Have you seen
what's happened since?
What? What?
"Master of the house"
isn't worth my spit!
Comforter, philosopher
and lifelong shit!
Cunning little brain
Regular Voltaire
Thinks he's quite a lover
but there's not much there
What a cruel trick of nature
Landed me with such a louse
God knows how I've lasted
living with this
bastard in the house
Master of the house!
Master and a half!
Comforter, philosopher
Don't make me laugh
Servant to the poor
Butler to the great
Hypocrite and
toady and inebriate!
Everybody
bless the landlord!
bless his spouse!
Everybody raise a glass!
Raise it up
the master's arse!
Everybody raise a glass
to the master of the house
I love you, too.
Everybody
bless the landlord
Hush now
Do not be afraid of me
Don't hide
Show me where you live
Tell me, my child,
what is your name?
I'm called Cosette
Mademoiselle.
Can I help you
with your bucket?
Whoa!
I found her
wandering in the wood
This little child,
I found her
trembling in the shadows
And I am here
to help Cosette
I will settle any debt
you may think proper
I will pay what I must pay
To take Cosette away
I love you.
This is a duty I must heed
And there is
a promise I have made
For I was blind
to one in need
I did not see
what stood before me
Now your mother is with God
Her suffering is over
And I speak here
with her voice
And I stand here in her place
Come on.
And from this day,
and evermore
Let me take
your coat, monsieur
Cosette shall live
in my protection
You are very welcome here
I will not forget my vow
Take a drink
Take a chair
Cosette shall
have a father now
What to do?
What to say?
Shall you carry
our treasure away?
What a gem!
What a pearl!
Beyond rubies is
our little girl
How can we
talk of debt?
Let's not haggle
for darling Colette
Cosette.
Cosette
Dear Fantine,
gone to rest
Have we done for her
child what is best?
I think so.
Shared our bread,
shared each bone
Treated her like
she's one of our own
Yes, our own.
Like our own,
monsieur!
The cost adds up.
Your feelings do
you credit, sir
And I will ease
the parting blow
Let us not talk of bargains
and bones and greed
Now may I say we are agreed?
That would
quite fit the bill
If she hadn't
so often been ill
Little dear, cost us dear
Medicines are expensive,
monsieur
Not that we begrudged a sou
It's no more than
we Christians must do
Than we Christians may do
No more words!
Here's your price
Fifteen hundred
for your sacrifice
Come, Cosette,
say goodbye
Let us seek out
some friendlier sky
Thank you, both, for Cosette
It won 't take you
too long to forget
Farewell, Courgette!
It's "Cosette."
Cosette.
And, open.
It's for you.
Where I go, you will be
Will you be
like a papa to me?
Yes, Cosette
This is true
I'll be father
and mother to you
Not bad.
Not enough!
There's a copper at the door
What the devil have you done?
Where's the child Cosette?
She's gone with a gent
Didn't tell us
where they went
Didn't leave
his home address
You're a bloody fool
Look at what we got
Should've struck the iron
Struck it while it's hot!
Next time round, I promise
I'm gonna get the lot
Okay?
Suddenly you're here
Suddenly it starts
Can two anxious hearts
beat as one?
Yesterday I was alone
Today you are beside me
Something still unclear
Something not yet here
has begun
Suddenly the world
seems a different place
Somehow full of grace
Full of light
How was I to know
that so much hope
Was held inside me?
What is passed is gone
Now we journey on
through the night
How was I to know at last
That happiness
can come so fast?
Trusting me the way you do
I'm so afraid of failing you
Just a child who cannot know
That danger follows where I go
There are shadows everywhere
And memories I cannot share
Nevermore alone
Nevermore apart
You have warmed my heart
like the sun
You have brought
the gift of life
And love so long denied me
Suddenly I see
What I could not see
Something suddenly
Has begun
Halt!
Let's see your papers.
Where are you traveling?
Cosette. Cosette.
Give me the doll.
Come.
Valjean!
Come, Cosette.
Come quickly!
Come on.
24601!
Cosette. I've got you.
Come, come.
Valjean!
Who's there?
Please, monsieur.
I need your help.
Please, please.
Monsieur le Mayor?
Who are you?
Fauchelevent.
I fell under my cart.
You saved my life, monsieur.
Fauchelevent.
We need a place of sanctuary,
this child and I.
We need to disappear.
We'll give thanks
for what is granted
What the sisters may ordain
Come.
Here we pray
for new beginnings
Here our lives
can start again
There,
out in the darkness
A fugitive running
Fallen from God
Fallen from grace
God be my witness
I never shall yield
Till we come face to face
He knows his way in the dark
Mine is the way of the Lord
Those who follow
the path of the righteous
Shall have their reward
And if they fall
as Lucifer fell
The flames! The sword!
Stars in your multitudes
Scarce to be counted
Filling the darkness
With order and light
You are the sentinels
Silent and sure
Keeping watch in the night
You know your place in the sky
You hold your course
and your aim
And each in your season
returns and returns
And is always the same
And if you fall
as Lucifer fell
You fall in flames!
And so it must be,
for so it is written
On the doorway to paradise
That those who falter
and those who fall
Must pay the price
Lord, let me find him
That I may see him
Safe behind bars!
I will never rest till then!
This I swear
This I swear by the stars!
Come on, boys!
Come on.
Look down and see
the beggars at your feet!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can
Look down and see
the sweepings of the street!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man!
How do you do?
My name's Gavroche
These are my people,
here's my patch
Not much to look at,
nothing posh
Nothing that
you'd call up to scratch
This is my school,
my high society
Here in
the slums of Saint Michel
We live on
crumbs of humble piety
Tough on the teeth,
but what the hell
Think you're poor?
Think you're free?
Follow me! Follow me!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man
Wait, Gavroche!
There was a time
we killed the king
We tried to change
the world too fast
Now we have got another king
He is no better than the last
This is the land
that fought for liberty
Now when we fight,
we fight for bread!
Here is
the thing about equality
Everyone's equal
when they're dead
Take your place!
Take your chance!
Vive la France!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man
When's this gonna end?
When we gonna live?
Something's gotta happen now
Something's gotta give
It'll come,
it'll come, it'll come
It'll come, it'll come
Where are
the leaders of the land?
Where is the king
who runs this show?
Only one man,
General Lamarque
Speaks for
the people here below!
Lamarque is ill
and fading fast
Won't last a week out,
so they say
With all the anger
in the land
How long before
the Judgment Day?
Before we cut
the fat ones down to size?
Death to the king!
Liberty for France!
Before the barricades arise?
Death to the king!
Tell your friends.
We come tomorrow.
We meet here at
General Lamarque's house.
Bring your friends.
Vive General Lamarque!
Marius!
Grandfather!
Have you any idea
of the shame you
bring on our family?
An utter disgrace.
Marius.
Vive General Lamarque!
Vive la France!
Hey there, monsieur,
what's new with you?
Plotting to
overthrow the state?
You still
pretending to be poor
Come on,
I know your grandpa's rich
Won't take a franc
that I've not earned
All of those bridges
have been burned
I like the way
you talk, monsieur!
you always tease
Little he knows
Little he sees
Here, take this.
Eponine!
Everyone here,
you know your place
Brujon, Babet, Claquesous
You, Montparnasse,
watch for the law
With Eponine, take care
You turn on the tears
No mistakes, my dears
Please, monsieur,
come this way
Here's a child
that ain 't eaten today
Save a life, spare a sou
God rewards all
the good that you do
Wait a bit!
Know that face!
Ain't the world
a remarkable place!
Men like me don 't forget
You're the bastard
that borrowed Colette!
Cosette.
Whatever.
What is this?
Are you mad?
No, monsieur,
you don't know what you say!
You know me! I know you!
And you'll pay
what we're due
And you'd better dig deep
'Cause she doesn't
come cheap
Brujon.
It's the police! Disappear!
Run for it! It's Javert!
- Cosette!
-  Papa.
Another brawl in the square
Another stink in the air
Was there a witness to this?
Well, let him speak to Javert!
Monsieur,
these streets are not safe
But let these vermin beware
We'll see that
justice is done
Look upon
this fine collection
Crawled from
underneath a stone
This swarm of
worms and maggots
Could have picked you
to the bone
I know this man over here
I know his name and his trade
And on your witness, monsieur,
I'll see him suitably paid
But where's
the gentleman gone?
And why on Earth
would he run?
You will have
a job to find him
He's not all he seems to be
And that girl
he trails behind him
Is the child
he stole from me
Yeah, and me.
Yeah, both of us.
Could it be
he's that old jailbird
That the tide now washes in?
Heard my name
and started running
All the omens point to him
In the absence of a victim
Dear Inspector, may I go?
And remember
When you've nicked him
It was me what told you so
Let the old man
keep on running
I will run him off his feet!
Everyone, about your business
Clear this garbage
off the street
Cosette! Now I remember
Cosette! How can it be?
We were children together
Look what's become of me
Eponine! Who was that girl?
That bourgeois
two-a-penny thing
Eponine, find her for me!
What will you give me?
Anything!
Got you all excited now
But God knows
what you see in her
Aren't you all delighted now?
No,
I don't want your money, sir
Eponine, do this for me
Discover where she lives
But careful how you go
Don't let your father know
Eponine! I'm lost
until she's found
You see? I told you so
There's lots of things
I know
'Ponine
She knows her way around
The time is near
So near it's stirring
the blood in their veins
And yet beware!
Don't let the wine
go to your brains
We need a sign to
rally the people
To call them to arms
And to bring them in line!
Marius, wake up!
What's wrong today?
You look as if
you've seen a ghost
Some wine, and
say what's going on
A ghost, you say?
A ghost maybe
She was just
like a ghost to me
One minute there,
then she was gone
I am agog!
I am aghast!
Is Marius in love
at last?
I've never heard
him "Ooh" and "Aah"
You talk of
battles to be won
And here he comes
like Don Juan
It is better
than an opera!
It is time for us all
to decide who we are
Do we fight for the right
to a night at the opera now?
Have you asked of yourself
What's the price
you might pay?
Is this simply a game
for a rich young boy to play?
The colors of the world
are changing day by day
Red, the blood of angry men!
Black, the dark of ages past!
Red, a world about to dawn!
Black,
the night that ends at last!
Had you seen her today
you might know how it feels
To be struck to the bone
in a moment of
breathless delight!
Had you been there today
you might also have known
How your world may be changed
in just one burst of light
And what was right seems wrong
And what was wrong seems right
Red!
I feel my soul on fire!
Black!
My world if she's not there!
Red!
The color of desire!
Black!
The color of despair!
Marius,
you're no longer a child
I do not doubt
you mean it well
But now
there is a higher call
I know.
Who cares about
your lonely soul?
We strive
towards a larger goal
Our little lives
don 't count at all!
Red!
The blood of angry men!
Black!
The dark of ages past!
Red!
A world about to dawn!
Black!
The night that ends at last!
Listen, everybody!
General Lamarque
is dead.
Lamarque,
his death is
the hour of fate
The people's man
His death is
the sign we await!
On his funeral day
they will honor his name
With the light of
rebellion ablaze in their eyes
From their candles of grief
we will kindle our flame
On the tomb of Lamarque
shall our barricade rise!
The time is here!
Let us welcome it gladly
with courage and cheer!
Let us take to the streets
with no doubt in our hearts
But a jubilant shout!
They will come one and all!
They will come
when we call!
Did you find her?
How strange
This feeling that
my life's begun at last
This change
Can people really
fall in love so fast?
What's the matter
with you, Cosette?
Have you been
too much on your own?
So many things unclear
So many things unknown
In my life
There are so many
questions and answers
That somehow seem wrong
In my life
There are times when
I catch in the silence
The sigh of a faraway song
And it sings
Of a world that I long to see
Out of reach
Just a whisper away
Waiting for me
Does he know I'm alive?
Do I know if he's real?
Does he see what I see?
Does he feel what I feel?
In my life
I'm no longer alone
Now the love in
my life is so near
Find me now
Find me here
Dear Cosette
You're such a lonely child
How pensive,
how sad you seem to me
Believe me,
were it within my power
I'd fill each passing hour
How quiet it must be,
I can see
With only me for company
There's so little I know
that I'm longing to know
Of the man that you were
in a time long ago
Please, Cosette.
There's so little you say
of the life you have known
Why you keep to yourself
Why you're always alone
So dark
So dark and deep
The secrets that you keep
In my life
Please forgive what I say
You are loving
and gentle and good
But Papa, dear Papa
In your eyes I am
still like that child
who was lost in a wood
No more words
It's a time that is dead
There are words
That are better unheard
Better unsaid
In my life
I'm no longer a child
and I yearn for
the truth that you know
Of the years, years ago
You will learn
Truth is given by God
to us all in our time
In our turn
In my life
She has burst like
the music of angels
The light of the sun
And my life seems to stop
as if something is over
And something
has scarcely begun!
Eponine, you're the friend
who has brought me here
Thanks to you
I'm at one with the gods
And heaven is near!
And I soar through
a world that is new
That is free
Every word that he says
is a dagger in me
In my life
There's been no one
like him anywhere
Anywhere, where he is
If he asked, I'd be his
In my life
There is someone
who touches my life
Waiting near
Waiting here
A heart full of love
A heart full of song
I'm doing everything
all wrong
Oh God, for shame
I do not even know your name
Dear mademoiselle
Won't you say?
Will you tell?
A heart full of love
No fear, no regret
My name is Marius Pontmercy
And mine's Cosette
Cosette,
I don't know what to say
Then make no sound
I am lost
I am found
A heart full of love
He was never mine to lose
A heart full of you
A single look
and then I knew
Why regret
what could not be?
I knew it, too
These are words
he'll never say
Not to me
From today
Not for me
Every day
His heart full of love
For it isn 't a dream
He will never feel this way
Not a dream after all
Cosette?
Cosette,
what are you doing?
I told you to stay inside.
Who is this hussy?
It's your brat Eponine!
Don't you know your own kid?
Why's she hanging
about here?
Eponine, get on home
You're not needed in this
We're enough here
without you
I know this house,
I tell you
There's nothing here for you
Just the old man and the girl
They live ordinary lives
Don 't interfere
You've got some gall
Take care, young miss
You've got a lot to say
I'm gonna scream!
I'm gonna warn them here!
One little scream
and you'll regret it
for a year!
My God, Cosette!
You wait, my girl!
You'll rue this night!
I'll make you scream!
You'll scream all right!
Police!
Must be Javert
He's found my cover at last
I've got to get Cosette away
We'll go to our apartment
at Rue de l'Homme Arm,
it's safer there.
Then I'll arrange
our passage to England.
No.
Hurry, Cosette!
Prepare to leave
Say no more
Tonight we'll away
Please, Papa, we can't!
Hurry, Cosette!
It's time to
close another door
and live another day!
Get dressed,
we're leaving. Now!
Please, no!
On my own
Pretending he's beside me
All alone
I walk with him till morning
Without him
I feel his arms around me
And when I lose my way
I close my eyes
And he has found me
In the rain
The pavement
shines like silver
All the lights
Are misty in the river
In the darkness the trees
are full of starlight
And all I see is him and me
forever and forever
And I know
It's only in my mind
That I'm talking to myself
And not to him
And although
I know that he is blind
Still I say
There's a way for us
I love him
But when the night is over
He is gone,
the river's just a river
Without him
the world around me changes
The trees are bare
and everywhere
the streets are
full of strangers
I love him
But every day I'm learning
All my life
I've only been pretending
Without me,
his world will go on turning
A world that's
full of happiness
That I have never known
I love him
But only on my own
One day more
Another day,
another destiny
This never-ending
road to Calvary
These men who seem
to know my crime will
surely come a second time
One day more
I did not live until today
How can I live
when we are parted?
One day more
Tomorrow
you'll be worlds away
And yet with you
my world has started
One more day all on my own
Will we ever meet again?
One more day
with him not caring
I was born
to be with you
What a life
I might have known
And I swear
I will be true
But he never saw me there
One more day
before the storm
Do I follow
where she goes?
At the barricades
of freedom!
Shall I join
my brothers there?
When our ranks
begin to form
Do I stay and do I dare?
Will you take
your place with me?
The time is now!
The day is here!
One day more!
One day more to revolution
We will nip it in the bud
We'll be ready
for these schoolboys
They will wet themselves
with blood!
One day more!
Watch 'em run amuck
Catch 'em as they fall
Never know your luck
when there's a free-for-all
Here's a little dip
There a little touch
Most of them are goners
So they won 't miss much!
One day
to a new beginning
Raise the flag
of freedom high!
Every man will be a king!
There's a new world
for the winning!
There's a new world to be won
Do you hear the people sing?
My place is here!
I fight with you!
One day more!
We will join
these people's heroes
We will follow
where they go
One more day all on my own
We will learn
their little secrets
We will know
the things they know
One day more!
Tomorrow
you'll be worlds away
One more day
to revolution
What a life
I might have known
We will nip it
in the bud
And yet with you
my world has started
We'll be ready
for these schoolboys
Tomorrow
will be far away
is the judgment day
Tomorrow we'll discover
What our God in heaven
has in store
One more dawn!
One more day!
One day more!
Do you hear the people sing
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again
When the beating of your heart
Echoes
the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong
and stand with me?
Beyond the barricade
Is there a world
you long to see?
Then join in the fight
That will give you
the right to be free!
Do you hear the people sing
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of
your heart echoes
the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Will you give all you can give
So that our banner
may advance?
Some will fall
and some will live
Will you stand up
and take your chance?
The blood of the martyrs
will water
the meadows of France!
Do you hear the people sing
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of
your heart echoes
the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Halt!
Draw!
She's an innocent woman!
Murderer!
Come here, you!
Charge!
Push them to the right.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, monsieur.
To the barricades!
Vive la France!
Get to the barricade!
Come on!
Get down! Get down!
Go, go, go!
Get off your arse!
It's begun!
The barricade!
Sorry, madame. Thank you.
What are you doing?
We need as much furniture
as you can throw down!
Throw everything you have!
Below!
Watch yourself,
watch yourself.
Go on, boys!
No!
Thank you, madame.
I need a volunteer!
Someone who can
find out their plan
and when they will attack.
I can find out the truth
I know their ways
Fought their wars
Served my time
In the days
Of my youth
See? The people unite!
I pray you're right
Dogs will bark
Fleas will bite!
They will do what is right
Red,
the blood of angry men!
Black,
the dark of ages past!
Red, a world about to dawn!
Black,
the night that ends at last!
He's back!
Listen, my friends
I have done as I said
I have been to their lines
I have counted each man
I will tell what I can
Better beware
They have armies to spare
And our danger is real
We will need all our cunning
to bring them to heel
Have faith!
If you know what
their movements are
we'll spoil their game
There are ways that
a people can fight
We shall overcome
their power!
I have overheard their plans
There will be
no attack tonight
They intend to starve you out
Before they
start a proper fight
Concentrate their force
Hit us when it's light
Liar!
Good evening, dear Inspector
Lovely evening, my dear!
I know this man, my friends
His name's Inspector Javert!
So don 't believe
a word he says because
none of it's true
This only goes to show
what little people can do
Bravo, little Gavroche
You're the top of the class
So what are we going to do
with this snake in the grass?
Take this man and throw him
in the tavern in there
The people will
decide your fate,
Inspector Javert
Shoot me now
or shoot me later
Every schoolboy
to his sport!
Death to each
and every traitor!
I renounce
your people's court!
We keep looking forward!
To your positions.
Move!
Now, hold your fire.
Hold your fire.
Front rank, kneel!
Save your gunpowder.
Take aim!
Get down.
Who's there?
French Revolution!
Fire!
They're coming!
They're coming
over the barricades!
Get back!
Marius! No!
Marius!
What are you doing?
Get down!
Marius, watch out!
No!
Fall back!
Fall back,
or I blow the barricade!
Blow it up and
take yourself with it!
Christ!
And myself with it.
Back! Back!
Man the barricade!
What were you thinking,
Marius?
You could have
gotten us all killed!
Marius,
you saved us all.
My life is not
yours to risk!
Eponine.
What are you doing?
I kept it from you.
It's from Cosette.
The rain's
going to ruin the powder.
I'm sorry.
What have you done?
'Ponine.
Don't you fret,
Monsieur Marius
I don't feel any pain
A little fall of rain
Can hardly hurt me now
You're here
That's all I need to know
And you will keep me safe
And you will keep me close
And rain will
make the flowers grow
But you will live, 'Ponine
Dear God above!
If I could close your wounds
with words of love
Just hold me now,
and let it be
Shelter me, comfort me
Hush-a-bye, dear Eponine
So don't you fret,
Monsieur Marius
You won 't feel any pain
I don 't feel any pain
A little fall of rain
Can hardly hurt you now
Can hardly hurt me now
I'm here
That's all I need to know
And I will stay with you
And you will keep me safe
Till you are sleeping
And you will keep me close
And rain
Will make the flowers
Grow
Gavroche, will you
do something for me?
Anything. Without you,
I'd have bitten the dust.
Letter from the barricade.
From the barricade?
I'll take it.
Something for me,
something for you.
Who needs charity?
Boy.
You stay away from there,
you understand?
"Dearest Cosette,
you have entered my soul
"And soon you will be gone
"Can it be only
a day since we met
and the world was reborn?
"If I should fall
in the battle to come
let this be my goodbye
"Now that I know
that you love...
"You love me as well
It is harder to die
"I pray that God
will bring me home
to be with you
"Pray for your Marius
"He prays for you"
Oh, God.
This is the day
that most I feared
Now a young man has appeared
to change my life
This Marius will take away
the treasure of my
autumn days to be his wife
But he could die tonight
I must find this boy
Don't shoot!
I come here
as a volunteer.
You see...
You see that
prisoner over there?
A volunteer like you!
A spy who calls
himself Javert!
He's going to get it, too!
Get in there.
Get inside.
Don't kill him.
I know him.
Enemy marksman!
On the roof!
Where are they?
We'll take the left.
We'll
take the right.
Eyes forward!
Eyes to the roofs,
eyes to the roofs.
Thank you, monsieur.
Give me
no thanks, monsieur
There's something you can do
If it is in my power
Give me the spy Javert!
Let me take care of him
Do what you have to do
The man belongs to you
No. Enjolras.
We meet again
You've hungered for
this all your life
Take your revenge
How right you
should kill with a knife
Get out of here
Don't understand
Clear out of here
Once a thief, forever a thief
What you want,
you always steal
You would trade
your life for mine
Yes, Valjean, you want a deal
Shoot me now for all I care!
If you let me go, beware!
You'll still answer to Javert!
You are wrong and
always have been wrong
I'm a man
no worse than any man
And you are free and
there are no conditions
No bargains or petitions
There's nothing
that I blame you for
You've done your duty,
nothing more
If I come
out of this alive...
You will find me at
Rue de l'Homme Arm, number 5
No doubt our paths
will cross again.
Courfeyrac,
you take the watch
They may attack
before it's light
Everybody, keep the faith
For certain as
our banner flies
We are not alone
The people too must rise
Marius.
Rest.
Drink with me
To days gone by!
To the life
that used to be
At the shrine of friendship
never say die
Let the wine of friendship
never run dry
Here's to you
and here's to me!
Do I care if I should die
now she goes across the sea?
Life without Cosette
means nothing at all
Would you weep, Cosette,
if I were to fall?
Would you weep, Cosette
For me?
God on high
Hear my prayer
In my need
You have always been there
He is young
He's afraid
Let him rest
Heaven blessed
Bring him home
He's like the son
I might have known
If God had granted me a son
The summers die
One by one
How soon they fly
On and on
And I am old
And will be gone
Bring him peace
Bring him joy
He is young
He is only a boy
You can take
You can give
Let him be
Let him live
If I die
Let me die
Let him live
Bring him home
Bring him
Home!
Enjolras, the rain has
damaged the gunpowder.
We're low on ammunition.
We're the only
barricade left.
What?
We're the only ones left.
The people
have not stirred
We are abandoned by those
who still live in fear
Let us not waste lives
Let all who wish to
Go from here
Do you hear
the people sing
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again
When the beating
of your heart echoes
the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Enjolras,
we need more ammunition.
I'm going into the colonnade.
There are dead bodies there,
dry ammunition.
The gunpowder
is wet through.
Let's round it up.
Let's get everything out here.
Little people know
when little people fight
We may look easy pickings
Gavroche.
But we've got some bite!
Come here.
So never kick a dog
because he's just a pup
Gavroche!
We'll fight like 20 armies
and we won't give up
Gavroche! Gavroche,
what are you doing?
Someone pull him back!
You dirty bastard!
So you'd better
run for cover
When the pup...
Grows...
You at the barricades,
listen to this!
The people of Paris
sleep in their beds!
You have no chance
No chance at all
Why throw your lives away?
Let us die facing our foes
Make them bleed while we can
Make them pay through the nose
Make them pay for every man
Let others rise
to take our place
Until the Earth is free!
Cannons!
Quick as you can! Come on!
Look lively!
Far right first.
Wait for it!
Fire!
Marius.
They're bringing
in replacements.
Second cannon!
Fire!
Take aim!
Take cover, boy!
There's more men!
There's more men, Enjolras!
Cannons ready!
Fire!
And fire!
Advance!
Watch out!
Please!
Open the door!
We need the door!
We need to barricade
the door!
Marius! Marius!
Take positions!
Steady, lads!
-  Go!
-  They're coming!
Thank you!
Long live the revolution!
Here's a pretty ring.
Oh.
Hello.
You're alive! I saved you!
You!
How do I get out of here?
It's that way!
All the way down
and to the left!
It's you, Javert
I knew you
wouldn't wait too long
The faithful servant
at his post once more
This man's done no wrong
He needs a doctor's care
I warned you
I would not give in!
I won 't be swayed!
Another hour yet
Then I'm yours
All our debts are paid
The man of mercy comes again
And talks of justice!
Come, time is running short!
Look down, Javert
He's standing in his grave!
One more step
and you die.
Who is this man?
What sort of devil is he?
To have me caught in a trap
and choose to let me go free?
It was his hour at last
to put a seal on my fate
Wipe out the past
and wash me
clean off the slate
All it would take was
a flick of his knife
Vengeance was his
and he gave me back my life!
Damned if I live in
the debt of a thief!
Damned if I yield at
the end of the chase!
I am the law and
the law is not mocked!
I'll spit his pity
right back in his face!
There is nothing on Earth
that we share!
It is either
Valjean or Javert!
And my thoughts fly apart
Can this man be believed?
Shall his sins be forgiven?
Shall his crimes be reprieved?
And must I now begin to doubt
Who never doubted
all these years?
My heart is stone
and still it trembles
The world I have known
is lost in shadow
Is he from heaven
or from hell?
And does he know
That granting me my life today
This man has
killed me even so?
I am reaching but I fall
And the stars
are black and cold
As I stare into the void
of a world that cannot hold
I'll escape now
from that world
From the world of Jean Valjean
There is nowhere I can turn
There is no way to go on
Did you see them
going off to fight?
Children of the barricade
who didn 't last the night
Did you see them
lying where they died?
Someone used to cradle them
and kiss them when they cried
Did you see them
lying side by side?
There's a grief
that can't be spoken
There's a pain goes on and on
Empty chairs at empty tables
Now my friends
are dead and gone
Here they talked of revolution
Here it was they lit the flame
Here they sang about tomorrow
And tomorrow never came
From the table in the corner
They could see a world reborn
And they rose
with voices ringing
And I can hear them now
The very words
that they have sung
Became their last communion
On this lonely barricade
At dawn
Oh, my friends,
my friends, forgive me
That I live and you are gone
There's a grief
that can 't be spoken
There's a pain goes on and on
Phantom faces at the windows
Phantom shadows on the floor
Empty chairs at empty tables
Where my friends
will meet no more
Oh, my friends, my friends
Don 't ask me
What your sacrifice was for
Empty chairs at empty tables
Where my friends will sing
No more
Every day you walk
with stronger step
You walk with longer step
The worst is over
Don 't think about it,
Marius!
With all the years
ahead of us!
I will never go away
And we will be
together every day
Every day
We'll remember that night
And the vow that we made
A heart full of love
She was never mine to keep
A night full of you
She is youthful, she is free
The words are old
but always true
Cosette, Cosette!
Love is
the garden of the young
I saw you waiting
and I knew
Thank God you are here
Waiting for you
Let it be
At your feet
Thank God you are home
Let it be
A heart full of love
And it wasn't a dream
This I give you this day
Not a dream after all
Monsieur, this is a day
I never can forget
Is gratitude enough
for giving me Cosette?
Your home shall be with us
And not a day shall pass
But we will prove our love
To you, whom we shall call
A father to us both
A father to us all
Not another word, my son
There's something now
that must be done
There lived a man
whose name was Jean Valjean
He stole some bread to
save his sister's son
For 19 winters
he served his time
In sweat
he washed away his crime
Years ago
He broke parole and
lived a life apart
How could he tell Cosette
and break her heart?
Marius...
It's for Cosette
this must be faced
If he is caught,
she is disgraced
The time has come
to journey on
And from this day
he must be gone
Who am I?
You're Jean Valjean
Monsieur, you cannot leave
Whatever I tell
my beloved Cosette
She will never believe
Tell her
I've gone on a journey
A long way away
Tell her my heart was
too full for farewells
It is better this way
Promise me, monsieur
Cosette will never know
What I have spoken
Why I must go
For the sake of Cosette
It must be so
Thank you, Marius.
Where's he gone
without a word?
That wouldn't be
his way to go
Why so sudden,
why so strange?
Oh, did he say
how long he'll be gone?
All he asked for me to say
is he's on a journey far away
He can't leave us now
How he breaks my heart
And we will never be apart
I promise you.
The Baron and
Baroness du Thnard.
Go away, Thenardier!
Do you think
I don't know who you are?
He's not fooled
Told you so
Show monsieur
what you've come here to show
Tell the boy what you know
Pity to disturb you
at a feast like this
But 500 francs
surely wouldn't come amiss
In God's name,
say what you have to say
He speaks
You pay!
What I saw, clear as light
Jean Valjean in
the sewers one night
Had this corpse on his back
Some boy he had killed
in a vicious attack
I was there, never fear
I even found me
this fine souvenir
I know this
This is mine
This is surely
some heavenly sign
Then it's true
Then I'm right
Jean Valjean was
my savior that night
Jean Valjean, the old con
You pay up
or I'll say where he's gone
Where is he?
The convent!
Cosette, come with me.
Come with me.
Watch the buggers dance
Watch 'em till they drop!
Keep your wits about you
and you'll stand on top!
Masters of the land
Always get our share
Clear away the barricades
and we're still there
We know where
the wind is blowing
Money is the stuff we smell
And when we're rich
as Croesus
Jesus! Won't
we see you all in hell!
How dare you!
Alone I wait in the shadows
I count the hours
until I sleep
I dreamed a dream
Cosette stood by
It made her weep
to know I die
Alone at the end of the day
Upon this wedding night
I pray
Take these children, my Lord,
to Thy embrace
And show them grace
God on high
Hear my prayer
Take me now
To Thy care
Where You are
Let me be
Take me now
Take me there
Bring me home
Monsieur,
I bless your name
I am ready, Fantine
Monsieur,
lay down your burden
At the end of my days
You raised my child in love
She's the best of my life
And you will be with God
Oh!
Oh...
Fantine.
Papa, Papa,
I do not understand
Are you all right?
Why did you go away?
Cosette, my child!
Am I forgiven now?
Thank God, thank God
I've lived to see this day!
It's you who must forgive
a thoughtless fool
It's you who must
forgive a thankless man
It's thanks to you
that I am living
And again I lay down
my life at your feet
Cosette,
your father is a saint
When they wounded me
He took me from the barricade
Carried like a babe
And brought me home to you
Now you are here
Again beside me
Now I can die in peace
For now my life is blessed
You will live, Papa
You're going to live
It's too soon
Too soon to say goodbye
Yes, Cosette,
forbid me now to die!
I'll obey
I will try
On this page
I write my last confession
Read it well
when I at last am sleeping
It's the story
Of one who turned from hating
A man who only learned to love
When you were in his keeping
I know it, Papa.
Come with me
Where chains
will never bind you
I am ready, Fantine.
All your grief
At last, at last behind you
Lord in heaven
Look down on him in mercy
Forgive me all my trespasses
And take me to Your glory
Take my hand
I'll lead you to salvation
Take my love
For love is everlasting
And remember
The truth that once was spoken
To love another person
Is to see the face of God
Do you hear
the people sing lost in
the valley of the night?
It is the music of a people
who are climbing to the light
For the wretched of the Earth
There is a flame
that never dies
Even the darkest night
will end and
the sun will rise
We will live again in freedom
In the garden of the Lord
We will walk
behind the plowshare
We will put away the sword
The chain will be broken
and all men will
have their reward!
Will you join
in our crusade?
Who will be strong
and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond
the barricade
Is there a world
you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear
the distant drums?
It is the future that we bring
when tomorrow comes!
Will you join
in our crusade?
Who will be strong
and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond
the barricade
Is there a world
you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear
the distant drums?
It is the future that we bring
when tomorrow comes!
Tomorrow comes!