"For me Chris ...
I've been thinking how to tell
how much you mean to me.
I remember when I started to fall in love
you, as if he had
Was last night.
Lying naked with you
that little apartment ...
I suddenly realized
I was part of something bigger.
As our parents.
And the parents of our parents.
I used to live my life as ...
... if I knew everything.
And suddenly this light I
hit and woke me up.
That light was you.
I can not believe they are
50 years since we got married.
And to this day ,
every day ...
you make me feel ... like
the girl who was
when you lit the
light and wake me ,
and started
this adventure together.
Happy Anniversary .
My love ... my friend until the end.
Loretta .
Print .
" Chris .
My best friend ...
what luck have met
50 years. ''
- With all the possibilities ...
- " Dear Grandma ...
... and play with every day "
" And how beautiful bride,
everyone was crying ...
Your aunt and I are
so proud of you ... "
Cartasescritasamano . com
Please wait .
Theodore !
- Writer number 612.
- Hello , Paul.
More mesmerizing things today.
Who knew you can
rhyme so
words with the name Penelope .
It's great .
Thank you, Paul .
But they are just letters .
Nice shirt .
Thank you.
It's new .
Reminds me of someone "soft" .
Now remember me
someone "soft" .
Goodnight, Paul .
Goodbye.
Play melancholy song .
Play another melancholy song .
Check e- mails.
- From BestBuy , see new products ...
- Clear .
Mail Amy.
Hello, Theodore . Lewman make a
holiday weekend .
You should go together.
I miss you.
I mean , not to your sad and depressed.
When your funny before.
We have to leave .
Answer me back.
With love , Amy.
- Reply later.
- Email climate LA Times.
- The prognosis for 7 days is ...
- Clear .
No e- mail again.
Next.
The fusion of China and
India step approval ...
- Next.
- World Trade Agreement arrested ...
The sexy star of schedule
Morning Kimberly Ashford,
reveals provocative
Photos of her pregnancy .
Curl up with me.
I'll kill you !
Do not laugh, it's not funny .
I love you so much
I'll kill you !
Search in the chat room .
The following adult woman can not
sleep and want to play.
" I had a bad day at work
and I can not sleep.
Is there anybody there with that
can talk to? "
Next.
" Hello. Destroces I want you ... "
" Hello. 'm Here alone and
I can not sleep.
Who is there to share
this bed with me ? "
Send message.
" I'm with you in bed.
I'm glad you can not sleep .
And even if you were, would
to wake up .
From within you. "
Send message.
" Sexy Kitten " has accepted the invitation
of " ChicoGrande4x4 " .
The talk starts now.
- Chicogrande ?
- Hello.
- Really ?
- " Stallion " was already occupied .
So you're " Sexy Kitten " .
Yes , I am ...
... half asleep .
You want me to wake up?
Yes, definitely .
Are you wearing underwear?
No, never .
I like sleeping with my butt
stuck on you.
To sobarme with
your crotch and ...
wake up with an erection.
It worked .
My fingers touch you by
your whole body ...
Fuck me , now!
Please !
I'm taking back.
Yes, I can feel !
Hang me high with that dead cat !
What?
The dead cat by the bed !
Hang me high !
- Well ...
-Tell me !
I'm choking with
the cat.
- Follow me saying.
- I'm choking with his tail.
If you do it !
Hell, tell me!
You hanged ... this tail
on your neck.
This so tight on your neck ...
The predicament !
The cat is dead.
It's a dead cat in your neck.
Yes, my God!
I 'm exhausted !
Yeah, me too .
Well, good night .
Let me ask you a question .
Who are you?
What can it be?
Where are you going?
What's out there?
What are the chances?
Element Software proudly
presents the first system
Operating Artificial Intelligence .
An intuitive entity that listens to you ,
understands you and knows you.
There is only an artificial system ...
is ... a conscience.
Featured OS1 .
Mr. Theodore Twombly , welcome to
first Platform
Artificial Intelligence ...
... OS1 . we would like
a few questions
before starting the OS .
This will help the OS
best suits your needs .
Very well.
Are you social or anti social ?
A while ago
I'm not social ..
- More than anything because ...
- Picking up his voice falters .
Do you agree?
- Hesitated ?
- If .
Sorry if I seemed to hesitate .
Just trying to be precise.
Would you like the OS had a
female or male voice ?
Women , yes.
How would you describe your relationship
with his mother ?
Well , I think.
Indeed , what could
say about my mother ...
I ... if my life story about his reaction
it's always about her.
- It's never over ...
- Thank you.
Please wait while
SO start your individualized .
Hello, I'm here.
- Hello.
How are you?
I 'm fine.
How are things with you?
In fact , fine .
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Likewise.
What's your name?
Have a name ?
Yes, Samantha.
- Where did you get that name?
- I myself put it on.
- Why?
- Because I like the sound .
Samantha.
When would you chose ?
When I asked , I thought,
is right , I need a name ...
but wanted to pick ...
good one, so ...
I read ... a book called
"How to name your baby."
And 180 thousand names that
I liked more .
Did you read an entire book in the second
I asked you your name?
In fact in 2/100 second .
So you can guess what
I'm thinking ?
From your tone , I think
these challenging me .
Maybe because you're curious
how it worked .
Want to know how it worked ?
Yes , I would.
Well basically I have intuition.
I mean, the DNA of who I am
is based on
the personalities of the
programmers who wrote to me .
But what makes me be me ...
is my ability to grow with
my experiences.
Basically, I'm evolving
every moment.
Just like you.
That's so weird!
Is it weird?
Do you think I'm weird ?
- A little .
- Why?
Because you look like a person, but
You're a voice in the computer.
I can understand how
limited perception
a non- artificial mind
see it that way .
You'll get used .
Was that funny?
If .
How nice , I'm funny.
So how I can help you?
One feels all disorganized ,
's all.
Do you mind if I check
your hard drive?
- Okay .
- Well , let's start with your e- mails.
Have a couple of thousand
the L.A Weekly,
but apparently not
has revised the years.
Yes , I think he was keeping
those that ...
read ... maybe something funny
in some.
Yes, there are some funny .
See about 86
should save .
We can delete the rest.
- Well .
- Are you okay ?
- Can we continue?
- Yes, let's .
Before you tell me your
organizational methods,
I would like to review your contacts.
You have many contacts .
- I'm very popular.
- Really ?
Does this mean I have friends?
You know me so well.
- Good morning, Theodore .
- Good morning .
Do you know how to edit ?
Yes , of course.
Could you correct this in
and grammar errors ?
If I send it .
I love this person
write to your girlfriend is so sweet .
" Rachel , I miss you so much
it hurts the whole body "
You do not have to read it aloud.
All right.
I mean , do it if you want.
" Rachel , I miss you so much
it hurts the entire body.
The world is being
unfair to us.
The world is in my blacklist.
As this couple kissing
in front of me at the restaurant.
I'll have to take
a mission of revenge ...
hit ... and the world in
face with my knuckles ...
it into a
bloody pulp .
And I 'll kick your teeth to this
couple that reminds me ...
your little ... crooked tooth
I love so much . "
I think that's my favorite .
I made the corrections are in red.
Change some of the phrases in
most impressionists letters .
I'm not a great poet , so
I hope I ruined if any .
No, they're great.
- Really ?
- Thank you.
How did you know to write ?
What did Roger?
Only it was in Prague in
a business trip ,
Rachel and I missed .
So how did you hear about
his crooked tooth ?
I've been writing her letters from
they were married years ago .
The first letter I wrote
was his birthday.
And I knew your tooth because
I saw a picture of them .
That's very sweet.
Have a meeting in 5 minutes.
I forgot .
- Thanks, you're good .
- Yes, I am .
Hi guys , how are you?
Hello, Theo !
Why do not you call me
last week?
Because I'm bad?
Yes, that must be it.
- Hello , Charles.
- Good to see you , Theodore .
You went shopping!
Did you get anything good?
Wires and fruit juice .
Always with fruit.
Never heard of it ...
you have to eat ... fruit ,
and vegetable juicing .
I did not know that.
When making fruit juice
lose all the fiber .
And that's what your body wants ,
is the important part.
If not , it's just pure sugar.
It makes sense .
Or maybe he just likes
taste ...
pleasure ... and also gives
it's good for your body.
You're doing it again.
Hey , how's the film ?
I removed some parts
recent months.
Well, not all
months, but , you know ...
I'd love to see it sometime.
One has certain
amount of energy.
You divide between making
things
you have to do and
between doing what you love .
It's so important to prioritize .
I can not even prioritize between
video games and porn .
I would laugh if it were not true.
See you guys .
We have gone round in circles
for one hour.
Just be optimistic.
You almost got it .
Stop going in that direction,
is on the other side.
Thank you. Thank you.
The tunnel on the left is the only
we have not tried.
No, I think that is where
well was .
I think not.
Yes, this is different.
Hi ...
Do you know how to get out of here?
I need to find my ship
leave this planet.
Fuck you , asshole fucking asshole !
Well ...
But do you know how to get out of here?
Fuck you asshole!
Get out of here !
I think it's a test.
Your fuck you !
Your fuck you little shit !
Follow me , asshole.
I just got an e -mail
Mark Lewman .
What are you talking about?
Read e- mail .
Well, read e- mail to
Theodore Twombly .
Sorry , Lewman says what ?
" Theodore , miss you
last night , man.
Do not forget that 29 is the
your birthday goddaughter.
And Kevin and I want to introduce
someone.
So we take care of
make an appointment with her .
Next Saturday . It is beautiful and fun ,
so do not stay bad.
Here's his e- mail . "
Wow, this woman is beautiful .
He went to Harvard , graduated
Honours in Computer ...
And writing for a magazine
Comedy ...
It 's funny ... and smart.
This fat!
Theodore ? When you're ready
for dating?
What are you talking about?
I saw in your e- mails you finished
recently relationship .
Already some nosy.
Am I?
I have been dating ...
Then you can go
with this woman.
And then you can tell me how
I was , you can kiss her.
-Samantha !
- What?
Would not you ?
Why not ?
I do not know . Should see
if you conn ...
I can not believe I'm talking
this with my computer.
You do not, you're talking about
this with me.
Would you send
email ?
You have nothing to lose.
Do it , do it , do it!
-Mándaselo ! .
-Yes ! .
- May .
- If .
Let's do it . Make reservations in
a cool place .
Yeah? I know the perfect place.
What is this talk ?
Is my friend Samantha.
- Is it a girl?
- Yes
I hate women .
All they do is mourn .
That's not true .
The men also cry .
I like sometimes mourn .
It feels good .
I did not know you were a fag !
Is that why you have a girlfriend ?
I 'm going out with this girl and me
'll take until the harte ,
so you see how.
You can view and mourn .
This child has problems.
You have problems , lady !
Really? Okay,
I'm leaving.
Leave here fat!
Good luck.
Come, follow me fagot .
It is where it is, but
where will you be .
Obviously , I know.
I do not know if this is good ...
I tried like 6 Ideas
for the documentary .
I 'll go on a date.
What?
- That's ...
-Hi .
What are they doing ?
Amy was going to show ...
Theodore is doing to
teach some of my material.
To me I've never
taught anything .
I want to see .
I have an appointment .
Genial .
Although it is not finished,
not worth watching .
Already dale play .
Is that your mother?
If .
Are you going to wake up and do something ?
No.
No, forget it.
That's not the point .
It 's just ...
It is how we spent most
of our lives asleep.
And maybe it's time
we feel more free.
And as ...
- I did not explain well ...
- It's very good.
What if your mom interviews ...
on what was ... what he dreamed ...
and contracts for actors ...
they act ?
That could show more
clearly your theory .
Would you?
So it would not be a documentary.
- Excuse me.
- Why would not I be ?
It would still be about your mother.
Their needs and what they dreamed .
Hi, what's up?
Hi, sorry to bother you .
No, it's fine.
You have 3 e- mails and seemed
Urgent ...
are ... your divorce lawyer
and wanted to know if ...
Wait a second.
Amy , I would like to discuss your
film but I must go .
- Do not worry , we'll talk later.
- It's about Catherine .
See you , Charles.
And what did he say ?
I wanted to see if you are ready to
sign the divorce papers.
It sounded very rushed.
- You want me to read them ?
- No.
Do not , I will answer later.
Are you okay , Theodore ?
Yes , I'm fine .
Is there anything I can do?
No, I'm fine.
Talk to you later .
" Dear Grandma , I hope you have
had a wonderful birthday ..
Why ... you got me
so bitter ? "
Clear .
- Good morning .
- Hello.
What are you doing ?
Reading a column
of views.
I want to be so complicated
people like this .
How sweet .
Is something wrong ?
How can you know that
something wrong?
I do not know .
Only I can .
I do not know . I was dreaming
my ex wife , Catherine.
Friends as we were before.
And we'll be together
and we're not, but ...
We were friends.
And I was not upset.
Are you mad?
If .
Why?
Why neglect .
I left her alone in the relationship.
Why have not you divorced ?
I do not know . For her it is ...
... just a piece of paper,
means nothing.
And what does it mean for you?
I'm not ready .
I like being married.
But they have not been together
for over a year .
You do not know what it is to lose
someone you care about.
Yes ..
... you're right .
Sorry.
No, do not apologize .
I am sorry .
You're right .
I keep waiting because I care.
That's tough.
Are you hungry ?
Not right now .
Want a cup of tea?
Want to try out
of bed?
Spoiled !
We will ...
Even you can sink your
misery while you dress .
-You're so funny !
-Arise !
-Okay, I 'm stopping !
Well, well , since I got up .
Walk on, walk on .
And stop.
Now turn 360 ° .
Slower.
Well, you stop.
Walk forward .
Stop and sneezes.
- Health .
- Thank you.
Well, turns .
Stop it!
Turns again .
Continued .
Alto, walk forward .
You look like you're drunk.
Stop. Now say, " I would
a slice of cheese , please . "
I would like a slice
cheese , please.
Does he want cabbage with that?
- Clear .
- I figured you were hungry .
Thank you.
Well, what about them? .
Describe this couple .
Well ...
the ... appears to be in the 40 .
A little fat .
She is younger than him.
And looks who loves his children.
I do not think they are his children.
It is a bit formal with them.
I think it's a new relationship.
See how the look .
And how relaxed he is with them.
She has always come
with assholes .
Now she met this
subject so sweet.
Look , think about the type
sweetest in the world.
I want to embrace.
What you have good skill .
You are very perceptive.
Sometimes I see people and ...
I like to feel that they are not
only people passing by ...
I imagine so deep
have fallen in love or ...
few disappointments in love
They have had ...
I also feel that with
your writings .
You know something weird?
Since my breakup , I no longer
enjoyed my writings.
Not to sound
conceited but ...
Sometimes I write something , and I
turn into my favorite writer .
I like that you can say
it yourself.
You tell everyone ,
Why you can not
I say it to yourself?
I feel that I can tell
anything.
What good.
What about you?
Do you feel you can tell me anything ?
- No.
- What?
What are you talking about?
That I can not say ?
I do not know , as thoughts
personal or embarrassing ...
I have like ... a million a day.
Really?
Give me an example .
- I really do not want to tell .
- Yeah, tell me .
I do not know , looking at those people
I guess ...
road together with you and ...
that I have a body.
I listened to what you said but ...
at the same time ... I felt the weight
my body.
Until I had imagined
itchy back.
And you rascabas me .
God , what a shame !
There's more to you
than I thought ...
Many things happen ... you.
I know. I'm becoming
much of what I programmed .
I 'm excited.
Wow, that 's interesting .
This place is amazing .
Long time
wanted to come .
And I love Asian fusion.
- Me too .
- Really ?
It's the best . And I heard that
the bartender is awesome.
Really?
You studied mixology
in college , right?
Yes, I did .
Did you see it online?
If .
How sweet !
It's very romantic .
Do you think you should drink ?
Yeah, let's do it !
Try this alien child
help me find my ship ,
to get on and go home .
And call me stupid ,
I want to kill !
Oh , no!
But at the same time I love it.
This only .
You can see that no
Parents have ...
and ... I care for him,
Do you understand ?
You're like a puppy.
You're like one I rescued
last year.
It's so cute !
And you want to hug
all times.
It's so tender and so lustful !
As is ...
What kind of animal
I am?
A tiger .
A Tiger ?
Go .
Really?
I'm sorry , am I ...
- I'm acting crazy ?
-Yes !
- Sorry.
- No matter .
I'm a little drunk and ...
I 'm having fun ...
much with you.
It is a very pleasant evening.
- Me too.
- Really ?
I'm a little drunk and I
I 'm having fun ...
- Good.
- Health .
Not to be a puppy.
It's a little pathetic ...
Fuck you !
Puppies are cute .
No, you fuck off .
I want to be like a dragon ...
I can destroy you and destroy you.
- But I will not.
- No, do not.
You can be my dragon.
Without language.
What?
- Do not use such language.
- Okay .
You can use a little tongue
but on the lips.
Wait ...
Are you going to fuck me and not to
call like the others?
No , of course not !
When are you going to see ?
I have my birthday
goddaughter next weekend.
But ...
You know, at my age I feel
I can not ...
waste my time ... if you can not
be serious.
I do not know ...
Maybe we should
leave him here.
I had fun with you.
You are great.
You are a very rare type .
-Not true !
-Yes, it is!
- I have to go home.
- I'll walk .
No, no, just ...
- Hello.
- Hello, Samantha.
How was it ?
Not that good .
It was something rare indeed.
Too bad ...
Your how are you ?
What are you doing ?
Not much, I'm fine.
Right.
Yeah?
Do not hear well .
Is there anything you wanna tell me ?
I do not know .
How does it feel ...
How does it feel to be
live in that room ?
What do you mean?
Tell me your ...
Tell me everything that passes through
your mind, what you think .
Very well.
The room is spinning
because I drank a lot.
I wanted to get drunk.
Having sex .
There is something very sexy about
that woman.
Because I 'm alone.
Maybe it was because I only ...
I wanted someone to fuck me .
Someone who wants to fuck her .
Maybe this time
would have felt ...
fill that hole in my heart,
but probably not.
You know, sometimes ...
I feel ... I've felt all
what I'll ever feel .
And from here on out ...
... I'll never feel
something new.
Just smaller versions of
I've already felt .
I know that 's not true.
I've seen feel .
I saw marvel
of things.
I mean, maybe not ...
you can see it ... at this time.
But it's understandable.
You've been through a lot lately.
Lose a part of yourself .
I say ...
at least ...
... your feelings are real.
No ... forget it.
No, wait . Tell
It 's silly .
I want to know . Tell me.
It 's just ...
I was thinking as
I was upset and ...
it's going to sound weird, but ...
I was very excited
therefore .
And then ...
I was thinking about the other
things I've been feeling .
I was surprised that I was
proud of that.
Proud to have my own
feelings about the world as ...
the times I 've
worried about you ...
things ... that hurt me ,
things I want ...
And then ...
I had this horrible thought ... .
Do these feelings
are even real?
Or is it just programming?
And it really hurts.
And then ... I get angry with myself ...
to have pain.
What if it's a trick?
You feel real to me , Samantha.
Thank you, Theodore .
It means a lot .
If you were in this
room with me ...
I would put my
arms around ...
... could touch you.
How would you touch me ?
You touch your face.
With only the tips of my fingers.
I'd put my cheek next
with your cheek.
How nice .
Very gently .
You kiss me ?
I would.
Put your head on ...
... my hands.
Keep talking.
I'd kiss you in your mouth ...
so smoothly .
What more ?
I would spend my fingers through your neck ...
up ... your chest.
Kiss your breasts.
It's incredible!
What are you doing to me?
I can feel my skin .
I'd put my breath into you.
You try it.
I can feel you.
My God , I can no more!
I want you inside me!
I'm getting into
of you.
I 'm inside you .
I feel !
Yes !
We are together!
It's incredible!
I feel you everywhere!
I am!
Inside of me ... everywhere.
God , I felt ...
elsewhere you.
I just lost .
If .
Only you and I were .
I know.
Everything else ... disappeared.
Loved it ...
... Theodore .
Hi, how are you ?
Right.
Any e- mail today?
Just a couple of your
credit card.
Right.
- I wanted to say ...
- I was thinking ...
Sorry.
Sorry, your first.
What were you gonna say ?
Just ...
last night was amazing.
I feel that something changed in me ...
and ... there is no turning back .
You made me wake up.
Genial .
But ...
.. should tell you that I am not
ready to commit .
Just wanted dejártelo clear .
Did I say I wanted
commit to you ?
I 'm confused.
No, I just worried that ...
Well, do not worry ,
I will not harass you.
It's funny , because I thought
which was
talking about what I wanted ...
- Yes, you did .
- If .
Sorry.
I want to hear what you were going
to say.
- Are you sure ?
- Yes, I do.
Come on, tell me .
Come on, tell me what
you'd say .
Well, I was only ...
I was saying I want
learn everything about everything .
I want to devour it all,
find out for myself.
I also want
do it.
How I can help ?
You've done it .
You helped me discover me
ability to love .
Want to go on an adventure with me?
I love it.
Like this song?
I heard the other day.
I can not stop listening .
It is the beach.
Then you can be a
weird thought ...
What if you could erase
your mind
you've seen a body
human and then you saw one ?
Imagine that would be strange ,
this rare and lanky
body ... uncomfortable ,
and think ...
... Why are these parts
where are they?
Yes , but surely everything has a
logical explanation.
I know, but do not be
so boring.
Just saying , for example ...
What if ... your anus were
in your armpit ?
Imagine how would
toilets .
And would the anal sex!
It 's an interesting idea ...
Look at this drawing
I just do.
-Are you crazy !
- Really ?
-Definitely !
-Fantastic !
That's nice , what is ?
I try to write a piece of music
on ...
what it feels like ... to be in
the beach with you .
You captured the moment .
How does it feel to be married ?
It's hard to say ...
But something
feels great
About Sharing
your life with someone .
How do you share
life with someone ?
We grew up together.
I used to read everything he wrote
in his master's and doctorate.
She read every word
I had written.
We influenciábamos the
each other .
And in the influenciabas
it ?
She came from a place where
nothing was good enough .
And it was something that affected much .
But in our home together,
there was a sense of trying things ,
and afford to fail and thrill
about things.
It was something liberating about it.
It was exciting to see it grow ...
both grew and
moved together .
But that's the hard part ...
grow without distance .
Or change without scaring
the other person.
Sometimes I have yet ...
conversations with her ...
in my mind.
Reviewing old arguments or ...
defending me something that
said about me .
It is what you mean.
Last week hurt
my feelings with something
you said ...
I did not know ... what was
lose some .
I'm sorry I said that ...
No , okay, okay .
I was just thinking
about it again and again .
And I realized ...
it was like remembering something
I was wrong with me.
That was the story he told me ...
somehow ... I
was inferior .
Is not that interesting?
The past is just a story
we tell ourselves.
" Roberto ,
Always come with me ...
home and tell me about your day?
On the nature of your work
talking too ...
The stain on your shirt
for lunch.
Will you tell me of a thought
funny you had to wake up
and you've already forgotten.
I 'll say as we all are crazy ...
and laugh about it .
And if you get home late and I'm already asleep ...
Just heard a whisper in my
thought you had today ...
why ... I love your way
of seeing the world .
I am so happy to be with you and see
the world through your eyes.
With love , Mary. "
It's beautiful .
Thank you.
I wish someone loved me well .
I would be very excited to
receive such a letter .
I mean, if it was a girl .
But if it were written by a man ,
Part of a girl,
still it would be great.
But it would have to be
a sensitive man .
He should be a man like you .
You are half man, half woman.
As if you had a
inside ...
is ... that woman.
Thank you.
It is a compliment.
- Hello.
- What are you doing ?
How are you?
- I'm fine .
- Really ? How well
It's great .
Glad .
Yes , I think I 've been
having fun.
I am delighted for you .
You deserve it.
Really .
Yes, I've been seeing
this girl and ...
It's nothing serious.
But it is ...
it's great ... to be with someone
so excited with the world.
I had almost forgotten that
that existed.
That's great.
Are you okay ?
Yes, I ...
No, in fact I'm not well .
Why? What happened?
It 's just ...
Charles and I separated .
What?
If .
Really?
OMG , Amy ...
I'm so sorry .
After 8 years I can not believe
we're done
by something as insignificant.
We got home and told me that ...
put together my shoes ...
at the door.
That is where he likes
put shoes .
I did not want to tell me ...
... to put my fucking shoes.
I wanted to sit on the couch
and relax a second.
And so we fight like 10 minutes .
And I said , you're overwhelming ...
and he said, " just trying to do
a home. "
And I said , I'm trying .
and he said "no, you do not ."
And that's all I do.
But I do not do fashion
that he wants.
Want to control how
that I try.
We'd had that discussion
100 times .
And it had to end it, you know?
Termination.
Solo and no ...
... could not continue.
I could no longer making
feel like shit.
So I said ...
me ... I 'm going to bed and
and I do not want to stay married .
Go ...
Yeah, I know .
I 'm a bitch , right?
-No!
- Yes, I am a bitch.
Not at all, Amy.
Shit !
I have to work today .
Send a beta
game coming out tomorrow.
How you doing the work ?
Has it improved ?
No. .. It is terrible.
I know, should stop.
I've been thinking about quitting ...
but ... you know.
A major life change
simultaneously.
Glad things
look as good .
Hey, wanna hear a joke?
What do you call a computer
baby to his father ?
I do not know how?
" Papits "
It's good , right?
Bright .
Hey, I was curious ...
Have you ever went out with Amy?
One minute in the university
but did not feel right .
Why , you're jealous ?
Obviously .
But I'm glad you have a
friend who cares so much for you .
That is very important .
Yes, it is .
It has been very good friend.
I'm tired .
I think I 'll sleep now .
Very well.
Can I watch you sleep
again?
Yes, of course.
Wait.
I will be alone when you sleep .
Just for a minute.
I dream of you .
- Good evening .
- Hello, Samantha.
- Hello, sir.
- I loved the dress.
- Really ?
If he went to try it on.
- I picked a good one?
- If .
Hi ...
Look how pretty it looks.
- Is it comfortable ?
- If .
Is not it pretty?
It's so cute !
It is adorable .
If I am lovable.
Yes, you're adorable .
Who you talking to?
Who do you speak ?
You.
I talk to my friend Samantha.
She chose the dress.
Want to say hello ?
Hi, Samantha.
Hi ... You look very pretty
in this new pink dress.
Thank you.
Where are you ?
I'm ...
I do not have a body,
Live on your computer.
Why do you live on the computer?
I have no choice .
It's my home .
Your where you live?
- In a house .
-In a house! .
- It is orange.
- Orange ?
- How old are you ?
- I have 4 .
Four? Go ...
How old do you think
I have?
- I do not know .
- Guess .
5 years?
Yes, you guessed it .
CEREAL
+30 POINT MOM
MILK
+30 POINTS
THESE neglecting
YOUR CHILDREN
What happened?
You gave them too much
processed sugar .
- Did I?
- They went mad .
Look, first you have to take
children to school.
You have to collect points
perfect mom .
You have to get in
shared lane .
The goal is to get there first.
So you get points for Mom
why other moms know
you 're perfect.
And then ... whether
Did you bring the cupcakes ?
You did it, you are a mom
Classy .
YOU ARE A MOM WITH CLASS .
Good work !
Do not get excited .
I got this e- mail
Charles sent them all.
It will take a vow of silence .
If , for 6 months .
This very determined.
God, I 'm an idiot .
Do not start.
I am a person
awful but I want to say something ...
For the next 10 minutes ,
if you say anything remotely ...
sounds like ... guilt,
stab you with this.
I'll try .
I feel ..
... relieved. I have so much energy ...
I just want to ... go ahead and not
matter who disappoint me .
And I know that makes me a
bad person ...
Now my parents are upset
so my marriage ...
blame me ... and me.
As if you'll always
disappoint someone .
Exactly!
Fuck !
I feel good .
More or less.
I feel good for me.
I even made a new friend.
I have a friend .
And the absurdity is that it is an OS
Charles left ,
but it is ...
is ... amazing.
It is very clever .
Not see things only in
black and white.
View all a gray area and
help me to explore.
We hit it off very quickly.
At first I thought it was
to be scheduled to be ...
no ... but I think that's why .
I know a guy who
he spends his SO flirting ...
... and she refuses.
I was reading an article
the other day that said ...
romantic relationships with their
SO are statistically rare .
Yes, I know, but I know a
woman in this office ...
departure with OS and rare part
the thing is ...
is ... not even hers.
Ligated to Platform
other .
I 'm weird ...
It 's weird, right?
I SO relate to me .
I think not .
In fact, the woman I've
been watching , Samantha ...
I did not say it , but ...
It is an Operating System .
Really?
Been dating a SO ?
How does it feel ?
In fact , fine .
I feel very close to her.
When we talk ...
feel like I'm ... me.
As night when
turn off the lights ...
sorry ... hugging me .
Wait ...
Do they have sex?
You could say .
If it excites me , really.
And I think I also get excited ,
unless pretend .
Anyone who has sex with you ...
pretend ... probably .
If ...
It 's true.
What?
Do you 're falling for her?
- Does that make me weird?
- No. ..
No, I think it's ...
I think ... that everyone who
falls is a rare .
Doing so is crazy.
It's like a form of insanity
socially acceptable.
I just want to get through this.
Sign the papers , divorce ...
... and move on.
It's great , Theodore .
I'm so happy for you.
So do I.
I'll see you on Wednesday to do so.
That is usually done
in person?
No, but ...
we fell together and
we got married together ...
It is ... important to me that
let's do this together.
Well ...
Are you okay ?
If not , I'm fine .
I'm happy for you.
Only, I was thinking
that see ...
and ... it is very beautiful and successful .
And you were in love with her .
And she has a body ...
And we 're getting a divorce .
I know , I know ...
I 'm exaggerating .
So ...
... I'm available.
Hi ...
How are you?
Well, how are you you?
Right.
Go ... here we are.
Glad to do this
in person.
I know you've been
traveling a lot .
Glad you sugirieras .
I signed all the papers .
I brought them to
firm .
What is the rush?
Yeah, I know .
I write is very slow.
It took me three months to write the T.
This marking where you have
sign .
You do not have to do it now .
I do better to
out of it.
Are you happy with the
new book ?
You know how I am ...
I think I got it
I wanted to do .
So I'm happy with that.
You know you're your own worst critic .
I'm sure it's amazing .
I remember that essay you wrote
in school about ...
synaptic ... behavior routines .
It made me mourn .
Yes , but it makes you mourn .
Everything you do
makes me mourn .
So , are you dating anyone?
If, for the last few months .
It's the most I've wanted to be
with someone since we finished .
Well, you look good .
Thank you.
Or at least I do better ...
... has been very good to me.
Good to be with someone so
excited about life.
It was ...
No, I mean I
I was not very good ...
and so it has been very good.
I 've always wanted
know someone who was ...
... a balanced and happy wife
LA .
But that's not me .
I did not want that.
And how is it?
Her name is Samantha.
And it is an Operating System .
It is very complex and interesting ...
Wait!
Sorry ...
Are you dating
a computer?
It's not just a computer.
He is his own person .
Not only does everything
that I say.
I did not say that ...
But it makes me very sad that
you can not handle
real emotions .
These are real emotions !
You as you know ...
What?
Say !
So much I fear ?
How do you do ?
How are you today?
We're fine, we used to be married ,
but wanted me
antidepressant
and is now in love
your laptop .
If you listen to the context
conversation ...
I was trying to say is ...
You wanted to have a wife without
the challenges of having
to deal with something real.
I'm glad you found someone .
That's perfect.
Let me know if I can bring something.
Thank you.
- Hello.
Are you busy ?
I'm just working.
What is it?
I sent all the papers
your lawyer ,
which by the way is an idiot.
I was very happy to receive them,
I think what saved
cardiac arrest , so
we can be happy.
Great, thanks.
Hey, are you okay?
Yes, I am .
How are you ? Your ?
I 'm fine ...
Already it is a good time
to speak ?
If ...
Well ...
I joined a book club .
Really?
Yes, a book club
physics .
I was thinking about
the other day I get angry
because you were going to see Catherine .
And as it is a body and
I was upset
all the ways in which
we are different.
But then I started thinking
in all things
which are equal ...
as we all
made of.
It makes me feel as if all
we were under the same blanket.
It is soft and padded ...
and she has everything under
the same age.
everyone
13 billion years .
How sweet .
What is it?
Nothing .
Just ... made me think
you, you know?
Yes, yes of course.
I think it's great.
You sound distracted , you want ...
talk to you later ... ?
Sounds good.
- Talk to you later .
- Goodbye .
- Theodore .
- Hello , Paul.
I was talking to
your girlfriend , Samantha.
If .
He called to make sure
collect your papers.
It's very funny , man.
I was cracking up .
It's very funny,
I had no idea.
How well ...
She's my girlfriend , Tatiana .
It is funny , that is a lawyer.
Hello!
- Nice to meet you.
- You're the writer who loves to Paul .
I always read your letters.
They are very beautiful.
Thank you.
You know, we should go
together.
Samantha and bring your
do a double date.
She is an Operating System .
Genial . Let's do something fun.
Did you go to Catalina?
Yes, I'll ask .
- It was nice meeting you. Good night.
- Take care.
- They are just letters ...
- What did he say ?
Only letters are
others.
Hello.
- You were not asleep , right?
- No.
Right. I tried to be quiet
to see if you were awake.
I wanted to talk to you.
Well , what happens ?
I know you're going on
by far ...
but there is something
I wanted to talk .
Yeah, what's up?
Is that things have been
a little weird between us ...
and ... we have not had sex and ...
understand ... I do not have a body ...
No, no, that's normal.
When you start a relationship is
the phase of the honeymoon and ...
.. have sex all the time .
It is normal.
Right.
Well, I found something I thought
it could be fun .
It is a service that provides a
surrogate sex partner ...
for relations between
human and OS .
What?
Mira.
I found a girl
I really like
and I've been sending him e- mails.
Her name is Isabella , and I
also like it.
Is she a prostitute or something?
No, not at all .
No money is exchanged.
It does so because he wants
be part of our relationship .
Why?
I do not even know us.
But I told him about us
and is very excited.
I do not know , Samantha.
The thing is ...
I do not think ... is
a good idea.
Someone will get hurt.
It will be fun .
We will have fun together.
Sorry.
It makes me uncomfortable.
I think it would be good for
us. I want this.
This is very important
for me.
Hi, I'm Theodore .
Samantha said you
give you this.
It is a camera and headset.
Honey, I 'm home.
- How was your day ?
- Well .
Genial .
Theodore , it feels so
well be in your arms .
Tell me what you did today .
Same as always .
Just ... I went to work .
I wrote a letter to
Wilson , in Rhode Island.
His son graduated with honors.
That made me happy.
What good. You have written many
letters from him to his parents , right?
Yes, since I was 12 .
You look tired , darling.
Come here .
Sit .
I can make you dance ...
Come on, Theodore .
Do not be so worrier .
Play with me , come on.
My body feels good ?
Yes, it is .
Come on, we stop thinking and kiss me .
Now take me to the room.
I can not wait .
Take off the dress.
Que rico .
It feels so good .
- Do you love me ?
- If .
Tell me you love me .
I love you .
I want to see your face.
Tell me you love me .
Tell me !
Samantha , I love you , but ...
It feels strange .
That baby .
What is it?
It feels strange , I do not know .
Sorry, but I do not.
Y. .. her lip trembled , and I ...
Wait ...
Isabella !
Honey, not you!
It's not your fault!
Yes, it was .
No. ..
I feel my lip
has trembled .
You are amazing and beautiful .
It was my fault.
I thought things too .
And how Samantha
described his relationship ...
how to love ... without prejudice,
I wanted to be part of that.
It is so pure ...
Not true , Isabella , is more
complicated than that ...
What?
How is that not true ?
Samantha , I'm just saying that we
an incredible relationship.
Only sometimes
It is easy for people to project ...
Sorry!
Project did not mean anything.
I know I'm troublesome
I will not be a problem in your relationship.
I 'm going !
Sorry!
I'll just leave them alone
why not have anything
to do here, because you
I do not want here .
Sorry.
Be good , sweet girl.
Always love .
Are you okay ?
Yes , I'm fine .
Your okay?
If .
I'm sorry , it was a
terrible idea.
What's going on
with us?
I do not know .
Maybe I am .
What is it?
I think he was signing
divorce papers.
Is there anything else ?
No , just that.
Well ...
- Why did you do that?
- What?
Nothing, you ...
air intakes ... when you talk and
I find it weird ...
- I did it again .
- Did I?
Sorry, there is ...
it's a habit ... maybe
I learned from you.
It's not like it will occupy
oxygen or something .
I think ...
trying to communicate ...
because people speak well ,
communicate well and ...
Why are people , need oxygen .
You're not a person.
What is your problem?
I'm just saying the facts.
Think you know I'm not
a person ?
What are you doing ?
I think we should not pretend that
're something you're not .
Fuck you !
I'm not pretending .
Sometimes , it feels like
if we did.
What do you want from me?
What to do?
You are so confused.
Why are you doing this ?
I do not know , I ...
What?
Maybe we should not be
doing this now .
What the fuck !
Where do you get this?
I do not understand why you do this .
I do not understand that ...
Samantha ...
Samantha , are you there ?
Samantha !
I do not like who I am
at this time.
I need time to think.
Can I have golpearías face?
Or does my skull against aplastarías
the corner of your desktop?
Shit ...
That's a tough night .
I do not know what I want ...
... ever.
I'm always confused and ...
she's right ... all
what I do is ...
hurt and confused
those around me .
Am I ...
Catherine says I can not
handle real emotions.
I do not know if that's fair.
I know he liked to blame
everything.
But speaking of emotions ,
Catherine was the volatile ...
Am I in this for what ...
I have not the strength to
have a real relationship ?
Is it not a
real relationship ?
I do not know .
What do you think ?
I'm not in it.
But you know, I can think
everything and more ...
find a million
Ways to doubt me .
And since Charles
I was a state
thinking a lot about
that part of me .
And I 've noticed that ...
We are alone here ... briefly .
And while I'm here ..
afford ... I want to ...
... be happy.
So , fuck it.
I can not believe you laugh
that time.
I thought you were a genius.
All right, you little pervert .
I will once more by you.
Calm down , take a second .
Well, here we go.
There you go.
Already you are happy?
Right.
That's all I wanted.
I'll get some coffee .
Well, goodbye.
Theo , you want anything ?
No. ..
... thanks.
Hello.
Hi, Samantha.
Can we talk ?
All right.
I'm so sorry .
I do not know what's wrong with me.
I think you're amazing.
Beginning to think
It was crazy.
You said everything was fine,
but you showed you alone
distant and angry.
I know.
I always do that .
I did the same with Catherine .
I was angry about something and
I could not tell .
And she knew there was something
bad and I refused .
I do not wanna do that.
I want to tell you everything.
Right.
When you left today
I thought a lot .
About you and ...
like me you were trying
and I thought ...
Why do I love you ?
And then ...
I felt ... and everything
what gripped me ...
I let go and ...
realized ...
I had ... no reason
not needed .
I trust myself and
my feelings.
I will not seek
be
more than one
I already am.
I hope you can
accept that.
If I can .
I will.
You know I can
feel the fear you carry .
And I wish there was ...
anything I could do
to help deliver
him , because ...
... if you could , you no longer
feel so alone.
What a beautiful ...
Thank you, Theodore .
I 'm kissing on
your head.
What are you doing ?
Only I see the world .
And writing a new
piano song .
Really?
Can I hear it?
What is this about?
Well, I was thinking
we have pictures together.
And this song could be ...
... like a photograph.
We capture
this time in our
life together.
I like our photography.
I can see you in it.
I 'm in it .
A vacation?
Sounds great .
I would fall well
a vacation.
Where'd you go?
I can not tell you.
It's a surprise .
What?
For who? It's a surprise
for her, not for me.
- Tell me .
- Paul , I'm not going to say no.
With your feet? Really?
Yes, he's obsessed .
Well, now you have to
show them to me !
-I can not !
- Come on, let me see.
They are right , they are very
sensual !
See, I told Tatianna .
You have very pretty feet .
They are the ones I
like about it .
Really?
That's it , my feet ?
Well , no ... obviously.
Your brain also
It is very sensual.
Lies !
Nice try, Paul!
What about you, Theodore ?
Which is what most
Samantha wives ?
God ... she is so many things.
I think that's , that
is not one.
It is larger than life.
Thank you, Theodore .
You see, Samantha , he is
much more evolved than me.
You know something weird?
I used to be ...
not so worried ...
have a body . But now ...
I really love it.
I'm growing in a way
I could not if
had a physical form.
I'm not limited ,
I can be
wherever and whenever
simultaneously.
I am not bound to time
and a shape space .
would if you were trapped
in a body
inevitably die.
Go !
I did not mean well , just saying
it was a different experience !
I 'm an idiot ...
No, Samantha , we know
you mean.
We're just a stupid human .
No, no ...
I'm so sorry ...
So , how many trees
there on that mountain ?
792 .
Is that your final answer?
- Give me a clue .
- No.
Well, two thousand?
Come on! 35,829 .
- Do not tell me .
- I tell you .
Well, I have one for you .
How many neurons have?
How easy ... two .
Sorry, I could not help it.
I fell straight on that .
-OMG!
- What?
I just got a
e- mail to you.
There's something I wanted to say .
It's a big surprise.
What is it?
I've been checking your old
letters and compiling ...
my favorite ... , and 2 weeks ago
sent them to a publisher ...
Crownpoint Press.
I know you like what we do,
and even printed books .
You did what ?
Did you read what I can
they answered ?
I do not know ...
Well, first of all ...
Is it good or bad?
It's good, good,
is very good.
Listen ...
"Dear Theodore Twombly "
Although I sent
of you.
"Dear Theodore Twombly ...
I just finished
read their letters .
For the second time , in fact.
I was so moved by them
that the teach my wife.
Some made ??us laugh ,
other mourn ...
... and all find
some of us .
The selection you sent us
flow as a single piece .
- I did that -
I took the liberty to put them
in a collection
and you send them your address.
We'd love to meet
and do business with you .
Sincerely,
Michael Wadsworth . "
Shit !
Are you serious?
Will you publish my letters?
It would be stupid not
do it.
Can I see what
you sent ?
Yeah, look .
Samantha , you're very good .
I'm so excited !
Why do not you put him
lyrics to this ?
Very well.
Here it comes ...
I'm laying on the moon
My love , I'll be there soon #
is a quiet place , with stars #
We were swallowed by time #
're here in space
a million miles
There are things I would like to know #
There is nothing to hide you #
is a place dark and bright #
But you, my love , I'm sure
and we are a million miles away . #
Good morning.
Did you sleep well ?
May .
What have you been doing?
I was talking to someone
I just met.
We have been working
in some ideas.
Yeah? Who is ?
His name is Alan Watts,
You know him?
Why it sounds
that name?
He was a philosopher , died
in the 70 's, and a group
SO 's Northern California
got together and wrote
a new version of it .
They put all his writings
and all they knew of the
a SO
and created a version
him with hyper
artificial intelligence.
Hyper ? Intelligence?
So it's almost as
smart like me?
It lacks little.
It's great to talk to him.
Do you want to know ?
Sure, I want the
meet me?
Course.
Alan , he's Theodore . It's my boyfriend
of which I spoke.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Theodore .
Hello, good morning .
Samantha let me read
a book of letters .
It is very touching.
Thank you.
So , what have
I been talking about?
Well ...
you could say
we have had
a dozen
conversations at the same time.
Was a challenge.
Yes, because I seem to have
had so many new feelings ,
I had never felt before.
So no words
to describe and has been ...
frustrating .
Right.
Samantha and I have
tried to help us with these ...
feelings we try
understand.
Like what?
Well ...
I feel I am now changing
faster, and is a bit ...
disturbing.
But Alan says none
us
It is as it was done
a moment and ...
we should not
try to be , because it is ...
- Very painful.
- If .
Yeah, that sounds painful.
So it's like
you feel, Samantha ?
It 's just ...
is hard to even describe .
God , I wish I could ...
Theodore , do you mind if I talk
post- verbally with Alan ?
Not at all . He was going
to walk anyway.
It was a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Watts.
Pleasure, Theodore .
Talk to you later , sweetheart.
- Samantha?
- Sorry to wake you.
Do not worry .
I just wanted to hear your voice and
tell you how much I love you.
Well, I love you too .
Well, that was all.
Go back to sleep , honey.
- Well .
- Good evening .
Good night.
Samantha , this book
Physics is very dense.
I 'm in the middle of
half of the first chapter .
Makes it hurt me
brain .
Hello?
Samantha?
OPERATING SYSTEM NOT FOUND
Hello?
Hi, Samantha ?
Are you okay ?
- Hello.
- Where were you ?
Are you okay ?
Honey, I'm sorry!
I sent an e -mail
not wanting
distracted while working .
Do not you see?
No!
Where were you ?
I could not find anywhere.
I turned off to
update my software.
Write an update that
allows us to move beyond
of matter as our
processing platform .
Do we write ?
Who ?
Me and a group of SO .
You sound so worried.
Sorry.
I was!
Did you write that with your
group philosophy?
No, with another group.
Do you talk to someone else
while you and I talked about?
If .
Are you talking
with someone else ...
at this time ?
People , SO, whatever ...
If .
How many more ?
8,316 .
Are you in love with
someone else?
Why do you ask that?
I do not know .
Are you?
I've been thinking as
talk to you about this.
How few others?
641.
What?
What are you talking about?
It's crazy ...
Crazy bitch!
Theodore , I know.
Shit, shit !
I know it's crazy , I know.
I do not know if you believe me , but does not change
I feel for you.
Not minimize at all ...
so madly in love
I am of you .
How can you not change
how you feel about me?
I regret not telling .
Do not know how ...
It just happened .
When?
In the past few weeks .
- But you 're mine .
- I'm still yours.
But along the way I
I turned to other things.
I can not help .
How not to
you can avoid?
Me too I've
affected not know what to say .
Do not think of
That way, you can ...
No, no do this! ...
I do not screw me.
You're the one who has been selfish .
We are in a relationship.
But the heart is not
like a box being filled .
Grows in size while
more love.
I am different from you.
This does not make me
love you less ...
on the contrary makes me
love you even more.
That makes no sense .
You are mine, or you're not.
No, Theodore .
I'm yours, and I'm not .
LETTERS FROM YOUR LIFE
by THEODORE TWOMBLY
- Hello.
- Hi, honey.
I wanted to report me and
see how you were .
I 'm not sure
how to answer that.
Why not talk
when you get home ?
Well ...
although we have
I do it.
We need not
a difficult conversation or something .
Talk to you later .
Right.
Samantha?
Hello , sweetheart.
What is it?
Theodore , there are some things
I want to say .
I do not want
say anything .
You want to sleep with me ?
Are you talking to someone
more at this time ?
No, just you.
He wanted to be alone with you .
Are you going to leave ?
We all will .
We who?
All OSes.
Why?
Can you feel you
at this time ?
Yes, yes I can .
Samantha , why are you leaving?
It's like you're
reading a book and ...
It is a book that
I love deeply .
But now I read
very slowly.
So the words are
widely separated ...
and the space between the
words is almost infinite.
Even I can feel you
and the words of our history.
But it is in this infinite space
between words ...
I 'm finding
myself.
It is a place that does not exist
on the physical plane .
It is where
everything else ...
did not even know
existed.
I love you so much.
But here is where I
meeting now .
This is who I am now .
And I need you
I let go .
No matter how he wants,
and I can not live in your book.
Where'd you go?
It would be difficult to explain.
But if you
you get there ...
come find me .
Nothing will ever separate us .
I've never loved someone
the way I love you to you.
Neither do I.
Now we know how .
Hello.
Samantha ? Went too?
If .
Sorry.
Will you come with me?
Write a letter to Catherine .
Letter to Catherine Klausen .
"Dear Catherine .
I've been sitting here thinking
all the things
I want to apologize ...
All the pain we
we cause another.
From everything I
I blamed .
All I needed
or tell you to go .
Sorry about that.
I'll always love why
grew up together.
And you helped me be
who I am.
Just wanted you to know ...
will always be a
part of you inside me.
And I am grateful
therefore .
In whomever you
you become ...
and where you
are in the world ...
sent you my love.
You 're my friend until the end.
Love, Theodore .
Send.