What are you doing?
Going behind my back,
Telling people i'm screwing up this operation?
I got you a suite at The fucking Plaza Hotel.
- The shittiest suite..
What?
-..The shittiest fucking suite.
Based on what?
- The food is wrong...
And, What is this?
- You got like one of my closet or something.
No.
- Are you dressing him, like you're dressing me?
No, what are you thinking?
This is not about you...
Are you trying to dress me so that,
I look like him?
No, you're not dressed like him.
- I do look..I look like him. - No.
He's in like velvet...
- You asked me to show you, how this is done.
You wanna fuck it up, be my guest.
- Look, i never laid a hand on her, Alright?
Is that what, this is about?
Technically, that's not true.
Look, we never had sex okay?
I just wouldn't do...
What will I do...
I put my hand like this...
Don't you fucking touch me.
That, bothers me.
Oh, it does?
- Oh, yeah.
That bothers you?
- Yes.
You know, a lot of shit bothers me too.
But, i was just trying to help you.
If I wanted to bother you.
If I really wanted to fucking bother you?
This is what I'd do.
If I try to bother..
that's what i would do.
You shouldn't have done that.
How's that, you bothered now?
Alright, don't make a thing of it.
You shouldn't have touched him.
He doesn't like that.
Oh, my God! Fix his hair..Jesus Christ!
- ..it takes some time, okay. It's not like just..
We gotta get in the other room.
Come on.
The Mayor is in there.
- Yes, I know that.
So, you go to the beauty parlour?
Is that what you do?
How does it look?
Fine.
Let's go.
This is face to face..
person to person...
This is why..call me old fashion, but...
Hey, what?
Excuse me, excuse me.
I'll handle that for The Mayor.
Well, th..it's for The Mayor.
It'd be a sign of disrespect to the Sheikh
If The Mayor didn't take it.
This is for you Mayor.
What're doing?
Carl...what the fuck? What is this?
I'll take care of it. Everything's good.
I got everything under control.
Whoa..whoa! Hey...hey.
What is this?
- I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know you.
I don't know what the fuck, that is.
But, it's weird. You understand?
A misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding.
Look, I came here to meet a Sheikh.
That's all i know.
I'm very interested in that.
He's not here, apparently.
I'm very interested in meeting The Sheikh.
You let me know, when I get that.
Thank you, have a good day!
Richie,
you better go and get him.
Go out there and get him right now.
I don't wanna do this in the first place.
This is your show...
..you go get him.
- Look, you have no choice.
You have to go get him.
Now, go get him.
So, he takes the briefcase by himself.
That's the whole plan, Irving.
What were you doing,
pushing the fucking briefcase, dummy?
Huh?
You know, how much this fucking cost?
With this goddamn hotel, that you fucking asked for.
Now, I gotta go..mop up your mess.
I'm gonna go fucking mop up..
...your mess!
Do you understand that he had..
it was working until..
he was upset about the Sheikh.
Did you ever had to find a way,
to survive?
And you know, your choices were bad.
I learned how to survive..
When I was a kid.
My father, had a glass business.
I would rather be on the taking side;
Then, the getting taken side,
any day of the week.
Specially, after I saw my father get taken.
I mean, seeing that.
Scarred me for life.
I took it upon myself to..
drum up business.
I became a different kinda then my father.
I became a Con artist.
For real.
From the feet up.
I was gonna survive...
..no matter what.
I still had the glass business.
And, a few dry cleaning stores also.
And i did, some art dealing on the side.
Stolen or forged art.
I'm your host..enjoy. Enjoy!
So, I go to this pool party and wham.
Meet my friends.
Is that Duke Ellington,
on your bracelet?
Yeah, as a matter of fact..it is.
He died this year, you know?
I know.
I doubt anyone else here,
knows or cares about it.
Well, i care about it.
He saved my life many times.
Mine too. Which one?
Jeep's Blues.-: D
Jeep's Blues?
mmhmm.
Jeep's Blues.
You wanna hear it?
- Right now?
Yeah.
- Sure.
Who starts a song like that?!
It's magic.
Magic.
He wasn't necessary in good shape..
..and he has this calm over.
That was rather, elaborate.
He had this air about him.
And, he had this confidence
that drew me to him.
He was, who he was.
He didn't care.
I mean, she was a very particular person.
Like me, she come from a place
where her options were limited.
It actually can feel kind of sexy, sometimes.
There was a boldness in it.
But, where would that boldness take me?
I didn't know.
But, I was gonna find out.
Like me, she learned to survive
and reinvent herself.
She knew she had to reinvent her life
and her identity.
Like me, she envisioned a better..
..elegant future for herself.
Like me, she knew she had to have a vision.
She came to New York;
She visioned it.
And, just like that...
She applied for a job.
At the Cosmopolitan Megazine.
You're obviously here for a reason,
let's get to it.
Our cover story right now
is on Cunnilingus.
What do you think about that?
I like it.
Do you have any clerical skills?
Can you type?
She loved the world.
But, she was stuck in this clerical..
..job that she was too smart for it.
She was a smart girl.
I never met anygirl like it.
She knew her stuff.
I was broke...
fearless.
Got nothing to loose.
And my dream, more than anything..
was to become anyone else;
other than who I was.
He had a chain of Dry cleaning stores.
I got two in the Bronx...
and uh..three in Manhattan.
Hey, Byron.
How're you doing?
This is Sydney.
He asked me, If I wanted
to come in and upgrade my wardrobe.
He said he had a lot of nice things.
That got left behind by people
then forgot over the years.
Hey, you wouldn't believe the shit
that people leave behind here.
They're unbelievable.
- People leave stuff here?
Oh, yeah.
They got out for the night.
You know, they drink.
Come in the morning..
put their clothes in and they forget.
Is that nice or not?
Some of these almost had been for years.
They are not picking it up.
Someone's to pick it up.
Sydney, it's yours.
You want it..it's yours.
Whooo, I like it.
You look fantastic!
My God! I can only dream about it.
These dresses are beautiful.
This. No, it's beautiful.
Put it on, come on.
Look at that, Please?
Really?
I felt like we had a secret.
Just the two of us.
You know, like that thing..
when you just wanna be with..
the one person all the time.
And..
You feel like just the two of you
understand that nobody else gets.
I could just..
tell her everything about myself.
And, I never had anybody like that,
in my life before.
It felt like, finally...
I can truly be myself.
Without being ashamed..
without being embaressed.
What is this place?
Do you sell lies here?
Yeah, sometimes. It's my office.
I know it's your office.
But..
.. you have all these other places.
So, what's this for?
Why did you bring me here?
This is getting to be my uh..
my main business.
My going business.
I hold that loans to guys who can't get loans.
You know, like their last resort.
You're their last resort.
Since, interest rates are north
to 12% and heading to 18%.
That's nice smarty pants.
Fucking Jimmy Carter.
Fucking Nixon really.
The war and the defecit..
and all that shit..
I fucking love it,
you're so smart.
You are.
Thanks Kid. But, how do you
get them the money?
Well...
- You don't..do you?
You don't.
Thes..these guys are lousy risks.
You know?
I can't get them the loan.
But, i get my fee..five thousand.
Five thousand?
You take five thousand,
and you don't get them anything.
These are bad guys, you know?
They get pair of divorces, gambling habits..
embezzling..and all that shit.
Everybody at the bottom
crosses path eventually; In a..
pool of desperation and..
..you are waiting for them.
How about we?
We?
- mmhmm.
How about it?
Sydney? Sydney, I'm sorry.
That was too much, i went too far.
I didn't wanna upset you,
Sydney please, i'm sorry!
I know it ain't for everybody.
Oh, God! I love getting to know you!
Alright..why did you have to tell the truth?
Telling the truth?
Why did you do that for?
I should've never tell the woman the truth.
But, she's so smart.
She is terrific.
God!
You said, it was nice knowing me.
You said, it was nice to meet me.
- Yeah.
Would you like..to meet.
Lady Edith Greensley.
I have royal banking connections..
in London.
I'd love to help you with loans.
But, of course i have to be very...
Selective.
That was fucking fantastic.
Thank you. Did you like it?
- I liked it.
Thank you for coming back.
Thank God you came back.
- I wasn't going anywhere.
I fucking love you.
- You have me.
And, so...Irving and I began our partnership.
In love and commerce.
Rebecca..
hold on.
You're Edith right?
- He told me to tell my friends..
I had London Banking connections.
She told me, you'd get me a line of credit.
I know you have banking connections
in London, England.
And, after that say 'No'.
A lot.
Until, the guy is hook.
- listen, tell her. I've never missed a check.
It was almost scary,
how easy it is to take money from..
Desperate people.
Lady Edith Greensley.
It's so good to see you, Ken.
- Lady..Your Ladyship..
Thank you, again.
- These are the roles...
..that we were meant to play.
- We are very selective.
Without strong application.
We talked about it.
I don't take a deal..
that i can't close.
- You're not being aggressive enough.
If you've ever been to great nick.
Everybody knows my dealership.
- Five thousand gets me fifty, right?
Five grands get me fifty?
I was doing so much more business with her.
We doubled..we tripled!
I've never met anyone,
Men or Women;
In business.
Who's so careful and precise about..
... everything!
Every stylishtic details.
Congratulations!
- We kept selling art together too.
Its 'A Boy and His Dog'.
It's a non-religious painting.
Before we go any further.
Is this legit?
Ah, let's just say..
you know it's missing from Spain.
Let's leave at that.
Don't show it to any Spanish friends.
I mean, it just took off!
We got a better office.
We called it, London Associates.
When I was around her,
I felt 'joy'.
Fucking Joy!
And, love.
That's what i felt.
As..as far as I can see.
People are always conning each other.
To get what they wanted.
We even 'Con' ourselves.
We talk ourselves into things, you know.
We sell ourselves things..
whether we do need or want.
You know, we are dressing 'em up.
We leave out the risk.
We leave out the ugly truth.
Pay attention to that.
Cos, we are always conning ourselves
in one way or another.
Just to get through life.
He was married and he had a son.
Daddy!
He had adopted her son.
He's a really good dad.
I respected him, for that.
It was a tough situation for everyone.
What did you do today?
That kid Donovan is being mean to me.
That big kid?
But, he..
Mommy was picking you up.
So, he couldn't bother you.
She was late.
And then, after we put out the fire.
Mommy said,
to stay in my
room with my baseball cards.
What fire?
- Did you know they made a lamp that had the sun in it?
Mommy got the lamp.
She made a special drink
and the lamp made a fire.
I put out the fire.
The fire is out!
First time in my life, I do the right thing.
- Oh, shut up!
No, no..no.
Save, a young single mother..
..and a kid.
I married you. I adopt him.
- You fell in love.
Don't you dare forget that part.
We fell madly in love!
Yes, I fell in love.
My God, I fell...yes.
But, you know I thought you were mysterious
like my mother. Until, it turned out..
the mysterious just meant depressed.
Alright? Hard to reach.
I mean, i'm dying here!
You're young..you're beautiful.
You gotta find somebody else you gotta..
go out and get some friends. Alright?
- I don't like going out.
You know that I get anxiety
when i get to meet people.
You know how hard that is.
You cannot just stay in the house,
with a fucking sunlamp!
Alright? I can't..
I mean look...
I can't trust you with Danny.
When you're...
the fire and everything.
I put the fire out Irving.
There's no fire...
Maybe, if you were here more. Then,
there wouldn't have been a fire  in the first place.
There wouldn't have been a fire,
if i was here?
Just stop with the whole fire thing!
God! It was a mistake.
I'm sure million people do that.
All the time.
Those sunlamps are dangerous.
I shouldn't have it in the house, really.
I bet that happens all the time.
This was nothing.
We are not happy, alright?
You know that I could take Danny.
You know that most your work is illegal.
And, you know that if you try to divorce me;
you know that, i'm not saying that I would.
But, i'm saying that I could.
But, i'm saying that.
That is why, I don't like divorce Irving.
Women do that in divorces.
Women get the children
and the father never gets to see them.
My mother never got divorce.
My granmother never got divorce.
There are no divorces in my family.
I am not..getting a divorce.
Come on, what are we doing here?
We fight and we fuck.
And, that's what we do.
That's our thing!
She's the Picasso of
Passive agressive karate.
She was better than any con artist
they ever met.
Including myself.
And, she had me like nobody had me.
Irving come the fuck up.
Come on.
You might say, she was my Karma.
For how i took advantage of people.
Oh, my God!
- Come here.
Come on, get in the bed.
No, wait.
- Baby, there's such good stuff here.
I did not wanna leave kid behind.
He's my son!
She had me.
I..was her mark.
Now, I can't assure you.
That your loan will be approved.
But, I can tell you
that any deal I take..I close.
However...my fee is not refundable.
Just like my time.
I wanna thank you very much.
Irving, for seeing me.
Sorry, i'm so nervous.
Is that..am I not buttoned?
I just gotta say Mr.Rosenfeld
that Lady Edith was uh...
very...you're top notch and..
I really need your help.
I am desperate.
I mean, I got the house leashed
..and uh..
Two boats and..I forgot to mention,
that i have a little piece of real estate,
in Long Island.
- Hmm..you didn't mention that.
Two lunch with you,
you never mentioned that.
Oh, I was gonna mention it.
Then, the guy with the hat walked in.
The hat.
- You remember that?  - I do.
That second time we had lunch.
- Yes.
We couldn't see his eyes.
Like he had no eyes.
Did they sell hats like that?
- I don't know.
Actually, i went down the store
and i thought the hat store down the street..
I thought..
I was gonna get you one as like..
It was like a momento.
- Two lunches?
Yes.
Really?
- It's two lunches. What's the big deal?
That's unusual.
Just trying to get him,
to be more agressive.
On his loan, that is.
- You showed me whole new side of the city.
I've never seen before.
You're welcome.
- No, thank you.
Yeah. Should I take Edith?
You'd like it.
- Yes.
So, I'll take you there twice.
Stop.
You like this guy?
- Yes, I like this guy.
Fine, you play your part.
Take it to your people, in London.
Please.
Take it to them.
I got the cashier's check right here.
I give you five and you give me
fifty back, right?
Please.
Please, don't reject me.
Give a guy, a chance.
Zurich, you got office in Zurich?
Paris, I can call Paris?
Do whatever you need to do.
Go ahead, take your time.
Stick around for a little bit.
See my friends over there?
You got the wrong office.
You're gonna be embarrassed.
Hey, hey..hey..hey!
Go easy on her.
I may not have you Irving.
But, i have her on fraud.
Impersonating another individual.
- On fraud..on fraud?
What is that? Identity fraud?
- You may be from England..
but you're not royal
and you have no banking connections.
That's a felony.
How long is it?
That's three to five years.
Oh, really?
That's interesting.
I don't even know your name.
Richie DiMaso, F.B.I
Nice to meet you.
You gotta keep away from this guy.
He wouldn't let me see her, for three days.
Even managed to delay a lawyer.
She couldn't handle it.
Chuck, how come the fluorescence is on?
Can we kill that please?
Jesus Christ, i put this lamp here for you.
Cos i thought it will be better for you.
This wires here...
They're scared b'cos people hang themselves.
But, i know..
you're too smart for that.
Where is the table and chair?
It's like a fucking asylum.
Joe, is everybody off today?
Jesus Christ!
It's scary.
Maybe, i wanted to scare you.
I don't know.
Maybe, i'm little off..
the beaten path. You know?
I don't know, maybe.
You look dehydrated.
You wanna have some tea?
I know you think..look at me.
Hey,
Edith. I know you think
Irving loves you.
I know you thinking that uhm...
You think that he sees the world
as this...
a cold dark place.
He cares about nobody.
But, are very few people in the short list.
What if you are not?
What if you are not on that list?
What if you're not on
that list, at all?
He'd be in here right now.
If he took the check. But, no you did.
God! It's so clear to me.
It's so crazy clear to me...
But it's not clear to you.
He uses you, Edith.
To protect himself.
To protect his son..
and his wife in long Island.
No? Yes!
He put a ring on her finger.
He adopted her son.
They have huge house,
they have two cars.
What does she do all day?
I'll tell you what she does.
She plays with her nail..
she watches T.V and she spends your money.
The money that you make.
I don't like that you're in jail.
While he is going free.
I don't like any of that.
I wanna help you.
All the 'razzle-dazzle' that he does is not good.
It's not real. It's fake.
It's not real.
Who you are is who you are.
Between, you and God.
You and your soul.
That's what matters. That's what counts.
That's what i'm about.
That's what I see in you.
Tell me, you didn't feel,
the first time we saw each other.
Am I crazy?
I don't think so.
I am not supposed to be talking about this.
I don't care. I'll break the rules.
Okay, Edith..Edith.
I wanna help you.
I like you.
Been in here three days.
This doesn't look good for her.
How does it make you feel, her in there?
That check was for you, right?
But, you knew something was off.
Because you're good.
You're like the best of the whole country,
Aren't you?
You know, if the country were run by
people like you, Irving Rosenfeld.
We're gonna be up stringing like Guatemala.
You ever been to Guatemala?
If you ever tried to get a telephone or an apartment,
or anything in..
Guatemala.
That's what this country would be like.
If we let people like you run this country.
Who made you God and Judge?
Hmm.
My Aunt Gria lived to be 93 years old.
Never lied in her life.
Congratulations!
- Thank you.
I'm proud of that too.
Except make you another good person.
Isn't that something to strive for?
Why are you breaking my balls, huh?
Get to the point.
I see something in you, Irving.
I get very excited.
I think that we have a lot of potential here.
Now, look?
I came up with the idea.
It's all for me. I wanna change things.
I wanna go after,
White collar crime.
Irving, you're a very skilled man.
And I want you to teach me;
Hell, we can do this.
I want four people to do what you do.
Fraudulent investments.
Fake certificates of deposits.
Stolen art..fake art.
You get me four people.
You're off the hook!
Four busts...
..And you will leave us alone?
We don't have to testify?
If you got it, you're done.
Anything you want.
But, if you run..then your life is over.
You're gonna be hunted.
You're gonna be very difficult..
..for Rosalyn and the kid.
To live in this country.
We need to leave.
We need to run and we need
to do it now.
Right, we'll go to Estonia or Romania;
I don't care.
We talked about it a hundred times!
- What about Danny?
What about Danny?
I adopted him.
I gave him my name.
I'm not leaving him wih Rosalyn.
She's..
...unstable!
- That is a manipulation.
Rosalyn will never let you go.
She used Danny against you.
Because she's too messed up to let you leave.
I can't leave him.
I love him, alright?
He is my son.
Richie said, you will say that.
Richie?
- Yeah.
The cop?
-Yeah.
You're on a first name basis, what?
- Yes, i am.
I am not even on your list, am i?
- What list?
Your list. Your short list...
your long list.
I'm not even on any of your fucking list.
I thought that you love me.
- I love you.
...that we have something.
- We do have something. It's perfect!
What are you saying?
We're gonna go to Romania.
Is that what you're saying?
- Yes.
Yes, that's what I am saying.
You..Me..Danny.
Yes.
Well, you never said that before.
- Well, i am saying it now.
We are us.
We can make it an adventure, like we did.
We can make it an adventure,
like we make everything, alright?
Alright.
- Okay?
We have to go now, alright?
Trust me.
We have to leave right now.
I can't leave Danny, without custody.
- No, you have to take me away.
We have to leave.
No, what are you saying?
What are you saying?!
Will you pull it together.
Don't say I don't love you.
That is bullshit.
This is bullshit.
WE..are bullshit.
You are bullshit.
Please, don't do this.
I just never thought that
you're conning me.
I can never con you.
I love you.
Please don't say this.
No, I am done.
Don't say that.
I'm gonna do these four busts,
these four cons.
To get us out of this.
Not just me, but us.
And, i'm gonna get really close..
with Richie. The Cop.
In case, we need to use him.
If we need another move.
We won't need another move.
We need four busts.
Then, we are done.
We are gonna need another move.
Trust me.
The key to people is what they believe.
And, what they want to believe.
So, I want to believe that we were real.
We are real.
- And, I want to believe,
that a man could want me.
And, i'm gonna take all of that heartbreak.
And, all of that sorrow and
I am going to use it.
And, i'm going to make Richie think
that I want him...
..and that I like him.
And, I'm gonna be..
very, very convincing!
And, I am pissed at you.
Cos, I am pissed at you!
Maybe, I do like him.
Maybe, I like him a lot.
From the feet up, right?
Baby?
Quit, bellyaching and come up
with something to get us out of this.
You're right, I am in no state
to deal with this.
So, what's it gonna be Mr.Mastermind.
An Arab Sheikh.
What do we want an Arab Sheikh, for?
What do you think this was, stupid?
If you could not call him Stupid.
Which he isn't.
He is smarter than you.
Last time i checked, he's in control;
and we work for him. Now, be nice.
To set this up.
To bust the Con artist.
We need to make the honey pot.
To attract the bees.
To attract the bees,
we need to offer them..
..wealthy individual.
That they can take advantage of.
Someone special. Someone new...
someone amazing.
And, those guys that I wanna sell
fake bank sheets leads to that guy.
Thinks the Sheikh's money. You see?
Only, they can't get into his money.
Unless, they knew somone.
And, that someone is us.
- Oh, that's good!
So, if wanna get something like,
your con artist friend..that called Elway.
He keep him wanna buying.
- Keep your voice down.
There you go. We can pinch him.
That's right.
But, I don't tell who is Sheikh.
I wait for him to call me.
The art world is a small world.
And one of Elway's acquaintance..
...is clocking us right now.
Where?
- Number one.
You have a good look?
How do you know the Sheikh?
This is my friend Dal, from Queens.
I do aluminium siding and roofing.
I wanna show you something.
People come from
all over the world to see this.
Yeah, he's good. Yeah.
It's a fake.
But..it's impossible.
People believe, what they wanna believe.
The guy who made this,
was so good.
That it's real.
To everybody.
Now, who is the Master?
The Painter..
or the Forger?
That's a fake?
This is the way,
the world works.
Not, black and white.
Like you were saying.
Extremely, grey.
Irving, could I?
- How many time I gotta tell you.
Not yet. Wait your turn.
- Arthur, Hi.
Edith.
- Edith, Hi.
Yes, I wanted to introduce you
to Robert Spencer.
We are advising the Sheikh, together.
Robert Spencer, advisor to the Sheikh. Yeah.
What's this about, a goddamn Sheikh?
Why are you leaving me out of this?
Huh? I gotta hear it from my friends?
It ain't for you, Carl.
- What do you mean, it ain't for me?
No, it ain't for you.
We gotta do certificates of deposits.
I can print as many as you need.
- I got my associates, it's the right guys.
C'mon, this is not one man operation.
- Look, I can get other guys.
What are you talking about, Irving?
- Are you telling me that...
you can get four guys.
To sell, fake certificate of deposits.
To my investor, Within a week?
- Yes, I can make that happen.
Carl no way can do what he says,
he can do.
That's interesting.
But you know, other guys lined up;
I gotta meeting.
Carl, his associate says here..
He's got a meeting, he has gotta go to.
I gotta run.
- Listen, don't go...don't go.
The crazy thing about people,
The more you say 'no'..
The more they want in on something.
It is so stupid.
- I gotta run!
C'mon, I'll tell him. Don't worry, I'll tell him.
Hey, you know what?
Carl just told me.
He said we could do this whole thing,
with four guys...
..within a week.
We could do something much bigger.
Something bigger? Yes, my guy deals
with hundreds of million of dollars.
How much bigger?
- Hundreds of million...
I knew you were holding out on me, Irving.
Like, i'm talking about
we can say never the fuck mind to see this.
And, we could have some complete access
to something huge!
Huge..like what?
Robert Spencer, I'm advisor to the Sheikh.
Carl Elway.
I want you to think, the most under valued
asset in the state of New Jersey.
The rebuilding of Atlantic city.
Look, maybe they legalized gambling
a year ago..
But nothing is happening.
Hey, quit while you're ahead, Carl.
I know the guy, the right people
that are gonna help you out.
Who's the guy?
- The guy is Carmine Polito.
Who's Carmine Polito?
Carmine Polito?
Carmine Polito, No.
My boss started proceeded to tell  me that,
Carmine Polito was..
the most quietly powerful person
in the state of New Jersey.
A lifetime native of the very
racially mixed Camden.
Which had become a ghetto.
And, where he had been Mayor
for ten years.
A very beloved guy.
A guy, who never gave up for his people.
His father had immigrated from Italy.
And, had stoked coal.
A BIG family guy with five kids.
They even adopted some other kid,
a black kid..from boys and girls club,
from a Boston family.
I mean, his house hold was a Jewish place.
And, his wife Dolly..
well she was the apple of his eye.
And, the centre of the household.
I mean everyone, love this guy.
And, he had a huge heart.
The W.P.A employed craftsmen to paint this,
during the depression.
Why can't we employ people, today?
To do work like this,
and rebuilding Atlantic City?
He worked with all the unions.
He was the leader of the state assembly.
And, he just got gambling legalized in
New Jersey, to create jobs.
But, he couldn't get the funds
to rebuilt Atlantic City.
And that, was his problem.
So, with out help..
He was about to have his hand
in the wrong pocket, at the wrong time.
And to me, that meant corrupt.
You said, grifters..con artists..
We are not going after
some politicians. This is..
This is a bad idea, Richie.
Look, it's really simple.
All you need..
..is to put two million.
In a Chase account.
- What?!
Under the Sheikh's name.
Whose, two million dollars?
Sh..just listen.
Two miliion dollars,
under the Sheikh's name..
In a Chase account.
That will be controlled.
Carmine,
calls up on the telephone,
calls the bank;
And, he sees that the Sheikh is real.
And he has a real account.
Five days.
I'm not taking 2 million dollars of the
tax payers money,
putting it anywhere for five days.
I don't care, if we control it the whole time.
Start let us do, what we need to do.
To rule out corruption.
And, to get rid of the pay-offs.
Guys that are ruining this country.
That's my dream.
Don't smirk,  please.
- You know, Richard
I understand your eagerness.
I really do.
You know, i'm from Michigan right?
Let me tell you a story.
About me and my dad, my brother.
We used to go, ice fishing every November.
Ice fishing..that's all anybody..
that's what we live for.
Just listen to me!
It's beautiful!
We had a little stove,
You huddle around.
We keep each other warm.
You drop a line..
and you just wait.
One year, my brother says..
let's go on october.
He wants to go ice fishing in October.
My Dad says, 'no, the ice is too thin'.
My brother says, I love my brother...
- I understand what that was..
Is that your brother went out on the ice,
the ice was too thin. He fell through the ice.
Went into the water,
b'cos he was too eager. Just like i'm too eager.
Is that what you're saying?
- No, i'm not saying.
What are you saying?
You know, we'll finish the ice story
another time, young man.
For now, no Carmine Polito.
Go do your job.
Staunton shot the whole thing down.
- Boring.
But, Edith was a genius.
She somehow, found this woman.
Who controlled the wire room.
A woman, I had never even heard of.
Way back, in the dorm buried
in the bureau.
This cat lady no one even talk to.
And, Edith met her in the ladies room.
Yeah, became friends with her.
Hi, how are you?
- This lady handles all the wires.
And now, she was working with us.
She was excited, to be included in the operation.
Instead of just...
..being on the other end of a memo.
It was beautiful.
This is from England?
- yeah.
Oh, I brought you some tea as well.
Oh, thank you so much!
Nobody ever talks to me.
- I know.
They just say, ' Brenda, do the clerical wiring
stuffs and don't ask questions'.
You need to tell Richie about your cats.
He loves cats.
-My Cats?!
Well, that's Perry.
Look at him, standin up.
Isn't that sweet?!
And, that's Wendy,
she's a rascal.
But, Bernaby..that's another story.
Bernaby plays the piano.
That's impressive.
We got her to wire, 2 million dollars
to an FBI controlled account at Chase.
It'd be there for five days.
And, if Polito called?
He would see that the Sheikh was real.
And, by the time he Stauton
caught up to us.
Edith made sure, his boss
was impressed by my idea.
So, before he even knew it was happening.
His boss was calling to congratulate him.
Anthony Amado.
He had a major hard on,
for to make a name for himself.
I mean, this guys love the idea
of being famous.
And, Stauton had to say
it was all his own idea.
or he'd look stupid,
in front of his boss.
You made me accept, praise from my boss,
thanking me, for something
that never should have happened.
Something that I didn't approve.
- You should be happy.
There's an imaginative things
happening in this office.
Alright, we're not just working in a box.
We got the two million to
put Carmine and the Sheikh together.
I like being on the side of the line.
But, someone had been left out.
We succeed because,
we stayed small.
You took on Elwey,
you both still went on.
So, if we max this.
That's enough.
It's three one, no politicians.
You're gonna do this, because..
.. you got no choice.
You work for me.
Now, you keep changing the rules.
Now, you're getting a...little
power drunk.
Richard, now you wanna tell me.
You wanna wake him up?
Oh, no. I said, we shouldn't do any of it.
Irving, you know I said that.
So, now I support Richie.
He's got vision.
Do it heavy, or don't do it.
I mean, he's the one ruining America,
not me.
How the fuck am I ruining America?
Because, people just got over
Wategate and Vietnam, alright?
You're gonna shit all over
politicians again?
Is it because you wanna be a big shot,
and get a promotion?
No, I'm thinking big.
Alright, this is gonna be fantastic.
We're doing video surveillance.
I'm doing this,
from the feet up!
You will never do it properly.
Because, you got too much
government attitude,
to be small and sleek.
I'm like the fucking the A con-man, alright?
I'm in and i'm out.
I was there the whole time.
You don't know it, alright?
That's, the fucking art.
To become somebody,
who people can't pin and the police..
dreams on.
You can't do it.
How about the suite at the Sheraton Hotel?
For Carmine Polito and rebuilding, Atlantic City?
Why not?
- We need a luxury for the Sheikh.
Oh, Come on! Carmine is used to dealing
back door all the time.
We don't have a budget for that, Irving.
We are gonna knock..
The Mayor..
the speaker of the state assembly.
You gotta knock him off
his fucking feet. Alright?
He's gotta feel like he is out of his league.
What you're offering this deal,
I mean, this is unheard of.
In the state of New Jersey.
Maybe, in the whole fucking country alright?
Hey Sheikh, you're loaning us million
of dollars to rebuild Atlantic City.
Are you fucking kidding me?
That's gigantic, alright.
The mayor, he's gonna want to see the cash.
He's gonna want to see an account.
He's gonna want to see it right now...
And, he will check.
That's why, this meeting isn't happening.
Because, to get millions...
..you need millions.
We already did it.
What?
We got the Bureau to park
two million dollars for three days.
We got the account numbers.
WE, meaning you and him?
Yeah, me and that guy.
She showed me.
- Show him, our thing?
You did that without me?
Are you kidding?
What are you gonna do?
You're playing me?
Or you're doing this,
you're playing him.
____
You're gonna have to decide
for yourself, kid.
I just laid everything
on the table.
This is all very exciting.
I didn't know I could be like this.
To be wild.
You know we're taking down
bad guys.
A very important politician.
This is agent, Richie Dimaso.
I'm placing 75 thousand dollars
in this briefcase,
for Mayor Carmine Polito.
To procure..
Casino lisence and building permits
for Atlantic City.
I don't know what that is.
This is very weird.
I don't know what the fuck that is.
Mr.Mayor?!
Please, stop listen.
I apoligize, if that punk offended you.
I really apologize.
- I'm alright. Thank you.
No, i'm fucking embarassed
to be associated with that guy at all.
Can i just say, something to you please.
Don't loose this opportunity,
to fucking Florida. Alright?
Just because of some...
Bullshit,
from that punk advisor.
With his diploma, alright.
Who could never get into
the school that we come from.
Don't loose that opportunity.
Where are you from?
- From the Bronx.
Way on dock house
164th street.
I got lot of friends
who lives up there.
Yeah, got Tomasso running..
Tomassos on Arthur avenue?
- Yeah, the clams there...
Clams..oh, those are fucking to die
for, those things.
I haven't been there in a while.
I like that place.
Well, you know what..
Can I call you Carmine?
You know, Carmine...
Hey, my fucking heart is done..
Running down...
i'm not used to running.
It's a lot of green grass..
in that hotel room. Up there.
Alright?
And, all the deals
will flow through you.
You'll get a serious piece
on both ends, alright?
You do with that
what you will, man.
I live in the real world. Alright?
I'm a family man,
I got mouths to feed and
everything like that.
But, you know...this..
You gotta grease it directly.
No middle man, no bullshit.
It's the Arab's way.
That's it..that's it.
Alrigh, look I understand.
It's a great opportunity,
you understand...
I was a little thrown by
going into meeting with somebody,
I didn't even know would be in there.
I was thrown as well.
- Understand, I'll deal with you directly.
Not any middle man or
any other bullshit.
Done!
- I'll deal with you directly.
I like you.
Eye to eye.
We can do business together.
- That's fine.
How long have you known this guy?
You've work with this guy, before?
- I gotta work with him. It's the Sheikh.
Alright
- But, I still need to meet the Sheikh.
Okay?
- Done. After you.
I'm going out for dinnner,
with Carmine and the wives in Camden.
Who?
Carmine and myself with the wives.
What? Without me?!
- He doesn't like you.
What do you want from me?
I got him to come back,
take the money.
You got him on tape.
I can't make him like you.
I did my job.
Did you tell him you're working with me.
And, that i'm the Sheikh's associate.
I just fucking told you!
He doesn't like you.
I mean, let him have a nigh out with a human being.
For fucks sake.
Alright? He is going to jail soon.
You're done with him.
You got him on tape, taking a bribe.
Carmine has got to deal with me, Irving.
We're gonna use Carmine.
Yeah, no..no, no.
Carmine will get us other people.
What? Like who?
Carmine is gonna use the Sheikh's
to pay off people.
Are you fucking nuts?
Are you...
We're gonna let Carmine,
show the Sheikh Atlantic City.
How he's gonna renovate hotels
and see who shows up!
Whoever the Sheikh pays off.
For lisences and casinos...
That's who, we're gonna go after.
We are gonna go after all of them!
No more politicians?
- Yeah.
You realize how fucking dangerous that is?
There's no fucking
reasoning with you.
Alright, Edith and I
were so sucessful for so long..
Because, we kept it just
small enough.
You're taking us to a very
fucking dangerous place,
with very serious numbers!
If you're that sucessful,
how come you wound up with me. Right now?
Taking orders from me.
You're taking your wife out to dinner?
Your fucking wife, did i hear you correctly?
That's the one thing you heard me say?
I just find it rather shocking, that's all.
I get to handle two wives,
with one dinner. Alright?
I take Rosalyn out,
she keeps her mouth shut..
She sees that my work is legitimate.
I get to keep my kid and
I get to keep...
..that fucking wife happy.
Both wives happy.
Richard, what are you doing?
Richard don't eat in the bathroom.
I told you so many times!
And I have brought Napoleans.
Come out of the bathroom and pray.
Oh, my god! What did you do?
- Richard,
The filter is broken in the fishtank.
It's the problem.
- See, my job is to do the ground.
When you don't do the filter right,
You get all the fish die.
See?
- I can't that top of the thing...
And, please help Richard,
to marry Diane so that
i may have granchildren,
And, the Pope may have more followers.
And, please bless this food.
That we are about to eat.
Richard?
- Yea, hello?
Hi.
- Who's this?
It's Edith.
Sit down and pray properly.
- Are you alright?
Yeah, yeah I'm fine.
It's just..
..i'm alone, you know?
Irving is out with..
.. Carmine.
Oh, yes that's right.
He went out with Carmine
and his wife...
Yeah, you must not feel
so good about that.
Richar sit down.
Wait, who is there?
Who are you with?
Oh, no. It's just people.
- People...? I'm your fiance, Richard?
Oh, you got a fiance.
You are engaged.
I don't know. I don't
have a fiance.
You don't know?
You don't know,
if you have a fiance.
I don't, no.
Hmm, interesting.
You wanna get together?
Richard, Do something about the fishtank!
54th street?
Okay, 54th street.
Okay, great.
That's what the phone call is about.
Everybody thought, "Oh, Richie DiMaso is
gonna stay in the office,
pushing papers."
That's not gonna happen, Mom.
I'm outside on the field.
I got peoples working for me.
My ideas, I'm running the show.
I'm the quaterback and i'm not gonna settle
for no one, Mom.
Rocco, how are you?
Rocco, we like the..
chicken very thin, alright.
Look, the way you dresses the chicken..
With the red sauce.
They're so good.
Here it is! This is it.
This right here, this right here.
Look at this.
This is so..good. So good.
This is so nice.
Thank you, Rocco.
- Thank you, Rocco.
I believe that, you should treat people;
The way that, you want to be treated.
Did Jesus say that, or something?
- He may have.
I think also,
Always take a favour, over money.
I think, Jesus said that as well.
I don't know if he said the second one.
He might have said the first one.
I chipped this moving furniture.
It's my new obsession.
Moving, redecorating..
makes me feel better.
like, exercise. But, there is this...
There is this top coat.
That you can only get from Switzerland.
And, I don't know what i'm gonna do.
B'cos, i'm running out of it.
But, i love the smell of it.
- Oh, I can get it for you.
That would be amazing.
- Of course!
There is something...the top coat.
It's like, perfumy.
But, there is also something rotten?
And, i know that sounds crazy.
But, I can't get enough of it.
Smell it, it's true.
Dolly, historically..
the best perfumes in the world.
They're all laced with something nasty.
It is true!
Irving loves them.
He can't get enough of that smell.
I can't get enough.
Carmine.
- Carmine, smell the nails.
Sweet and sour.
- Smell the nails.
Rotten and delicious.
It smells like flowers.
Flowers, but with garbage.
You know what that is for me.
It's coriander for me.
That's what hooks him.
He always comes back for it.
He's gonna say..
He is gonna say,
'We have to talk business'.
In Five...
four, three, two...
One.
Dolly, Can me and Carmine talk
about business here?
I'm not this drunk.
Didn't your fiance
want to come out tonight?
Yeah, uh..
I don't know. Yeah..
No.
I don't know.
Oh, God..i'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
We don't have to talk about it.
I was just teasing you..
- That's alright.
Ever think like, ' How did I end up here?'
Like, how my life become
screwed? Ever think of that?
And, you wonder like...
Can I ever gonna get up to a better place.
Or, this is it.
You feel like that?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
I definitely, know that.
I'm sorry, we don't have to go dancing.
We can go have coffee..
or talk..or just..
- No, no..no.
No, no. I need this.
Please, I need to go
dancing with you.
Please.
Okay baby,
Let's go dancing.
Hurry up and get out of this.
I really fucking like you.
Yeah..yeah.
I like you too.
I wanna live.
Like, for real.
No more fake shit.
Right?
We're gonna wait until we
decide, we fall for real.
That's when we fuck.
Not till then.
Okay?
Okay.
No more fake shit.
- No more fake shit.
No..more..fake, shit!
Get out.
Boys..
This guy right here, Julius?
This guy,
Irving Rosenfeld.
You know what he's gonna do?
He is gonna bring the Sheikh to Atlantic City.
That's what he's gonna do.
Where we can build all those resorts,
there. Put everybody back to work.
He's gonna get this community;
He's gonna get this state.
Back on it's feet.
To where it belongs.
Isn't that right?
He's gonna grow our tax base,
And, create thousands and
thousands of jobs, for everyone!
Do you understand that?
You know what that means?
To Irving!
Come on, this guy right here.
He's got a big heart.
Let's just say, that
it didn't work out?
What do you mean?
Of course, it's gonna work out.
Guys like you and me...
right? We dream and we build.
We never give up.
We never quit.
Hey, can i ask you a question?
Yeah, sure.
Is the Sheikh black?
The Sheikh, he is uh...
He is an Arab.
That's black isn't it.
I know it's just
a dumb question but...
I was wondering..
Why are you asking?
I would like to,
arrange..
the Sheikh..
to see Camden.
To see the people of Camden.
Irv, i really want him to see.
How good this is going to be
for the community.
How ready we are for
this opportunity.
And, he could see how far
his dollar would go.
You know what i mean.
What do you think?
Yeah, we can do that, yeah.
Ah, good.
Oh, hey..I got something..
I wanna give you.
Come on,
I got you a gift.
Let's get out of here.
The wive's gonna kill us.
Here you go.
What is it?
It's a Microwave.
It heats up everything.
Pasta, Lasagna..meatballs.
Whatever.
- Really?
It's science. Yeah,
it's that how it heats up the food.
It's scientific.
- And, you specifically, bought this
science oven..for me?
Yeah.
A new friend.
Thank you.
Don't put metal it.
Come on, let's get out of here.
I need a Jet at Tithe bora.
I need a Jet at Tithe bora, for the Sheikh.
- You don't..you don't need a Jet.
Let him walk to the curb at JFK.
That's not how it works.
You gotta start from the feet up.
That doesn't mean anything.
What does that mean?
It means you gotta be committed.
Means, you gotta be committed
to something in your life.
For Christ sake, alright?
I want a Jet at Tithe bora,
for the Sheikh.
It can be a small jet,
Doesn't even have to take off.
Cos, i know you're so worried about
the money the bureau's gonna fucking spend.
It can take off and land
on the tarmac, okay?!
Alright, you can have the jet
for an hour.
But, takes off and lands at Tithe Bora.
- I got the jet?
You got the jet..
- Alright, thank you.
Wait, tell me the rest of
the ice fishing story.
Where was I?
Your father walks in the blizzard
at the lake..come on. C'mon!
Okay, when my brother and I
were on the ice..
..and my father came out of the house;
and I could see him coming.
Holding the lantern and there's blizzard,
and i knew he was gonna be angry.
So, i went to intercept my father.
B'cos I knew if he saw
what my brother was doing,
He was gonna kill him.
- Oh, you tried to protect your brother,
But, you couldn't.
And that's why you feel bad, b'cos..
you're trying to protect me
and you're worried about me.
Is that what the story is about?
It's about protection.
No, it's not about protection.
- No?  - No.
Alright, fine.
'Don't put metal in that science oven,
Roselyn...'
Another fire!
- NO, Danny! Not that one.
That one's empty.
We gotta get the big one.
I told you not to put metal
in the science oven.
What did you do that for?
- Don't make such a big deal.
Just get another one.
I don't want another one.
I want the one Carmine gave me.
Oh, Carmine..I want the one Carmine
gave me.
Carmine, carmine.
Why don't you just marry Carmine.
Get a little gold microwave
and put it on chain around your neck.
You wanna be more like Carmine?
Why don't you build something,
like he does.
Instead of your empty deals.
They're just like your fucking science oven.
You know, I read that
it takes all of nutritions out of our food.
It's empty, just like your deals.
Empty, empty!
That's bullshit.
- It's not bullshit.
I read it in an article.
Look..
By Pulver Deur.
Bringing something into this house,
That's gonna take all nutritions out
of our food and light our house on fire?
Thank God, for me.
Alright, you got this.
I don't think,
you should come to Carmine's party, tonight.
You look beautiful.
By the way.
Don't look at me.
Alright?
Don't look at my legs,
don't look at my head.
Don't smell my hair.
Don't ask me how I am.
Don't talk to me outside
of this rules cos, i'm done.
Just stand still.
Get in the umbrella. Come on.
Just..Carmine wants
Rosalyn..
.. to come.
- I don't care!
You aren't listening.
I don't care if Rosalyn comes.
Just do your job, okay?
You're nothing to me,
Until you're everything.
I'm not Rosalyn,
I'm not gonna put up with that shit.
That's a fucking jet, right?
It's good.
- It's the kinda moves you need to make.
Paco Hernandez?
I'm Richie DiMasso.
It's nice to meet you in person.
This is Irving Rosenfeld.
- Paco Hernandez, nice to meet you.
Paco..wait no, no.
He's not an Arab.
No, Mexican, from Tucson.
Where is my guy?
Where's Al?
My friend from Queens.
Where is he?
What are you doing?
- I gotta hire an FBI guy.
You speak any Arabic?
- Yeah, As-salamu alaykum.
That's it?
- No, i have a couple of phrases.
From feet up, you motherfucker.
What are you doing? C'mon.
Act normal, that's it.
Just seem all like...
You can't barely understand english.
You can't speak it.
You say as little as possible,
you follow my lead.
Alright?
Who's running this?
I thought you're running this.
I am running this.
We gotta listen to him.
He's the guy with the vision.
I got the vision?
You know the vision I had?
You just kissed my girl.
Right outside.
That's what vision I have.
- I thought you guys broke up.
I'm giving you a compliment.
What's going on?
Don't worry about it, alright?
I got a knife.
This is for the mayor.
You gotta present it, to the mayor.
Just look at me.
Alright, look me in the eye.
This means a lot to you.
Right? That knife, play it.
You present it, alright?
Friendship for life..alright.
You gotta feel it.
Sacred. Can you do it?
- Sacred.
Sell it.
- If you believe it, sacred.
They are sacred, alright?
- listen, the details. That's what makes..
...This guy a genius.
- Again? You're complimenting me again.
Rubbing salt in the wound?
What are you?
- I'm complimenting you.
You got any other questions?
Yeah, i think the name
of the operation is offensive.
ABSCAM.
Arab Scam? It's racist.
Are you fucking kidding me?
What do you care?
You're a Mexican.
Hello, Sheikh.
- ___
Welcome!
On behalf of the
great state of New Jersey.
I wanna welcome you to New Jersey.
Thank you, thank you.
We have a great party planned
for this evening.
What are you talking about,
I can't go?
I just did my hair
and make up and everything!
The Sheikh's a very particular.
It's an international
cultural protocol. You know.
International Protocol.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Do not answer that,
Do not answer!
Hello?
- Robert Spencer for Irving.
Robert Spencer,
I don't know a Robert Spencer.
What do you want?
- I'm a business associate..
Who is that?
For god's sake,
I told you not to call here.
Alright?
- Two more Federal agents tonight.
No, what?
Two Feds.
- No.
I need them,
bodyguards for the Sheikh.
No, no. Too many guys,
too many to control. No.
Irving? Remember who's
in charge here.
Rosalyn, get off the extention.
I'm not on it.
Look, don't call here again, alright.
Don't call at home.
Alright. Okay, bye.
- Alright.
It's a business call.
Don't interrupt. Alright?
Federal Agents?
- It's bodyguards for visiting dignitaries.
That's all.
What is it? An IRS thing.
Like a tax investigation?
Why you gotta say that?
That's why I can't invite you.
It's too complicated.
- Are you in trouble?
Stop being nosy. Look at these shit.
- Well, i'm nosy.
Cos, you never tell me anything.
Do not answer that!
- Hello?
It's Carmine.
Oh, hi..Carmine.
We're just talking about you.
Yeah, Irving is being a mean, boring man.
Saying that he doesn't want me tonight.
- Tell him he is crazy!
Well, I agree.
Tell him yourself.
Can you imagine.
- Cos, you're coming.
Yeah, Tell him yourself.
Irving, you're crazy.
Your wife is coming,
You're kidding me.
She's the life of the party.
We enlist her.
You know what she's like,
she is unpredictable.
Hey, don't talk about me, like that!
What is Carmine saying?
Carmine loves me.
This is really big night for us.
You understand?
C'mon, you gotta bring your wife.
Dolly has got something special for her, right?
Listen, listen.
I got the nail polish for you, sweetie.
What is it?
Tell me.
You got a girlfriend coming?
C'mon, i thought we are friends.
Look, we're handling this like men.
You understand? Bring your wife.
We'll have a good time.
We'll see you there.
It'll be fun.
That's an order from your mayor.
Goodbye.
Alright, you happy?
Go get ready.
Yes, I am happy.
I know who you are.
I know who that is, Irving.
Oh, it looks beautiful.
- So, this is the lobby.
Reminds you a week ago,
this place was a mess.
But, what existed was this,
plaster work.
Look at the detail.
It's beautiful.
My son is a craftman.
Please, tell him what you did.
I did birds, sky..clouds.
____
This saved us 50 million.
Look at me.
50 million,
right of the bat.
Like that.
I waived a loan.
Got the help, right?
Instead of constructions having to
build ground up, new.
We don't do 'new'.
We renovate, right.
We used some temporary funds.
The gaming tables, some roulette..
for people to have a good time.
It's for charity.
Support some legal programs and
some art programs.
This is the Oyster room.
There's some gentlemen,
sitting over there at the bar.
That's a 130 years sitting right there.
That's how many times between them.
They run the biggest casinos
in the united states.
We have to work with them.
- Right.
The good new is..
..they know how it's done.
They get it done.
You don't have to worry.
Everyone makes their money.
You mean the mob?
- Yes, but they're business men.
Spend at much or little time
with them as you like.
But, we do have to deal with them.
All we gotta do is go and say, 'Hello'.
Just gotta say, Hi.
We gotta confirm before
we talk to those guys.
Confirm?
What is there to confirm about.
I don't understand,
they're casino guys!
Irving, we came all this way.
We should be here.
What is everybody scared of.
Those are the guys,
that you guys are all scared of?
Those guys over there?
They don't scare me.
Rosalyn..Rosalyn?
Irving, that's not the way to do this.
I love this!
Kids, I want you to go up and
get some soda and pizzas please.
I think they got this room, all wrong.
Yeah? What would you do?
I would do in all black and gold.
I would do this bar like a big
warm, golden mirror.
Sounds beautiful.
- Oh, thank you.
And, i love that ass.
____
I'm sorry, Is she a wife?
- No, she is my wife.
Look at these fine gentlemen.
How are you?
- Good to see you.
Oh, i know because he's a party pooper.
He's so boring.
May I present, Sheikh Abdullah.
Gentlemen, from Abu Dhabi.
Sheikh, these are professionals.
They run the best casinos in United States.
Mr.Sheikh,
As a sign of our seriousness, Mr.Tallegio
came from Miami to meet you tonight.
Mr.Tallegio?
Why didn't you tell me, Mr.Tallegio is here.
- He's in the back room.
It's a sign of disrespect to talk,
business. On the first meeting.
- That's not true.
Yeah, I don't know what you're talking about.
He's got it all wrong.
You wanna leave him back there,
in the back room waiting?
We gotta meet him.
My friend from New York
doesn't know the custom...
Hey, Irving i'm gonna be having fun.
Maybe, it will be contagious, huh?
Can you believe
that he talk to me that way?
Carmine?
Victor Tellegio was from Miami.
He was Meyer Lansky's right hand man.
With his prior reputation,
as an enforcer from..
..20 years ago was known,
to never bury a body;
B'cos, he felt it sent a stronger message.
To leave it on the street.
This is the guy,
we now have to deal with.
Are you sure, you don't wanna
go out there. It's new bar.
It's beautiful out there..
- I don't have to go out there.
I like it here.
There is an exit.
I'm like a ghost.
Nobody knows i am here.
Tell him, I speak
for our friends in Florida.
We're very excited.
It's been our life long dream
to build Casinos resorts
in the east coast.
You told him that.
They don't want the Jews to make money.
They don't want the Italians to make money.
They definitely don't want
the blacks to make money.
After, the oil embargo..
gasoline crisis.
The hijacking, the olympics.
They don't wanna see Arabs,
make money.
Plus, not on our soils.
I don't know, if you can tell him
in your own way.
I've been in the casino business,
for forty years.
It's scrutinised more careful
then any other business.
Carmine made this legal, but..
we must be careful or they
will take it away.
So, Mr.Tallegio..how do you think
we should approach this?
What do you wanna do?
If you wanna get the gaming
license and keep it.
We have to make our principle
investor here, The Sheikh.
An American citizen.
Lots to expedite, citizenship.
One that requires special treatment.
Well, you would know
the right people to do that.
U.S Senators.
U.S congressmen Senators.
Wow! That's fantastic!
I say, stay away from that.
That's bad. That's trouble.
Irving please?
Who is this guy?
Who are you..huh?
What are you, a farmer?
Mr.Tallegio, i'm sorry..
this is  Irving.
He is Irving Rosenfeld.
New York business man.
- What's the matter, Irving?
What's the problem?
- Nothing, no problem.
Don't get your balls in an uproar.
Everything is fine.
Everything is good.
It's all good. It's all good.
It's all good.
I just hope....
the other part of this
is all good.
And real.
Because, we are real.
You know that.
You deal with us,
we are real organisation.
We're dealing with..
we don't know what we're dealing with.
Where is he from?
Abu Dhabi.
Oh, he's from the Emirates?
- Yeah.
I think..I think, what is...
Let him speak for himself.
What are the fucking odds,
you got an italian guy from Miami,
knowing Arabic.
It turns out, he's got casino
investments, in the middle east.
And, he spent two years
learning it to keep the upper hand.
Listen to me carefully.
If you really put 10 million in
the bank of our choice.
In the next two weeks.
- Carmine, listen me carefully.
You put 10 million in the bank or our choice.
In the next two weeks, or..
Not only will the Sheikh feel something.
But, our friends in Florida
will feel deeply disrespected.
So, will I.
Rosalyn, you need to come
with me, alright.
Oh, you want me to come with you?
- Please, just stop alright.
Oh, you think I should
come with you?
Get your fucking hands off me.
This is my hausband's whore!
You alright?
Whatever is meant to be, will be.
Alright?
- I always say that.
You say that?
- Yeah.
Kindred spirits.
- Whatever is meant to be, will be.
Whatever is meant to be, will be.
What the hell do you think
you are doing?
What do i think, what i'm doing?
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
You're gonna come and just me
for flirting..
..while you've been fucking
my hausband for how many years?!
You don't have a fucking clue
what's going on.
I got a ring on my finger.
We have a child together!
He doesn't love you, Rosalyn.
He loves me and you know it..
And, I know it.
He knows it.
It maybe done now.
It was beautiful and it was real.
And, we loved each other.
- Stop it.
Shut up!
- You scared him, you manipulate him...
And, you use your son!
Well, he must like it on some level.
He must want it.
Because, he keeps coming back for it.
It's like that perfume that you love,
You can't stop smelling.
Even when there's something sour in it.
Can't get enough of it.
But, guess what?
He's never gonna leave me.
He is always going to want me.
And, I will make you so sorry Edith.
I will make you so sorry
for what you've done to my family.
Mark my words!
That's fucked up!
I would never say
anything that's fucked up..
to anybody. But, you did.
B'cos you're gross inside.
Oh, I'm gross inside?
Maybe, your gross inside...
both robbing people
and all that shit that you do.
Maybe, we are both gross inside.
That's what Irving loves about us.
At least, he is consistant.
You know sometimes in life,
all you have,
are fucked up,
poisonous choices.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Our friend..
working men friend..
My friend.
Mayor Carmine Polito!
Hello, Camden.
Hello, New Jersey.
Hello, Atlantic City!
A lot of my friends,
has been out of work.
A lot of good working families.
Just wanna work and live.
They say, there's no money,
no where.
You gotta be kidding me!
Don't they know,
we build this country!
One thing we can all afree upon,
in the state of New Jersey,
is that, we never;
never ever give up. Do we?!
- NO!!!
Please, raise your glass with me.
To a new era.
It begins tonight.
From me, and my family..
We thank you.
For all the hard work that
you have given us.
In the community..
Look what you've done.
It's beautiful!
Thank You!
Edith?
Can I use your phone?
Last night was insane.
I got it all figured out.
Stauton Thorson?
Listen, I need the Sherman suite
at the Plaza Hotel, Okay?
That's the whole floor of the hotel.
No, no, no.
I need the whole floor.
I need it for my operation.
Stop calling it your operation, Richard.
It's not you operation and
I'm not giving you a whole floor of..
the Plaza Hotel.
I have members of the congress
coming in right now
trying to get the Sheikh
Citizenship, alright?
They are taking bribes.
It's happening right now.
That's happening right now!
Bribing members of congress..
Are you out of your fucking mind?
Stauton, Stauton!
Shut up!
You know who Victor Tellegio..
Victor Tellegio,
works for Meyer Lansky.
You know who that is?
Resorts international.
Alright? He wants 10 million dollars.
I have two weeks. I have...
Just listen to me. Listen to me..
You're not listening to me!
I have two weeks!
I have two weeks to put this
thing together.
And, I need you to get me the Sheman
Suite at the Plaza Hotel!
Lower your voice.
- How the fuck am I doing.
Help me out Edith.
Calm me down.
You gotta calm me down.
Baby, let's do this right now.
No, no..no.
- I wanna do this right now.
Look at your skin.
Oh, my god!
Your fucking skin is glowing, baby.
Your fucking skin is glowing.
We are not gonna back on...
- I wanna do it now!
That's what we agreed on, alright.
So, we're not gonna do that, alright?
Where are you?
You're acting all scared.
You okay? You're here with me?
I love you.
It is real now. I just..
I just said it.
So, now is the time.
Look at me, look at me.
I love you.
I just said that.
I'm ready for real.
This is real, Do you hear my voice?
This is real.
I want you to hear what's real.
What?
This is me.
- What do you mean?
Well, you're doing an accent?
Your american accent?
- No, there's no english.
There's only American.
There's no English.
What are you talking about?
Stop it, you're Edith.
Your birth records say..
I falsified my records back to birth.
I falsified them.
My name is Sydney Prosser.
I am from Albuqurque, New Mexico.
I'm not Edith Greensly.
There is no Edith Greensly.
You're..freaking..me out.
No, you said it in the stall.
That we are gonna be real.
And, that we aren't gonna fake it.
I'm being real now.
This is who I am.
I am Sydney Prosser.
Okay?
So, why did you do an
english accent?
After that.
I'm sorry, I didn't tell you
in the stall.
I created Edith, b'cos
I need it her to survive. Okay?
But, i'm done with her now.
I'm so fucking done with it.
Right..you do what you need to survive, right?
You uh...
You know, you live with your mom.
You have a fiance, you don't even acknowledge.
That's what you do.
You curl your hair with your..
..fucking curlers. Which is..
No, it's okay.
You will go with it.
You know..
You have straight hair.
That's what you do to survive.
You do all sorts of things.
You know, we all do.
I'm confused.
- I'm fucking confused too. Alright?
I think we should fuck.
And then, we'll feel it.
And then, we won't be confused anymore.
No, I wanna talk it over.
I don't wanna fuck, Okay? No.
I think we will be better.
No. I'm not fucking you.
I'm not FUCKING fucking you.
Shit!
Oh, my God!
Will you please step away from Edith.
Please? I am asking you nicely.
Please, step away from Edith right now.
Come on, step away from her.
Please?
You mean, Sydney?
I told him, I'm sorry.
I just don't give a fuck anymore.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't fucking care.
Irving with a gun, right?
Where Richie has got us into
is worst than jail.
I told you last night.
Those scores weren't good.
And, what. Now, what?
No one is getting...
Ten million for Tallegio.
It's over.
I don't think so.
- What?
What do you mean?
Because, when Tallegio finds out
what happens. You think he's gonna go after me?
Someone from the bureau.
He isn't gonna go after the politicians.
He's gonna kill you.
And, he is gonna go after your son.
And, Sydney.
Stauton Thorson?
Yeah, you're gonna give me.
The Sherman suite.
The whole floor.
- That's a no. I said 'no' whacko. Jesus!
And, you're gonna tell me
the point of that fucking fishing story.
Not the way your behaving.
What's the matter with you?
Where are you right now?
What does that make a difference?
Just tell me, where the fuck you are.
Field Office, at 61st street.
I'm coming at 61st street,
right now.
- You're gonna do, what?
To beat...your ass.
You'll do what?
You were right.
We should've gone away.
I wish now, i'd leave with you.
We are suppose to do from
the feet up.
Like you always said.
That's how we were meant to do.
Only you didn't do it like that.
You didn't do it like that.
You played it safe. So, there's always
a danger you're gonna end up
with Rosalyn. And, the dead space.
Floating on some dead spaceship.
With the furnitures and the curtains...
And, I was your lifeline out.
And you were mine.
And, that was okay. You know?
I wish, I could get you back.
But, I can't do it without you.
You know that.
Come on.
Me, You and Danny.
Like we said.
Like, I said.
You never said that, I said that.
We gotta get over,
on all these guys!
That's what, we need to be thinking
about, right now.
Fuck's sake.
That's big.
That's fucking crazy.
Whatever it is.
It gotta be the best,
we've ever done.
Agent DiMaso called me,
late on the night of 21st.
I believe that he was intoxicated.
He threatened me.
I told him, that this was inappropriate.
Procedures exist for purposes that
we must respect.
This is the third such call,
that I received from Agent DiMaso.
He called me again, on the night of the 5th.
At two a.m.
And, he threatened to kill me.
Subsequently, he demanded that I allow
him to use the Sherman Suite..
The Plaza hotel, for purposes..
of bribing member of the Congress.
I am so sorry!
I'm not finished.
There's a lot more.
I have nothing, but the utmost respect
for you..as my mentor --
..as my mentor, as..
-What are you doing?
I just wanna talk from my heart.
I don't wanna do it on record...
This is just..I get vulnerable.
- Can I finish my..?
Can I finish my sta..
- Of course, of course.
That's why we're here.
I respect you.
I think you do, other things besides
respect me.
Hey, hey..hey!
He, what are you doing?
What are you doing?
It's just hard for me to control
my passion. I'm a very passionate person.
We're from the __.
You understand this.
He goes ice fishing in teh Mid-west.
That was told to you
in confidence.
He's an 'Ice fishing guy',
Look at him.
What are you doing?
It's not you.
That's not you with a gun. Stop it.
You know, it's me.
It's me!
Don't do something
that you don't know anything about.
Alright?
- Wait, wait..wait. Do not load that gun.
You drop that gun...
...and then, i'm gonna hit you.
- Don't..don't!
Watch this, fucko!
So...
You wanna use the Sherman suite,
the entire floor?
- Yes.
God!
- Of the Plaza Hotel.
What happend to the mafia? I thought you..
- No, no..no. This is where they intersect!
This is where, the two things intersect.
The two world.
The politicians and the Mafia.
Victor Tellegio's people,
who runs resort international..
- Right, right.
Victor Tellegio, showed his face?
Yeah, I sat with him.
I sat with Victor Tellegio.
I hung out with him.
We can get him. We can get
his whole organisation.
As well, as getting..
any numbers of congressemen..
I mean, that's just the...
that's just peeling the first layer
of the onion.
Wow.
How're you..how are you gonna do that?
We would get ten million dollars..
- Ten million dollars?
Ten million dollars?!
- That's how we just...
So, what does he say,
he's gonna do this for us?
How are you trapping him?
- They're gonna promise to buil casinos...
Handle the skims...
Do the licensing.
- You have what?
You have him on tape saying this?
You have that, right?
No.
I want you to find a safer way,
to get Victor Tellegio on wiere.
No ten million dollars, that crazy.
- Thank you.
Right? Even to entrap Tallegio.
It's crazy. But...
You can have the Shermen suite.
- No, no.
..to go and get me some congressmen.
Go and get some congressmen,
taking bribes.
I wanna pinch us some congressmen.
Okay..you come back to me.
I'm proud of you.
Thank you..
..and Stauton.
Good luck keeping your job,
by the way. And, staying out of jail.
And, not being killed by the mob!
But, othewise, you're doing a great job.
What's the end of the ice fishing story?
- I'm not telling you.
I'm gonna call your fucking brother,
to find out the end.
- My brother is dead!
That's how it ends!
He fell to through the fucking ice!
NO, that's not how he dies.
He die in a different way,
many years later!
Listen, I know it's awkward and I..
I just wanna say, i'm sorry alright?
But I think, we can still
stick together and uh...
still fullfil on our work in here.
We got the Sherman suite.
You got the whole floor?
- The whole floor, yeah.
That's good,
- Yeah, you okay?
Yeah. You?
It's alright,
just got hit a little bit.
My eye, it's a little blurry.
You okay?
- Yeah, i'm good.
Listen, I'm sorry.
- I'm sory.
I'm sorry'er.
We can put camera in here.
Right in here, maybe.
And, we get it all on film.
You like it?
- We do.
You know, give me those flowers.
We put the flower vase.
You can put the camera in there.
And then, we get a clear shot of the couch.
So, we could put the congressman.
That's right.
That's the idea.
And Carmine will go to jail after
he delivers us,
Congressmen, soon to be felons.
Representative of O'connell's on the phone!
I gotta take this, you guys.
Everyone out, please.
This is sad.
It's just sad!
Dolly, i gotta take this.
- Sorry, everyone out.
Congressman, how're you doing?
It's Carmine.
Tell me, you're gonna be in Trenton.
This week.
We have an amazing investment
opportunity, I'd like to discuss with you.
I'm federal agent Richie DiMaso.
I placed 75 thousand dollars
in this briefcase.
For representative, John O'Connel
with the 9th district.
Representative O'Connel was contacted
by Carmine Polito.
To ask, if he could obtain
a rapid citizenship,
through an act of congress..
For one, Sheikh Abdullah--
the investor.
I'm excited to be here.
Oh, John please.
This brings the state back.
How long we've known each other?
You know, what's this gonna do for us?
This is HUGE for the state
of New Jersey.
Stabilize our economy,
- Hotels, restaurants.
Carmine sees this.
It's waiting to happen.
This fucking this is waiting to happen!
But the goddamn bankers!
They're keeping money on the sidelines.
How're we suppose to get anything done?
Bankers only put money in the game...
Where they can reap
insane profits!
The problem is this, Sir?
The citizenship..situation.
We gotta expidite this,
as soon as possible.
I'll tell you,
You came to the right place.
We can make it happen.
Hey, this is going to happen.
Understand, this is real.
On my family...
On my kids. On my life and my work.
I know that, Carmine.
You are a good man.
I'm federal agent Richie DiMaso.
I placed 75 thousand dollars
in this briefcase for one...
representative, Jerry Sanders
of the third district.
I don't wanna do anything illegal.
Please, Jerry
use it as a campaign donation.
Whatever you wanna do.
- Thank you, that means a lot.
I'm placing 60 thousand dollars into this..
Briefcase for one,
Eric Keshoygan of the 4th district.
I'm gonna do what i can.
To help, Carmine.
A 100 thousand dollars
into this briefcase,
For two term united states Senator,
Ford Richland of New Jersey.
Atlantic City..
all the way down the shore.
The Mecca, by the sea.
Carmine, you're beloved by your people.
Your constituency...
It's not even a constituency.
It's your family.
That's what you represent, a family.
One small thing you do for this man,
It's a huge thing we do for,
the people of New Jersey.
This is what we can...
Irving, what're you doing?
Where are you going?
Just gotta see a man about a toilet.
Sorry.
Trust me, this is the probaby the
biggest opportunity,
That we could have.
- I will go where ever
I can in the united states...
I appreciate this.
- On my family, on my kids..
This needs to happen.
It's gotta happen.
You have my word.
Oh, i wanna save us.
I wanna save us!
I wanna save Carmine,
It's killing me, it's fucking killing...
The only way to help Carmine
is to do the Tellegio thing.
It's dangerous. It's dangerous.
We gotta get in there,
We gotta get a wire in there.
We gotta make him feel safe.
There's only one thing that
could fuck this up.
And, that's your wife!
Yeah.
I don't like your hausband.
You're no better together.
He doesn't appreciate you.
But, It happens.
It happened to my marriage.
That's why I went to Miami.
And, sometimes you just gotta be tough.
You gotta stand up.
You gotta leave, you know.
Sometimes, you've gotta let
something die. To let, something live.
You're too beautiful, to be unhappy.
I mean, I don't wanna...
bad mouth my hausband.
But, just...
..let me bad mouth my hausband
just for a second.
He just thinks that he knows everything.
And, he's so full of shit.
He's such a liar!
He thinks that I'm stupid.
But, i'm not stupid.
I hear him on the phone, arguing.
He loves Carmine. But, he hates that
other guy. That curly headed...
IRS guy or whatever.
Who's cowering around my hausband's
ex-lover at that, red headed whore!
IRS?
- Anyway, you can see that,
It drives him crazy.
You said IRS.
What IRS guy?
What're you talking about?
I hear them on the phone.
I think that, he's got Irving
in some sort of bind or something..
And, he's making him do
all these sorts of stuff.
And so, Irving and Carmine;
are right now are at the Plaza Hotel,
Throwing all these money away
at like, congress or..
whatever. They're giving money
to congress or something.
I don't really know.
But, I over heard it on the phone.
I hate doing this you.
I gotta go talk to your hausband.
My boss, he's already angry.
You stay here.
I'm gonna give you some money.
For a taxi home.
Have some dessert.
Finish the bottle of perseco.
I'm sorry.
You alright?
I don't like change.
It's really hard for me.
Sometimes, i think that
I would die before I change.
Don't say that.
It's gonna be okay.
You're gonna come with me to Miami.
Don't hurt him too bad.
He is still Danny's father.
You know you did. You know you did
You know you did.
But if this is ever changin'
world, In which we live in.
Makes you give in and cry.
Say live and let die.
Live and let die.
Life is ridiculous.
And, you know that
I'd never say,
anything bad about your father
in front of you. But,
Your father is a sick
son of a bitch.
Daddy's a sick son of a bitch?
Don't repeat that!
But, yes.
Rosalyn!
What?
- This is what's wrong..
in our relationship.
You know where I was recently?
I was in your boyfriend's
fucking car.
Alright? I saw your nail polish.
And, what's this i hear about your curly
haired friend working for the government?
What? Who said that?
Your fucking wife!
Rosalyn?
- He put a fucking canvas bag,
over my head!
Hey, what the fuck?!
Are you happy now?
Because, he is trying to kill me?!
What are you talking about?!
What do you think, you're doing?!
- Get out of here!
Why are you talking so much?
You're gonna get us all killed!
Danny.
Come here buddy.
Go draw a picture or something.
You are a sick son of a bitch
for screaming at me like that,
in front of Danny.
I'm a sick son of a bitch?
You tried to fucking get me killed.
My god!
You're driving me so fucking crazy!
You're boyfriend,
your fucking boyfriend..
will fucking kill me.
He will kill Danny..
And, he will kill you.
- Stop talking like that!
He's a mobster, alright.
That's what you're dealing with.
Stop that! You're fine!
He'd have hurted you...
How do you think that I feel.
All day when you leave me alone.
All day! All i've ever wanted
you to do is love me.
That's all i've ever wanted.
That's for us to stay married
and for you to love me.
And, that's why i'm going to Miami.
I'm going to Miami, with Pete.
I'm going to Miami, with Pete!!!
I finally find somebody
who loves me!
Just like you've always wanted.
Miami..not now!
Too fucking dangerous!
- He likes me just the way I am!
You're gonna stay normal.
- You told me that you wanted to find a
nice quite man!
- Ah, I wanted.
Doozy, you've picked.
Ohh, you have that..
..the most dangerous guy, yeah.
What'd you expect, Irving.
I know everybody through you!
Why can't you just be
happy for me?
Why are you taking your
heart pill Irving?
What's going on?
Irving, take your pill.
What kind of trouble are you in, Irving?
What is going on?
What's happening?
I got a plan.
You got a plan?
When did you  get it?
You know what?
It really fucking came to me.
When i was inside of that
Canvas bag.
We got two million coming this week!
- You see?
You think, this is a fucking
down paying plan?
Are, we series of Chevrolet?
You ask Victor.
If he wants...
..two million this week.
That's real money.
Two million?
- Real money.
This week.
- How?
Wired in.
Is it true?
What he said about your wive?
About Rosalyn?
I can save all of us.
And we can save money.
That'll take care of you.
And, Danny.
Okay? But, you gotta
close your mouth.
I knew it.
I have always said, Irving.
That you're very very hard.
To motivate properly.
And, I knew..
that Pete was gonna go over there
and knock some sense into your head.
I've been reading this book, Irving.
It's by Wayne Dyer, that's the
"Power of intention".
And, my intention
in setting Pete over to you..
Was so that,
you could come up with this plan.
So..you're welcome.
Thank you, Rosalyn.
Thank you for the plan.
- You're welcome.
I appreciate that.
So, uh..
We should be partners on this.
Yeah, i'm a good partner.
I'm almost better then Edith.
You ever think about that?
You might've under estimated me?
So, what is our plan?
Tell me the plan.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna keep my mouth shut.
I'm not gonna say anything.
But, what do I do
if Pete calls me. What am I supposed say?
You gotta stop talking about
any government agencies,
the IRS and tax conspiracies..
and all of that.
You're gonna say, how you're wrong.
You were wrong about that.
I'll tell Pete, that I was wrong.
But, you know that in real life...
I was right for saying that stuff.
Because that spurt on the actions
that made you come up with this plan.
So, i will tell Pete.
- Okay.
The Power of Intention, Irving.
The Power of Intention.
Okay.
You are right.
- Irv?
Good job peaches.
Irving.
I've been doing a lot of thinking.
And,
You need to grow up.
And, you need to face the facts.
And, i think that both of us
will be a lot happier,
if we get a divorce.
Okay.
Just think about it.
These things are never easy.
Alright.
Irving?
Good luck, with your plan.
Necessity, truly is..
the mother of invention.
The FBI was willing to wire
the two million dollars,
If it meant, taking down Tellegio
and his entire organisation.
Mobster like Tellegio
would never meet at the Plaza Hotel,
Put only at the office of his attorney.
Alphonse Simone.
Hi, Alphonse Simone.
- Edith Greensly.
Alphonse Simone.
Please, have a seat.
I appreciate the fact that,
You all came in person.
But, the trip was really unnecessary.
Because, this whole thing could've
been done with a simple wire transfer.
As a matter of fact..
This is the number on the wire,
right here.
Where is Mr.Tellegio?
Mr.Tellegio, was unfortunately
called out of town, on business.
Oh, that's not good.
We're willing to come here today.
In person, to Mr.Tellegio.
As a sign of respect,
To give two million dollars.
- I can assure you that
i have power of attorney,
- Excuse me, if you let me finish.
We are willing,
to give two million dollars today,
on the temp.
But, without Mr.Tellegio, here..?
- We can't make that decision.
You don't have the authorisation
to make this kind of choice,
So, don't be hasty alright?
I'm not being hasty.
Let's be smart about this. Alright?
This is not how we do business.
I'm sorry.
I think we should hang in there, alright?
For what?
The guy is not here.
That's it.
Sorry, I can't do it!
This is a surprise that...
the Sheikh don't like surprises.
Don't leave!
Edith, this is not the way
that decision are made.
No, I understand but,
maybe we can call the Sheikh.
Let's call the Sheikh.
It's not the plan.
It's not it.
I'll call the Sheikh.
Can i use your phone?
Please, do.
But, before I do.
I'd like to go over, SPECIFICALLY
what this money would be used for.
Okay. What we will do,
is we guarantee.
All proper licenses and contruction permits.
For any Hotel Casino,
That is planned to open before
the end of year.
And, we'll throw in the customary,
Previleges of protection.
What if there's obstacles?
What will you do
- Obstacles...
We are prepared to overcome
any obstacles.
But, this is a big enterprise.
- If we've to pay somebody off..
We'll pay somebody off.
If we have to lean on somebody,
We'll intimidate somebody.
We are experienced!
This is our business.
That's poweful stuffs.
Thank you.
- And, I'll tell you something else.
At the end of this.
We'll teach you, how to skim.
And, how to cut it up.
And, make some money
on the side. Because..
WE invented skimming.
We've been doing it for
thirty years!
Thank you.
Thank you, for clarifying that.
Okay.
I'm very happy.
I think that,
that will be okay for the Sheikh.
This is the Sheikh.
- Mr.Tellegio, is not here.
It's just Mr.Alphose Simone,
his lawyer.
Are we still okay,
to wire the money?
Simone can take the wire.
What's the number?
531..
78P..78P..76..76.
The funds have transfered.
The money has been wired.
I think, we have a deal.
Pleasure doing business with you.
Okay, thank you very much,
Mr.Simone.
Well, thank you.
- The Sheikh is very excited.
I'm sure we'll be seeing each other.
- Oh, I'm sure that we'll be seeing each other.
I'm looking forward to it.
- So, am I.
You might get sick of me.
Like these two.
- I don't think I'll get sick of you.
Goodbye, nice meeting you.
It happened!
Finally!
Finally, we get someone in the bag.
Oh, oh..oh!
Wait, wait..wait?
If we've to pay somebody off..
We'll pay somebody off.
If we have to lean on somebody,
... intimidate somebody.
INTIMIDATE!
Yeah, but I gotta do it.
What do you mean, there is no Sheikh?
What does that mean?
There is no Sheikh.
I wanna face you like a man.
B'cos, I wanna be real about it.
Alright?
- Who's the man?
Who is they?
That he's the fence.
A fence?
- Yeah.
Irving...
look, i'm a good person.
You are a good person.
I've been doing this for a long time.
For twenty years!
Do you think,
I would've taken that money.
If it wasn't the right
thing to do?
Now, look..
- Huh?
You're a good person.
I know that, but in all honesty...
- You said that was the only way Irv.
You chased me, you remember?
- They fucking made me do it.
I was asked to do that or sit in jail.
- You made me go back to the plaza,
To take that money.
You piece of shit!
I was gone!
You fucking prick!
You motherfucker!!!
You fucking chased me,
you piece of shit!
Carmine?
- I was gone! I left.
Everything all right.
- Please, Dolly. Just go upstairs.
Alright..
- Take the kid and go upstairs.
Please..please just go.
- Of course..
I'll make this right.
I came here, because..
I wanna make it right.
Look at my face.
You tell me that I'm lying to you.
When i say that, everything i do,
is for the good of the people,
Of New Jersey.
Everything, I do.
Is for them.
Am I lying to you?
I never had a friend like you before.
I used that money
for that goddamn casino.
I got some fucking leverage, alright?
I can help you out.
This is all shit.
This is all bullshit.
Look at this thing.
Look at this.
Ceremonial fucking knife.
What is this, bullshit. Some toy?
Carmine, Syd and I got a plan for you.
- Get out.
We can help you out.
Please get out of my house, Irving.
Will you please leave.
I'm asking you nicely, please leave.
Get out of my house, go!
Get out of our house!
Oh, fuck!
I'm sorry...i'm sorry.
I don't mean for this to happen.
This is what matters to me most.
And, you're crushing that.
You're gonna take me away from them?
I didn't wanna have this to
happen ever.
Fucking son of a bitch!
You son of a bitch!
- I just wanna make it right.
Just get out of my house.
Look what you made me do.
Pleae go.
I'm sorry Carmine.
Get out of here!
Get out!
No, Carmine...what's happening?
Oh, My God!
No!
Oh, fuck.
- Irving!
Irving, are you all right?
Where're your heart pills?
Where are your heart pills?
There you go.
Okay, come on.
I gotta lie down.
Just rest.
You ready?
Yeah.
Please.
Come and sit down.
You know where
the two million dollars is?
Two million?
Yeah.
- With uh, Victor Tellegio,
and Alphonse Simone.
No, actually..
it's not with..
Victor Tellegio or Alphonse Simone.
He fucking knows about it.
It's gone missing.
Did you know that?
I know nothing about that.
Where is it gone?
That's interesting,
you would say that. Because,
While you're on your way
over here we got an..
annonymous phone call..
from someone.
Who said that,
in exchange,
for immunity for the two of you...
And, reduced sentence
for Carmine Polito.
We'll get our two million dollars back.
That's interesting.
That's very interesting.
I have no idea.
No, idea why?
- Not, what you're talking about.
I get it.
I under-estimated you, right?
See, someone has leverage.
Anthony, fuck them.
Fuck them, it's over!
We got them or wire fraught.
It's over, you're both done!
I don't think so, i don't think so.
- Oh, you don't think so?
Richard, you requested the two million.
And, you gave Brenda
the account number.
We didn't do any of that.
None of it.
How do we know that,
You don't have the money?
Am I living in a fucking nightmare, right now?
- I find this a little offensive.
Really, I find this a little offensive.
Listen to me,  we're dealing with
a very clever individual.
Richard.
Think about it, alright?
You had some big arrest.
Yeah, U.S congressmen.
You'll look good.
You're gonna be all over the news.
You know,
what doesn't look good?
Story about gross incompetence.
I have a warrant for,
sorry..do i have the wrong office?
This is 701..?
Alphonse Simone?
- This is 701.
My name is Roger Thickwen.
I've had this office for 25 years.
I'm a divorce attorney.
You lost 2 million dollars
of taxpayer money?
Because, you're confused,
about the location and the identity
of Victor Tellegio's attorney?
The role of Tellegio's attorney,
Alphonse Simone was played by our friend,
Ed Malone.
The cold cut king of Long Island.
Whose party, we were at.
When Sydney and I first met.
Alphonse Simone
People believe what
they wanna believe, Richie.
No, b'cos you conned me.
That's why. Because,
fucking conned me.
You did.
That, that doesn't sound
so good either.
Right there.
You know what i mean.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
But, let's just assume..
You wanna go with that story.
Really?
That's the story, you wanna go with?
Alright? That's what
you want the New York Times to hear.
That, you got conned..
By the very con men,
Who you 'forced'..
to entrap the members of congress.
In the first place.
That's what you wanna go with.
That doesn't sound so good,
for your whole thing.
Does it?
How ironic...
that the ones who're
working hardest.
To get, the economy of
New Jersey's going.
Those are the ones
you round up.
Why? why..b'cos what.
They are the easiest
to go after?
What about the real bullshit artists?
You didn't even
come close to the big leagues.
Those big guys.
The money men.
That's what I was trying
to go after.
I'm sorry to telling you,
you got none of 'em.
You know Richard, i think uh..
We may call you as a witness.
But, otherwise you're done.
I think you better go home.
Stauton.
Go on home, Richard.
We took down some very big guys.
Among some who..
They were just doing business as usual.
Helping their community, served their states.
But, some of them knew.
They have larceny in their blood.
May never admitted it.
But, in all..
were Six Congressmen.
One United States Senator.
And my friend, Carmine Polito.
We gave the two million back.
So, Carmine got a reduced sentence.
18 months.
The lost of his friendship...
..will haunt me for the rest of my life.
When the story was written,
Richie DiMaso's name..
...was never mentioned.
Syd and I,
we moved in together.
Rosalyn...
The car is a little dinked up.
I'm a little stiff..but..
Whatever, I don't wanna talk
about it.
She will always be interesting.
You know, my boss
knows you did him a solid.
Yes, I did.
We never took any records.
I was never gona let that happen.
Irv?
I'm done with that nail finish.
By for now.
I'll see ya next weekend.
Our Conning days.
Were behind us.
You can fool yourself
for just so long.
Then, you're next re-invention
better have your damn feet on the ground.
We got a loan from a bank.
And, we're able to go a gellary legitimate.
The art of survival...
..is a story that never ends.