(CLOCK CHIMING)
Hostilities will end officially
at one minute after midnight tonight.
The German war is therefore at an end.
We may allow ourselves
a brief period of rejoicing.
Today is Victory in Europe Day.
(CHEERING)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
REPORTER: Outside Buckingham Palace,
the crowds cheered themselves hoarse.
CROWD: (CHANTING) We want the King!
We want the King!
MARGARET: Lillibet!
Drawing room.
Hurry.
(GIGGLING)
(TICKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
QUEEN ELIZABETH: Half past ten,
Archbishop of Canterbury and Mr Churchill.
Goodness.
Will you alert the Yeoman of the Gold Pantry?
Ah, there you are.
Half past 11,
the Australian High Commissioner
will be joining us for coffee.
- Why the hell wasn't I informed?
- Yes.
- At a quarter past 12...
- You know, Mummy,
it is such a special day.
Lillibet and I could go out, couldn't we?
KING GEORGE: Out?
Out where?
Into the crowds to celebrate
with everyone else.
You'll be far too busy in here.
Quite.
Bertie, darling, sit down.
Where was I? Quarter past 12. Ah...
A Polish delegation will present gifts.
One o'clock, lunch with the French
Ambassador and his wife.
Elizabeth, make sure you have
prepared your remarks.
Yes, Mummy.
Six o'clock, the man from the BBC arrives.
- Ready?
- Hmm-mmm.
The French Ambassador's wife
will be so elegant.
Très chic.
And, of course, turning up her nose at
la cuisine Anglaise, exécrable.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, who cares what they think?
They're only French, after all.
I will deliver my remarks.
And what remark would be
suitable for the French?
"We couldn't have done it without you"?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
What-ho, Mickey?
The latest tid-bits, ma'am.
Nice feature on the Curzon Club.
A rather outré spot, it seems.
Oh, thanks awfully, Mickey.
Oh, I say. Look at that.
Everyone in the entire country
will be living it up tonight.
It has to be you who asks them.
They won't listen to me.
(SWING JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(HUMMING)
Oh! Listen to this.
Listen. Listen.
"The Curzon is considered
by those deep in the know
"to be the best club west of Piccadilly."
"Barely a Bath Oliver's
throw from Claridges,
"just around the corner
from the American Embassy..."
- Margaret.
- "Mr Gregory Peck was there...
"Only last week drinking
martinis and dancing."
(GIGGLING)
Which one is that again?
The Lindy Hop. Come on, bumble feet.
I'll show you.
One, two, three, four...
- Margaret...
- And...
Mickey tells me there's
going to be a wizard
all-nighter at Chelsea Barracks.
One of his friends gave him the password.
Would they let me in, do you think?
- I think so.
- Being a princess.
Just being you would do it.
Really?
The best nightclub in all of Mayfair...
Mummy said, "No."
What kind of "no"?
"No," as in...
"Absolutely not, under any
circumstances whatsoever."
What did she say?
The life we live...
(BOTH) Is not fully our own...
Blah, blah.
Does she think I'm going to end up
on the front page of the Daily Mirror
in the arms of a drunken
sailor or something?
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- Hardly.
(CLOCK CHIMES)
You didn't ask properly.
You can't have done.
Lillibet!
We'll be walled up in
this ghastly mausoleum
for the rest of our blooming lives.
I'm completely cheesed.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR OPENING)
Speaking from our Empire's oldest
capital city,
war-battered,
but never for one moment
daunted or dismayed,
I ask you to join me
in that act of thanksgiving.
So far?
Very good. Full of character and sincerity.
- Awfully impressive.
- Oh, you really think so?
- Absolutely.
- We all do.
Go on.
(CLEARS THROAT)
At this hour, when the...
(STAMMERS)
At this hour...
When the dreadful shadow of war
has passed...
- The thing is...
- What?
My sister and I have been brought up
to believe in the importance of sincerity.
Everyone, this is hard enough as it is.
Fairness too.
And for six years now
we've been positively cloistered.
- Like nuns.
- We understood the reference.
Margaret and I deserve the right
to celebrate too, outside.
I agree with her completely.
I'm sure you do.
You know we can't do that.
Besides, what's so special about going out?
I don't know and I never will
unless we go out tonight.
QUEEN ELIZABETH: Darlings...
We have invited your closest friends
to be with you tonight,
suitable young people...
My very close,
my extremely suitable friends?
You're always with me
when I give my speeches.
We four. The family should be
together, tonight of all nights.
We would be still, Papa,
in a way,
but with us out there amongst the people.
Hmm. Hardly the same thing.
I could tell you how it was received.
What they really think.
One day, Lillibet,
far off in the future, you shall be Queen.
- I know that, Mummy.
- And your subjects...
My subjects? What do I know about them?
Your subjects need to see you
as incorporating in your person
the very essence of royalty.
One knows about essences and all that,
but one would still like to
have a dance from time to time.
- The Lindy Hop, for example.
- The what-y hop?
Let them go.
We should let them go.
But they might be recognised.
We would be incognito.
Why not?
After all, we had our fun, remember?
It was different for us.
You weren't the heir.
This might be the only chance she gets.
And me.
(SIGHING) Well...
That's that, then.
KING GEORGE: Good.
Now can we please get on
with my bloody speech?
Yippee!
(SCREAMING AND GIGGLING)
We're off, Mickey! We're off!
(RINGING)
Yes, would you be so kind as to
connect me to the Chelsea Barracks?
The Colonel.
We're going out...
Incognito.
Does the tiara rather
give the game away, ma'am?
Yes.
Thanks, Mickey.
(GASPING)
What a stunner.
Et moi?
Beautiful.
I thought.
Trafalgar Square for a
splash in the fountains,
then the Curzon,
going on to that wizard all-nighter
at Chelsea Barracks.
Whatever you want. Tonight we're in charge.
There you are. Don't you look lovely.
Well, Captain Pryce and Lieutenant Burridge
from the Guards at Chelsea Barracks
will be your chaperones.
(BOTH) Chaperones?
They will escort you to the Ritz
and stay with you all night long.
Ma'am, we are honoured
by this great and sacred charge.
Lieutenant Burridge?
Deeply, ma'am. Inexpressibly.
I'm sure you will have a wonderful time
under their close and
scrupulous supervision.
- Understood?
- (BOTH) Yes, Mummy.
Back by midnight.
- Midnight?
- That's not fair.
Come on, darling. Peace begins at midnight.
We'd like you to be out there
watching us in the crowd.
Lillibet,
I want to know how they all
really feel at that moment.
Hmm?
One o'clock, not a minute later.
Margaret?
Best behaviour, honestly.
No question.
Now, off you go.
Ladies and gentlemen, get your flags!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
PRYCE: Driver, hurry it up, will you?
We have a schedule to keep to.
(HONKS)
That's one glorious party out there.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
WOMAN IN CROWD: Isn't it marvellous?
Horn, man!
- Horn!
- DRIVER: Yes, sir.
Captain Pryce, Lieutenant Burridge,
do please remember that we are incognito.
Then, Junior Subaltern Windsor,
please do adjust the angle of your cap.
I prefer not to be seen with an officer
who is improperly dressed.
(HONKING CONTINUES)
Thank you.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Excuse me! Beg your pardon, ma'am.
Bear with me just a moment, please.
(CHEERING)
PRYCE: Out of the way, you people.
We need to get through here.
MAN IN CROWD: Hey, buddy!
Buddy! Come on up here!
- We got a load of liberated champagne!
- ELIZABETH: There's so many.
- BURRIDGE: Excuse me.
- Hey, baby. How you doing, huh?
- Margaret.
- Clear off, you...
- AMERICAN SOLDIER: Relax.
- ELIZABETH: Come along.
BURRIDGE: Come with me, ma'am.
He called me baby.
- WAITER: Champagne, sir?
- Your Royal Highnesses.
We're incognito. Lizzy, Mags.
- Yes, Your Highness.
- We're here for the dancing.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Champagne.
Ma'am.
This way.
Waiter.
Other exits?
This is the only one, sir.
Your guests await you, ma'am.
Guests?
My Lords, ladies and gentlemen,
Her Royal Highness, the Princess Elizabeth
and Her Royal Highness,
the Princess Margaret.
(WHISPERING) Bloody Mummy.
- WOMAN: Can you see them?
- MAN: They're over there, I think.
DANCERS: Hey!
- Hey.
- Time for a quickie, surely, sir.
(BURRIDGE SINGS TO MUSIC)
Burridge. Not tonight, Burridge.
Get back here. Not tonight.
Lord and Lady MacCloud.
Ma'am, just delighted.
Understand there is a visit scheduled
to our Scottish estate.
Your great-grandmama shot with us,
450 grouse in the game-book that day.
Burridge.
(CHATTERING)
BURRIDGE: (CHUCKLING) Oh, fantastic.
Captain.
Get back where you belong,
Lieutenant Burridge.
We have our own suite
at the railway station.
So looking forward to welcoming
the royal train there once again.
BURRIDGE: Loosen up, old man.
We can see the door from here.
Hmm?
- LIFT CONCIERGE: Going up?
- Wait. Wait for me.
It's VE night.
MARGARET: Woo-hoo!
(LIFT DINGS)
Fine.
Oh, it's all right.
Nobody gives a monkey's what I do.
SERVER: Excuse me.
- Oh.
- I say...
Things are looking up. Come on, poppet.
(GIGGLING)
- Oh.
- (SQUEALING)
Our polo ponies are the talk of the north,
as I'm sure you will see.
Maybe you'll even ride one of them.
- Lady MacCloud, Margaret and I would love...
- (GASPS)
She must meet my grand-nephew.
He's heir to that part
of Scotland you aren't.
Splendid idea. I'll tell her. Excuse me.
OFFICER: Captain.
Whoa!
Oh!
Hmm.
ELIZABETH: Stop. Excuse me.
WOMAN 1: Well,
you look marvellous, darling.
WOMAN 2: Well, yes, I know, but...
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
JEFFERS: I know somewhere
much more exciting. Come with me.
Margaret!
- (LAUGHING)
- Excuse me.
Oh!
Oh...
- Margaret.
- Oh, just popping down for some air.
One, two,
then I like to throw in a twirl...
- And then one, two, the other way...
- Wait for me!
And then I'll go so...
Margaret!
Oh...
MARGARET: I want to dance all night long.
- ELIZABETH: Margaret, wait!
- JEFFERS: Follow me.
Let's hop on the bus.
Oh!
(SHATTERING)
(GASPING)
(CROWDS CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (BRAKES SCREECH)
- (ELIZABETH SCREAMS)
No!
- DRIVER: (HONKING) Out of the way!
- Ah!
Sorry.
A bus. Excellent.
If you'll be so good, please,
to follow that other bus.
- Hop on!
- Oh.
Shall we move to somewhere
more comfortable, sir?
I can imagine nothing
that will break my sacred trust.
Nothing, sir?
Nothing?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Excuse me. Would you mind?
So kind.
Margaret!
(KNOCKING)
Margaret! Get off the bus, Margaret!
Where is your bus going?
(INAUDIBLE)
ALL: Trafalgar Square!
- God!
- (LAUGHING)
No! Margaret!
(INAUDIBLE)
- MARGARET: Cheers.
- JEFFERS: Cheers.
When the bus stops, you get off...
Ritz, you got on, wasn't it, dear?
Tuppence, dear.
Sorry. I don't have any money.
Well, you'd better get off, then.
You're making her pay tonight?
There is a war on, you know,
in the Far East.
No money. Who do you think you are?
Come on,
little miss toffee nose, off you go.
I've got it.
Allow me.
(WHIRRING)
Any more fares? No reduction for VE Day.
Only passengers with money allowed.
Thank you. It was very kind of you.
Hmm.
Oh, Margaret.
Oh!
Wait. Wait. Hang on a minute.
Miss.
Your bag.
How do I stop the bus?
- Push that.
- This...
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
For future reference,
that's not how you get off the bus.
- (BICYCLE BELL RINGING)
- You could hurt somebody.
- Oh, no!
- And your heel's bust.
(HONKING)
- Oh!
- Come on.
(HISSES IN PAIN) Ow.
Hurt your hand?
Here.
(GASPING)
You're touching me.
Don't worry. My spit's very hygienic.
No, don't.
Quite enough. Thank you very much.
- RED CAP: Show us your papers.
- MAN: Come on. It's VE night.
- RED CAP: Let's see 'em.
- WOMAN: Leave him alone.
Well, you'd better
get yourself cleaned up, then.
- Where do I do that?
- This way.
- RED CAP: Papers.
- WOMAN: You must be joking.
RED CAP: Calm down, love.
OFFICER: Come on, let's go down
the Rose and Crown.
- RED CAP: Let's go down to Piccadilly.
- WOMAN: Bloody Red Caps.
(ELIZABETH CLEARS THROAT)
Ever so sorry.
I don't know what's come over me.
(CROWD SINGING)
JACK: Excuse me. Coming through.
Mind your backs.
♪ Ring out a song of good cheer
♪ Now's the time to roll the barrel ♪
Yay!
JACK: Come along.
♪ Coz the gang's all here
♪ Roll out the barrel ♪
All right, love?
♪ We'll have a barrel of fun ♪
The ladies is over there somewhere.
Which ladies?
Where you can see to that hand,
and your hair and that.
♪ We've got the blues on the run
♪ Zing ♪
Have you seen much action, Lieutenant?
Not quite as much as
I'd have liked, but er...
But hoping to make up for that tonight.
But it was one's duty to serve
in a more secret capacity.
- Really?
- Naval intelligence.
Hush-hush.
- The name's Jeffers.
- How exciting.
Let's go for a splash.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Oh... In the name of...
What is it?
Er... Excuse me.
Telephone call, sir.
Give me the phone.
I've got a lot on my plate here.
Who the hell is this?
The King.
- Er...
- Everything all right, Lieutenant?
Yes, Your Majesty.
- Where's Captain Pryce?
- Indisposed, sir. Comfort break.
The soirée's going splendidly, sir.
Princesses Elizabeth and Margaret
are enjoying the company
inside the ballroom, sir.
Good.
Everyone ready and waiting for my speech?
Expectation is enormous, sir.
Do remind the princesses
that I want to hear exactly
what everyone thought.
Hmm?
Exactly.
Erm... Sorry, sir. Terrible connection.
(DISCONNECTING)
Who was that?
Burridge, reporting in.
Hmm, not Pryce?
Comfort break.
- Is that English?
- Apparently.
Everything all right?
Absolutely.
Can we get on with the bloody thing?
Well...
Here we go.
CAMERAMAN: All right, everybody. Stand by.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
♪ Two lovely black eyes
♪ Oh what a surprise
♪ Only for telling a man he was wrong
♪ Two lovely black eyes ♪
(LAUGHING AND CHEERING)
Thought I'd lost you.
I really should be going.
The King.
(GULPING)
Mmm.
(CHUCKLING)
(PANTING)
You were thirsty.
Another?
My sister's gone to Trafalgar Square.
I have to find her.
LANDLORD: (RINGING BELL) Pipe down!
Everybody listen!
A little hush for His Majesty.
The speech.
Oh, I'd forgotten.
I'm rather dreading this.
Me too.
KING GEORGE: (ON RADIO)
At this hour, when the...
dreadful shadow of war
has passed from our hearts and homes,
we may turn our thoughts to the tasks
all over the world, which...
Peace in Europe brings with it.
Today we give thanks to Almighty God
for a great deliverance.
Surrounded by my dear family,
I am speaking to you from London,
our empire's oldest capital city.
What a tosser.
But never for one moment
daunted or dismayed,
let us remember the fallen,
their sacrifice in the face
of a merciless enemy.
- We are proud to have shared...
- Which he'd know all about.
How dare you.
You, little prick,
are being disloyal and abusive
to your sovereign.
- The King is 10 times the man you are.
- He certainly is.
Oh, come on. You're not buying
this load of bollocks, are you?
Shut up. Shut up.
Nobody's gonna make me miserable today.
I've waited too long for it.
SOLDIER: Sit down, love.
KING GEORGE:
It is the children of our country...
- The King!
- The King.
ALL: The King!
KING GEORGE: ...please God, forever.
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
SOLDIER: Sling your hook.
If you ask me...
Which I wasn't.
You got exactly what you deserved.
Wait!
The King... Excuse me.
The King was trying jolly hard,
as a matter of fact,
to offer words of encouragement...
Well, he jolly well pissed me off.
"Fallen."
That's a nice word for a nasty,
dirty, painful business.
Stop!
- Where are you going?
- This way.
I need to get to Trafalgar Square.
The people in that public house
love their king and their country.
War's over,
and for some reason I came back
to the same old column-dodging posh gits
with plummy voices on the wireless...
Plummy voices like mine, I suppose?
Exactly.
Well, let me tell you,
whatever your name is,
my whole family served in this war.
Sandwiches, maybe.
(SCOFFS)
La-di-da.
As a matter of fact, my mother
did exactly that in the Blitz.
And did you help with the sandwiches?
I'm in the Auxiliary Territorial Service,
Mechanical Transport Training
Section, Second Subaltern.
A bloody officer.
In that dress.
Well, mostly in that dress.
Lost your uniform?
(SIGHS)
What are you, then, incognito?
How long?
- Incognito.
- ATS.
Eleven weeks.
Shoe. Shoe. Give me the shoe.
What's your name, then?
Eliza... Lizzy.
Jack.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Handmade.
Family well off by any chance?
- We manage.
- Hmm.
And your sister is lost.
Well, that's what
I've been trying to tell you.
Will you please take me
to Trafalgar Square?
No.
Why not?
Because... We're already here.
(CHEERING)
Come on.
SOLDIER: All right, boys! We won the war!
WOMAN: Look at you! Marvellous!
(CHEERING)
Good luck.
Wait for me!
Jack!
I suggest we start by the lions.
She looks a little like me.
Her dress is pale pink.
- Flowers. Oh!
- SOLDER: Sorry, folks.
Steady on.
(JACK LAUGHING)
Cosy, Lieutenant?
I can see that you have certain
expectations for this evening,
but the fact of the matter is,
I'm sort of, well, taken.
Unavailable. Very much so, actually.
Fair enough.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Jack! Help! Help!
How are you?
Help!
ELIZABETH: Jack?
(ELIZABETH SCREAMING)
♪ It's a long way to go... ♪
Margaret?
Come on, in you get.
MAN: There you are.
Margaret.
Margaret, no, you can't!
Oh, here! What's your game?
Get your own fella.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Should think so too.
- Come on, you.
- All right.
- WOMAN: What's your name?
- STAN: Stan. What's yours?
(CHATTERING)
Have you seen my sister,
like me only older?
She'll be here any minute.
- Shall we go dancing?
- Oh, yes.
The Curzon. It's in Mayfair.
Barely a Bath Oliver's throw
from Claridges', actually.
Awfully outré.
They do the Lindy there, you know.
- Then let's go.
- (SQUEALING)
We can, er...
We can pop back later for your sister.
(GIGGLING) Oh, OK.
Thank God.
Shall we carry on with the search?
This is Mary and this is Jane.
- Hello. Hello.
- Hello.
We're going to The Mall.
What about my sister?
The girls here are dying to see
their King and Queen,
which is probably what
your sister's gone and done.
(MARY AND JANE LAUGHING)
I really don't think so.
- Don't you speak posh!
- (LAUGHING)
Ladies.
- Bye.
- Let's go to Buckingham Palace.
Fine. If that's what you want, go.
I'll just carry on looking on my own,
surrounded by strangers,
which could be very dangerous
to a person in my position!
(CHEERING GROWS)
(LAUGHING)
Here we are.
Gosh, look.
JEFFERS: Huh.
Madam.
I knew the Curzon was hot.
(CROWD CHANTING) We want the King!
We want the King!
Excuse me.
(CROWD SINGING)
ELIZBAETH: There.
♪ Long to reign over us
♪ God save our King ♪
(GIGGLING)
Oh, you.
(LOUD CHEERING)
Where are the princesses?
In an awful lot of trouble.
It's pandemonium down there.
I could murder a G&T.
Oh, me too.
Why aren't you waving, then, Miss La-Di-Da?
They got us through this bloody war.
You really think so?
Some of us.
Did you lose someone?
(CLOCK CHIMING)
CROWD: Ten,
nine, eight,
seven, six,
five, four, three,
two, one!
(CHEERING)
(CHIMING)
(LAUGHING)
Excuse me.
Do you make a habit of kissing
other people's boyfriends?
Boyfriend? Take him, then.
Spoilt for choice tonight.
Are you absolutely determined
to ruin my evening?
I thought you were going to help me.
My sister mentioned something
about the Curzon Club.
Could you please show me the way there?
And afterwards...
Afterwards?
We could go for another drink.
(CHUCKLES)
But you're sort of taken.
He's abroad.
But you know what they say in the forces.
Overseas doesn't count.
Well?
All right.
Come on.
Let's go and find your sister.
Excuse me. Sorry. Excuse me...
(CHATTERING)
(HUMMING)
Wake up, old man.
Time to get the princesses
back to the palace.
(GASPING)
The princesses!
(FALLS TO THE GROUND)
PRYCE: Excuse me.
Sir!
LADY MACCLOUD: Not generally known
but we are descended
from King Macbeth himself.
Oh, God!
Sir.
- Oh, God.
- Yes, sir.
LADY MACCLOUD:
He got a bad press, you know,
from that Englishman.
- (GROANS)
- Sorry, sir.
(MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
This way!
(LAUGHING)
I'll go look...
PRYCE: Burridge!
Oh, it's you!
PRYCE: Where is she?
JEFFERS: Such bad luck about the Curzon.
What a swiz. I so wanted to Lindy.
Lord Stan's is the place for the Lindy.
Is it hot?
- Very.
- Wizard.
Ooh...
(KNOCKING)
- Evening, Raymond.
- (HICCUPS)
(MARGARET GASPS)
(MUMBLING)
- BARTENDER: Did you order, sir?
- MARGARET: Oh, Golly.
- Follow me.
- (GIGGLES)
- Drink? Large one, presumably.
- (LAUGHS) Yes.
- Head on through. I'll be right behind.
- OK.
BARTENDER: There you are, gentlemen.
Evening, Andrew.
- Two pink gins, doubles.
- Of course, sir.
And a...
Pair of bennies to make the night fly.
Certainly, sir.
(LAUGHS) Oh, gambling.
(CHUCKLES)
- Enjoy.
- Place your bets.
- Oh!
- CROUPIER: No more bets.
- Cheers.
Mmm.
JACK: This is the Curzon Club.
Excuse me. Mind your backs, please.
Excuse me.
Good evening, doorman.
I'm looking for my sister.
Perhaps you've seen her?
Pink dress, flowers?
I can't be expected to remember
everyone who comes in here.
Watch it.
Forget something, bomber boy?
Let's have that again, airman,
this time like you mean it.
Piss off.
Jack.
(CLEARS THROAT) Sir.
Now I remember.
There was a girl in a pink dress.
She was with some bloke. Erm, Officer.
- Navy.
- Where did she go?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh.
We've got to talk about money.
Lord Stan's. It's a club...
- DOORMAN: Sort of.
- ELIZABETH: Where?
Soho. Silver Place,
round the back of Dean Street.
Jack, do you know where that...
Jack... Jack?
Honestly. Which way?
Oh, you take a left, go straight ahead,
left into Lexington,
first right onto Broadwick,
second left, up St Anne's Court,
through the alley on your left
and it's on your right.
Can't miss it.
(CHEERING OUTSIDE)
Things are getting out of hand.
They'll wear themselves out soon enough.
I wonder what
it's all going to be like now,
now the war's over.
Mr Churchill will keep everything on track.
If he wins the election.
Darling.
The people will be grateful.
He'll get everything
back to normal in no time.
Normal?
I wonder if those people quite realise
what a demanding new world
they're waking up to.
Lillibet's world.
(SINGING)
Excuse me. I wonder if you could help me.
Where might I find Broadwick...
- You love it.
- (SCREAMS)
- (SCREAMING)
- (LAUGHING)
Oh! Don't hurt me!
That wasn't what I had in mind.
(SIGHS)
- You're back.
- Yeah.
Sorry about disappearing.
First you stand up to that
silly little captain,
but when he comes back at you,
you just turn tail and run.
It wasn't the brown job captain.
It was the Red Cap he was with.
Come on. I know blue funk when I see it,
I don't need help from the type like you.
All right, it's only Soho,
criminal heart of the capital.
Home of razor gangs and opium dens
and murder incorporated.
Won't bother an ATS Second Subaltern
with 11 weeks in.
At least I didn't run away during them.
You didn't have time to.
Please, just...
Tell me where Broadwick street is.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
Yeah, they took 'em off of me.
- For what?
- Talking back.
There's more to it than that.
You think?
(DOGS BARKING)
(BABY WAILING)
Don't worry.
We're going to find your sister.
DAISY: All right, darling.
Look.
Piccadilly commando.
A working girl.
- All right?
- All right, love? How can I help you?
Yeah. Erm, we're looking for
a bloke called Lord Stan.
Red.
CROUPIER: Red.
- Hmm.
- Place your bets!
Mmm.
- Red.
- Place your bets, ladies and gentlemen!
There we are, you see.
Oh, erm.
CROUPIER: No more bets,
ladies and gentlemen.
Mmm.
(MOANS)
(GASPS)
WOMAN: You all right, darling?
- (YELPS)
- Where are you going?
I need the... You know. You're hurting me.
Be quick.
(CLATTER)
(COCKS GUN)
- Hello.
- Good evening.
Not seen you in here before.
Bit high class for us, ain't you, darling?
Who are you, then?
- I'm P2.
- P what?
Princess number two, silly.
(CHUCKLES) Margaret.
Bloody hell.
P2 in my knocking shop.
- Wonderful.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Bit of a snooze, actually.
Nobody takes any notice of me at all.
Ah, it's OK, old boy. She's with me.
Tad too much fizz. Sorry.
That horrible man hurt me.
Nonsense. I'm looking after her.
- Come on, old girl.
- No, no, I don't like you any more.
You heard the lady. Raymond.
- Sod off, you jumped-up little spiv.
- Show the naval gentleman the door.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
- Your Majesty.
- Highness will do.
Would you condescend
to view my collection?
- (JEFFERS GRUNTING AND STRUGGLING)
- Collection?
How interesting.
- (JEFFERS GROANS)
- This goes back to your
great-great-grandmama,
the Queen Empress Victoria,
a truly splendid lady.
(YAWNS)
Raymond.
(MUTTERS AND GRUNTS)
- Take the weight, Your Highness.
- Thank you.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) Thank you.
Rough night, Your Highness?
Incognito.
But I must say, things haven't worked out
at all as I'd hoped.
The Curzon was a bore.
Mmm.
I say, this is much better coffee
than we have at home.
And it looks like I'll never make it
to Chelsea Barracks.
Chelsea Barracks?
Are you foreign?
English to my fingertips.
Hmm. We're all German, you know,
but it's de trop to talk about it.
(CHUCKLES) Not supposed to.
Pas devant les sujets.
The Curzon I can understand,
but Chelsea Barracks?
Marvellous party there.
Should be in full swing by now.
Officers galore...
Any call for girls?
Why, naturally.
And I have the password, you know.
The password?
Good.
Let me rustle up
a few of my closest associates.
Raymond, action stations.
On it, boss.
This is jolly exciting.
Why don't we pop round the barracks first?
And I'll drop you home afterwards.
Excellent plan.
Goodbye.
(KNOCKING)
- (CLATTERING)
- (GASPS)
Oh, my God.
What?
- Hello, Daisy.
- She's with me.
In you come.
No pimps.
What? Come on, let me in.
(GIGGLING)
Are you a wine merchant?
I could give your card to my mother.
MARGARET: Oh, my God!
- What is that?
- Solar Chariot.
Well, half of, anyway.
Second in last year's Saint Leger.
I think I dished out the prizes for that.
Thank you.
(ENGINE REVVING)
How long have you been on this game, then?
Well, actually, this is my first time out.
Sort of out... Ish.
On one's own in so far as one could be.
- What's your name?
- Margaret.
Your real name?
- Oh, that's a coincidence.
She's got lovely skin, ain't she?
Lovely everything.
Reminds me of me at her age.
Oh, what it is to be young.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(SIGHS)
(WHISPERS) Jack.
Jack. Up here.
(GRUNTS)
Hurry up.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
All right. All right.
(ELIZABETH CLEARS THROAT)
Let's get a move on, shall we?
(SIGHS)
(CHATTERING)
(BOTH GROAN)
- I thought you'd gone.
- Me?
Mmm, with Stan and the girls.
To the, er, buttocks.
Buttocks?
- Bollocks?
Bar... (MUMBLES)
(LAUGHS)
She thinks I'm Margaret.
Gone with the girls.
Excuse me, miss.
- Miss?
- JACK: Wake up,
wake up, come on.
No.
- (SLAPS)
- Oh!
Where did they go?
The bar... Bar...
He took all of the girls to Chelsea.
- Barracks!
- Mmm, in the car with the girls.
- Which girls?
- Working girls.
Mmm. Working hard as well, thank you.
We're very busy at the moment.
My sister has gone to Chelsea
with a carload of tarts.
Oh! Thought I told you, no pimps.
- You need a smack.
- All right.
(GRUNTS)
- (THUD)
- (CROWD GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Come on, then, sonny boy.
Come on.
(CHUCKLES)
Come to Papa.
- (CLANG)
- (GROANS)
JACK: Come on, then.
Jack.
Come back here.
Hi, can you, er...
(GROANS)
- Dance.
- Can't dance.
For goodness' sake, make an effort.
Not that much effort.
(SCOFFS)
Mmm.
What exactly is your problem
with the military police?
What problem?
Truth is...
I don't have the right
papers to be out tonight.
If they get hold of me,
I'm in one hell of a lot of trouble.
You're a deserter?
You! Aye, you!
JACK: Quick, run.
Come back here, you nedgie!
Quick, go, go!
RAYMOND: I'm gonna batter your tan in.
Aye, run!
Run!
Over here.
Where now?
Chelsea Barracks?
Thank you very much.
I can manage very well on my own from here.
You've done your bit.
My bit?
Sorry about the money.
It's not something my family think about.
(SCOFFS)
Nice for some.
Mine think about it all the time.
Comes with working for a living.
- They're street traders.
- But not deserters.
It's called Absent Without Leave, Lieutenant.
AWOL.
Same thing, isn't it?
It will be if I don't get on parade
at 8:00 tomorrow morning.
Why?
What will they do to you?
A lot.
Court Martial.
Colchester Prison.
That's if they don't shoot me.
But they'll have to catch me first.
I don't understand. Where will you go?
Paris. Canada.
Somewhere I have choices.
Battersea first. Someone I've got to see.
Does she know about the AWOL...
- Your friend?
- My mum? No.
And I'm gonna keep it that way.
(CAR HONKS)
(GASPS)
- (CAR HONKING)
- Taxi.
(CHEERING)
You won't get a taxi tonight, love.
But I can't walk to Chelsea.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
JACK: Lizzy, this way.
A tugboat?
Quicker than a cab if you can get one.
Hurry up.
It's two bob.
Each.
(BELL RINGING)
How's it all gone for you, ducks?
My feet have barely touched the ground.
Knee tremblers all the way,
these busy nights.
First it was the conga at the Ritz.
- I get you.
- Then the bus with this naval officer.
- The bus?
- Between the Ritz and Trafalgar Square.
- He had his money's worth.
- But now I'm rather late.
Mother will be so cross.
She's got high expectations,
that mother of yours.
Hmm, yes.
- Right. Here we go. Here we are.
- Mind your step.
Ah.
OFFICER: Well, hello!
- Can I help?
- You certainly can.
What's the password?
God save the King.
Hurry along girls.
- God save the King.
- Fresh meat.
- Oi.
Watch your mouth. God save the King.
P2, stick with me.
- Evening.
- Hello, you.
- Hello, officer.
- Watch your hands.
One at a time. One at a time.
(TUGBOAT CHUGGING)
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING)
Look at the poor sods.
Still carrying on and keeping calm.
Still making the best of it.
- That's the spirit.
- It got us through the war.
Hmm, look at it. It's a ruin.
Would have thought 58 nights
freezing my arse off in that bloody cockpit
would have entitled me
to something more than this.
Yes, absolutely.
This belongs to your lot.
Nothing for me here.
Except your mum.
You do listen.
Why?
It was a bad night.
We were coming back
from killing people in Berlin.
One engine was dead.
We only got 600 feet.
Caught flak, bad.
Bang.
Bloody mayhem.
Plane was a mess.
Holes I could see stars through.
Smoke everywhere.
And I was climbing up
through it to my mate...
Charlie.
I got to him and he was...
All wet.
Go on.
I held his hand all the way back.
He talked and talked.
About what?
Bollocks, mostly.
He was off his head with the pain,
morphine I gave him.
By the time we got back,
his hand was cold as ice.
Anyway... (CLEARS THROAT)
When I got back, I went to see the...
Station Commander,
good old Winco Glossop.
And I asked ever so politely
to be stood down for a bit.
He takes my stripes,
stamps "low moral fibre" over my pay-book,
sends me straight back
out to fight the Japs.
Who says the RAF
hasn't got a sense of humour, eh?
(SIGHS)
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
Wait.
It'll keep till morning.
The condemned men had one last drink
before they died.
A drink.
A bloody good drink.
Nothing else for it.
You know,
you're not such a bad chap, really.
Same goes for you.
JACK: Wait a minute.
Red caps.
They'll want to see my papers.
Are you sure about this?
No. I'll meet you inside.
- By the band.
- Be careful.
QUEEN ELIZABETH: I distinctly asked
to be kept informed.
- AIDE: You two, at your posts!
- Yes, sir.
(CLOCK RINGING)
QUEEN ELIZABETH:
They should've been home long ago.
- We'll have to send out a search party.
- No need to panic, woman.
As you say,
we have reliable people looking after them.
(SCOFFS) So where are they?
They weren't ready. I knew it.
One little whiff of
freedom and they're gone.
Lillibet will bring them through.
She's responsible. She knows her duty.
She knows how a princess
should conduct herself.
I hope so.
(LAUGHING)
I say,
Lord Stan, isn't it marvellous?
If you don't mind my saying so, ma'am,
it's time you were leaving.
Oh, just another minute, Lord Stan.
It's so lovely.
- I don't know. I'm not so sure it's a good idea.
- Care to dance?
- Just one dance.
- Hang on!
Who let you in, spiv?
Now, listen. I have to take the lady home.
I promised.
Boys, boys, boys, can't we talk about this?
Look, how are you boys doing for Scotch?
Nylons?
Bananas?
Let's go in here and we'll discuss it.
Say a bunch each?
- Oi!
- (DOOR LOCKS)
♪ God save our gracious King
♪ Long live our noble King
♪ God save the King
♪ Send him vic... ♪
Evening, chaps.
Incognito.
Security is dreadful here.
- Absolutely appalling.
- Hm.
Carry on.
Hmm?
Oi, airman.
What are you doing here, son?
RED CAP: I said oi!
Your coat, miss?
You look that side, I'll look this side.
All right.
You look lovely.
- She's mine. (LAUGHS)
- Hello.
- BARKEEP: Can I get you anything else, sir?
- Don't fancy a dance, do you?
Are you a lady of the night?
I could be anything
you want me to be, Captain.
Oh, no, I'm all right, thank you.
- You're quite sure?
- Oh, no, no.
- Two, please.
- Coming up.
I saw her first, Pulteney. She's mine.
- Let go of me.
- You're outranked, Lieutenant.
Oh, well, I outrank both of you...
Enormously.
MARGARET: Ow! No! Ow!
Please, get off!
MARGARET: Let go!
I order you... Ow!
Jack. Jack!
There, over there!
- MARGARET: It really hurts.
- OFFICER: Let her go.
- Help!
- I saw her first.
Ow!
(GRUNTS)
Thank you.
- Margaret.
- Lillibet.
Thank God you're here.
It was all getting a bit fraught,
I must say.
Are you all right?
I've had the most remarkable night.
So I see.
Come on, Lillibet. This is what we wanted!
The Lindy Hop. Remember?
(LAUGHING)
And round.
Good.
Then like that.
(LAUGHING)
Woo!
Here's to you, fine sir.
Jack.
(LAUGHS)
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me, sir.
(GRUNTING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Stop that.
I said stop that at once!
Let go of him.
And who are you?
The Princess Elizabeth.
- (GASPS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
Let go of my friend, please.
Your friend, ma'am?
Yes. I'd like to think
he was my friend still.
Princess.
Yes.
Margaret, we need to go.
Please come with us.
(SIGHS)
Airman, show some respect
for your princesses.
(GRUNTS)
Attention!
Are you gonna command me?
Ask you.
MARGARET: Marvellous party.
Thank you all so very much for bothering.
- Ma'am.
Princess Elizabeth,
thank God we found you, ma'am.
They'll be going doo-lally at the palace.
Go there, tell the King and Queen
that everything is under control.
They'll have us shot, ma'am.
We aren't letting you out of our sight
for a second,
not this time.
Pryce,
you may be a captain,
but I'm a princess.
And where is your cap?
I will not be seen
with an officer out of uniform.
(GULPS)
Hmm.
MARGARET: (HICCUPS) Lillibet.
Margaret.
Bloody princess.
Just my sodding luck.
You said you were going to see your mum.
Can we come with you?
I can't take her back like this.
(THUNDER ROLLING)
ELIZABETH: Jack.
- Jack!
- (MARGARET GROANING)
- I'm absolutely clapped out.
- Margaret.
PRYCE: We must get them
back to the palace immediately.
- Watch out, man.
- Taxi!
Jack.
Jack, let me explain.
The situation was... Complicated.
You lied to me all night long,
because you're a princess and you think
you can get away with whatever you like.
On the contrary.
- So what do I call you?
- (MOANS)
- Your Highness?
- Lizzy.
Your Majesty?
- Lizzy is fine.
- No. No, it's not. Not any more.
You made a first-class prat out of me.
Well, I had to.
I've never so much as made
a cup of blooming tea for myself.
Never been out on my own.
Not once, not properly.
Even in the ATS, I had to sit between
chaperones and come home for dinner
while the rest of them ate compo rations.
But tonight nobody gave a damn who I was.
And if it wasn't for Margaret running off,
I never would have had
the opportunity to be just...
(SIGHS)
Ordinary.
On the most extraordinary night of my life.
Just so you know,
my mum's right out of red carpet.
PRYCE: Ma'am?
Come along, Burridge.
- Ma'am.
- Yes, keep up with them.
PRYCE: Ma'am, it really would be
rather more comfortable in this taxi.
Ma'am?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Cheers, Jack.
Isn't it a bit early?
She's a costermonger.
She sells fruit and veg.
- Where am I?
- Who's there?
- All right, Mum?
- Jack?
What the devil are you doing here?
(SIGHS)
I'm awfully glad to meet you.
We both are.
- (GROANS)
- (CLATTERING)
JACK: You all right?
Ooh. Oh, Hello.
Mags. I appear to be tipsy.
(CHUCKLING) Can't think how.
In you come. Let's get you sorted out.
JOAN: I'm just getting her into the bath.
- Thank you Mrs Hodges.
- Call me Joan.
(TAP RUNNING)
Thank you, Joan.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
JOAN: Take the kettle off the boil, dear.
JACK: I'm borrowing the van, Mum.
Did you hear his speech?
- Yes.
- Poor old boy.
Never wanted the job, did he?
Got on with it, though.
Yes, he did, didn't he?
My sister, who's not used to having a drink,
got into a bit of a fix.
Jack, well, he got her out of it.
Doesn't usually move in your circles.
No. He doesn't care for my type.
He had a bad war.
- Told me.
- Really?
These boys went into the Air Force
with such idealism.
Where'd it all go, I wonder?
At least he's safe, though. Thank the Lord.
He's safe, isn't he?
I mean, turning up
in the middle of the night like this.
But it's not just any old night, is it?
It's VE night.
All sorts of unusual things are happening.
I feel certain an exception will be made.
(DOOR OPENS)
JOAN: Are you feeling
any better now, dear?
- Wake up, man!
- Oh, yes.
- Thank you very much for the bath and...
- (CAR HONKS)
Oh, a taxi!
(LAUGHING)
Stop. Thank you.
We'd just like to thank you very much
for helping us.
Most kind.
We couldn't have done it without you.
Would you mind going back on your own?
- On my own?
- BOTH: On your own?
I'm going with Jack.
Do you think that's a good idea?
We can't go back without you.
You can. I'll be along shortly.
But one princess is better than none.
Buckingham Palace, please.
Come along, Captain. Come along. That's it.
PRYCE: Sorry.
Fun night, don't you think?
Toodle-oo!
(SIGHS)
You will look after yourself,
won't you, Jack?
Yeah.
Bye, Mum.
Coo-ee!
I'm back!
(EXHALING SLOWLY)
You two...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'll deal with you two later.
Now, where the hell have you been?
That's not going to help.
Where have you been, dear?
Everywhere.
And all in all, I must say...
(YAWNING) I've had an
awfully interesting time.
Why don't you sit down
and tell us all about it?
- Oh, yes, do tell, please.
- Mmm.
- I'm rather tired.
- (YELLS) Margaret!
- What?
- Where is your sister?
Yes.
Lillibet.
She's gone off with this fellow she met.
Gone off? With whom?
Jack. Airman.
A nice chap.
- I think she rather likes him.
- And where is she exactly?
(BOTH STOMP FEET)
(BELLS TOLLING)
ELIZABETH: What now?
- I'll drop you off at your place and then...
- You're off.
Something like that.
Why didn't you go with your sister?
I didn't want it to end.
I just wanted...
I don't know.
I thought princesses already had
everything they could possibly want.
But what if the real me
wants not to be her?
That princess.
What if she wants something else?
Like Paris.
Don't look so disapproving,
Great-Great-Grandmama.
(CHUCKLES)
JACK: Little detour.
There's no rush.
I could sit in the Café de Flore all day,
with no schedules, no meetings
and prepared remarks,
drinking excellent hot chocolate
with cream.
You could get a job there.
Got to make ends meet somehow.
Walk down the boulevards under the trees.
Go up the Eiffel Tower...
If it's still there.
(LAUGHS)
Montmartre looks so pretty in pictures,
and the Louvre,
and the Luxembourg Gardens.
On a Sunday afternoon.
Just another girl in the crowd.
Without everyone bowing and curtseying.
- We could go dancing.
- (CHUCKLES)
- I do dance rather well.
- I remember.
And I'd teach you to be better.
Thank you.
All that freedom to breathe.
All that "what if?"
(ENGINE SLOWING)
(SIGHS)
We both know that's not going to happen.
Quite.
(ENGINE REVVS)
After the Ritz, Trafalgar Square.
Then the Curzon Club with this first chap,
the one before Raymond and Stan,
where he gave me this
pink fizzy stuff to drink
that I must say tasted rather strange.
Then Soho.
- Soho?
- An interesting place.
Dead horses, this strange smoke
that everyone was just wild for...
By the way, what's a knocking shop?
(CLEARS THROAT)
MAN: Just stack 'em over there.
Come on.
Papa... Mummy.
Sorry we're late.
This is my friend, Jack Hodges.
He should have breakfast with us.
I don't think that that
would be appropriate.
Well, I do.
We heard your speech, sir.
In a pub.
KING GEORGE: Did you indeed? In a pub?
Presumably everyone was too drunk
to take any notice.
Actually, they liked it.
They liked it very much.
Where did you meet my daughter?
On the number 14 bus.
Really? I've always wanted to go on a bus.
I jumped on the wrong one.
Margaret was on the number nine, you see.
Jack's been wonderful all night.
Really?
In what way wonderful?
I was very lucky to have him
to look after me.
He's a hero, you know.
He flew more than 50 missions over Germany.
Oh, right. How did you get along?
I did the best I could.
You see that badge?
That one?
It indicates Jack's an ace
and has shot down at least five planes.
He thinks I don't know
what that badge means, but I do.
He's a bit of a good 'un underneath.
Lizzy.
(LAUGHS)
I don't see what's so funny.
Jack has to go somewhere now
and I would like a word with him
before he does.
Oh, and I owe him some money.
How much?
Seven pounds, eleven and fourpence, please.
Well, we...
Don't keep much here,
but I'll, er, have a whip-round
amongst the footmen.
So...
You seem to have
brought her home for us safe and sound.
Well done.
- For everything.
- Thank you, sir.
Lillibet...
No one must ever know about this.
You spent last night at the Ritz.
Lillibet.
I'm having luncheon
with the American ambassador.
Foreign affairs. Would you like to join us?
I'd like that.
Oh, good.
Good.
(COUGHS)
(YAWNS)
Sorry.
Could sleep for a week.
By the way,
I don't think the future
belongs to just my lot.
And I don't think you do either.
Right.
Papa should have that money by now.
(LOUDLY) Is it action stations again?
(CHUCKLES) Go back to sleep.
Jack's off.
Mmm. Bye, Jack.
There's no way I'm going to be on parade
in 30 minutes.
I could get Papa to call.
He's rather influential.
- Actually, I could call.
- No.
Thank you,
but I can take care of it myself.
So are you going to go back?
Yes, I am.
Thirty minutes, did you say?
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Whoa! Careful!
Do be quiet.
I've been driving since I was 11.
One of the advantages
of owning half of Scotland.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Second Lieutenant Windsor driving
Airman Hodges on a special assignment.
(LAUGHS)
We had a good night, didn't we?
We shall treasure it always.
(SIGHS)
Goodbye, ma'am.
Goodbye, airman.
Not a bloody word, right?
(ENGINE STARTS)
(CAR HONKS)
AIRMAN: Come on, Jack. We're on parade!