CIA headquarters - Langly, VIRGINIA
Mr. Director, this agent Vivi Delay
In the last 10 years, the Central Intelligence Agency
searched for Wolfgang Brown.
- "Wolf".
As you know, we do not have a positive identification as
wolf looks.
We know that he is a former German nationalists
,
selling radioactive material to terrorists around the world.
Intelligence
confirm that the transaction will be played
next week in Belgrade.
The Vuk man, Albino
will sell a "dirty bomb"
Syrian customers.
We have already sent a team to eliminate
buyers
to secure the bomb and catch Albina.
How can I help you, sir?
- Your goal is Wolf.
We have reason to believe that he would be present.
Find it and eliminate it.
- Yes, sir.
Let them Wednesday, Albina, and you Wolf.
Sir, if I may...
Who is our agent in the field?
Ethan Renner. Veteran.
Do you have work to do.
Customers are neutralized.
Bravo, Ethan. Bravo.
- Come on down.
Cleaning services.
I brought you extra towels.
This cold is killing me.
Do? - Where are you? -
Left a big mess. - Yeah, so...
I tell you I was sick.
No kidding, you have taken the
day due to illness for 32 years.
Here scanner.
- Thank you, Yasmin.
Make sure to put in my room
one bottle of shampoo that I like.
All teams in positions.
ZOEYIN BIRTHDAY
Pardon .
Good job, man.
Zoeyin birthday.
I need a moment to call.
Cell phones are not insured,
Ethan. - Yes, that's my daughter.
You have a booth there,
you have five minutes.
Look at the scan.
Is done
Hi, I'm trying to call the
out of there and...
I have no change, if I
borrow some of that money?
No, no. -
I can go back and get back to you. - Never.
Come on.
- Son of a bitch.
Good. This much is true.
I will take a few pennies.
I'll be back at it.
Ooops!WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
Have not we met before?
Remembered to me, are not you?
Karachi!
Yasmin was exposed.
We have to go now, Axel!
Do not anybody move in Albina,
until you see what's in the bag.
Let . - Yes, yes, yes. We met in
Karachi last April, exactly so.
But you're serving cocktails,
if I remember correctly.
Shit. - We have confirmation.
- It's a "dirty bomb."
Boss.
- Break it up.
Bye, baby.
Hello.
- Hi, honey. This is your father.
You have not forgotten, so
that I probably love it.
Of course I love you, Zoey.
This we can prove by becoming
we sing happy birthday. Loud.
I could, baby, but I'm at work...
You can leave a message after the beep
. - What the...
good. Happy birthday to...
happy...
- Come on. They are ready. Cover me!
... You...
Happy birthday, dear Zoey.
Cover  Ethan!
Moving!
Enough.
Put ​​it down.
Put it down.
Now.
Now I add.
I, and the more you chase, you jerk.
I see you've read the report.
's Called glioblastoma.
- Yes.
This is a type of brain cancer
and spread to the lungs.
Does not say how much time is left
.
Three months and five possible.
- Yes.
No Christmas this year.
I'm afraid not.
I advise you to bring things in line.
CIA
Thank you for your service.
3 DAYS OF MURDER
Translated: Bambula
What the...?
Tata, white at the door.
How can I help my friend?
What are you doing in my apartment?
- I do not speak French?
No, I'm American.
I live here.
On which floor?
- No, it means that live here.
You? You're the owner?
I'm glad to finally meet you.
Greet owners.
This is his apartment.
Good day, friend.
This is my wife, Teresa.
My son Abatte.
My daughter Sumi is in the kitchen,
pregnant.
These are my cousins.
They came to visit us from Mali,
until they go to stay with my brother in
Saint Dannyiu.
Do you know Saint Danny?
- No. I do not know Saint Danny.
What are you doing in my apartment?
- We had nowhere to go.
We were looking for shelter.
You're lucky to be here.
Evil spirits inhabit the space. - Yes, but...
now I'm back. - And it's good to have you
finally returned.
My name is Zul. - Ethan.
Where all my stuff?
- I also started painting this room.
My wife thinks it's best to have a
cheerful color.
Do you like yellow? I look forward to
work. Not a problem, Ethan.
Actually, Jules, there is a problem.
I'm afraid that nothing can make up to 13
April.
This is only for a month.
We have laws that protect
and squatters during the winter.
Then I guess it is something I
throw. - No, no.
This is not a good idea. Because you go in
jail for breaking the law.
I'll... I'll go to jail?
- Of course!
So, what exactly should I do?
- Wait for Spring.
Like the birds, bees,
girls and boys.
Did you really say that?
Ethan, Ethan!
I need to talk to your father.
Please give me
minutes to finish the conversation.
I'm sorry, Ethan. - Let's talk
private, Jules, in my room.
Assure you,
're not touching your stuff.
I'm not saying that you have touched.
But I think it's time to
bit better.
Because no intrusion is only
so in someone's apartment.
No problem, Ethan.
'll Pack my bag and go.
's Okay, forest. Go.
- Where do you get pregnant with your child?
I do not know, but we'll go
without packaging. - Sit down.
Do not need more to go, Jules, at least...
not when your daughter is born,
but remain under my rules.
- I also believe in rules.
The first rule, no more
to enter this room.
No one, of course. I'll put a higher mark.
- That's right, put more character.
Second rule,
always do what I say, no questions asked.
Yes, of course.
And the third rule, do not be afraid
more room.
Do not like the color? - I do not. - I told the woman that
yellow color is not for men.
No, black is not a color for men.
You also have a daughter?
- Yes.
Like the forest.
Okay, okay, no more yellow.
Who is the most beautiful girl in the world?
Is that you? - Look, Daddy!
This is so cute!
Come on, come on!
Hi, Christine.
- Hi.
Hello.
This is Christine. - Hi, Tina.
I. I'm in town.
I am currently in a meeting, so far
is not a good time to talk.
I do not want to talk.
I want to see.
Yeah, I'm really busy, so...
Unless urgent... -
I need you to look any legal matter
before you leave town.
- Why?
're Getting married you?
- No. Why? You're getting married?
No, not today.
- I'll meet you there.
Well, see you.
Why are we really here, Ethan?
- I wanted to see.
And our daughter,
i also want to see her?
Yes. Yes. I started a fund for college.
How sudden interest?
- Not unexpectedly, Tina.
I try to stay in touch.
I left a message for her birthday.
Yes, and now will have to wait another year
to hear again.
I'm Tina. - You think this is easy for me
? - No, I'm...
I'm sick.
I mean,
dying.
Sorry it took so long,
but I'm afraid I will
must be signed in
French and English.
I do not want to Zoey finds out
at least not immediately.
Enter.
Nice.
Apartment looks better than before.
Do not Look deep into too.
Falling apart.
I know that I was not there for you and Zoey.
I want to see before I leave.
You have to promise me something.
I'll let you see the
on one condition.
Have you stopped?
Are you really stopped working for them?
Am.
- Promise.
.
- I've missed it.
I should have let it go a long time ago.
I'll be fine.
I have a full day planned. First...
No, honey, no.
She's got his own plans.
You'll have to catch up
material. - Hi, honey. - Hi.
Hi, Zoey.
How are you?
Hello, how are you?
- I'm fine, thank you.
Good.
Mama please do not cry. I'm fine.
- No, I just... I'll be home at 8:30.
Okay? - What should we do?
- Well, you say that I cook?
Worth.
Do you want me to call you Daddy
or just Ethan?
I think I like the dad.
Favorite place to go after school?
- We do not have a favorite place.
Flying chairs, remember?
Well, Ethan, we do
do, right?
I know you probably want to
talk and learn about.
So I switched back to Paris.
- I'm not mad at you. OK?
Do not need to explain to me.
It's not a big deal.
Come on, Zoey, go to the coffee shop.
- Hugh, I want you to meet Ethan.
Who?
- I Zoeyin father. - Hi.
I'm so glad I met you,
Ethan... Mr. Renner.
I'm sorry, but sometimes excited
when I see the American cowboy.
Good...
's older than you. - Yes, a senior.
Is there something wrong with that?
When I was growing up, if you...
- Hugh is a lot different than you.
Look, I know that destroy, Zoey.
I...
Look, I... I thought
would want to drive it until you go home?
Wow, this is for me?
- Yes.
It's purple.
- Yes, your favorite color.
Yes, when I was 10 years old.
I will go by subway with your friends.
We'll be home for dinner?
Zoey, you'll be home for dinner?
What is this? - Fresh. - Fresh? Only
the need to save money, right?
Do not forget to dip it in milk.
Milk?
- Only if you plan to fry...
I have not got that far.
Like
man who does not pretend to know
how to be in the kitchen.
- You're talking to the right guy. - To...
I think so.
I tuna dip in milk and...
Thanks to you,
'll fry it for your daughter.
So today Zoeyin lucky day?
What did you say your name?
You can call me Vivi.
Fine I ran into you,
Vivi, but I'm not interested.
Maybe we can talk.
My wife gave me this.
Come on, baby, take a ride.
Good, but my bike
go along with me.
The bike comes with me.
Who exactly are you doing, Vivi?
- I work for the CIA director.
I do not know one from the top.
Serbia was my operation.
I asked Wolf.
Believe that he was at this
day and I think you might have seen him.
A minute.
- I'm ready to bet
when you see him
you'll recognize it.
I want to work for me.
- No way. I already have plans.
Do not you think Zoey
deserves to have a father around
more than a few measly months?
Jesus! It was really close.
In exchange for your cleaning services
I can offer an experimental drug.
Are you interested?
This you can extend life, Ethan.
For information about her?
You know, the results of the tests.
How come no one is
told this before?
'Cause you're not worth the cost of treatment.
Wow, you make me feel so special.
You were not. Now you have.
- Why?
're Sick and dead
man with nothing to lose.
I have access to many things, Ethan,
But you just can not give access
wolf.
I need you to find him and kill
.
So back to redeem his life by killing for you?
A man running inside the
Vuk accountant.
You should start immediately.
I need to fry fish and late.
I can drop
home in time for dinner, Ethan.
Question...
kill or die?
Pretty public place.
- What does it mean?
What does it mean to my muffler...
welcome.
How many people are we talking about?
- Once.
Halo?
- Let me in there.
Bomba!
Screwed us handle the door.
Pretty good for workers.
I told you to be a man, not
five. - Oops.
But I told you to leave the life of a young man
mustache.
How do you think this guy looks like?
Middle-aged. - No way. Tell her how you got
years. - I have...
Try. Worth?
I'm trying to save your life.
Tell her how old you are.
- I'm 32 years old.
Middle-aged.
- Jesus Christ!
So this...
is a young man with a mustache.
- No, that's a goatee.
These are just grown a mustache and hair.
This is a goatee. -
Goat goatee? - This is the mustache, right?
It's a goatee.
- It's just grown hairs.
Looks French. - Since when? - It is
goatee. - From your century, Grandpa?
Look at that, it's a mustache.
- Well, what about the other guys?
Who are these other guys here?
- I do not know.
And you do not mind?
- No.
Because I usually like
know who he kills.
That's why you never got to
high position, my friend.
Goatee, it's your turn.
Looking for an accountant. When returning
in Paris? - I do not know, I swear.
Kill him. - Wait, I
force this guy that sings.
Not know.
Hell.
'll Need a significant raise.
I want to leave something daughters
more than your shitty pensions.
I'll give you 25 but I have to ask you to do your job
6 murders.
I already halfway there.
From all of us have been asked to tighten our belts
.
Do not get me wrong, Viv,
but not my type.
I am everybody's type.
Are you sure this works?
- No.
But I'm sure you will if you do not try,
die in two months.
I want 50 thousand, not 25
I credited you're gonna
merits of the three types above.
I also will not need shelves
life insurance of one million dollars.
Take it or leave it.
- I do.
Like package.
Well, do it.
Breathe, Ethan.
It will have a quick impact on the
you like morphine.
In one way or another
I will make you feel better.
Do not forget to dip the fish.
Promised me my bike.
Zoey!WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
Zoey! Are you okay?
- No, I'm good.
Look at this. It looks horrible.
Do... Your hair?
No, no. Yes, my hair.
I look like I'm blown hair.
- Great.
Really? - Yeah. - Do you think that this
hair can go to the prom?
If you go,
could be brought.
Is this a joke?
- No, what I mean...
Do you think now is the time for jokes?
- I mean, maybe...
Maybe you can fix your hair.
- Fix It? Can I fix this?
No, you can not...
could wash...
could sleep on her
and tomorrow will be...
'll be back to normal, right? Maybe...
You really think so? - Yeah.
What do you say to make dinner?
Hey. No offers are getting ready to
dinner, if you will be delayed three hours.
Listen, I'm sorry, Tina.
But I was...
Do not waste words. I was mad that I
thought I could count on you.
I wanted to ask you pričuva Zoey
when I go to London for work.
- They know.
Really, you need to go.
I can with this deal.
You can not handle
dinner. How will the teenager?
What's up with that I have just solved
great drama, her hair, right?
I have to catch the first flight tomorrow
morning. Call the babysitter.
I was late because I found
doctor who can help me.
What? - Here in Paris
has one specialist
she has an experimental drug that is
ready to test on me.
Experiment?
What exactly does that mean?
So I might be able to implement
a little more time with you and Zoey.
You should have called, Ethan,
because I wanted to kill you.
Can we stop
argue for a moment?
Do not talk of whose murder.
Or mom.
I would like us could
fry tuna.
Tuna? - Yes.
- Tuna. - With all that live?
No way!
'll Fix that door, right?
Yeah, that was a mistake.
- You're not here spent less than 24 hours.
I hope this will be a comfortable couch.
Better than the Polish
beds in Karachi.
Do you need something
to help you fall asleep?
Yes, it will take me far.
're Terrible.
I knew you'd call.
What the hell did you give me?
- Will not stop?
No. I feel dizzy, my head...
I feel dizzy.
Vivi...
Read the instructions.
- Stop! Hallucinating.
Hallucinating.
- Drink vodka. - What?
Vodka. 'll Relax you.
Is everything all right?
Yes.WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
I had a small problem
I find vodka.
You can call me anytime.
Only one hour
differences between Paris and London.
Here. - You can also call me.
- I love you. - Good.
I'll be back in two days late.
- Dad has a list. - A long list.
Washing powder in black lingerie...
- See you, folks! Have fun!
Zoey, come breakfast.
Look at me. Come on. Only once,
up here. Just one.
Good girl. Zoey!
What is it?
- Wow, that's...
What is it? - Jesus...
- So what, Ethan?
This is red.
Vivi? You'll let you?
Sorry. Nobody important, just my boss
Vivi. - She called me in the middle of the night?
We talk a lot, because we
international sale.
Is always somewhere in the day.
Well, now we have 3 days
for murder. - What are you doing?
Name is ringing bells, Ethan.
I'll give you mine.
Maybe we can talk more than once a year.
There. Welcome to this century.
Zoey. Zoey.
Do not you want to ride a bike to school?
Do you think Hugh
like my hair color? - Will. - Really? - Yes.
Do you think he'll really like it?
- If he cares about you, he will.
You do not like?
- No.
No. I want to say that...
Zoey. I really like it.
Great.
I see you do not believe in the usual
gap of 48 hours between the murders.
Length you have only three days.
- I will not get into your car, Vivi.
Not until I get a second opinion
in connection with what god you gave me.
I told you it was kosher.
- No, it's not.
The instructions say, you
the trouble to read it...
If you can hold
low rhythm of the heart,
shit
will act as a hallucinogen.
Well Maintain a low rhythm of the heart.
It's a little difficult given the job
that you made me do.
Get  already in the car.
I need you to locate an accountant Italians
who arranges the book to his old friend
Albina.
How to locate this guy?
With the help of this man.
It's called Mitat Yilmaz.
Rent limousines and serves them Albina.
Meet him and
will take you right to the accountants.
Good.
I, Ethan? - Yes?
- Fuck the bike. Buy a suit.
Why?
- Because I love my boys
are better trained than those that kill.
've Lost my horse, dear?
Comes from "Brokeback Mountain."
Realize that we rent
luxury cars, right? - Yeah.
How did you hear about us?
- Albino said.
Did you also told
that we offer discreet luxury?
Told me not to talk to
servants, but to talk to the boss.
We did not servants, right? We
executive vice-presidents of sales.
He's crazy.
You two feces.
What does this mean?
- Shit. I think.
Listen, asshole,
a small piece of excrement,
for us're nothing.
I'll never meet the boss.
Understand? - Well, I'm sorry. - Yes.
I had a really weird night,
know, two weird night.
Jet leg. I think we have a bad start.
I am guilty. - Yes.
Let's start from the beginning?
You are very rude man
to sit at my table
and you are not invited, sir...?
- Why are names important now?
'Cause I do not want to kill
complete stranger.
Why do you want to kill me, Mitate?
Sitting in my chair.
- I'm just waiting.
Albino sent you? The bastard!
I have always been loyal. Please.
Is this your daughter in the picture?
- How do you dare to watch?
Seat. I also have
beautiful teenage daughter.
Father to father,
Has your daughter ever...
Are you your daughter
ever locked in a room?
A haircut,
painted in red, you know...
put wigs and shit?
- No. Never.
Knew.
I'm in trouble.
Albino did not send you to kill me?
- No.
So, who are you?
Ethan. Come on.
I'll talk to this man in the bathroom.
I do not want to be disturbed.
Yes . Rule number two:
We do as you say.
Right. Rule number two.
- He's a bad guy? - Something like that.
And you're a good guy?
You are a professional? Why does
've never seen Paris?
I was away on business,
five years.
What is so important that he
daughter so long?
I've never been good at keeping
balance between work and family.
You know, when I go home, this life
murder, etc.... all that disappears.
I brought the wrong decision when I left.
Every day take their girls to school
and dinner with my family.
This is the key.
Good for you, Mitat.
Do not miss dinner tonight.
When  accountant arrives in Paris?
Please remind me, who is he?
Halo?
- Hello, this is Mrs. Dryscal.
I would like to talk with Zoeyinim father.
I Zoeyin father.
Is she okay?
Zoey is good, but we have to meet
.
We need to talk about Zoeyinom behavior.
I can get right now.
- Well, hurry up.
Go to school.
As I said Zoey,
studies have shown
that aggression increases
because of the violent display of popular culture.
Zoeyina her mother
raised to be a pacifist.
Hitting friends in person
hardly a passive response.
Open hand or clenched fist?
What's the difference?
From my experience, anger, frustration
insults.
All they require...
All they require different responses.
Mr. Renner,
is extremely important that you send your daughter
clear message that no matter
with which one has to face in life
violence is not an acceptable answer.
I'll try.
If it was not so weird,
it would be really embarrassing, Ethan.
Let me see your hand. - What?
- Let me see your hand, Zoey.
My thumb. - If you're going to hit someone
clenched fist,
Take care not to bend the thumb
it.
've Been gone for five years
and you tell me this.
O God.
You're a Muslim? - I do not.
I told you that this efičin car.
Vivi is a Muslim?
- No.
I'll put it on my phone.
This shit is terrible. - I know.
I like that, who are they?
Did not important at all
why I got in a fight?
Why do not you just listen and try to understand
?
Well, why do not you tell all
.
I have a new friend from Pakistan
i have one Briton
which he constantly called Paki.
Today she put bacon in
boxes, so I hit her in the face.
So, no longer do it, right?
Just a minute, honey. Sounds like the
spare tire dumped in the trunk.
Hey!
I try to talk with her daughter.
I'm sorry, honey.
Where were we?
Hitting girls, right?
- I feel really bad.
Do not  because it is sometimes the only way to stop
bad person.
're Not mad at me?
- No, I'm not mad at you.
I'm proud of you,
stood up for a friend.
Whatever. I'll subway...
I, Ethan...
- Yes?
Maybe you should take something for that cough
. Really gets on my nerves.
Jesus Christ!
Let's see if I can
you activate memory Mitat.
This is my daughter.
Zoey?
- Hi. Sorry about that just now.
It's okay, honey.
And I was also sorry.
Favorite
hanging out after school?
I'll finish a meeting in connection with the sale of
and we'll see you there at 3:30, baby.
Just invited me to hang out
. What do you think?
These girls will constantly roll.
You have to draw the line,
Do not be so soft.
're Right, Mitat.
I was too soft.WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
Where can I find Albinovog accountant?
Hi, Zoey. - It's 3:40, Ethan.
Where are you? - On the bike, baby.
Forget, always late.
I'm going.
No, no, I'm almost there,
real, Zoey. Give me...
Give me 5 minutes. - OK, five minutes
. I have homework.
Children.
I'm sorry I flipped out last time.
This is Hugh,
prom and you come into town.
This is new for both of us. I see.
Favorite place to go after
flying chair, remember?
I remember. - More or less?
- Yes. - Good.
God bicycle.
What happens, Ethan?
Some flu I picked up.
Can not seem to heal.
What if something worse?
Nothing worse.
Remember when we drank hot chocolate
at the beach?
Less.
- I would not mind living there.
Prefer it more than Pittsburgh?
I kidding? - Yes, more than Pittsburgh.
You know, I kept our
home movies in a box.
What do you think
dinner and to watch tonight?
Yes, that would be great.
- Good.
Oops, I forgot.
I have to go to the Customs tonight.
Who? - Carina,
My partner lab.
Together we design science.
I'll sleep with her.
Spend the'll see her tomorrow
go to school? - Yes. Sorry, Ethan, really.
No, it's okay. Just...
Should not
call her parents?
Yes, if you speak Russian.
Her parents only understand Russian.
Call my mom, she'll tell you it's okay.
- No need to call my mom.
We watch a movie tonight?
- Yes, of course.
See you later.
Hi, this is Christine.
Can not occur, so please leave a message.
Tina, I am.
Can you believe we Zoey
and I hung out on the flying chairs
and we drank hot chocolate
and it was her idea?
Thank you for this, Tina.
You're a really great mom.
Hello. I'm glad everything is going well
. But who is this friend?
I've never heard of her or her
Russian parents. Anyway, call me.
Finds himself in TATU GALLERY
SEE YOU IN 7 evening! - Zoe!
Son of a bitch!
Is this your car?
Pardon...
Is this your car? - I do not.
SPIDER
Hey, you know the rule.
Never get involved family.
This is not a business meeting, customs duties this...
more like a visit to his father's father.
's Time for dinner.
- Mitat?
Do you know this man, Mitat?
- Yes, we are working together.
I have not previously seen.
- He's an American.
Okay, come on, join us.
- Thanks for this.
These are Rashel and Sarah. -
I have a serious problem with his daughter Zoey.
've Been gone for 5 years and
did not expect problems?
We can help you.
- That's right, you probably do not,
but your daughter would perhaps
could not tell where to go
16-year-old
could go to a party the night before school.
What does this "spider"?
They are good girls do not go to
entertainment. - What does the "spider"?
"Des Soirees House".
- How do you know? - Thank you.
Sir, forget it.
- My daughter is in there.
I said forget it.
You will not get into. You did not hear?
Zoey. You want to dance? - Yes.
Bring it.
Zoey!
Stop, please... please.
Busy, guys.
Make a U-turn,
continue.
Stop, please.
Busy, boss.
- Ethan!
Ethan!WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
Ethan ! Please!
- What are you doing?
Come on, Zoe, come on.
I got you, babe.
What are you doing here?
A better question, Zoey,
what did you do last night?
This is so embarrassing...
They will not let me over there.
Why would you want
to return to such a place?
'Cause I love to be there with my friends
. - Your friends?
Do you remember at all what happened?
In the bathroom?
Zoey! - What is it? - In the bathroom,
Do you remember what happened?
Carina and I broke up a trial test.
OK?
No, you did not. - Yes, we are.
So we decided to hang out with some friends
.
I have to catch the metro,
I'll be late for school. - You will go by subway. - What?
're Not going to school today.
Not like that.
'll Put on it and go home.
I'll talk to you.
Exactly how to get home?
- Riding this bike.
I think you will not be able, Ethan.
-'ll Climb on the bike
I'll follow your every step along the way
. - You will.
Stop talking and get on the bike.
I thought that's what you want to do
, Ethan, talk!
Get on the bike.
- Or what? - Now!
I do not even know
ride a bike, right?
What the child does not know how to drive a bike?
The kind of child who never
did not have a father to teach him.
Damn. This is the straightest
place, let's try here.
God, you had to buy the most?
Not the greatest bike, Zoey,
it is a female bike.
So, I chose him because
had a great tie. Is not it?
No.
I can explain a great tie. I understand. You know...
There are too many people.
Can we go to a lonely place?
God.
- There are too many people.
But purple is.
Purple is. Climb. -
How to come up? - Just climb.
Wow, we did it.
We're halfway there. Go.
Give yourself time to
pushing away, okay? Below. OK?
Zoey, it's okay. Are you okay?
Right.
- Slowly, please.
Well, I got you. Now alone...
know how to pedal.
I'm here. - Very high.
Do not go. I'll...
Why did you leave us, Ethan?
Why did you leave me and my mom?
I travel, baby,
and your mother and me... - What?
There is no easy...
There is no good answer, honey.
Do you have a family?
- No, honey, I do not. Come on.
Do you have another family?
Is that it? - I do not.
Do you have another beautiful daughter
somewhere? - No, it's not...
You saw me and did not want me?
- No, honey...
Do not you love me?
-... It's not that.
Why is it so
should go back?
Look! - What was long gone,
I tend to be back.
Okay, okay, okay.
That's all. No
nothing to do with you.
Would you still cared about me
I was doing terrible things? - Of course.
Sure.
Full  lie.
All the time about everything.
Even when I'm forced to.
I do not know why.
Sometimes it's easier than telling the truth
.
This girl I've gone to school
not the one messing friend
Pakistani, hitting on the Hugh.
's Okay, he prefers football.
- Yes. - Hugh!
It's so nice, thank you.
Hold on, I'll be right back.
Ethan, do not say anything weird.
Are you the raw entertainment, Hugh?
- What?
Are you the raw fun?
- Not at all, Mr. Zu.
I am an athlete. Forward.
By the way, the last game I
scored two goals.
Do hammer?
- Yes, I definitely do.
No! So, I think...
field.
Yeah... - only on the field, yes.
- Football? - Yes.
I do not like it. I'm from Pittsburgh.
We play real football.
Yeah, football.
- No.
True football.
Good.
Fin bike.
- Do you like your bike? - Yes.
The only way you like it.
I will come back home late, Ethan.
Where are you two going?
- At school.
Great, I'm going in that direction.
- No, you're not.
I could.
I'm going to the market.
Hello, I'm... OK.
See you later, Mr. Zou.
I do not like to be called that.
- I do not like it Hugh?
I am in the sales department, honey.
It's my job to read people.
You know, fathers
many of my friends are working in sales, Ethan,
and none of them dress like you
. - What do you mean?
I say wear suits.
To wear when they go to work.
Hey, I love you!
Did not I help you?
- You know the drill.
Bookkeeper disappeared.
I need you to tell me where he is now.
I ratted him yesterday.
- I know you did.
And now you're back.
I thought you were a pro.
I suddenly became a single father.
Complicated.
Is it my fault that your daughter is
out of control
and it affects your work and reasoning
?
're Right, Mitate.
Affect my judgment
because you're supposed to be dead a long time ago.
My wife had to work late.
I have to pick up the daughter of a half 5
I can not promise anything,
but I'll try.
Open.
I can bypass your rearview mirror.
Well, asshole.
Mom! - Stop immediately.
And!
Ethan! Ethan!
It briefcase has
Identification Number Bank
Albinovim associated with the account.
Do not you? - Yes.
Do not open. Brava has
explosive trigger.
I have the code for the briefcase.
Give me the code for the trigger, Guido.
But once you have them,
're going to kill me.
No, but I swear to God
I'd really bother
if you force me to count to 3
- No. - One. - I do not.
Two... - I do not. No.
Zoey? - Ethan, listen,
I was thinking about tonight.
Honey, I'll be home in time for dinner.
OK? I promise. Can...
Can I call you back? -
I want to make dinner for Hugh.
Only the two of you, as...
Romantic dinner?
- Sort of.
I want to make a real spaghetti sauce,
I do not know what else goes
except tomatoes.
I can not find mommy,
and I need your help.
Just a minute, honey.
Guido, are you a true Italian?
What? - I mean, are you a real
Italian, are you born there?
Yes, Catania, Sicily.
- Do you have a recipe for the sauce?
Sauce?
- Yes, the sauce. Do you know? Sauce.
Is that code?
No, not code. You just said you're a real
Italian, is not it? - Yes.
Do? You have to know a little bit about
spaghetti sauce.
Spaghetti Sauce!
- Red or white?
Red or white? - Red,
vegetarian, not too spicy.
Vegetarian, not too spicy.
- Good. I know what to tell her.
Honey, it happens that I
meeting with real Italians.
His mom has a great recipe.
He ​​wants to give it to you. His name is Guido.
Why do not you say "hello" to my daughter?
Hello. I'm a Guido. - Hello,
Guido. It will only take a second.
No, no! Please subtract
me as much time as you want.
No, no, no.
This is my favorite sauce
moms, reducing the sauce.
You will need tomatoes, capers
and garlic. She always uses
tomatoes from your garden.
Your mother has a garden?
This is so cool.
Yes, she worked her entire life
so I could go to school.
Now I'm the only one left
to take care of her.
What else , Guido?WWW.SUBTITRARI.PRO
Heat the olive oil, crushed garlic
.
I peel tomatoes.
After 10 minutes, no more,
add capers and parsley.
A mother's secret is a glass of red wine
teaspoon of sugar.
The Guido is a real mama's boy, huh?
I think it's sweet that
loves his mother. Thank you, Ethan.
Remember, do not come home too soon.
- Good.
No, wait!
Please call again.
I want to give her mother's
favorite recipe for cannoli.
Do you watch the clock?
Where is one?
Where the three?
It's two hours.
You're letting this guy for 2 hours.
Guido, remind me where will you go after
and this small release.
I'll be back home to live with my mom.
Late.
'm In the middle of training.
Yes, I do.
The job is done.
Not having any fun.
- Not really. - Sit down.
Champagne?
- No.
You're the only American who is
a good time in Paris, right?
Who does not love Paris? Now that we have
Albina we left without a cent
will come running back to Paris with his tail between his legs
leading us right to the Wolf.
When.
Soon.
Do not you like to go.
- What's wrong with the way I dress?
I saw you, for a start, Ethan.
I would have killed to
acting like a good spy
to try might disguise.
Like Albina. It looks good.
Also limp.
Do you want that to try?
What is your size, baby,
42 long?
Yes.
- Good. Strip.
What's going on?
- Baby. - The baby?
You let that guy go, right?
Did not it hurt?
No, keep it.
It's yours now.
God.
- Not your first time, after all.
Actually, it is.
- What about your daughter?
I was not present.
I've been away,
in Africa to be exact.
Good you were?
I do not remember.
Coming baby!
A girl.
Before the baby for the first time
leave the house,
is our custom to give
family blessing.
Quit? - Yes.
We keep our word given to you. - What?
Word? What word? I mean, just...
Brought Chinese food, right?
I have a 100 fortune cookies.
's Okay.
All is as it should be.
I think you have to go
immediately after child birth.
There is plenty of room for everyone.
- May be too much space.
My wife wants a smaller apartment,
out of town. Without yet.
Just me and the kids.
All was fine until we are together.
Sumi wants to call baby Ethan.
This is a boy's name.
- No.
This is the name of a great man who
We did not shoot when he could.
A instead gave us a home.
Carefully selected.
The name is perfect.
Hey, how'd it go? - Hugh me
invited to the prom.
Good. Dinner was a success.
Wow, you look great.
Bought it for me today?
- No.
Coming to the pre-prom
tomorrow? - Well, if you wanna call me.
Organized on the roof Hughovog father.
You know Hugh comes from a
refined family. - Yes.
Do not forget that through your veins flows the blood of
"Stelersa".
Hugh was sent to a special school
to learn dancing when she was 8 years old.
I? - It means that
probably a very good dancer.
I?
- I do not know that dance, Ethan.
No. - Come on. - I will not dance.
- Stand on my feet.
Too old for that. - You
too. Now hold on to my feet.
I'll teach you to dance to your favorite song
your mother. - Good.
And back.
Pretty easy, is not it? -
Not so bad. - Now we come down to the feet.
Can you wear that suit for me tomorrow?
Course.
Mom.
Honey.
You coughed.
Not since I got back. - You're right.
Did you tell her?
- No.
You'll have to.
- I know.
Just tell her you love her.
- She knows that.
I need to hear from you.
Of course I love her. I love the
as I love you.
Good morning.
- God.
You're on the couch. - No, Tina,
I'm not on the couch. What's wrong with that?
What happens when you leave?
Do?
- Albino staying at the Grand Hotel.
Good.
Hey. I will not go anywhere.
Halo? - You noticed me. -
I'd be blind to not notice it.
Do not do anything stupid, Mitate.
Your daughter tonight and expect home.
The  and your beautiful wife.
Who are you talking to?
Come on, pick it up!
Come on!
Come on, faster!
Did we lose him?
I know this guy.
Never give up.
Why do not you kill me already?
You're a father who knows how things
.
Watch out!
's Okay.
I've seen him this way.
Sick.
What are you doing?
Just kill him!
Will not be long, dear.
Kill him, damn it!
Just kill him!
Welcome back.
Again you let your
Vuk slip away.
Where am I?
- Safe...
Today I got the results back from the lab
, Ethan.
I was very curious.
And it turns out that...
Seems to treat
has a positive effect on you.
I do not want to spend the rest of life
killing for you, Vivi.
're Almost finished the job, Ethan.
Kill the Wolf.
I'll need a new suit.
Heard him.
A change of plans.
We leave tonight.
Take me home to my partner.
It will help me to leave Paris.
Mama, do not destroy the night.
- Why do not you try this? - I will.
Look, at least try them.
- I will not!
Just smile and have fun.
Why? I hate these shoes.
I look like Little Miss Sunshine.
You look great, honey.
- No, not that.
Zu. - Hugh.
- Look great. - Really?
Yes, of course.
Mr. Renner, Ms. Renner,
These are my parents.
Glad to see you again.
Thank you for inviting us. - Not at all.
This is Ethan, Zoyein father.
- Hi. And this is my partner.
I'm so glad I met you.
Yourself.
How are you?
Elated.
Can I take your coat?
- Yes. - Thank you.
Is not it great?
- Yes.
Zoey, do me a favor.
Use your best judgment in terms Hughua tonight.
Cheers.
Doing again!
Yes. There's a problem here.
Why you came back to Paris?
No. I came back for you and Zoey.
It was all a lie. You promised
keep their jobs away from us.
Probably not even sick.
- It's not a lie, Tina.
I do not have time to explain.
The police will be here in 10 minutes.
You used us both!
- I never would have done.
Make sure the street is blocked.
At least have the decency to look at me.
Kill him.
It's just bad luck.
This is incredible.
- Yeah, I know. It's crazy.
I'm sick.
- Come with me.
Do not, please do not go. Come with me
home. - Please stay here.
Zoey!
- Down!
Can you hear me? I'll send you down.
Dead.
Shit.
Do not.
- Never give up!
It.
I got it.
O, my God.
Am I in hell?
- So that resembles you, Ethan.
I'm not surprised.
Finish it.
- What?
Jesus Christ.
Promise. Are you really
stopped working for them?
Ethan! - It was all a lie! - Ethan!
Promise me you'll never tell a lie.
Have you really stopped working for them
? Promise me. - Stop it.
I think not.
My wife wants me to stop it.
Can I talk to her? - No,
down on the beach, throwing stones.
What? - A real break
each other now.
At least I'm not firing stones.
Is everything all right?
Yes, it was good.
There were good days and bad days.
She said some things,
I said some things.
There were tears, but the week we spent
was really worth it.
Hello. These are a
gifts from me and...
package left at home.
Hear that your car is still working.
Will you come back?
I love you, Tina.
If you can say one word
you change your mind,
would you give me that chance?
I have done a lot of mistakes in my life, Tina.
I was a terrible husband. I was doing...
I was doing things that can not be explained by
. I'll spend the rest of my life,
no matter how much I have left,
by going to miss you.
I just want to spend as much time
be with his daughter and wife.
What is it?
- What?
What would that word
made me change my mind?
Christmas.
These are the two words, Ethan.
- Hi, Mommy. - Hey, baby.
I'm so glad you came!
Come on, let's go inside. Tata
we will make hot chocolate.
Go.
Is Dad a tough guy?
Worked some things.
Do you think Dad will stay?
- How it can, honey.
A lot of loves.
Merry Christmas, baby!