Based on a true story.
Enmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay became the
first climbers to summit of Everest.
Over the next 40 years. only professional
climbers attempted the same feat.
One in four died
New Zealander, Rob Hall pioneered the concept of
commercial guiding on Everest for amateur climbers.
Over the next four years, his team, Adventure Consultants,
successfully led 19 clients to the summit
without a single fatality.
Other commercial operators follow Rob Hall's lead,
including Scott Fischer's Mountain Madness.
More than 20 expeditions compete to summit
Everest in the same two week window.
Please listen up.
Guys.
We got 2000 feet (ft),
600 vertical metres (m)
to Camp 4.
Let's rope all the way,
so I know you can make it.
Alright, once we get to the
Yellow band, we're going to regroup.
Put on the mask,
turn on the gas.
Make sense?
$325 a bottle,
- for oxygen.
(6 weeks ago...)
- It's daylight robbery.
Yeah. Well, he's cornered
the market, he's got it
He reckon there's going to be
20 teams at Base camp this season.
20 teams?
I mean with all the
Sherpas and porters
it's going to be
squeeze up there.
Lets...
scrum on the ropes right there.
What is this?
It's Helen's.
It's a little decoration
for the mess in.
- Hey, you can wear them on your head, y'hear.
- I'll have it, thank you.
Okay, I got some news.
- We got Krakauer.
- Huh?
Oh, yeah!
- You stole him from Scott Fischer.
- No, he made his own mind.
Good job, Rob.
How much is he paying you, Rob?
Well, he's...
only paying for his airfare.
but we got 5000 words
in the magazine and our picture
in the front cover.  Huh.
That makes it all worthwhile.
Right there.
Or if you get him to the top.
If... If...
How can you say that to me?
- There you go.
- I got you.
You alright? Thanks, Guy.
Cheers, mate.
- Hey.
- Hi, Rob.
- Good to see you.
- Oh, yeah. How are you?
- I am good. Oh, look at you.
- I know.
- Big.
- Here you go.
You good?
- Yeh, you know.
- Okay.
Just going to miss you.
Let's go, Guy.
Just-Just go careful, alright?
- It's just...
- Please don't.
Come on, please don't worry.
It's just that doing nothing back here
that's making me worry.
- You're not doing nothing.
- No, but...
What?
It's the waiting for you.
- For him.
- Ha ha.
- Her.
Just, be back for the birth,
Rob Hall.
You try and stop me.
- Okay, I love you.
- Go, or I'll cry.
Go.
KATHMANDU, NEPAL
March 30th 1996
Here.
- That all you got.
- Yeah. That's it.
I think we're over here.
Hey...
What work outfit you guys with?
- Adventure Consultants.
- Uh, good, me too.
I'm Beck.
Beck Weathers.
Doug Hansen.
- Jon Krakauer.
- How're you doing?
- Okay.
- Are you...
Krakauer from Outside magazine.
- Yeah.
- Really?
What're you doing?
Writing or climbing or what?
A little bit of both.
Well. I'll let you know
how the Summit goes, okay?
- No need, I'll be there.
- We'll see.
What do you do when
you're not climbing, Doug?
- What? Work?
- Yeah.
Uh, different things.
Carpenter. Mailman.
- Carpenter. Mailman.
- Yep.
- Seriously, you deliver the mail?
- Yep, I deliver the mail.
Mailman on Everest?
- Hope so.
- Ha ha. I like that.
Mailman on Everest.
There we go.
- Beck.
- Yeah.
You know, he made it to the
South Summit on Everest last year.
- Who? Doug did?
- Yeah.
- That's pretty hot for a mailman.
- Yep
Brown's Peak,
McKinley.
I never made it up to
the top of McKinley myself.
I know.
- How did you know that?
- 89', right?
Ohhh.
You done your research.
That's what we do.
GARUDA HOTEL
You, my friends, are following
in some very famous footsteps.
A histroy made famous
by George Everest,
George Mallory, Tenzing Norgay,
Edmund Hillary...
- And Rob Hall.
- lege...
- Yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
legend... lege...
legends, all of them.
- Ha-ha-ha...
- Eh ha ha...
That's right.
For those of you who dare
face the dreams,
Adventure Consultants offer something
beyond the power of words to describe.
And why don't we
describe it in the brochure.
Because it's mostly just pain.
- Yes.
- Ain't that the truth.
And the odd,
if you don't mind, Mike.
And the odd missing toe.
There we go.
- Oh.
- Ooo.
To put it simply, guys.
Human beings
simply aren't built to function
at the cruising altitude of a 747.
Okay, once we get above here,
above the South Col.
Our bodies will be literally dying
and I mean literally dying.
It's not called the Death Zone
for nothing, guys.
So, the game is,
can we get you up to the top
and down to the bottom
before that happens.
- You sure can.
- Oh.
Beck Weathers,
ladies and gentlemen.
You might've noticed he's a
bit of a lone star state.
100% Texan right here, people.
100% Texan.
You met Mike Groom.
I like to introduce you to Andy Harris.
- Or Harold.
Harold had got out of Queenstown.
Taranaki actually,
originally Canada.
Helen and the rest of the team are
already on their way up to Base Camp.
They're setting it up
when we get there.
- Today is March 30th, people.
- Yeah.
I plan on going to
the Summit, May 10th.
It's been a lucky day for me
in Adventure Consultants,
and the weather is usually
pretty stable around then.
So that means,
We have 40 days,
to train your bodies and your minds
to go for it.
Now. I know there is a lot of
mountaineering experience in this room
you wouldn't be here without it.
- Stu, K2, Broad Peak.
- Nice.
John Taske,
1192m of Mount Kosciuszko.
- Ha ha ha...
- Eh ha ha...
- And Yasuko Namba.
- Oh.
- 6 of the 7 Summits.
- Yeah.
- An amazing woman.
- There you go.
- Let's make it 7.
- Thank you.
But, Everest though, is another beast.
Another beast altogether.
That's why you're here.
Isn't that right, Dougy.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
So, listen.
Tonight, that's it for me.
Eat, drink, be merry.
Tomorrow we trek.
Alright, let's go.
Alright, folks, hang on.
Okay.
That's it.
Here we go, colonel
Alright, everybody, earbuds.
Take your seats.
Buckle in, everyone.
Thanks, bud.
Murdock, here we go.
Okay, everybody.
Hey, can you believe it.
Lukla : 9,383 ft
2,860 m
Take it easy.
Nice work.
- Ready.
- Let's go.
You lead the way.
- Are you alright?
- Come on, man.
NAMCHE BAZAAR : 12,303 ft
3,750 m
Guys, man want to see
your climbing permits.
Need to see all
Thank you very much.
We'll see you on the way back.
- All good?
- Yeah, yeah. Yeah, you?
- Yeah.
- Hey...
Thanks, Rob.
- Thanks for what?
- You know, the discount.
You're working 3 jobs, Doug.
It's the least I can do, right?
I know you didn't have to do it.
I appreciate it.
Let's just get you
to the top this time.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
How're you feeling, Beck?
About a third to midland.
Come on, buddy.
You can do it.
Thought I was going to
acclimatize faster than this.
Uh.
You'll be alright.
Go on, critters
Woo.
- Well.
- Yeah.
How close did you get?
I got really close,
but...
got a lateness ,
pretty shot anyways, so...
I think I would have
made a run for it.
- Everyday I wake up thinking that.
- Then why didn't you do it?
Because I turned him around.
1:15 (PM) of the South Summit.
That condition, we weren't going to
make that 2 PM turn around.
It's all good more to make
the top, Beck.
but you pay me
to bring you down safely.
Remember that.
Okay.
What's eating him?
One of those Sherpas is Tenzing.
He had an accident.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah.
... on the icefall.
It's not good,
had to bring him down.
TENGOCHE MONASTERY : 12,687 ft
3,867 m
Blessing at Tengboche Monastery
Namaste.
THE CLIMBERS' MEMORIALS, THOK LA : 16,000 ft
4,877 metres
EVEREST BASE CAMP : 17,600 ft
5,367 metres
Congratulation, you all made it.
Welcome to Base Camp.
It'll be a united nations
here this year.
We've the Allmax teams.
South africans.
And right up here,
in the best spot of all,
we have the Adventure Consultants
Base Camp.
- Hey.
- Hi, Helen.
- Hi, how are you?
- Nice to see you.
- Welcome, nice to see you.
- Thank you.
- Hi, Rob.
- Hey.
- You alright?
- Yeah, yeah, good. You?
- Yeah. You know, we're good.
- Yeah, it looks good.
For those of you that haven't met.
This is Helen Wilton,
Base Camp manager.
She'll be your mom
for the next... few weeks.
Any problems take it to her,
and she'll sort it.
Alright.
Um.
Well, it's very nice to finally
meet you all in person.
Ang Dorjee, come here.
This is Ang Dorjee, everyone.
He's you climbing sirdar,
your lead sherpa.
- Hey, how are you?
- Okay.
- You... You speak English?
- Better than you, Mr. America.
- Bet you climb better than I do, huh?
- Yeah.
Ang summit it 3 times, Beck.
Alright, alright.
I hear you, I hear you.
Alright. Well, there's tea
in the mess tin
when you dumped your sacks.
And...
The comm's tent down the back.
That's the cooking tent
and over there
- is the toilet.
- All good?
It's a little bit drafty,
but just remember that...
When the wind gets
upheave, you got
the same view as
George Everest did.
For those of you who haven't
used crampons before
left and right are mark
you can't get it wrong.
- Alright, so, simple.
- Okay.
First of all, you push it
into the shoe, like this.
Unbelievable.
If it isn't the
mayor of Base Camp.
Scott Fischer,
Mr. Mountain Madness.
In the flesh.
You want a cup?
Sit down, man.
Acclimatize.
Okay. I'm normally a
tea man myself, but...
- Let's give it a go.
- Thank you so much.
Well, it's crazy this year, aye.
I know, man.
Some idiot kiwi goes and
advance Himalaya guide here.
Look what happens.
Yeah. Didn't take you too long
to get in on the act.
Got to make a living, man.
You... went ahead and
fixed the ice post, I see.
Yeah, yeah.
It's pretty messy up there this year.
- Yeah?
- The vasses are pretty big.
Strung 4 or 5 ladders across.
You use good ropes there, did you?
You ready?
Okay.
This is April 7th
about 10:30 am
This is Sandy Hill Pittman reporting
for Nbc Interactive Media
and we are official at
Everest Base Camp.
- She one of yours?
- Oh, yeah.
Someone went and stole my journalist
so I had to get another one.
She's a lot easier on the eye
than Jon Krakauer, that's for sure.
Listen, just to be clear
I didn't steal your journalist.
Hey, man.
It's all good.
- Outside magazine gave me a call...
- Hey.
- They gave me a call...
- Hey!
-  said they wanted...
- It's all good.
they're going to sent
a journalist up the hill
and asked me if
I was interested.
It was his call in the end.
Alright.
Carol Mackenzie, team doctor.
Why don't you kick it off, Carol.
- Hi, everyone.
- Hey, Carol.
Hi, there.
- Hey, sorry.
- No, it's fine.
Um. So...
Rob and Harold and Mike
will tell you all sorts of stuff
about mountaineering.
but, from a medical stand of point,
getting you to the top of Everest
was really about oxygen.
and the lack of it.
To give you the best chance
of summiting,
you need to prepare your bodies
for the thin air up there.
So, over the next month
before the final ascend,
you are going to make
3 partial acclimatizing ascends,
returning here, to Base Camp,
after each one.
The bad news is that each ascend
begins and ends with the icefall.
I'm sorry,
but there's no way around it.
There're millions of tons of glacier ice
continue moving day and night.
Your crevasses so deep they
probably don't even have a bottom.
It is not a place that you want to
get caught hanging out in,
especially when the sun hits it.
So, we're going to be up, nice and early
and through that as soon as possible.
Now, the Sherpas are going ahead and
fixed the ladders across the crevasses
and we've made it
as safe as we possibly can.
But, that is not to say
that it is completely safe.
19 people have died
in that icefall.
- Whoa whoa whoa...
- Hold on.
Steady.
- You alright, Jon?
- You alright?
- I'm good. Okay.
- Alright, steady up.
So, remember,
we're a team,
let's look up for each other.
- Lookout for hypothermia.
(CAMP ONE : 19,500 ft  : 5,944 m)
Things like slur speech
and irrational behaviour.
I've seen hypoxia climbers
ripped off all their clothes
at 8000 m because
they are feeling hot.
You all know about cerebral edema,
the swelling of your brain
to the point of lost of motor
function and eventually death.
And pulmonary edema, which is
your lungs filling with fluid.
till you fatally drown.
The only cure is to get
down the mountain fast.
- Alright. Okay.
- Alright, buddy.
But, it is not all doom
and gloom here, okay?
Myself and the whole AC team are here
to make sure you get up and down safely
and you will acclimatize naturally.
So, why don't we all,
give Carol a nice big thank you.
- Oh, you don't have to give me that.
- It's her first time here.
- Hey.
- Alright.
Nice job.
April 23rd
CAMP TWO : 21,300 ft
6,492 m
- Well done.
- Have a seat.
You want to get on the regulator
or you want to hear that
Can you get hosed.
- Yasuko.
- Beck.
- How're you doing, darling?
- Okay.
- Good?
- Yeah.
- Well done.
- Hang in there.
Help yourself with that.
In a situation like this,
you just want to catch your breath
go right up to 4, you should
start feeling pretty good.
Yeah, I can feel that already.
How did you boys go?
- Instant happiness.
- Hey.
- Amazing.
- Very happy.
- Doug, you okay?
- Huh?
When we get back to base,
I want you to...
get Carol to get
a look at you.
Nah, I'm alright.
I'm okay.
Then... do me a favor,
swinge another oxygen.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- You got enough?
- We got plenty.
Alright.
Get some tea in here.
Just lift your shirt up a bit.
Thank you.
Now, take a deep breath for me.
Just take one of those
in the morning
with a little bit of water
before breakfast.
Okay. thanks.
- Right, Beck. You're up.
- Sorry.
Yeah.
Go for it.
Read it and weep.
Take it easy there.
- Right, you can stop.
- Yeah?
- You're in great shape, Beck.
- I'm in great shape.
- Yeah.
- 6 days a week in the gym
- ought to do it.
- Your wife must have love that.
Yeah, she does.
Oh no.
What's the date today?
- April 25th.
- No.
No.
I need to send a message to my wife.
Can I use your fax?
You might want to look at this one first,
came in for you last night.
Happy Anniversary Beck
- Peach.
Lord.
What?
Can I-Can I use your satphone?
Woo. Well, if this did come in
last night, it is an emergency.
- It's...  25 bucks a minute, Beck.
- Yeah, fine.
- No. This one is on us.
- Seriously.
Thanks.
Rob.
- Beck?
- Peach, it's me.
What happened?
Nothing. Nothing.
I'm fine.
Where-Where are you?
I'm at Base Camp right now.
You're calling me from Everest?
Yeah, it's a satellite phone, honey.
Oh my god.
How much is that costing?
- What's the problem?
- There is no problem, Peach.
I'm sorry, we were
up at Camp 2 and
that's why I didn't send
you a fax yesterday.
Happy anniversary.
Okay.
- Get off.
- Mom.
- How're the kids?
- Fine.
- Hey.
- Peach.
- Get off.
- Bud's here.
Doing his homework
in the morning as per usual.
You want to say hi to him?
Yeah, of course I do.
- Hang on.
- Okay.
- Say hi.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, Bud.
- Hi.
I miss you, buddy.
Oh, and Meg went
on her first date.
- Mom.
- ...last weekend. Well, you did.
- Wow. Really?
- Um-hum.
- Get off.
- Peach.
I missed you, honey.
Mom?
Mom.
Missed the kids...
a lot.
Peach.
Listen, I got to get
the kids to school.
So, I got to run.
Okay.
Yeah.
Go careful.
Bye bye.
Is Dad okay?
Just... he never calls.
He's...
I think he's scared.
? It's going nowhere
on the mantlepiece ?
? Well, do I lie like
a loungeroom lizard ?
Yeah.
Beck.
Come in mate, come on.
- Come on.
- Come on, Beck.
You don't dance.
You don't climb.
Come on, guys.
Beck Weathers.
- Yeah.
- Come on, Beck. Come on.
- Go dance.
- Go go.
? ... take the weather with you ?
? Everywhere you go,
always take the weather,
the weather with you ?
Hey, man.
Breaking into the rations?
Yeah, you want some?
No. I'll...
I'll wait till we summit.
I don't know about that, Neal.
We'll get there.
I'm excited.
Anyway, me and Anatoli are here
to help you, you know.
It's too much competition, Anatoli.
We don't need competition
between people.
This competition, between
every person and this mountain.
The last word always
belongs to the mountain.
LHOTSE FACE : 12,400 ft
7,132 m
- Ang Dorjee.
- Yeah!
Stay there, Beck.
Stay there.
Okay, I'm coming down.
Harold, Mike.
The rope.
This isn't happening, guys.
Let's turn him around.
Get him off the Face,
and back to the Base Camp
Turn around.
Ang Dorjee. Come on,
we're going down.
Okay.
My hands!
Okay, make a fist again.
Just kind of keep clenching
to keep the blood flow.
What's going on, man?
Still waiting for the south Africans.
Taiwanese took forever as well.
Hey, Ian.
You haven't paid for these ladders.
Yeah, yeah.
Your yak fun money is coming.
- You serious man?
- Come on. Get a move on.
- How long you're been waiting him?
- A good 45 minutes.
- Man, it's freezing.
- Yeah.
- Stinging, huh?
- Hey, Rob, we got to get him over!
- We're working on it.
He's freezing, man.
- Are you set?
- Yeah.
- We're sending him over, mate.
- Do it.
Keep going, Beck.
Looking good.
- That's it.
- Now, head up, mate. Head up.
Hold on, Beck!
- Whoaaaa.
- Pull. Pull.
Help. Help!
Help!
Beck, you alright?
Are these ladders
going to take 2.
Yeah. I'll get a rope.
I'll belay you, okay!
- Stay right where you are, mate.
- I can't pull yourself up!
I'm going to
come after you.
Good-Good, Beck.
You're okay.
Untie these,
you got to tie me in.
Come and get me.
- On belay.
- Got it, on belay.
Let's go.
I'm coming after you, Beck.
Here I come, mate.
Nice and easy,
- I can't feel my hands!
- Looking good.
Help me.
- Beck. Beck. Beck.
- Help me!
Stay right where you are, mate.
- Can't pull myself up.
- I'm right here. I'm here.
I can't pull myself up!
I got you.
You okay?
No guarantees to the Summit.
I get it.
I can get killed because
I'm waiting in line.
Like I'm in a freaking Wal-mart.
Not while I paid you $65,000
Now get me off of here.
That's it.
Plant your feet, one at a time.
Alright, thanks for coming by.
(Meeting for guides, organizers)
Look. Base Camp as you know
is chalked up all this year, so...
I think it'll
all benefit us greatly
by coming together like this
and you know,
working out some kind
of plan and schedule.
- What, like some kind of rotor?
- Yes.
On Everest.
Everyone knows Everest is a business
for you, Rob, but are you kidding?
What gives you the right to tell us
when we can climb and when we can't.
I'm not telling you, man.
I'm asking.
If we know when everybody is
planning to summit, for instance...
You know we can avoid the chaos
that happened at the Icefall today.
Adventure Consultants
are aiming for May 10th.
So are we, man.
- Us too.
- May 10th.
Okay, that's bumper to bumper
traffic on the Hillary step.
Yes it is, that's my point.
Look, this is ridiculous.
We summiting when we want.
Alright. And I don't need
your permission to climb the mountain.
Ian, have you seen how
many people are here
- ... at Base Camp this year.
- We're finish here.
- Come on, lads.
- Hey, man.
Ah.
Come in, man.
- Hi.
- Ha ha.
- Have a drink, Rob.
- Yeah, have a drink.
Na zdorovye. (*To health.)
- Nostrovia.  (*Cheers)
- With a word. Yeh.
- Um-hum.
- You're a little crook, huh.
- I know, it's just a little.
- A little touch of the deli belly.
- He means Buddha belly.
What's going on Roberto?
I don't like the look of the
crowds on the ropes.
We ran into some trouble
once we're above Camp 3.
Well. You want to top
on the 10th, yeah?
- Yeah.
- So do I.
What're you saying,
we should team up?
Well, it's an idea, yeah.
Oh, man.
Oh, I don't know, man.
We have different styles, man.
Like...
All due respect,
you're a hand holder.
I mean the best, but...
I just believe that if you can't
get up there yourself
you shouldn't be on
the mountain at all.
You guide your team,
I guide my.
I'm just suggesting that we work
with each other instead of against.
The only way we both summit, mate,
is that we work together.
Particularly fixing the ropes.
It's got to make sense.
Ah.
Why not.
- Oh Yeah.
- Yeah, I see the sense in it.
Okay then.
- Thanks, Scott.
- Alright.
Who's going to lead
when we get up there.
Rob, if I say I want to lead,
could it be done?
- Whoa whoa whoa.
- Okay, hey.
You got to work with Ang Dorjee.
'cause we're working together now.
He's just saying if both of us...
Whoa whoa whoa whoa.
Okay.
Ang Dorjee.
We're all professionals here.
We work together and
we get the job done.
- Yes?
- Alright, yeah.
We're planning of stashing,
what 8 bottles of "O"
over the South Summit.
- Well, I'm not using "O".
- What do you mean?
- You're not using oxygen at all?
- Come on man, you know you want it.
In his health, don't need it.
Yeah, but Anatoli,
you're guiding for Scott this year.
You have people's lives
in your hands. It's a job.
Never used it.
Never will.
Bigger problems if you run out.
Okay.
I'll put some more
bottles of "O" up there.
- You know, that would be good.
- Alright.
Just as long as
you guys are clear.
You work for me you use oxygen,
otherwise you don't work for me.
Hey, you don't have to ask me.
I've been up here before without "O"s, Rob.
I don't need to deal with clients.
- Alright. Next we have the fixed ropes.
- Yeah.
Particularly, above the Lhotse Face.
You let us start
make new fixed rope.
- And Southeast Ridge as well.
- Yes, it does.
Well. My idea is that
we work together
and we fix ropes together,
we share the duties.
- Okay.
- Sounds good.
Alright, you and Lopsang
maybe get together,
talk about who want to
fix what and where, okay?
Ah.
Only essentials.
I'm not going to tell you what to pack,
but be brutal, okay.
1 pound down here
is like 10 up there.
Light and fast.
What, and just like that
you-you killed my summit cappuccino.
Go go go.
Run.
That camera is totally daine.
( May 5th )
Alright, it's going to be a tough week.
But, it's going to be the
best Friday of your lives.
Hey, what-what are we
doing in a boat?
- Summiting!
- Summiting...!
- Now it's up to me, right?
- Yeah, you.
I take 3.
- It's from Jan.
- You can't look at my card.
I knew it was
going to be a girl.
I can't believe it.
It's a girl!
- Yeah!
- That's great.
Alright, good on you.
I know. I knew.
I knew she was.
- Thank you. Thank you, Doug.
- Cheers, mate.
When is she due?
Mid July.
As soon as I get back.
- You can't leave now, buddy.
- Yeah, that's true.
Hey, Rob.
Yeah?
Jan doesn't mind you being here?
Oh oh.
Krakauer's sword is unleashed.
It's okay. I'm...
Jan's a climber, Jon. She gets it.
- Oh yeah?
- She is, Helen.
Now you, Doug.
What about your wife?
Oh, she's been fine with it
ever since we divorced.
- She's been great with everything since then.
- I'm so sorry, buddy.
- Oh, no, don't
- I'm sorry.
No no no.
I asked because
Peach said to me, "If you climb
1 more mountain, I will divorce you."
And you went ahead
and then booked this trip.
- Oh.
- Ow...
No no no. The worst-
The worst part of it is that, I...
I kind of forgot to tell her.
- No.
- Ha ha ha.
I forgot to tell her.
I did.
Alright.
It's all on the table here.
It hurts. It's dangerous.
It...
destroys relationships.
It's costing you all a small fortune.
- Were there any negative aspects?
- Yeah.
Come on, I got to ask the question.
You know I do.
Why?
Because
- Because it's there!
- It's there!
That's why.
Thank you Mr. Mallory.
Come on, guys,
I'm-I'm serious.
- Yasuko.
- Huh?
Why are you climbing Everest?
Uh.
I'm 47 years old.
I have reached
6 of the 7 summits.
So. Of course, now I have to
reach the 7th.
- It's not an answer.
- Oh.
Why...
No, why any summits?
- Well. I...
- Doug.
Why?
- Come on. Tell him about the kids.
- What.
- Tell him about the kids.
- Yeah.
- Oh. I...
- You have kids?
Yeah, I have kids.
But...
I thought I told you their's...
their elementary school back home.
I've been going and talking
to the kids there and they
actual helped me raised some
of the money to come and...
gave me a flag to plant
on the Summit and...
so, I was thinking maybe it's...
they see an...a regular guy can,
you know, follow impossible dreams.
Maybe they will be inspired to
do the same, I guess.
I'm climbing Mount Everest
because I can.
Because, to be able to climb that high and
see that kind of beauty nobody ever sees,
it'll be a crime not to.
Yeh yeh, Dougy.
- There you go.
- I like that.
Hello.
Hey.
Did I wake you?
No.
I did to, you liar.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah yeah, I'm good.
I'm better. I'm better now.
I missed you.
We go for the final ascend tomorrow.
Oh. So, you're...
you summit on Friday?
Yeah.
10th.
- It's your lucky day.
- It is.
How's the weather?
It's good.
Yeah, I think we're going to
get a good window.
- So... It's a girl.
- Oh yeah.
And, did you go to the doctor?
Did you get your scan done?
- Did you see her?
- Yes, we're good.
And?
Come on, what does she look like?
Oh, you know.
Blonde hair, nice smile.
Perfect height-weight ratio,
she's going to be a great climber.
She's there, Rob...
already.
- Wow.
- Me and you.
And a little bear, huh.
And in one day,
you,
me,
and our little Sarah, we'll all
go climbing together. Huh.
Sarah?
Yeah.
What do you think?
- No way.
- Come on.
- No.
- Please, think about it.
- Huh.
- You're still there?
- Of course I'm still here.
I love you.
I love you too.
Sleep well, my love.
Alright.
Bye.
* Everest climbers
Puja blessing ceremony
Take it easy now,
you're going to be okay.
Okay, we're going to get
you down the hill. Alright.
Hey, Neal.
You okay?
Yeah.
Dale, he doesn't look too good.
- I need to take him down.
- Yeah.
You can't get Scott
on the radio?
No.
No, I think he's-he's up ahead.
Best not to stay
too long at the Summit.
It's a long way to go, man.
Head down,
one step at a time.
You got it, boss.
You seen Dale?
Yeah, and he wasn’t
looking too good, but...
Neal seem to have
handle the situation.
Try to use your radio.
- You kidding me.
- No.
Guess it's not working, huh.
I'm going down to Camp 1.
If he's not doing so well,
I'm going to take him down to Base Camp.
and I'll head back up.
- You guys alright?
- Yeah.
He can't be too far
ahead of you, mate.
Yeah.
I'll make it down in half the time.
I'm going to catch him.
Woo.
Cheers, mate.
CAMP TWO : 21,300 ft
6,492 metres
Rob to Guy.
- Rob to Guy. You up there, mate?
(MOUNT PUMORI, 5 MILES WEST OF EVEREST)
- Guy to Rob. I'm here.
Good to hear you, Guy.
Where are you?
Camp 1, Pumori.
Yeah.
There you go,
Listen, I think you're on the
wrong mountain there.
Look, I can't talk and
we got to get out of here.
Alright, mate. Oh, listen.
You take care on the kiddy slope.
I ought to get back
to the real thing.
Hey, don't worry, Rob.
I'll keep an eye on you.
Aye!
Watch out!
Aw!
ROB!
- Rob!
- I got you.
Harold, you okay?
Is everyone okay?
We're okay!
Come here, come here, come here.
Sit. Sit down, sit.
I'm fine.
Look at me.
- Look at me!
- I'm fine, mate.
Look at me, Harold.
Look.
I'm tell you, I'm alright.
- Okay.
- I'm alright.
- Harold.
- Thank you.
Don't do that to me again, aye.
Rob, I'm sorry.
Okay, mate.
I'll get drop back with Frank,
he's struggling, alright?
- Alright.
- Okay.
- Alright. Straight here.
(CAMP THREE : 24,000 ft  : 7,315 m)
Let's get him on the oxygen.
Bravo to Scott Fischer.
Mountain Madness, how do you copy?
Hey, man.
Scott here.
I've been down to Base Camp
and I'm back to Camp 1.
I'm catch you tomorrow.
What? You not going to
rest up a day first, huh?
Scott, you sound a little rough.
Hey, take an extra day.
No way, Jose.
What, miss out on all the fun.
It's a lot of up and down in...
one day even for you, Scott.
You know what they say, man.
It's not the altitude,
it's the attitude.
You sure you're
going to be okay?
- Scott?
- I'll be good.
Just taking a shot of
dexamethasone now.
Just don't push yourself too hard.
Okay?
Over and out.
Rob, I've just been over the Miles
to get a weather update.
It's moving fast.
It's changed course slightly
and it could still go north but
if it doesn't
It's gonna hit sometime
on the 11th, I reckon.
Get some weather forecast, Helen.
The mountain makes it's own weather.
We're keeping an eye on it.
Yeah, sure.
Just, letting you know.
Appreciate it, Helen.
Why we do this to ourselves?
Oh, this is crazy.
You know I never told
Krakauer this.
When he was asking us
why we climb Everest.
When I'm at home...
I just got this big...
black cloud following me.
You know, like a depression.
When I'm out here...
on a mountain,
any mountain,
it's just like it's a cure.
Feel like I'm reborn.
So, you're happy now?
Now I'm starting to wonder.
This is suffering, man.
This is suffering.
Yeah.
Suffer a few more days.
The rest of your life, you'll be the guy
that climb to the top of Everest.
I just hope I get there.
Yeah.
Just hope I get there
and get home.
What do you think, Mike?
Almost pretty good.
A little bit of wind up high.
I mean, if it picks up, we can
always come back down.
- Exactly.
- It's your call, Rob.
Let's get them all going.
CAMP FOUR : 26,085 ft
7,951 m
Hey, Rob!
- You, okay?
- Not good!
I'm hoping it's going to
die down after sun down.
Been doing that.
I don't like this.
We don't go
if it doesn't calm.
- I talk to Scott when he come's here.
- Okay.
Scott!
- Scott!
- Anatoli, here.
Anatoli, where is Rob?
Where are they?
Did he go down?
Where's Rob?
What's Rob's team doing?
Rob will see
if it passes.
If he wait.
- We wait.
- Okay.
Friday 10th May
00:30 AM
Hey, guys.
Come out and take a look.
At least somebody
up there loves us.
Nothing.
Where the storm go?
Exactly.
- That's crazy.
- You ready to saddle up?
Okay, everyone.
We got a window.
We don't know how long
it's going to last.
But we're going to go for it.
Be ready in half an hour.
We have a 2 PM turn around.
Let's climb this thing.
Okay.
So, today's the day, huh?
Yeah.
Now or never.
Oh boy.
The south Africans were
laid out at Camp 3.
They never made it into Camp 4.
Probably got caught up in it.
- Maybe it blew though early.
- Yeah. Well, it hit us all night.
But that was nothing,
absolutely nothing.
So, it's definitely worth a shot.
I'll radio Ed,
tell him you're continuing.
Any messages?
Yeah. Ring Jan, tell her that
we're heading out.
I'll call you, Helen, in 12 hours
when we get to the Summit.
Turn around is 2 PM.
Good luck and
god speed to you all.
Okay. Thanks, Helen.
Bye bye.
I'll see you guys up there.
- Take it easy, Scott.
- Let's do it.
I get a couple of hours of sleep
and I'll be right behind you.
- Yeah, okay.
- See you at the top.
- Have fun, Pittman. Yeah.
- You get some rest, okay.
See you there.
- You got the ropes for the Hillary Step?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Okay.
THE BALCONY : 27,600 ft
8,412 m
04:30 AM
Can we go any faster?
Not a chance we can
go faster here.
It's too difficult.
This could take a while.
We're losing time.
Beck, what's wrong?
I don't know.
I had a operation couple
of years ago on my eyes.
That might be it.
I don't know.
Okay.
Guys, go in front of us.
- Alright, Beck, let's sit you down.
- Okay.
Beck.
Look at me.
I need to send you down
with someone.
- No. I don't want to go down, Rob.
- No, you got to go down.
I don't want to go down.
Okay.
Alright, Beck.
Listen.
You can wait here for half and hour.
Beck, listen to me.
If it gets better by then,
join in the queue and keep going up.
If it doesn't get better, Beck,
- I'm sorry, mate. It's over.
- Okay.
Sherpas are going to go and drop off the
extra oxygen on the south side while they can.
I'm going to send one of them
down for you. Is that clear?
- Yeah?
- Alright.
Okay, mate.
Alright.
God speed.
Sandy, do you want to go down?
What?
No, no way.
Look, Lopsang, I'm going
to make it to the top.
- Do you understand?
- Okay.
- I'm not going back, okay?
THE SOUTH EAST RIDGE
Hey, where are the ropes?
There is no rope.
No rope.
Yeah?
They should have been fixed.
Do you have more
in your pack.
Lopsang has the ropes.
He's not here.
- Harold, no ropes?
- No.
- Harold.
- Neal.
Hey, Rob.
Listen, we got a
problem here, mate.
There's no fixed ropes on the
crevasse to Hillary Step, over.
Where is Ang Dorjee and Lopsang?
Yeah, I got Ang Dorjee here
but there's not sign of Lopsang.
So, me, Neal, Anatoli are going
to set some new ones, over.
- Fine then.
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Let's do it.
- What's going on?
- No fixed rope.
What?
That's it.
1 step at a time, Doug.
Come on, Dougy.
Deep breaths, Dougy.
Come on, mate.
Keep it on. Keep it on.
- Rob.
- Deep breaths, Dougy. Hang on.
Hang on.
You can do this , Dougy.
- I know you can, pal.
- Yeah?
I don't want to see you
back here a third time, mate.
John.
You heading back down?
There's a hold up.
There's no fixed ropes
above the South Summit.
Yeah.
I know, mate.
But we are sorting that
situation out now.
Ran out of juice waiting.
Go.
I'm sorry, Rob.
That's your call, pal.
I don't want to run out
of oxygen up there.
Sorry, Rob.
We've a little bit of a set back.
Lou, Stuart and John Taske
just turned back, just...
just below the South Summit.
- How are the conditions so far?
- Cold and windy.
- Okay, let me know, Rob.
- Okay, Helen. Thanks, bye bye.
I hope we're not looking
at another year
with no clients at the top.
Well, if that ain't going to
move them pretty soon.
They're out of time, aren't they?
Yeah.
And...
What's Jon going to say
about that in his article.
- It's Rob.
(THE HILLARY STEP : 28,740 ft  : 8,760 m)
- Guy.
- We just lost Lou, Stuart and John Taske.
(The Hillary Step : 8,760 metres)
What's going on?
What's the hold up?
Yeah, yeah, mate.
We...
We sent Anatoli and Neal
to the top of the Step
fixing the ropes.
We're at the-
at the Face's Step, over.
Rob, Mike.
- How's Doug doing?
- Doug's just behind me.
I left him behind
to scoot forward.
Yeah, I got eyes on you right now.
Yep, that's me.
Let's move this
as quickly as possible, over.
We'll start moving everybody up
as soon as we get the all clear.
Rob to base. Rob to base, Hel.
Copy, Helen.
- You alright?
- Copy. Base camp to Rob.
Have you... Have you
heard from Scott?
Anyone manage to find
out where he is, over.
Woo-Eee!
Yo, dude.
Look. Where are you, mate? We got a
real logjam here at the Hillary Step, over.
- I'm more than an hour behind.
- Just chill.
People just sitting there
using up their oxygen.
Get here as soon as you can.
- Oh my god. You okay, Beck?
- Yeah.
Oh I got a little problem with my eyes.
You guys turning back?
There's a logjam below
the Hillary Step.
It's crazy.
Come down with us.
No, I can't.
Promise Rob I'd wait for him.
- Your call.
- I'm good.
See you down there.
Neal.
Andy.
Okay, Anatoli.
I'm done.
All through.
Safe to climb.
Okay, we're climbing up!
- Hey, Mike.
- What?
- You mind if I go first?
- Why.
I'm running pretty low on "O".
Rob, it's Mike here.
Eh. We have the all clear
on this end.
I'm going to stay here with Yasuko
till we got a clear line.
I'll be here till I get a visual
on Doug. Over and out
* 01:14 PM *
We did it.
We did it!
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Mom.
* 02:00 PM *
Yasuko.
- Seven.
- 7 summits.
Come here.
I'm so proud of you, Yasuko.
So proud.
Thank you.
Rob to base.
Rob, this is Helen.
Hello, where are you?
I'm at the top of Everest, Helen.
We made it.
- Yeah.
- They did it.
Copy us, over.
Oh, we copy you
loud and clear, Rob.
It's wonderful to hear
your voice up there.
Who are you with again, Beck?
At the moment
I'm with Mike and Yasuko.
Good job, man.
Rob, see you.
Thank you.
Jon and Kasischke have
already been and gone.
Doug is just coming over the horizon.
And-And what about Beck?
Beck was having a problem
with his eye sight.
He waited on the Southeast Ridge,
on the Balcony.
For the first people
who came back, over.
And I... I guess you'll be
leaving right away, yes?
Moving off in a few minutes
just as soon I see Doug,
we'll be heading
back down, over.
Alright, understood.
Oh, that's terrific, Rob.
We're all keeping
our fingers cross for Doug.
Over and out, Helen.
- Congratulation.
- You're welcome.
Yeah, ladsy.
You did it.
Woo yee!
You look terrible.
My stories,
not so good, man.
- You see Doug?
- Oh, yeah. He's way way...
way back there, man.
Hey, Roberto.
Where're the rest of your guys.
'Cause I'm pretty sure
my whole team
made it up, yeah.
Heh heh heh.
I saw them.
Don't worry.
I won't tell Krakauer.
Hold on, mate.
I know it's bad, huh.
I'll have to give you this year.
Scott, you really
don't look too good.
- Lopsang.
- Yeah.
Come, mate.
Let's get him down.
Alright.
Let's go.
Harold.
What're you doing?
I'm just trying to
sort out the "O".
I can't find any full ones.
There's full bottles,
I saw them on the way up.
No.
So I pretty sure you
should have another look.
- No. They just have, they're not full.
- Harold. Listen, I saw...
Look, Mike.
I've checked twice, alright.
Yeah.
Alright, man.
I'm going down.
Harold.
03:15 PM
Doug. Doug.
Doug.
- It's over, mate.
- No.
I' sorry.
No no no no.
Doug.
You're too late, okay.
You guys keep going, mate,
I'll catch up.
Doug. Doug.
Doug, listen to me.
- It's way too long, it's over.
- No, it's not.
Now, listen to me, mate.
I'm sorry.
But I got to turn you around.
Okay.
I can do it.
It's right here, man.
It's right here.
I'm not coming back next year, man.
It's my last chance.
You got to let me do this.
Let me do this.
- Okay.
- Please, Rob.
- Let's do it. Let's get it done.
- Alright.
- Come on.
- Thanks, man.
Alright, Doug.
And there's no hope,
I get it.
My double wide trailer.
- Beck?
- What?
- Are you okay?
- Who is there?
- It's Jon.
- I'm not seeing too well, Jon.
I'm freezing.
Mike's just behind me.
He's back there with Yasuko.
You'll be okay.
Mike's right behind me.
You okay?
I'll see you then.
04:00 PM
- There she is.
(04:00 PM)
Almost there, mate.
Dig deep, Doug.
Dig deep.
There you go.
Yehhhh!
Huh, you made it.
You did it.
Huh.
Yeah.
Because of you, man.
Guy to Rob.
You read me, mate?
Are you there?
This going to the kids.
Yehhh!
Hang in there, Doug.
Come on.
Easy.
Here, I got it.
Yeah.
I'm okay.
Yeah, I got it.
- Come on, let's get you up.
- I need...
- Huh?
- Need more "O".
No, Doug.
We can't give you more "O".
We got to get down
to the South Summit, come on.
Guy calling to Everest Base Camp.
Are you there, Helen?
Guy, this is Helen.
How is it going?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I got a clear view of the Summit
and...
you know, we still got climbers up there.
They are not any of ours, right?
We got 3 up and
they're all on their way down.
Well. What are they
doing there so late?
And there's 2 o'clock turn around time,
they're way past it.
Here we go. Cloud coming out
of the valley. It's a lot of it.
Thanks.
I'm calling them now, Guy.
Rob, come in.
This is Helen.
Whoa!
Easy. Easy. Easy, Dougy.
There you go. There you go.
We're going to go
around the corner.
That's it.
Rob, is that you?
Beck?
It's Mike, mate.
- What're you doing here?
- I can't see, it's bad.
You guys alright?
We got a problem with Beck.
Hey, Mike.
We're getting low on "O".
We got to move.
I'll get you to stand up, okay.
- I'll take Yasuko.
- That's it.
I got you.
You're okay.
Doug, come on.
Come on.
I'm cold.
Oxygen level : 0
Mike, Harold, Ang Dorjee,
put the brakes on, guys.
We got a problem.
- We're out of gas, Doug.
- Alright.
We're out of gas. We need to
keep moving, come on.
Come on.
Mike, Harold, do you copy?
I need someone...
I need someone to come
back up with oxygen, over.
Somebody, please.
I'm begging you.
Doug, come on, mate.
Come on!
Harold, do you copy, over.
Has anyone got eyes
on Ang Dorjee?
Mate, I have just had Ang Dorjee
go past me heading down, over.
He's going down.
Can you stop him?
Can you turn him around?
I need someone
to come back up now.
Hey!
Ang Dorjee.
Ang Dorjee!
Base camp, do you copy, over.
Helen to Rob.
Go ahead.
Helen, please.
I need a bottle of gas
at the top of the Hillary Step.
I can't get him down
without it.
I'm really stuck.
Understood.
That you need a bottle of oxygen
at the bottom of the Hillary Step.
We're sending it up to you
as soon as we can.
At the top.
The last thing I said to
Ang Dorjee was please
bring 2 bottles of gas
at the South Summit.
Yes, uh.
Copy that, Rob.
Boys. There's oxygen
at the South Summit, right?
No, Rob!
This is Harold.
There's no oxygen
at South Summit.
Repeat.
No "O".
Ang Dorjee stashed
4 bottles there, Harold.
Harold, where are you?
Can you hear me, Harold?
Harold.
Harold, can you hear me?
Figure it'll take me about
half an hour to get back up
to the South Summit.
Okay.
I'm coming.
If you don't have oxygen, mate,
don't come up, don't come up.
We're moving on.
I'm coming up to you, Rob.
Doug, come on, mate.
Come on!
Rob, this is Base Camp.
I copy you, Carol.
Rob, can you get yourself down?
Carol, we're not
at that point yet.
Rob, can you let us know
who you're with?
I'm with Doug.
We're both listening.
Come on, Dougy. Come on, mate.
One more alping, come on.
Rob, what is Doug's
state of consciousness?
He's really weak.
He collapsed after he
ran out of oxygen.
Okay.
Give him 8 mg of dexamethasone.
That's 2 tablets, Rob.
Guy to Rob.
Go ahead Guy.
I got you, mate.
Rob, I suggest
you get yourself down.
You know you're doing
no good up there.
And we got people we can
send up there to help Doug,
but you got to get
yourself down, you understand?
I mean, come on, mate.
We're playing with a man's life here.
There's no way
I'm leaving Doug behind.
We got to keep moving, mate.
We got to keep moving,
we are in some trouble.
Yeah, Helen gonna... need some help.
So I'm gonna try make my way back.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Alright.
Go on.
Hey, Scott.
Scott.
You okay?
Lopsang.
I'm done, pal.
I'm done.
You go,
send Anatoli.
Send Anatoli back with some "O".
- Okay.
- Go.
Okay.
I will send back, Anatoli.
- Let's go.
- You go down.
No, mate.
No. I'm not leaving
you behind, Doug.
- Come on.
- Got to rest.
No, Doug! Come on!
Come on with me!
I need 10 good minutes, Doug.
Come on.
Please, let me go.
Damn it.
We're at the bottom of the Step.
Come on, this leg.
This leg, Dougy, come on.
Come on.
Here we go.
Oh no.
Hey. Hold it down.
Hold that down.
Come on, come on.
Get the chairs.
No, no, no.
Come on, Dougy!
Go, let's go!
Hurry up!
Doug. I'm going to go to
the South Summit to get oxygen.
Okay.
Got to find oxygen.
But, you got to stay here!
Okay, stay here!
Don't move, I'll be back!
Rob.
Hey, Rob.
Hey!
Stop!
That's the wrong way!
Hey!
Turn back!
Easy.
Hey, Rob!
Rob!
- I got...
- Harold?
I got oxygen.
Here.
I found some half empty ones.
Where's Doug?
Doug's gone.
What?
Gone.
- Come on.
- Go!
Come on!
Camp 4 is that way.
Get up!
Let's go.
Come on.
Beck.
I'll get help!
Neal!
- Anatoli.
- Where-Where are they?
They're still out there.
Jon!
I need help!
What?
Get out there!
I need help!
I can't.
I can't see, Anatoli.
I'm snow blind.
Beck.
Doug.
They need help.
They're still out there.
I go find them.
You stay here.
12:00 AM
Good job.
Hey!
Anatoli!
Need "O".
- Can you walk?
- I can't!
I'll come back!
I'll stay!
Give me that, come on.
- It won't budge. It's frozen!
- Take this.
The gloves.
I'm sorry.
Come on, mate.
Come on, Harold.
Thanks for coming back.
- Hello, Base Camp.
- Helen, it's Jan.
Why haven't I heard from you?
Why hasn't anybody call me?
They've been hit by a storm, Jan.
It's really bad.
- Where is he?
- We don't know exactly. But...
He was still on the Summit at 4:00.
Oh no.
Can he get down?
Rob can,
but Doug can't.
There's at least 13 people
stranded up there and...
while the storm is getting worse.
Helen!
Get Ang Dorjee up there.
He'll bring them down.
- Helen, do you understand?
- Helen. Give me an update.
Get Ang Dorjee up there.
Jan, yep.
We will get him.
And I will call you
the minute I hear from him.
- As soon as I hear from him.
- Thanks, Helen.
- Alright.
- Okay.
- Where is he?
- Guy, I haven't heard from him.
- Okay, I'll get him.
- I've been trying.
- Guy.
- Just hang on, hang on.
Rob, it's Guy.
Where are you?
Guy, I've been doing
that for the last 2 hours.
Alright. Alright.
Rob, it's Guy.
- Just keep your energy, mate.
- Helen.
Once you catch a break, you move.
You know the drill.
Hey, Guy. We got a stash of oxygen
on the South Col.
- Whoever needs it can have it.
- That's the way, thank you.
Faust's team are gonna go up,
they got a man to search,
as soon as they can.
Anyone who is going, we're going to
leave at dawn with the commity.
That's right, David.
Go and let Ed knows what's going on,
I'll be right behind you.
- Camp 4, come in.
- Okay, great.
Hey, Rob.  Rob, can you hear me?
( 03:00 AM )
David Breashears has a stash of oxygen
at the South Col that we can use.
Alright, mate. Well, we're all organizing
a team, we're coming to get you.
Burning up.
No.
Yasuko.
Ohhh.
Andy!
Come on!
Rob, talk to me, please. Pick up.
( Saturday, 11th May )
- Pick up, mate. Please
( 05:00 AM )
Was there any word
from the others?
Anatoli managed to get 3 climbers back
from the South Col last night. But...
Beck and Yasuko
are still out there.
They're trying
to mount a search
but everyone who's been
up there is exhausted.
- Base.
- Rob, is that you?
Rob, where are you?
We're sending people for you.
Rob, this is Base Camp.
I can't.
Can't move anymore.
Can't move anymore
Hey, mate. Yeah, I know.
I know, mate. I know.
You got to keep on moving.
Hands...
I can't feel my hands,
they're frozen.
There's "D" ice on the ice.
I got "D" ice in my mask.
That's good. You got to get
that mask working. You got to.
The sun's going to
come up and...
you know you can get warmer
and you can get moving.
- Guy.
- Yeah.
Guy.
Harold was here.
Where did he go?
Rob.
Is Doug with you?
Doug.
Doug's gone.
Harold is gone.
I'm going to need
a little help.
Okay.
Rob, you got to get yourself down.
Where are you?
Guy.
I'm in the...
in the little...
in the little dip just below
the South Summit.
Alright, you can do this.
You just got to, you know,
pull yourself out of that dip,
and slide the rest of the way.
Guy, send them boys.
Okay. I'm going to
need a little help.
I got some Sheapas coming
up there with tea and oxygen.
You just got to
come on down, mate.
Aye, come on down.
Rob.
Can you patch Jan through?
- To Rob?
- Pat-Patch her through.
Let's-Let's just try it.
Let's just...
put the satphone next to the radio
and uh.
If anyone can motivate him
to move, and Jan will.
Guy to Rob.
Can you read me?
- Rob, are you there?
- We're getting him now.
Rob, this is Helen.
Copy.
Rob, I got Jan for you.
My Jan?
Yeah. She's just here.
- Jan, you're on.
- Okay.
Hi, sweetheart.
How are you doing?
Hi, my love.
I'm a bit
a bit cold.
My love, I'm okay.
I know you are.
But the sun will warm you soon.
Sweetheart.
You got to get moving.
You got to come on down.
My hands...
frozen.
My...
My feet are frozen.
We're sending people up to you
with tea and "O"s
But, you got to get moving, Rob.
Can you hear me?
You got to get
your circulation going.
Okay, my love.
You do it.
Do it right now!
I love you.
Over and out.
Come on, Rob.
We can't carry them.
That's not possible.
He's correct.
It's going to take "O"
just to get ourselves down.
Oh, damn it.
Helen, it's Mike here.
Do you copy?
Come in, Mike.
What do you got?
Yasuko and Beck,
did not make it
back to camp.
Okay, Mike.
Thanks for letting us know.
[NOT RETURNED]
[SOUTH COL, CAMP 4]
Meg.
Bud.
Hello, Base Camp.
Ang Dorjee, this is Helen.
We have to turn back!
There is the very
bad storm again.
- Your call, Ang Dorjee.
- Sorry.
We'll try to do again,
when the storm pass.
We'll leave some tea
and oxygen here.
Sorry.
We have to tell Rob
they're not coming.
Okay.
Hey, Rob.
It's Guy, mate.
Guy.
I can't stop shaking, Guy.
The boys hit a bit of a high wind.
And...
your best shot is going
to be to get lower.
Let me think about it.
Don't think I can hang out
here another night.
We'll try again first thing, okay.
Helen?
Yeah.
Yeah, he's still there.
He's just below the South Summit.
He's got oxygen
but...
it's iced up.
We don't know whether
he's been able to free it.
Is anybody with him?
No.
You have to get him down before dark.
He won't survive another night.
We know.
But the storms come back,
real bad.
We can't get anyone
up to him tonight.
We tried.
He might as well
be on the moon.
Uh.
Can you put me on
with him again?
Of course.
Guy.
Get Rob.
Hi, Rob.
It's Guy.
I've got Jan for you.
Hold on.
Give me a second.
Okay.
Hi, sweetheart.
How are you?
I'm thinking about you.
Please say, "I'm good."
Are you warm, my love.
I might have a little frostbite.
I'm looking forward
to making it all better.
Can't wait for you
to come home.
How's Sarah?
Sarah?
Yeah.
Yes, Sarah is good.
Will you call her that for me?
Yes, I will.
I don't think I'm going
to get to meet her.
I'm so sorry.
Don't say that.
If anyone can make it, you can.
Remember.
I love you.
Please don't worry too much.
Good bye, my love.
I love you, Rob.
I love you.
(Come on.)
(Come on, Dad.)
Beck.
Helen, it's Mike here.
Helen, do you copy?
Mike, come in.
Beck's still alive.
He walked himself into camp.
I got to get him down to Camp 1.
Thanks, Mike.
We don't even know how,
but he is alive.
The thing is, Peach,
we can't get him down the Icefall.
Oh no.
I'll get him down.
- I'll get him down. Okay.
- Dad.
Okay, what do we need?
We need a helicopter, right?
Yeah, but they can't a helicopter up
that high because the air is too thin.
We should try, but it is
one heck of a rescue.
And he's not in a
good way, Peach.  So...
I don't want you to get
your hopes up too high.
1 step at a time.
- You got to keep moving.
- I'm tired.
- I know.
I know you are.
I know you are. Come on.
Slow and steady.
Come on, keep moving.
Yes, I like the number of the
American Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal.
Yes, Nepal.
Ambassador, please.
No. Sweets, I can't hold.
No.
You listen, sir.
My husband has already died once
as you've seen on the news.
Trust me. Having him die a second
time is not going to play well on CNN.
There we go, buddy.
That's it, alright.
CAMP TWO
- Beck.
- Uh-huh.
How're you doing?
Oh, you know,
third amendment.
Warming up?
I'm not sure yet.
Look like you are,
a little bit.
How's Rob doing?
Rob's still up there right now.
And Doug,
what's he up to?
Doug's gone, Beck.
I don't know. No one's ever try
to fly higher than Base Camp before.
They gonna give it a go.
And find an LZ. Just mark up
with whatever you can.
Okay.
Worth a try.
Thanks, Guy.
Grab a Gatorade.
Got a chopper coming in.
We need to make a LZ
We got a chopper coming in!
- Clear the rope back to the tents!
- Okay.
Thanks.
Keep it clear.
Keep this whole area clear.
Come on.
We're doing fine.
It's not possible.
You land here,
we'll never get back up.
Okay, Major, let's go back.
- That's it.
- Can't get any more out.
it's as light as
we're going to get it.
- Tango to Charlie.
Right here!
Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, Beck.
Nearly there.
Okay.
Come on.
1 person.
- Only 1 person.
- Just him, just 1.
- Alright.
- There you go.
You good?
I'm going to lift the tail up.
Fly us over the edge.
- Is that okay with you?
- I'm with you.
Good, man.
Get yourself inside, go on.
It's alright, Anatoli.
I'm so sorry, Helen.
Come on.
Let's get you inside.
Hi, Peachy.
Beck.
Thank you so much, darling.
Oh, Jan.
I'm so sorry.
Rob's body remains on the mountain
alongside the others who lost their lives.
Scott Fischer
Andy 'Harold' Harris
Doug Hansen
Yasuko Namba
Adventure Consultants Team 1996
Beck Weathers lost both hands and his nose.
He still lives in Dallas with his wife, Peach.
In July 1996, Jan gave birth to a baby girl.
She named her Sarah.
Sarah Arnold-Hall